Welcome to Section 4 and this section you're going to explore the subscription operation.
So with queries we can fetch data with mutations we can change data with subscriptions as the name suggests
we can subscribe to data changes.
So imagine I use a query to fetch something like a post I get the title and the body.
But if those values change I don't get those changed values I would have to manually send off another
query to get the new information with a subscription.
We can actually subscribe to data and get notified in real time when changes occur because subscriptions
use web sockets that allows for a bidirectional real time communication between the server and the client.
Now all of this is going to allow us to add real time features to our app so we could render comments
for a post as they come in.
We can show notifications if your favorite author publishes a new post or we could do anything else
that requires real time apps.
All right let's go ahead and jump right into the section and see how to use subscriptions.