In this video you're going to be setting up and executing your very first subscription allowing the
client to subscribe to data changes on the server.
In essence the subscription operation is similar to the queery operation because its main concern is
allowing your client whether it's graft you a playground or a web application to fetch the data that
it needs.
So with queries we can get data we need with subscriptions we can also get data we need.
The difference is in how the data is fetched.
So when we perform a query like this one we send it off to the server and the server responds.
A single time with all of the data.
At that point in time if one of these comments got deleted or edited or an additional comment was made
the client would not be notified.
It would be up to the client to make the same request later to check for changes in the data.
This ends up leading to server polling where we run this operation from our client every minute in an
attempt to keep our client up to date in an attempt to show real time data to the user.
This is not ideal though because it's expensive and it requires us to perform operations every minute
or so in which case a lot of times the data hasn't changed and it's just wasting resources with the
subscription we actually use web sockets to keep an open connection between the client and the server
that allows the server to transmit data directly to the client.
That means that if someone does add a new comment to one of the posts the server can add that comment
then it can push that comment in real time down to all of the subscribed clients so they can get the
new comment data and they can render it to the UI keeping their application up to date.
In effect creating a real time application where you're seeing the latest data as it changes.
Now the process for setting up a subscription is a bit more complex than setting up a query or a mutation.
So in this video we're not going to worry about creating a subscription that actually makes sense in
the context of our blogging application.
We're just going to create a little dummys subscription that will eventually delete.
The goal is to explore how we can set all of this up.
Then in the next video we'll see how we can start to configure our application to use subscriptions.
For example allowing someone to actually subscribe to comments and get notified whenever a comment gets
created updated or deleted but now that we're going to work on creating that dummy subscription.
So let's head over to our schema file just like we define all of our queries and all of our mutations.
We also have to define all of our subscriptions in our type definition for this little dummy example.
We're going to create a subscription that just counts up from zero something super simple.
So you start off by getting zero Back then every second you get back the next number one to three and
so on.
So in the end of the day we're going to perform one operation to subscribe a single time.
And over here we're going to end up getting a stream of data back.
We'll be getting back a new number every second.
Now for the moment we'll be getting back a new number every second later on though we'll be getting
back new comments as they're created a more real world use case.
Let's go ahead and kick things off though by defining the type right here.
We're going to define the subscription type.
So that's type subscription and what goes inside of year are the various subscriptions we want to support.
So I might have one subscription allowing someone to subscribe to comment changes.
I might have they another one allowing someone to subscribe to changes in posts for our purposes what
we're going to do is set up a single subscription called count.
Now the actual syntax for doing this is going to look pretty similar.
We give it a name just like we named our mutations and our queries and we can also choose to set up
arguments.
But for this dummy one we're not going to have any arguments.
We'll explore that in a little bit.
And we're going to move right on to what comes back.
So when you subscribe to count what data do you get back in for this one we're going to say that you
get back an integer so you're going to get back 0 first then you'll get back 1 2 and 3 what you get
back is always going to be an int.
Now just like with queries and mutations we have to set up a new route property on our resolver.
So if you remember from our refactoring the resolver now gets set up over here an index dot J s.
But the actual methods live in separate files will be creating a new file for all of our subscriptions.
So I'm going to add one new file into resolvers.
I'm going to call this subscription dot J.
S and in here we're going to create a subscription object.
So Konst subscription equals an object will be defining just a single thing online or in a moment.
For now though let's go ahead and actually export that.
I am going to export subscription as the default export and from here what we need to do is set that
up an index.
J.
S..
So we actually want to go ahead and inport it.
Then add it on to resolvers down below.
First up let's inport it right below where I inport query nutation.
I'm going to inport subscription from any file that we just created.
So Dot forward slash it lives in the resolvers directory and in there it was uppercase s subscription.
Once again we can leave off that file extension.
So it would be fine to add it on.
The last thing we have to do is set that up to actually be on the revolver's object.
So right here I'm going to set the subscription property equal to the subscription variable using the
object property shorthand syntax.
Now before we go ahead and add anything into the subscription object there's one more thing we have
to configure with our graphical server to talk about this.
I actually want to pull up the documentation for graphical yoga.
So we're going to pull up the get hub repository page graft Well hyphen yoga if you Google and it should
bring you over to the right location.
And what I'm interested in talking about here is not actually graphical yoga itself but one of the libraries
that this library uses.
So if you remember from much much earlier in the class I mentioned that GRATHWOHL Yoga is great because
it comes preconfigured with everything you need to get started writing graph Cuil code down below.
We can see a lot of the libraries that are used behind the scenes and we're going to have to use one
called graph.
Well subscriptions to get things to work in this video.
Now in the end of the day what graph queue or subscriptions provides us is a simple pub sub utility
so we can use the pub publish and sub subscribe features to allow us to communicate around our application.
So if we scroll down a little bit there is a little information on exactly how all of this works.
In the end of the day what we're going to do is inport something we're going to create a new pub sub
instance then we're going to use just two methods on that to wire everything up.
Now it's not necessary to understand what's going on here.
That's the whole purpose of this video.
But what I do want to do is dive in to actually configuring that to do this.
We're going to move over to index dot J S and we're going to be grabbing something new off of graph
Cuil yoga like graphs you all server it is a named export.
This one is called pub sub that is uppercase P and uppercase s.
And this is the constructor function allowing us to create a new pub sub utility.
So down below what are we going to do.
We're going to create one right here.
Konst pub sub in lower case equals a new instance of pub sub.
We're calling it like so with the new keyword to create a new instance.
And now this is something that we want to pass to all of our resolvers we need to be able to use this
directly from our subscription methods which means that we need to add it on to the context to make
it something that's easy to share across all of our resolver methods Sudan below.
All we're going to do is add pub sub onto the context object alongside of our D-B property.
So what have we done so far.
We've set up a brand new file to contain our subscriptions.
We've created a new instance of something called pub sub but we have no idea what it does or how it
works.
That's OK.
And we've set up pub sub to live on our context so it's accessible from all of our resolver methods.
Now we're actually done with index dot J S and we're going to head over to that subscription file and
figure out how pub sub actually helps us create these real time subscriptions.
So let's talk about what goes inside of here.
For every subscription we have to set up a new property the property name needs to match up with the
subscription name.
In this case we have just one and we chose to call it count.
That means over here we just set up one property called count.
Now unlike queries and mutations the value for count is actually not a method it needs to be an object.
And on this object we set up a single method.
Subscribe right here subscribe and subscribe is what runs every time someone tries to subscribe to count
later on they'll be subscribing to things like comments or posts.
For the moment though this is exactly what we want now.
This is indeed a regular old resolver method and it gets called with all of those same arguments.
So unsubscribe we get access to parent.
We get access to args to context and to info and we can use all of them inside of here.
For the moment we're actually only going to be using one.
We're going to be using context.
And the only thing we're going to be using off of context is the little pub sub utility that we just
set up.
So right here instead of accessing context dot pub sub.
Every time I want to use it I'm just going to deep structure it.
So right here I will destructuring pub sub breaking it out into its very own standalone variable.
Now down below we're going to go through the two necessary steps to set the subscription up.
One we are going to set up these subscription and two we're going to publish data to it.
So let's start by creating our count.
Let count equal zero.
We're going to start at zero.
We're going to increment by one every second sending the new count back to all of the subscribers.
Now when it comes to the return value things are a bit different than with queries or with mutations.
So with a mutation the return value just matches up with whatever's defined over in the schema for create
user return a user and the same is true with queries for our posts query return an array of posts with
subscriptions.
We do not return an integer.
Instead we return something that comes from our little pub sub utility.
So right here we return pub at sub dot and we call a method on it.
It's called async iterator async iterator is a function so we're going to call it as such and it takes
a single argument.
This is a string.
And the value here is what's called a channel name.
So we're going to have channel names for all sorts of things and you can think of a channel name kind
of like a chat room name and something like these slack a chat application.
I might have one called General another called a random and one called off topic.
For example we're going to pick a name that fits our purposes.
I'm just going to call this something simple like count.
Now from here we actually have a valid subscription it's just not going to publish any changes.
Let's go ahead and test things out as they currently stand though.
So what are we going to do.
We're going to save subscription.
J.
S. And we're going to head over to graft Google playground over on the right hand side.
Let's go ahead and add a single new tab.
And we're going to subscribe to count so right here what do we do.
We start off with the operation name subscription then we go ahead and pick what we're trying to subscribe
to.
We have just one option over here we just have count.
So we're going to name that out.
Now if Count took arguments we would provide them but it doesn't and if count returns something like
an object it would provide a selection set but count returns an integer.
So this is actually all we need.
If we go ahead and run this what's going to happen.
Well you can see that graph Q playground isn't getting any data back it's not resolving.
It's still pending.
It's actually listening for changes so it's waiting for the server to push data down to the client and
when it does that new data will show up here whether it's new posts new comments or in this case just
a new number.
That means we're not quite done with the code from our subscription file right here but we're going
to do is use set interval so set interval is going to allow us to run some code after X milliseconds.
In this case we're just going to wait a thousand milliseconds which equals to 1 second.
It takes those two arguments.
The first is the code to run.
The second is the time you want to wait in milliseconds.
As I just mentioned we'll be using 1000.
And inside of here we need to do two things we need to 1 increase that count so count plus plus gets
that done.
And the second thing we have to do is publish our data by calling pub sub dot publish.
So async iterator is what sets up our channel and publish is what allows us to publish new data to all
of the subscribers.
So right here we pass into arguments to publish.
The first is that channel name we have to match it up exactly with the only channel we currently support
count then we pass in an object as the second argument.
And this is where we specify that data that should get sent to the client.
Now this is where things need to start matching up with our subscription type.
So right here we have an integer what are we going to do.
We are going to set up a count property that matches up with the subscription name and we're going to
give it a value that is an integer in this case.
We have that value stored on the count variable.
Now obviously here since we have a property name whose value is coming from a variable with the same
name we can use the object property shorthand and there we go.
We are now all done.
We can save a subscription database and test this out.
Now we had over to graph Q UL playground you are going to notice we have an error.
That is because we saved our file and restarted the server and we temporarily lost our connection.
This is OK and totally expected but we're going to do is start the subscription up again and you'll
notice that after one second what happens data starts flowing in.
And here we can see that every second comes with new data.
So we're already up to a count of nine.
Each time the data comes from the server what do we get.
We get an object with the data property on there we have our count property and the value of that is
the latest count stored as an integer.
So we went from 1 to 23 and this would continue on for as long as we let it.
Now at this point we have indeed set up a subscription but it's not doing anything meaningful in terms
of our blogging application.
So I don't expect it to be 100 percent clear how all of this actually works.
Later on for example we're not going to be publishing from inside of the resolver method where we set
up the subscription.
I would be publishing from something like one of our mutations.
So if I was listening for new users I would be publishing some data right here after a new user is added.
So don't worry too much if you're not quite clear on how the subscription works or how this is going
to be useful for our purposes.
This was just a little introductory example allowing us to get comfortable with the syntax throughout
this section.
We are going to start integrating subscriptions into our application in a meaningful way that actually
serves a purpose.
We'll be starting that process in the very next video.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.
I'm super excited to figure out how we can subscribe to comments and posts.