In the last video you explore the basics of how subscriptions get set up.
But we did not explore a real world example in this video we are going to move on to a more real world
example of subscriptions and we're actually going to create two subscriptions that integrate with our
blogging application.
We're going to create one for subscribing to new comments on a particular post.
So you'll be able to get all of the comments as they're added in real time.
And you're going to create a second subscription allowing you to get new posts.
So whenever someone publishes a new post you'll be notified and you'll actually be able to do something
with that data like render it to the list of posts you're showing on the client.
So to take all of this off.
Let's go ahead and move in to schema data graph.
Q Well this is where we are going to set up one of those two subscriptions for the moment.
We're going to start with a subscription that allows you to subscribe to new comments for a post right
here.
We are going to call that one comment.
Now count return an individual number comment is going to return an individual comment.
The comment that was just created.
So we are going to use the comment object type as the value that comes back.
Now as I mentioned with a comment we are indeed going to take in an argument and the syntax for that
is going to be identical to the argument syntax for queries and for mutations we are going to take in
a single argument called post ID whose value is going to be required ID.
So in this case we are allowing you to subscribe to new comments for particular post.
You do have to provide the ID of the post you're trying to subscribe to now that we have this in place.
Our schema definition is actually all done for this first subscription and we can move in to subscription
data J S and start working on the resolver method.
So once again we have it count for our count subscription.
If we have a new comment subscription we're going to create a new comment object and comment is indeed
just an object and on there we add our subscribe method.
So right here we have subscribed and we have all of the same arguments we've come to expect.
We are going to have parent who are going to have args we are going to have context and we're going
to have info in here.
It's our job to one determine if that post actually exists and if it's published and then to return
an async iterator with a good channel name.
So let's talk about exactly how we can get both of those done.
First up verifying that the post ID is of a real published post that's pretty easy to write here.
All I'm going to do is structure args to get the data we have.
We just have one thing post ID and then we're going to set up a little system just like we did before.
I'm going to use find to try to find the post and then I'll throw an error if no post is found.
So Konst right here post equals.
I'm going to look over D-B Doc posts since I'm going to use D-B.
I will destructuring context right here.
Grabbing D-B perfect once again that is D-B dot posts dot find we are looking for posts that match the
following criteria.
First up the post ID needs to equal the posts ID that was actually passed in.
So here we are grabbing the id property off of the saved post and we're comparing it to the post ID
the argument provided to the comment subscription.
We also want to make sure it's published so we'll use the logical and operator looking at post.com published
to make sure it's true.
So right here post got published.
Now if we did not find anything will throw an error.
So if there is no post what are we going to do.
I'm going to throw a new error and what does provide an error message something along the lines of post
not found.
Now if there actually was a post that means you are good to go and you can actually subscribe to that
data right here.
We're going to set that up using the following.
We're just going to use pub sub Dom async iterator.
Once again I am going to deep structure pub sub off of the Context object just like I did for D-B.
Then down below we can return a call to pub sub Dom async iterator This allows us to once again provide
a channel name.
And in this case the channel name needs to contain that post ID.
I wanted channel specific to the comments for this post.
So something like comment Colan one where one is the post ID.
Or maybe you want to put it all in uppercase like it's a constant comment space followed by the post
ID.
There actually is no standard for what these channel names look like.
The only important thing is that you a pick a pattern and B stick with it throughout your entire application.
So I'm going to use a template string so I can easily inject that post ID and I'm just going to use
the actual subscription name and all lowercase.
Followed by the space followed by the post ID.
So right here I will inject that post ID so if the post ID was 44 the channel name would be the following
comment space 44.
Just like this.
Now this actually wraps up what we need to do in subscription.
J S.
This file is all done.
We first verify that the post exists then and we go ahead and actually return the async iterator which
allows the subscription to actually happen.
All we need to do is use pub sub dot publish in the correct moment.
Now when do comments get created.
Well comments get created over inside of our mutation database file.
We have the Create comment method.
This is exactly where comments get created.
So this is the best place to call pub sub dot publish since we are going to be calling the Publish method
on the pub sub object.
I am going to also DB structure that from the context object.
Now down below.
Let's say right after we push the comment onto the comments array we're going to call pub sub DUP publish
with the correct information.
Remember we have to provide those two arguments.
The first is the channel name and the second is the actual data for trying to publish.
Let's start with that first argument and once again the channel name is comment space followed by the
post ID.
Now we do have access to the post ID we've actually used it above args dot data.
That post is where we can access that value.
So right here we are just going to add that in.
That would be args data dot post.
Now the second argument is our object and on there we have to provide a value for the comment property
remember.
This matches up with the subscription name its value needs to be whatever we expected to come back right
here.
An instance of commet I mean actually already have that on the comment variable up above.
So we have a comment property with the value coming from a common variable.
We can just use the shorthand syntax for that.
And there we go.
We now have our comment subscription all set up and we can actually test this out over inside of graph.
Well now I am going to head over to DB Dhananjay.
Yes real quick and point out that we only have two published posts.
We can work with the post with an ID of 10 or the post with an ID of 12.
Those are two options.
So let's go ahead and head over to graft UL playground and actually test things out.
Now we could create a new tab but since the account subscription is going to get deleted shortly we
can actually just repurpose this one for our needs.
Right here I am going to remove count and replace it with comment and then we're going to set up the
one argument we know we need to pass in post ID.
We can use either the value 10 or 12.
Or you could create a new post and use its randomly generated ID.
I'll just stick with 10 for the moment and we know that comment sends a comment object back.
So we do have to provide a selection set determining what we want from each comment.
I'm going to say that I would like the comment ID.
I would also like the comment text and that also like a little bit of information about the author who
made the comment.
So right here I can grab the author asking for its ID and will say I'd also like the author name.
And there we go.
We now have our subscription all set up.
We can fire this off to allow it to start listening then we can create some new comments and make sure
that things react correctly.
I'm going to go ahead and fire this one off and we can see that it is indeed now listening.
And then we can move over to the tambour we can create comments and we can start creating some comments
now right here the data I already have in place does indeed work with post 10 which is great.
So you don't have to make any changes to the Create comment mutation.
We can go ahead and fire this one off.
We can see the new comment was created and we should have a notification about that over in our comment
subscription tab.
I'm going to click over to that one.
End right here we can see that we have indeed gotten just one notification about a new comment my new
comment with the idea that we just saw it generated and we also have our information about the author
we have the authors ID and the author's name.
Now in this case we are indeed seeing the data because the comment was made on post 10.
Let's go ahead and change the Create comment mutation to work with a different post.
Post 12.
So right here I'm going to change the post ID over to 12.
I'm going to fire that mutation off the comment was created and this time around we should not have
a notification about it.
If I click over to the subscription tab we should see nothing.
And we are seeing nothing because we did indeed create that comment on a post other than the one we
subscribed to.
Now one last test if I try to subscribe to post 11 things you should fail because post 11 is not published.
If I go ahead and try to create the subscription we can see that it crashes with the posts not found
error.
So there we go.
Everything is working really well so far allowing our clients to subscribe to new comments for particular
post later on in this section will also learn how we can subscribe to comment updates and comments being
removed as well.
But for the moment this is a great starting point.
That's where we're going to stop for this one in the next video which is a challenge video.
It's going to be up to you to use what you learned about subscriptions to create another subscription.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.