In this challenge video it's going to be up to you to create a brand new subscription using what you've
learned so far with the comment to subscription already in place you're going to be creating a brand
new subscription called Post allowing the client to subscribe to new posts so they'll be able to get
notified whenever a new post is published.
There are a few steps for getting this done.
So let's go ahead and work through all four of these then I'll give you some time to actually knock
this out.
First up the big picture goal is to create a subscription for the new posts and there are four steps
to solving this challenge.
Step one is to actually define the new post subscription over inside of your type definitions.
There are no arguments necessary for this one.
And the response should just be a post object much like the response for the comment subscription is
just a comment object.
Now step two is where we actually define the resolver or subscribe method for the new subscription.
Since there are no arguments you can use a generic channel name something like post would work just
fine.
We're not concerned about subscribing to posts from a particular user.
We're just concerned about getting all posts so we're just going to have a single channel name for this
subscription.
Now that means that the SUBSCRIBE method is going to be very very short just a single line where you
return the async iterator.
That brings us to step three.
You're going to modify the mutation where new posts get created and you're going to publish the new
post data just like we did for creating comments.
Now there's only one catch to this.
When a comment is created it's always public but when a post is created it might have its published
value set to false meaning it's a draft post.
We only want to call pub sub dot publish if the new post was created with a published value set to true.
Now if the published value is set to false it can always be published later inside of the update.
Post mutation.
We're not going to worry about that for the moment you only have to modify create post.
You do not need to touch update post or delete posts.
We'll handle that later.
So in this case the subscription is only going to fire if someone creates a new post and when they create
it the published value is set to true.
The last step is to test your work.
So you're going to create a subscription to actually listen for the posts.
Then you're going to go ahead and define a few new posts that are indeed published when they start getting
created and that should fire off the subscription.
So take as much time as you need to actually knock this one out.
Feel free to refer to anything we've done so far.
Pause the video.
Test your work and when you're done click play.
How that go.
Let's go ahead and move through these steps one at a time starting with step one.
We're going to define our post subscription in schema graph.
Q Well over here we're going to call it post.
We're not setting up any arguments just like we didn't set up any arguments for count.
And what comes back is indeed going to be a post object.
Perfect.
So there we go.
Step one.
All done.
That brings us to step 2 which is to actually define our resolver inside of subscription.
J S.
I'm going to add that just below the comment object.
So right here we need a post object.
Then we have to set up the SUBSCRIBE method for a post naming.
All of those arguments we have parent we do indeed have args.
We also have the context which I'm just going to do structure to grab.
Pub sub since I know I'm going to use that.
And finally we have info awesome down below.
What do we need to do.
All we have to do is return pub sub dot async iterator and we're going to use a generic channel name
like post perfect.
That is it for step 2.
That brings us to step 3 which is to modify the mutation where new posts get created.
So I'm going to save this file and we're going to move over to mutation.
Dot J.
As I believe it is above just a little bit where we have the Create post method inside of here.
We want to actually publish the post if it was indeed created with the published value set to true.
We could actually just add an if statement right here to check that.
If args dot data dot published is true.
What are we going to do.
We are going to call pub sub dot publish to actually publish that data.
Now currently we do not have access to pub sub let's destruction that off the context object as well.
And now we can provide the two things necessary.
The first is the channel name we used post.
The second is an object with the post property set equal to the post object.
I already have a variable with the name post so we can use the object shorthand to get that done.
And there we go.
That is step three.
This brings us to the final step which is step 4.
Testing our work we can go ahead and do that by creating a brand new subscription.
One new tab right here I'm going to use the subscription operation we are then going to set up a subscription
to post since there are no arguments necessary we're not going to provide anything but we are going
to provide our selection set.
So in a new post is created I'm going to ask for the ID.
I'm going to ask for the title of an ask for the body as well.
And I'm also going to ask for some info about the author.
Let's go ahead and grab the authors ID and name Serat here author ID and author name.
Excellent.
If I refreshed the application schema this should turn into a valid subscription operation.
And now we can actually go ahead and fire that off.
Here it is indeed listening for new posts to be created.
So let's go ahead and test things out.
I'm going to move over to our create post mutation tab.
Now in this case we're creating a post but published is set to false.
So if I fire this off it does indeed create the post but I should see no change over my subscription
tab since we did not create a post whose published value is true.
Let's go ahead and move back to that tab and actually create a new public post.
So right here we have our create post mutation.
I'm going to change published to true and I'll just change the title a published post.
If I go ahead and fire this one off we can see that the post was indeed created with our title and the
correct published value this time since the post was created as published.
We should see a notification over here.
If I click over to the post subscription tab I do indeed have a new post data showing up.
I had my ID the title we picked the body and I also have some information about the author who wrote
the post.
So there we go.
That is it for this challenge.
We can now go ahead and clean things up just a little bit over inside of our project.
I'm going to remove the challenge comments.
We can delete all of them and I'm also going to remove the count subscription.
That helped us explore how subscriptions work but it's not going to make it into the final version of
the app so I'm going to delete it from subscription.
J s.
And I'm also going to remove it from our subscription type definition.
Perfect.
Now we have two subscriptions in place.
We have comment which allows us to get new comments for a particular post and we have post which allows
us to get new posts that are published.
We're going to continue on with this section exploring all of the other different operations that we
can subscribe to.
Whether it's something being updated or deleted.
I'm excited to continue on with subscriptions.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the very next video.