In this video we're going to continue to talk subscriptions and we're actually going to expand on the
comment and post subscriptions that we already have.
So let's take a quick moment to talk about the three main ways we can mutate data.
Data can be created.
Data can be updated and data can be deleted.
We want to notify subscribers.
In the case of all three currently both comment and post only notify subscribers in the case of that
first one when data is created.
So if I were to subscribe to all comments for post-flood then I am indeed going to get all new comments
for post 11.
The problem though is that if a comment gets updated or a comment gets deleted altogether the client
does not get notified about those changes and that kind of defeats the purpose of subscriptions.
The whole point of being able to subscribe to data is to keep the client and the server in sync.
So when a new comment comes in I want to show that to the screen but when a comment gets edited or deleted
I also want to update the UI to reflect that as well.
So all we need to do is make some changes to how we're structuring our type definitions for both of
our subscriptions.
Then we're going to add some additional pub sub calls into the mix.
In this video we'll be working on the post subscription together and in the next video as a challenge
you'll be working on expanding the comment subscription.
Now one change we're gonna need to make before we add more pub Sabat published calls has to do with
the data that's getting sent back.
When someone subscribes if you subscribe to comment.
What you get back as a comment if you subscribe to post what you get back is a post.
So for example we have our comment subscription over here and if I scroll up we can see the exact data
we got back just a couple of videos ago.
We have an object with the data property.
Then we have the common property.
Then we have all of the data we actually requested about that newly created comment.
Imagine if we continued to publish in this fashion for when a comment was updated or when a comment
was deleted it would not be clear exactly why I'm getting this comment back.
Am I getting this comment back because it's a new comment and I should be showing it to the UI.
Am I getting this comment back because it's updated and I should replace the text with the new text.
Or am I getting this comment back because this comment has actually been deleted.
In which case I should remove it from the user interface.
It's not clear to the subscriber the client why exactly this data is coming back to it.
So we're going to do is include along side of this data.
A simple string field the field name is going to be mutation and it is going to store one of three values.
Either the string created the string updated or the string deleted.
That's going to give the subscriber enough context to figure out what it should do.
Now don't knock that out.
All we're going to do is change the value that comes back from both of these subscriptions.
We're going to start together with.
Post what we're going to do is return a different object.
It is still going to contain the post data but it's also going to contain one additional field.
We're actually going to create a brand new typedef for this.
So let's add that down below.
At the very bottom of the file We're going to define a new custom object type using the type keyword
and then we're going to give this a name.
I'm going to call this post subscription payload so subscription payload is a common suffix for what
we're doing here.
The payload that we're defining that comes back from a post and then the initial word is just the actual
subscription name.
So right here the subscription is post.
So we start with post then it is actually the subscription payload so we add subscription payload afterwards.
This is a common naming convention you'll see used throughout the graph.
Ecosystem.
Now what exactly is coming back from the post subscription payload.
Well we're going to get two things.
One is going to be our new field mutation which is going to be a non nullable string.
So you're always going to get a string back that describes what type of mutation actually triggered
this event.
The other thing you're going to get is the actual data.
So in this case the data under the data field would just be the post exactly like we already have.
So now we have our new post subscription payload type and we can actually use that as opposed to the
one we're currently using up above.
I'm going to remove post and replace it with post subscription payload and this will also be a non nullable
field.
So you will never get notified about an event if the Post's subscription payload is not actually provided.
Perfect.
So this is all we have to change inside of schema.
Well we can actually save this file and we actually don't need to make any changes to subscription.
Jay as this subscribe method is still perfect it's exactly what we want.
All of the additional changes need to happen over in mutations.
J s starting with the one pub sub published call that we already have that is publishing to the post
channel.
This needs to be altered to reflect the new structure that we just set up where we have the mutation
field and the data field to start.
I am going to wipe everything we have in the object so far and I'm going to break it out on two separate
lines since we'll be adding in multiple properties.
And here we do still need that root post property.
This time though instead of being the post data it now is an object that matches up with the type we
just created.
So this is an object that needs those two fields.
It needs mutation with a string value and it needs data that contains our post object.
So let's set both up right here.
We're going to start off with nutation setting an equal to a string and I'm going to be using uppercase
letters for this either upper case created upper case updated or upper case deleted.
In this case it is a created based mutation.
Next up is our data.
So we have that data property set equal to and in this case all of the post data lives on that post
variable.
So we reference the post variable like so perfect.
Now if you're wondering why this is upper case it's just a common convention for some constants like
this.
It would be just fine to use lowercase or to call it whatever you want.
This is merely a stylistic choice.
It is not enforced in any way whatsoever by graft UL or the pub sub mechanism.
Now that we have this in place we can actually save mutation dot J S and test things out.
So far I should be able to subscribe to posts create a new one and see our new structure showing up
over in GRATHWOHL playground.
I am going to switch over to that post tab and we are going to need to make a few small changes to the
structure.
Remember post is no longer sending back the post date which is what we're currently selecting post instead
is sending back that object with the mutation and with the data fields are going to grab both.
We're going to grab mutations so we know what kind of mutation triggered that event.
And we're also going to grab data and from there we will provide a selection set asking for some information
about.
In this case the post I'm going to ask for the ID I'll ask for the title for the body and some info
about the author.
I'll ask for the authors ID and the author's name so I can display those as well.
Now we're going to be able to first refresh that schema to see that our current operation is valid.
I'm then going to run with the subscription and we can see down below that it's listening and the last
thing we have to do is create a new post.
I'm going to scroll over to that create post tab.
We can run the Create post mutation exactly as we have it since it is creating a post with published
set to true.
Once it's created we can go back over to the post subscription tab and right here I do indeed see my
object.
We now have the data property in the post property which we had before.
This time though we are getting the mutation type so we can see that this event fired because some data
was created.
In this case the comment data shown below.
So now we have successfully set up the created mutation status for that one we already had in place
for the one in create post.
Next up let's go ahead and knock out delete.
Post.
So when a post gets deleted We also want to respond accordingly.
And now this is where things get a little bit tricky when we're deleting a post.
We don't always want to alert subscribers because the post might be a draft post so if I'm writing a
draft for a post and I decide to delete it because the story I shared is a bit embarrassing I don't
want to send that embarrassing story out to all subscribers.
When I didn't even publish it in the first place so it's important that we add that conditional check
in.
I'm going to start by destructuring pub sub right here.
Then down below after the comment actually gets removed we're going to check if it was published.
So if and in the if condition we're going to look at the deleted posts published property.
So we look at the deleted posts or we grab that first and only item then we access its published property.
If that's true this code is going to run.
And in that case it is safe to run pub sub dot publish to alert people that the Post has been deleted.
So right here we do need to provide the two arguments necessary first our channel name posts and second
the correct data.
This time we have that route post property.
We're going to have a mutation value equal to the string deleted and then we're going to have that data
property equal to the deleted post itself which once again is in the deleted posts or accessing that
first item.
Perfect.
Now in this case you'll notice that in a few places we are grabbing that first item off of deleted posts.
We can actually use array destructuring to make that code just a tad bit cleaner just like destructuring
an object but I'm going to do right here is remove the word deleted posts.
I'm going to replace it with opening and closing square brackets.
Now I can choose names for the array elements I could call the first one A.
The second one be in the third one see.
In this case though we know we only have one array item.
I am going to call that one the post.
So right here we have the post that is indeed getting deleted.
Now that's just going to make the rest of our code a lot easier to work with down below.
I can just check if Post got published.
Then down below right here where I provide the data I can just reference that post variable.
And finally it where I return the post.
I can just return the post instead of needing to access that deleted posts.
Array.
Perfect.
So now we are successfully alerting people when the post gets deleted.
But I'm going to do is save the mutation and actually test this out before moving on to update post
over inside of graft.
Well playground once again I am going to start up our post subscription.
We can see that it is listening and I am going to delete one of the two published posts.
I have one with the idea of 10 and the other one with the ID of 12.
Right here I'm already deleting the one with the ID of 12.
This is perfect.
I can go ahead and run that request that I can move back to the post subscription tab and right here
I can see my notification this time.
Clearly letting me know I'm getting this data back because the post has been deleted.
Now if I were to delete a post like post 11 which is not published I would not expect a notification
to be sent out.
I'm going to remove it head back to the post tab and I can see nothing new is showing up which is fantastic.
Now that we're done with the delete post method.
Let's move on to the last.
And quite honestly the most confusing of the three update post remember.
Updating a post might not just be updating a post.
If I publish a posts using update post I want to send out that created event if I unpublished a post
using update post.
I want to send out that deleted event.
And finally if I just change something like the title on the body for a published post.
I actually do indeed want to send out the updated event.
That means in reality update post could be firing out all three different types of mutation events.
Now for the moment that is going to require us to use a little bit of additional code and it's not going
to be the prettiest code in the world but don't worry because in the next section we're going to be
spending our time vastly reducing the amount of code that we actually need to write in these resolver
methods.
So let's go ahead and kick things off by adding a if statement.
Down below inside of the if statement we already have.
So this if statement only runs if the user provided the published status.
That's going to allow us to determine if a post is becoming published in which case it's being created
or if it's becoming unpublished.
In which case it's actually being deleted now in order to set up the statement.
We need to know what the Post's published value was before it was changed and to do that we're going
to create a new variable.
Up above Konst original post original post is just going to be a clone of post.
At this point in time before any changes had been made to clone post I am just going to use the object
spread operator creating a new object and spreading out all of the fields from post perfect.
Now we have original post and we can actually use it down below.
So let's start setting up a little bit of conditional logic right here if and we're going to use the
following condition we're going to check if the post was published but is now unpublished.
So is original post published equal to true and using the logical and OPERATOR Is the new post published
value false.
So we're going to use the not operator then right here.
Post dot published.
Perfect.
So was the post originally published and now it's not published.
If so we're going to run some code and this is where we will actually fire the deleted event will actually
fire that off in a few moments for now let's just continue setting up our conditional logic.
We're going to add an else if.
On to here this time around we're going to see if it was originally not published and now it is published
in which case it's actually being created.
So right here we are going to flip using the logical operator original post got published.
So was it originally not published.
And then we're going to make sure it is now published.
And if that is the case right here we will fire the created event.
Now the last type of update we could have is if it's actually just being updated and the published value
isn't being changed.
So right here we can just add else if on to our original statement.
This one right here and all we're going to do is look at post dot published is the post published if
it is published.
But they did not already modify the published value.
So we know we can safely fire off that updated event.
Perfect.
So hopefully all of this conditional logic makes sense if this does not make sense.
I recommend not continuing on with the video and heading into the Q&amp;A to look at existing questions
on this topic or to ask your own.
It's important that it makes sense why all three events can actually be fired from the update post mutation.
Now that we have the basic structure in place all we have to do is use pub subduct publish a couple
of times right here.
I am going to deep structure that alongside of D-B grabbing pub sub and then we're going to start using
it down below.
I'm going to start with the deleted event right here that is going to be pub sub dot publish we are
going to publish to the post channel and then we're going to set up that object.
So we need our post property we need the mutation property on that subject.
I'll be using deleted which we've used before and then we need to set up data with the post data.
Now in the case of a post being deleted I'm actually not going to use post which contains the new data
because someone might have updated the title and body while they were on publishing the post.
All in the same operation.
And I wouldn't want them to accidentally leak that data when they might not have thought that's how
it worked.
So what I'm going to do is publish the old data right here.
All I'm going to do is publish original post so you can get back the deleted data without any of the
changes that were actually made from this particular operation.
So now we can remove that comment and we can move on to the next one.
The next one is the created events are right here.
It is like the post is being created because it is going from unpublished to published.
We're going to use pub sub and publish to publish some new data and in this case we are still using
the same name the same channel name post and we still have to set up that object with the post property.
That object is going to have a mutation with the value of created and we are also going to set data
equal to and in this case we are indeed going to publish the latest data.
Since this post has just been made public and the data is available anyways right here referencing post
excellent last up we have updated and then we can test things out and we'll be all done for this video.
I'm going to use pub sub dot to publish or publishing to post.
We're setting up that object with the post property on that object.
We have our mutation property with the value of updated and we also have our data property.
Once again I will use post with the latest changes since we know this is indeed a published post and
the users just change something like the title or the body.
Whoops that should be the post channel not pos.
Perfect.
Now we can actually test things out.
To do this all we have to do is run our Post's subscription exactly as we already had it.
And then what we're gonna do is use updates post to update posts in various ways making sure that all
three of these fire.
So to start I'm going to use the update post mutation on post 11.
If you remember post 11 is the post that is not published and I'm going to take it from being unpublished
to published.
So right here I'm going to update post 11 setting published equal to true.
Now when I do this the post is going from being a draft to being a published post so I should see the
created mutation value over in the subscription.
I'm going to fire this off head over to my subscription tab and right here.
I do indeed see create it.
If I update the post to unpublished it I should see deleted right here.
I'm going to publish it.
I'm going to fire things off.
Head over to the post subscription tab and I do indeed see that deleted mutation value last up let's
go ahead and just truly update an already published post.
I'm going to update post 10.
That one is already published an under going to change its body so right here I'll set body equal to
the string something new.
Dot dot dot.
If I actually fire that off we can see that it did indeed change the post and if I go over to the post
subscription tab you can see that updated fired.
So now someone using the post subscription can actually keep the user interface completely up to date
showing the latest post with all of the changes and removing posts as they get unpublished or deleted.
That's all we're going to do for the post subscription.
What you're going to end up doing in the next video is something similar for the comment subscription
though with the comment subscription.
We do not have this many conditions to take into account the conditional logic is a lot simpler and
that's going to make the process much easier.
All right now this one ran a little long but I wanted to make sure to put all of this in a single video
to prevent any confusion about what's what that is it for this one.
I will see you in the next one which is a challenge video.