In the last video together we updated our post subscription to support and he created updated and deleted
events in this video.
You're going to be doing the exact same thing as a challenge but for the comment subscription and the
good news is that the comment type does not contain any sort of published property like we have with
our posts.
So there's no strange conditional logic that needs to happen.
Working with the comments subscription is going to be way more straightforward.
All right let's talk about exactly what I'd like you to do over in mutation Dhananjay J s up at the
top.
I am going to paste in the challenge comments for knocking this one out.
Once again the big picture goal is to set up support for the created updated and deleted events on our
comment subscription.
Now step one is to set up a custom payload.
So currently we are just sending back the individual comment.
We still want to send that data back but we also want to send back the string that represents what type
of mutation actually caused this event to fire.
Was this comment that I'm getting back created updated or deleted.
So just like we did for the post subscription we want to send back a new custom payload by creating
a custom type with those two fields.
That brings us to step two which is to update our one existing call related to the commet subscription
that is in create comment and we just want to change what we're sending back to support the new custom
type we're creating.
So we have to add on that mutation property setting its value equal to create it then you're going to
do the exact same thing for actually deleting a comment.
Now in this case there is no existing published call for that.
So you're going to have to add one in once the comment is deleted.
You want to call publish sending that event off.
Now once again there is no conditional logic to worry about here.
Very straightforward.
And the same thing is true with Step number four right here you are adding a publish call to update
comment to send out that updated event just passing along the actual mutation string and the data that
brings you to step five which is to test your work.
You want to start up your subscription then you want to create a comment update a comment and delete
a comment to make sure you see all three events firing correctly.
So take some time to knock that out and feel free to use whatever we talked about in the last video
since this and the last video we're going to follow a similar set of steps paused the video test your
work and when you're done come back and click play.
How'd you do.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with Step number one.
Setting up our custom payload type for the comment subscription with data and mutation over in schema
damn graphs.
Well we're going to do just that by defining the new custom type near the bottom of the file right here.
A new type comment which is the subscription name followed by subscription payload
and we're going to set up the two fields we know we need one we do need the mutation that's the whole
point of doing this restructuring.
We went a little bit of context about why this event is firing and we still want the data.
So I still want to be able to get the comments right here.
Data is going to be of the type comment.
Now we can actually modify our subscription up above to use this type appear.
We have our comment subscription which currently sends back a comment.
I'm going to change that to sending back an instance of our comment subscription payload making that
a non nullable field.
Awesome.
This is actually the only thing necessary to change in schema doc graft.
Well that's the end of step 1 and we can move on to Step 2 which happens in mutation at J S.
Here we are changing our existing published call uncreate comment.
So if you remember Krait comment lives near the bottom and we currently do have a publish call.
We're not going to change anything about the channel name.
What we need to change is the structure right here like we did in the last video.
So I'm going to empty this object out and break it out onto multiple lines.
Now we're still going to have that comment route property but this time it is an object that matches
up with the custom type we just created.
So I need mom nutation field and I also need in my data field the value for mutation is going to be
the string created.
So let's add that in right here and the value for data is going to be our comment which I have in the
comment variable.
Awesome.
So now step two is done.
And we should be correctly notified about newly created comments.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next step.
Step three which is to change delete comment right now delete comment does not have a pub sub publish
call.
So I am going to go ahead and restructure it and add one in.
I'm going to grab pub sub from the context object down below just like we did for our posts.
I am going to structure this array grabbing the first item in creating an individual variable for it.
I'm going to call that one deleted comment and that's going to allow me to use deleted comment down
below.
As opposed to needing to grab it off the array every single time I want to access it.
Awesome.
Now this was not a necessary step.
If you left things as they were in regards to what I just change that's fine too.
All that's important is that you added the pub sub Dom publish call into the mix right here.
We have to specify the correct channel name.
Remember it's comment space followed by the post ID so comment space and I can grab the post Id off
of deleted comment right here.
Deleted comment.
Post contains that data.
And then we provide the second argument.
Our object we set up that route comment property we set up our mutation value.
In this case we are deleting some data so I will set the value equal to deleted and then finally we
set up data passing in the deleted comments.
Excellent.
And that is it for Step number three.
Our delete comment mutation method is all set up.
That brings us to step number for the last method to change is update comment.
Once again we do need to structure pub subs since there is no existing publish call and sign of here.
Then down below we can use pub sub dot publish we are going to pass in that channel name.
So once again comment space followed by the comment post ID.
Now the post ID is available on comment.
Post.
Then we're going to set up the object.
We have our route comments property on there we have a mutation property and for this one we are going
to send back our little updated event.
And finally we have our data which comes from the comment variable.
So right here comment perfect that is done for Step 4 and that brings us to the final step which is
to actually test all of this out.
So I want to go through the process of creating updating and then deleting a comment making sure the
event fires correctly.
I'm going to switch over to my comment subscription tab and before I can actually start this one up
I am going to need to change what I'm requesting since in this case Id text an author no longer exists
directly on here.
Instead what we have is mutation which I am going to grab.
And we also have data on data that's where we can grab things about the comment like it's ID the text
and some info about the author.
I'll grab the author's ID and the author's name.
Now if I refresh the schema this should become a valid operation.
Here it is indeed valid and the last thing I'm going to do is change this post ID to the idea of a post
that is actually published.
I'm going to use either 10 or 12.
I'll stick with 10.
Now if I fire this off we should start the listening process down below it does say it's listening which
is great.
And now we can move into our other tabs and actually create update and delete a comment.
I'm going to start by creating a comment using my Create comment mutation.
Now in this case it's the wrong post ID.
I'm going to switch this over to making a comment on the post with an ID of 10.
Now if I fire this off the comment was indeed created and I should be able to see that event over in
my subscription tab.
I'm going to click over to that and look for that new event to fire.
Right here we can indeed see the created event where we have all of the correct data.
Now let's go ahead and actually grab this comment ID.
I'm going to use this for my other tests.
Next up I am going to update a comment right here.
The comment has the idea of the ID I just copied.
I'm going to change the text to something like this is my new comment text with a couple of exclamation
marks and if I send that off we can see the operation did appear to succeed and over inside of the comment
tab.
We should have our second event firing with a mutation value of updated and there we go.
We have our mutation values set correctly and we have our new comment text showing up last up.
What do we have.
Well we have our delete comment event right here we have.
Delete comment.
The mutation we're going to delete the comment we created.
I'm going to paste in that same ID.
The same idea used for updating the comment we're going to fire that off.
We do indeed get our deleted comment data back and if I head over to that subscription tab we should
have our third and final event showing up right here.
We have our deleted event.
As expected we can see the exact data and we can see the actual event.
Type the mutation type was indeed deleted.
So there we go.
We now have both of our subscriptions and they're actually useful for keeping the front end up to date.
If a front end client actually subscribed to the comments for a post it could render new comments when
they're created.
It could update existing ones when they're updated and it could delete comments from the rendered output
when a comment is marked as deleted.
That's where we're going to stop for this video.
The challenge is now over and our two subscriptions are working really really well.
There are still a couple of videos left for this section there are a few things that I still want to
take the time to talk about.
I'm excited to get to those.
So let's go ahead and jump right into the next video and talk about the income's type.