In this video you're going to learn about the ENM type engraft Q L E Nom's are just another tool in
our tool belt allowing us to better model our application data.
And I actually want to start off with a definition of incomes then move on to some practical examples.
And finally will implemented in our app right here though.
I have a three part definition describing what an income is enough is short for enumeration.
And I just want to read through this definition then we'll go through it again with an example.
So an enum is a special type that defines a set of constants and this type can then be used as the type
for a field similar to how we can use our Scheller and custom types for fields.
And then finally values for that field must be one of the constants for the type.
So let's break this down with an example.
We're going to define a special type and a set of constants.
So if I was trying to represent user roles I might define an ENM called something like user role and
I might list out all of the potential values a user could be a standard user.
You could also be an editor and then maybe lastly you could be an admin.
So those are the three potential roles.
When I was to go to find the user I would then use that as the type for one of the fields.
So right here I'll just leave some comments since I'm not actually writing graphical type user.
We will then set up the closing curly brace.
I'll add a single field role of the type user role and now we're essentially enforcing that the value
for roll is one of these three values that cannot be anything else.
So let's go ahead and work through just one more example before we see this in practice.
Let's say we're using graft well to model a laptop.
If I was modeling a laptop I would likely want some field that allows me to represent whether or not
the laptop is powered on.
So I might have an is on field or is powered on and this could be of the Boolean type so I could set
it equal to true if the laptop is on or false.
If the laptop is off now this is a good start but it's not actually representative of all of the various
states that a laptop's power can be in.
You can have a laptop powered on you could have a laptop powered off but you can also have a laptop
that's in sleep mode.
So a boolean no longer really serves us since it can only represent two states and ENM can represent
as many states as we need and we can actually enforce that it's one of those.
So in reality we would probably have a laptop field called something like power status of an enim type.
And for that enough we might have a few different options like on off or sleep or anything else that
we happen to need.
So in the end of the day working with an enema could easily be replaced by a string.
I could have power status by string and just use one of these three string values.
The difference is that with enough times we can actually enforce it.
So if someone tries to save a laptop's power status or something other than these three it would actually
fail with an enum while it would work with a string.
This should seem familiar because it's exactly what we have with our subscription payloads.
If I head over to schema Audograph Well we have our post subscription payload.
And our comment subscription payload at the bottom bolt how they mutation field of the type string but
in reality the value can only be one of three things.
It's either created updated or deleted so it would be better to actually use an income.
Making sure it was indeed of one of those three values.
Now in this case the mutation value is always coming from the server to the client.
So it's not as important to use an enum when the data is coming from the client.
It's even more important to use an enum because we can actually enforce.
That is one of the constant types.
So let's go ahead and see all of this in action.
But I'm going to do is create our ENM right here and we actually start with the income keyword then
we go ahead and give it a name.
I'm going to call this mutation type and we're going to set up inside of here the potential constant
values.
Now it is a typical convention to use an uppercase character set for all of these values so it is not
enforced.
So you could use lowercase as well.
So for example if I was modeling that laptop I could use on I could use off and I could use sleep.
In our case though we are modeling the mutation type.
So I'm going to use either created updated or deleted.
Awesome.
Now that we have our mutation type in place we can actually use this instead of using the string for
both of these fields.
So right here I can go ahead and use mutation type making that non nullable and not do the exact same
thing down below for comment subscription payload referencing the mutation type.
Now the mutation field for both of these types must be one of these three values.
Currently it already is.
So we're not going to run into any issues.
But another advantage of using Gnome's is that it really makes it easy to catch typos and little inconsistencies
throughout your application.
So let's go ahead and save our schema graft you all file and actually see this in practice over in mutation.
Don J as I am going to remove the definition up above though you can find this in the PTF guide lessoned
notes for this lecture.
And down below we're going to go ahead and mess with one of our published calls.
I'm going to mess with the Create comment method right here we have our pub subduct publish call and
I'm going to change the mutation value to something that is not listed in our genome and definition.
So right here created is indeed listed.
I'm going to misspell that created with two E's followed by the D.
Now if we weren't using an email this would be perfectly valid because it is indeed a string so everything
would work as expected.
Now though we are using an enum though we're actually going to get an error when we try to send this
back because this value is not listed in the enim type.
It is not listed here.
In the end of the day are enum values are represented as strings.
So the fact that this is a string is great.
Now let's go ahead and test it out.
I'm going to move over to graph playground.
I'm going to resubscribe to our comments for post 10.
We can see it's lessoning that I am going to create a new comment over here in the create comment tab
it's all ready for post 10 and so I can just fire this one off.
Now the actual comment creation worked.
It is the subscription that should have failed.
So over here we can see an error.
The message expected a value of type mutation type but received and then it showing this one created.
So it's letting us know that the value it got back did not match up with the value that was actually
expected.
Now that would allow us to figure out there is a typo.
We could then address that by removing the extra e we could save things and test them out again.
I can restart that subscription.
We can see it's lessening.
I can go back and recreate that comment.
It works once again.
And now if I head back to the subscription tab it should indeed be working as expected.
And we should have our little event showing up right here.
We do indeed have it.
We have our comment data the type for mutation is indeed created and then we have all of the data we've
requested down below.
That's where I'd like to start for this one.
So let's take a quick moment to recap what we learned.
And this video we learned about the genome type in OM's allow us to represent a set of constants and
then any fields of that type must have a value equal to one of our Constans.
This is great when we're modeling data and we have a set of standard values that we know about ahead
of time.
It doesn't make sense to use income for a post's title because we do not know the various values for
post titles ahead of time.
It could be anything out there.
In the case of mutation though there are only three values.
So it makes sense to use an Ina.
Now if you're working with just two values you can typically get away with a boolean.
We saw how that was possible when we had the is on property for our laptop.
It's either on or off.
True or false when you start to get into three or more potential fixed values though that's where the
income comes in handy.
So if we were working with a laptop we would have on off and sleep here we're working with mutation
type and we have created updated and delete it.
All right.
That's where we're going to stop for this video and that's where we're going to stop for this section
and this section you learned all about subscriptions and how you can fetch real time data from a graph.
Well back end we're going to continue on with the course in the next section which is kind of like the
start of part two.
We're going to dive into some advanced topics we're going to start exploring data storage authentication
and other real world features.
I am beyond excited to get to it.
So let's go ahead and move right in to the section introduction video.