Welcome to Section 8 in this section the goal is to get your application deployed live to production.
So right now everything is running locally on your machine.
And by everything I mean your Prisma instance which is running in a local Dakar container and your.
Yes app which is just running through node.
The goal is to get both of those up and running on a production server that's accessible to the outside
world.
That's going to allow someone who's not in our local network to actually access the app that's going
to be important if we want others to be able to interact with the API or if we want to build out our
own mobile or web clients.
All right let's go ahead and see what it takes to deploy graphs.
Well.