It the goal of this section is to get a production ready version of our application deployed live to
the Web in this video.
We're going to explore the tools we'll be using in order to get that done in the end of the day.
There are three things we need to get done.
One we need a production database so we need a place to host our production data too.
We need a place to host our Prisma docker container.
We're currently running docker locally but that's not going to work if we want people outside of our
local network to be able to access it.
And third we need a place to host our node J.S. application.
So those are our three needs.
And we're going to fulfill those needs with two services.
The first is Heroku Heroku is where we're going to host our database host our docker container and host
our node J.S. application the other service we're going to use Prisma cloud is going to make it really
easy to manage those Heroku Prisma instances.
So we're not going to have to do anything fancy to get the database and the containers set up Prisma
cloud is going to handle that for us.
And the good news is that we can get started for free with Heroku and for free with Prisma cloud.
They have generous free tiers that don't expire after a month or a year.
They just require you to pay if you want to collaborate with others.
So for our purposes we can deploy our applications to production for free.
And that's exactly what we're going to end up doing.
Now we already have a Heroku account we created that earlier in the course to get our database that
we've used throughout the class so far with Prisma.
But we do need to explore Prisma cloud.
So let's go ahead and pull that up.
We can find it by heading over to Prisma dot.
I know it's a product released by the official Prisma team.
Now they currently have two products they have Prisma cloud the one we'll be using and Prisma enterprise
targeted at larger corporations if we actually click on Prisma cloud we can learn more about the tool
and if we scroll all the way to the bottom of this page we can look at the pricing table.
So for our purposes the free tier has everything we need.
We could collaborate with a couple of other people though if we want more than three we have to start
paying.
We also get less metrics and lobbying and support but all of those are just nice to have.
They're nonessential and we do get some Barebone ones which is great if you are moving into a application
where you have clients who are paying or you're building an app for someone else maybe the team plan
makes more sense and enterprise is a bit extreme for larger corporations.
But once again for us free is just fine.
It has everything we need to deploy our app securely to production.
So let's go ahead and actually create an account creating an account is free no credit card required.
All we have to do is go through the sign up process.
I'll take a quick moment to log out so you can see what it's like.
You just got to sign up with your e-mail and password or you can connect to your get have account.
Either approach works just fine.
In this case I am using my get how the account as my log in and once we log in we're going to be brought
to the Prisma cloud dashboard.
Now the first time you log in there's going to be a little survey asking you why exactly you're using
the service it's a new service so they're still trying to gauge what features are important and who
exactly is using it and for what purposes.
Now on Prisma cloud there are three main pages we have services.
We have servers and we have settings settings is just a basic page for account management.
The ones that we're going to be focusing on are services and servers.
So with servers we are going to create a single Prisma instance so we're going to take that container
and we're going to deploy it to Heroku.
This is going to give us something similar to the server we have locally at localhost 4 4 6 6.
So we're only ever going to create a single server.
Now under services we can have as many services as we want and we proved that earlier in this class
locally.
Remember we created the Prisma folder which contained everything for our blogging application.
But as a challenge you also created the Prisma review Web site and we didn't create another doctor container
for that.
They were both using the exact same server and this worked because inside of our database under schemas
we have our data organized under default default.
We have all of our data for our default service at the default stage and then down below we had the
reviews service at the default stage as well.
And that's where all that data lived.
So long story short we're going to have a single server and multiple services.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by actually creating a server.
Now if you click over the servers page you're going to have two things already there.
These are default servers managed by Prisma and you cannot manage or access them.
So we're going to go ahead and create a brand new one.
We're going to add our own server and it's going to bring us through this little wizard where we pick
things like our server name our databases and our server size.
So let's go ahead and stick with a nice specific name.
The name you're going to enter is globally shared.
So you don't want to use something generic like blogging application.
I'll typically use my name first.
You want to stick with just characters using hyphens to separate your words so I could use something
like.
Andrew Mead blogging app as an example that would be a pretty unique name.
Then down below just a quick description blogging application.
Awesome.
Now we can go ahead and click Create server we want to create a new one.
And first up we're going to create the database we're going to create a new database so make sure to
follow the same steps I'm following now and we create a new database.
It's going to ask us where we want to create that new database and currently Prisma cloud only integrates
with Heroku.
The other services are coming down the line so we're going to stick with Heroku which works really well
for us because we already have that set up.
Now when you click that it's going to bring you over to a list of all connected Heroku accounts you're
going to go ahead and connect an existing one that you have.
So click connect a new account.
This is going to redirect you to her Roku.
You'll have to click a button that says you allow Prisma cloud to manage your Heroku account then it'll
redirect you back to this site and the page you end up on will look a little bit like this.
It's going to ask for some details about the database you want to create.
Now we're going to stick with postgresql the only one supported and when it comes to your region you
can either pick us Virginia or EU Dublin just pick the one closest to you and your users down below
we have our database plan.
We are going to stick with the hobby dev plan which is completely free and doesn't require us to enter
any sort of credit card information.
You can always upgrade as users start to use your app down below we can actually create this database
and the process for creating the database just takes a couple of seconds.
It's communicating with Heroku getting that database set up for us.
And once the database is set up it's going to ask us to set up a server and that's what we're going
to do to wrap up this process.
We're going to click Set up a server and once again we can pick from different options.
We are going to use Heroku the only one currently supported even if there was other options supported
I would still be using Heroku.
It really is my preferred service because it's so easy to use flexible and customizable.
Right here we are sticking with that free plan once again as you have more users making requests to
your app.
Maybe it makes sense to upgrade.
I use the hobby plan for a lot of my client projects.
I honestly don't really need more than that for most applications down below.
We are going to create this server and this is where the wizard is going to stop.
Once the server is created we're all done.
Everything is set up and we can get back to looking at how Prisma cloud is going to help us.
Now the process of creating the server takes a bit longer than working with that database but once it
is done we're actually going to be able to see both the database and the server over on our Heroku account
and we'll even be able to connect it to our production database using PGE admin just like we were able
to connect to our other Heroku database.
All right.
Everything is done.
And now we can view the server viewing the server just brings us over to the servers page.
So we might as well just click that and if we give things a refresh we should see a third item in the
list 3 to 1 and there it is.
Andrew Mead blogging app.
It's currently in the booting stage and if we click on that we can see that there is the server and
there is the database both hosted on Heroku.
So the server listed here that's going to take care of this requirement.
It's going to run our Prisma Dakar container and the database down below.
That's going to take care of this requirement that's going to be our production database where data
for our real users is stored.
Now we haven't done anything to deploy our code to that Prisma container that's running and that's OK.
We'll focus on doing that in the next video.
And we also haven't done anything with our node.
JS app and that's fine too.
We'll address that later in the section to wrap up this video.
The only thing I want to do is connect to our production database via PGE admin.
So what are we going to do to get that done.
Step one we're going to head over to PGE admin.
We are going to Right-Click servers list and we are going to create a server and then we have to provide
all of those connection details.
I can call this whatever I want.
I could say something like Heroku production database as an example.
And then on the connection page we have to fill out all of those connection details.
Where do we get them.
We get them from Heroku.
I'm going to go ahead and knock this out by heading over to the Prisma cloud page right here and clicking
view on Heroku for the database.
This is going to bring us over to that Heroku application and once we're here we can actually get into
the connection details by clicking Heroku post grass which has automatically been added for us.
If I click that it's going to bring us over to the database connection details like we saw earlier in
the class right here.
We can go over to settings we can go to View credentials and this is all the stuff we have to enter
inside of PGE admin.
So let's go ahead and get started.
The first thing we're going to do is grab that host.
I'm going to copy that.
Pasting it over into the host label.
Next up is our port.
The port should be the same value.
Five four three two is the default.
I'm seeing that here as well after the port.
We have our maintenance database.
We're going to go ahead and toss in our database name right here.
I'm going to paste that in.
Then we have our user name so we have to copy the user name from Heroku and paste that in.
And the last thing we have is our password the password is really long it's sitting over here.
I'm going to copy it.
I'm going to bring it over to PGE admin and paste it in ticking that save password box so I don't have
to enter it over and over again.
Now if I actually save the connection we can see it showing up in the left hand side I'm going to go
ahead and close the other servers.
Expand that one expand the databases and we should get a really long list of databases once again.
But one of those is ours.
Now to find it we can always just grab the first few characters here it's d three one.
Q For me I'm going to use command to search on page 3 1 Q And right here I can see my database.
It's gold which means I do have access to actually explore it and if I open it up cracking open the
schemas What do we see.
We don't see anything like default default or default Prod..
We haven't added any services.
We haven't deployed Prisma So this is completely expected.
As long as we're able to expand that database we are indeed successfully connected and that's where
we're going to stop for this video.
So let's take a quick moment to talk about exactly what we did in this video.
We signed up for Prisma cloud.
It's a service that makes it really easy to host your Prisma applications.
It makes it really easy because it directly integrates with cloud providers like Heroku and it manages
all of the setup for us so we don't have to in the end of the day it's going to give us all the tools
we need to deploy new versions and manage our various services.
It's important to note that Prisma cloud is not a requirement for hosting Prisma neither of these are
they're both optional.
There are a ton of other choices you could have made as well.
This is just my preferred stack for example.
The only thing you really need is a hosting service that supports containers.
Amazon Web Services does Heroku does other services like digital ocean do there are a ton of container
hosting services out there and you need a service that can give you a post gresse database.
That's also a dime a dozen There are hundreds of different services that allow you to set up a post
gresse database.
So in the end of the day these are just a couple of tools we can use to make the job easy.
They are by no means the only tools you can use to get this done.
All right.
That's it for this one.
We have the basic setup in place and the next video we're going to focus on making some changes to our
project so we can actually get one of our services deployed and then we'll be able to interact with
that database reading and writing from the production database.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.