In this video you're going to be deploying your Prisma application to the server created in the last
video.
So the server is already up and running it's waiting for us to deploy to it.
And we already have our database up and running as well.
So all we have to do is deploy our data model file to that server.
Now in order to get that done we are going to have to make a couple of small changes to our app and
to start I want to crack open our Prisma like email file and talk about what happens when we run that
Prisma deploy command.
So how do we deploy.
Well we go CD Prisma to get into the Prisma project folder.
Then we use Prisma deploy.
But when we run this what happens.
Well it looks at this file to figure out what it should do.
This is where it grabs the data model that it sends to the server.
And this is also where it grabs the server location itself.
Now in this case we've hardcoded this you are well into the file.
That means every single time we run Prisma deploy it's always going to deploy to our local instance.
It's always going to deploy to the docker container we have running on our machine.
There's no way to pick between our local docker container and the production one.
And that's a problem.
So if I actually run Prisma deploy we're going to get the expected output.
It just gives us a little message saying that the service is already up to date.
So how do we fix this.
Well the goal is to have a dynamic value for endpoint.
We can then choose to deploy to development or to production depending on our needs to get this done.
We're going to create 2 configuration files one for development and one for production each with a set
of variables so a set of key value pairs are going to set up an endpoint value for each.
So we'll have two files each with a different endpoint value.
And when we run Prisma deploy we'll load one of those two files in.
So let's see what that looks like in reality.
Well we need to do is create a new director the inside of the graph.
Q Well Prisma folder we can call this whatever we like.
I'm going to go ahead and call it config and in here we're going to create a new configuration file
for each environment we want to deploy to.
In our case there's just two for now.
We're going to have development and we're going to have production.
So the first file can be called dev or development dot envy.
And the second file We're going to create is going to be called Prod. or production dot EMV.
Now in the end of the day we're really only going to have a couple of lines of code in each of these
and that's OK.
Let's go ahead and start with our dev dot envy file.
The format for this file is key equals value.
So here we've essentially created a variable called key and we have the value of value.
We would do something similar over in pride creating key but with a different value allowing us to customize
the variable values between environments.
Now let's go ahead and actually create a meaningful one.
We're going to create one for that Prisma endpoint.
So right here I'm going to call this Prisma underscore end point and we are going to set it equal to
the U r l.
We're already using.
So for development we do indeed want to deploy to this you RL.
So let's copy it bring it over to dev dot envy and paste it in.
Make sure you don't have any stray spaces or extra characters as that will affect the functionality
of our program.
When we try to deploy.
Now the question is how do we access this variable inside of Prisma dot wya now.
So this value gets used for the endpoint.
While over in this file We're going to do is remove the hard coded value and we're going to use the
following syntax.
It's a dollar sign followed by curly braces.
This allows us to inject things inside and we're going to inject in one of our environment variables
and to do that we use the following syntax.
It's NVI colon followed by the variable name we called ours.
Prisma underscore end point.
So over here we are going to type in Prisma underscore and point perfect.
Now when we deploy and we tell Prisma to use this environment file it's still going to be able to deploy
to development just fine.
Let's go ahead and actually test that out.
I'm going to save all three files even though the prod environment file has nothing inside of it.
And we're going to run Prisma deploy but we're not going to run Prisma deploy on its own.
We're also going to specify the easy argument.
So that's hyphen e.
This lets us provide the path to the configuration file we want to use right after the argument itself.
So that's hyphen eat space followed by the path to dev Dom envy.
So we are currently in the Prisma directory.
I'm going to use dot dot to get out of that folder then forward slash config forwards slash and then
right here.
Dev dot envy.
Perfect.
So in this case it is going to first load in all of the environment variables here then it's going to
inject those into this file.
Then it's actually going to deploy and the end result is exactly what we had before.
So this command can be used to deploy to development.
Now the question is how do we deploy to production.
We're not really sure what you Arel value to put inside of this file.
And the answer is that we're not going to put any value inside of that file.
We're going to let Prisma inject the you R-AL for us.
Now there are two steps to getting this done.
The first thing we have to do is log into Prisma using the command line interface not just anyone is
going to be able to deploy to our server.
We have to first confirm who we are so it can pull in all the servers we have access to to log in all
we do is from the terminal run Prisma line again.
This is going to require us to pull up a page in the browser.
The browser might automatically open it for you and all you have to do is click grant permission if
the page didn't automatically open.
You can just grab the you Arel that spit out in the terminal and open that manually.
We click grant permission.
It tells us we can close the window and if we head back to the command line interface we can see the
authentication completed successfully.
You can always check if your authenticated by just trying to log in again and you'll get a message saying
that you successfully signed in.
So now we are indeed logged in.
Which means that we're going to have access to that server we created.
Next up we have to go ahead and run Prisma deploy.
This time though we're going to tell it to use our production ENVI file even though it's completely
empty.
So right here Prisma deploy we provide that e flag setting up the path to that file.
That's dot dot.
Forward slash config forward slash Prod. dot E and V.
Now when we do this what's going to happen while it's going to try to inject all of the variables from
this file into this file since there are no variables in our ENVI file all of the values over here are
going to end up being blank.
So it's like we have no you Arel at all when the file actually runs.
Let's go ahead and run that and see what happens.
What happens is that it asks us to pick from a list of the servers we have and we're gonna pick the
one we created right here I have mine.
I called it Andrew Meade blogging app.
You're going to have your name in there.
You can pick that item.
Hit enter and next up it's going to ask us for a couple other pieces of information.
We're going to choose a name for our service.
Let's go ahead and customize it as opposed to using Prisma which is the default.
I'm going to call this once again.
Andrew Mead blogging app.
And next up it's going to ask us for a stage.
So are we in development testing production.
What is this.
In this case we are in production.
So let's use Prod. I'm going to hit enter and now what happens.
Well a couple of things happen.
First up we can see it says Our End Point has been written and it shows us the file it's been written
to.
It's actually right up above.
The next thing it's going to do is it's actually going to try to deploy to the server that Prisma cloud
created.
Now this process can take a little bit of time and that's perfectly normal.
The first time around down below the process has completed.
And what we're seeing is the same sort of output we would see if we deployed to development.
It's showing us exactly what it did.
All of the fields that were created as expected.
And once again we do indeed have that you are well written up above.
So this you RL is pretty important for our purposes.
What we want to do is NOT leave it in this file where I wrote it we want to bring this over to prod
dot envy.
So what the command did is it commented out our other end point and it added this one in.
We're going to take this you r l and copy it to the clipboard we're then going to go over to prod dot
envy and set up Prisma underscore end point sending it equal to the you Arel we just copied.
So now both files have a Prisma end point with different values which is good.
And over in Prisma lie M-L we can now remove entirely the line that was generated for us and we can
uncomment the line that we created.
Now when we deploy to production it's not going to have to do anything like that again.
All we do is we run the command with the EMV file the exact same command we ran moments ago and this
time we get the expected output.
We can see it deployed to the correct service and we have our little message saying that nothing happened
because it's already up to date.
And there we go.
We now have a system for deploying to development when that's what we want and for deploying to production
when that's what we want.
Now that we have deployed to production let's head back over to Prisma cloud and see what we have.
If I go over to the dashboard and go under servers nothing's changed.
But if I head over to services we now have a service before we had no services right here the service
name Andrew Meade blogging app and the stage production both things we configured when the command line
asked us for those values and we can also see the server it's associated with and everything is working
really well.
No requests so far but we're going to change that in the next video in the next video we're actually
going to mess around with this production service.
Reading and writing data from our production database I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next video.