In this video we're going to explore the service that we deployed in the last one.
Now we actually just click the service name.
It's going to bring us over to a page for that service and this page has a few great features.
First up we can actually view our data right here.
Users posts and comments though currently we're not seeing any because we haven't created any.
But don't worry we will create some.
In this video and the other page we have is our metrics page.
This gives us some information about our server and how things are doing so we can keep track of its
health.
We also have our deployment history so we can see that we only have one deployment up there and if we
actually click that we can dive into the details of what exactly happened from that deployment.
The other thing we have access to in these services page is this playground link.
This is actually going to crack open a new tab.
And that's going to load a graph QOL playground instance for our production service.
This is just another great feature of using Prisma cloud it can automatically open an instance of graft.
Well playground and it's also injecting the authorization header automatically via the you R-AL we can
see that down below.
It's been added which means that we can securely make requests maybe we just want to see what data we
have in our production database or maybe we want to change some data.
Regardless we can do that easily by just clicking that playground link and making some requests from
this instance.
Now this is actually going to read and write from our production database.
Currently there is no data inside of there.
Let's go ahead and change that.
So right here I'm going to start with a query we are going to query for all users and for each user
We're going to grab their ID and their name.
Now if I go ahead and fire that off what do I get back I get back an empty array as expected.
Well we're going to do now is create a second tab and in this tab we're going to use one of our mutations
down below.
We have our create user mutation.
Now it's important to note that all of the queries mutations and subscriptions we're seeing here match
up exactly with the ones we were seeing at local host 4 4 6 6 over here.
I have the exact same stuff available to me.
All we're going to do from our production service is create a users are right here for create user We
provide some data we have to provide a name and email and a password.
And that's exactly what we're going to do.
So I will create a mutation.
This one is for create user.
We are going to set up that arguments list and we're also going to set up our selection set for the
newly created user.
Let's just grab their ID and their name.
Now we have to fill out that arguments list.
We're going to have data data is going to have a name.
I'm going to create a user that represents me so I'll just use Andrew.
We're going to have an e-mail.
I will stick with Andrew at example dot com.
And lastly we are also going to have a password.
I'm going to pick a password like a red one two three four five.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can actually fire off that mutation.
And what do we get back we get back a confirmation.
Letting us know that everything went well and if I were to fire off my query once again this new user
should show up and if I do that what do we get.
We now have one object inside of that user's array.
So we have just successfully written and read from that production database and we can prove it by viewing
the data over NPG admin over NPG admin ongoing to right click schemas end of refresh the schemas list.
And what do we see we see are new ones showing up.
We have Andrew Meade blogging app dollar sign Prod. So we have the service name and the stage.
And if I expand that we can explore our data down below we have tables in there we have a few different
tables but the only one that's populated is the user table.
So I'm going to right click and view all rows and what do we get in just a second.
I should have my one user showing up and there it is.
We have the name Andrew the e-mail the e-mail and the password currently shown in plain text.
Now the password is in plain text for the moment because we didn't go through our node app the node
app is where the data actually gets hashed.
Once we set the node app up for production as well we'll have hashed passwords once again but we do
indeed now have a way to view our production data and also access it in graphical playground which is
a fantastic step in the right direction.
Now if we go back to cloud we can actually view this data there as well.
Remember we have that data browser tab for our service.
If I click on that we have the one user showing up.
We have the field name we have the graphic field type which is really cool and unique to Prisma cloud.
And then we have our data.
So over here we have all of the data showing up.
Now if we actually double click this user it brings up an editor so we can even change the fields using
this service alone making it a decent replacement for PGE admin.
When you're deploying using Prisma cloud just one more great reason to use this service.
Right that's where we're going to stop for this one.
We're going to continue on in the very next video.
And the focus is on that third thing we have to do.
We still have to host our node J.S. application.
We have the production database up and running.
We have our service deployed to the Prisma docker container but our No.
Ass app is only accessible locally.
So let's go ahead and fix that by jumping right in to the next one.