In the last several videos we used Heroku and Prisma cloud to create our production database and to
create our production Prisma instance in this video.
We're going to focus on the third thing we need to do which is to host our no J.S. application in production
as well.
And for this we are going to use Heroku Heroku makes it super easy to deploy all sorts of applications
including no J as apps.
And in this video we're going to cover how to get that done.
We'll be running a few commands from the command line changing a little bit of code and by the end we'll
have our app deployed.
There are two tools we're going to be using to get this done and the first is get the version control
system.
We're going to be using that to track our code changes and we're also going to be using it to take those
code changes and push them up to the Heroku servers.
So Heroku can deploy our application getting the latest code up and running.
Now understanding the basics of get is a pre-req for the class but that doesn't mean we're still not
going to work through things step by step because we are you can always check if you have get installed
or not by running.
Get with the version flag.
If you get a valid version like get version 1 or 2 you're good to go if you get an error message like
get command not found.
That means you are going to have to install and get.
Don't worry it's free and available for all operating systems.
You can find it at.
Get hyphen as CM.
Dot com.
Here you can grab the installer for your OS and you can also check out the great free e-book Pro get.
I remember reading this back in college and it was the first time that I felt I really understood what
gift was doing.
All right so that's the first tool.
Get the other thing we're going to be installing is the Heroku command line interface you can find that
by googling Heroku CLID.
And I'm just showing you where this lives on the web.
The Heroku CLID page shows you everything that this tool can do though will be walking through that
in this video.
Oh we're going to do is install it by installing an NPM module from the terminal.
So I'm going to close down that tab.
And from the terminal we're going to run an NPM installation command that is NPM install with the G
flag to install the module globally and the module itself is called Heroku.
This is going to give us a new command we can run from the command line to manage our Her Roku applications.
Now once the installer is done we're going to log in to our Heroku account via this command line interface
and that's going to allow these Seelye to manage our apps so we can create apps and deploy new versions
of our apps right here from Visual Studio code.
The installer should be done in just one moment and once it's done all we're going to do is run in that
Heroku logon command right here.
Heroku log in.
This is going to ask us for our credentials so we need to provide our e-mail and we have to provide
our password.
And once we provide both of those it should say logged in as followed by your e-mail.
And now we're ready to actually use both of these tools for the purposes of getting our node app deployed.
Now before we can take our code and give it to Heroku there are a few changes we have to make to our
project.
There are very small configuration changes nothing big.
In general our project is just fine to start.
We are going to close all open editors though I am going to leave my little note describing what we're
working towards open and we're going to focus on just a single file for the moment.
That is the index Dhananjay s file in our source directory and this file is of interest because this
is what starts the web server now and the end of the day we're still going to call server dot start.
Here's the problem.
By default the server is going to start on port 4000.
We saw that because every time we wanted to interact with our node app we went to local host 4000.
The problem with that is that Heroku doesn't use port 4000 It actually uses a port that it has signs
when your app gets deployed which means there's no number we can put in here instead.
Heroku injects an environment variable and we can use that variable to make sure rebinding to the correct
port.
Now server dot start does indeed take an options object.
So let's go ahead and pull up the documentation for that.
If I had over to the browser we can go to the graphic Well yoga get hub repository a page we have been
plenty of times before and if we scroll down we can look for the docs for the start method.
The first method documented is the constructor function for graphical server.
We don't have to make any changes to that down below though we have the documentation for start.
This is what we're going to change.
It takes as the first argument and optional options object and we can see all of the various configuration
values down below.
One of them being port now by default the port is four thousand.
We're going to go ahead and set up that object so we can customize the port property.
So over inside a visual studio code let's go ahead and get that done right here.
I'm going to pass in an object as the first argument.
Moving our function to the second argument and we are going to set up the port property.
Now once again Heroku is going to inject an environment variable and we're going to use that right here.
Process don't envy is where all of our environment variables live.
And the one that Heroku assigns is called port in all upper case.
It is important to use all uppercase.
Now this environment variable is going to exist when our code runs on Heroku so that's fine.
The problem is that it's not going to exist when our code runs locally which is going to be a problem
to address that.
I'm just going to use the logical or operator and provide a fallback value of 4000.
So we'll set the port equal to the environment variables value if it exists if it doesn't we'll use
port 4000 making sure that our app works correctly on Heroku and it still works correctly locally as
well.
So that is one of the changes we have to make in order for Heroku to be able to successfully run our
app the next file that's going to require a small change is Prisma data.
J.S. in this file we actually connect to the Prisma instance.
The problem is that the endpoint is hard coded which means that if this app was running locally it would
connect to local host for 4 6 6 which would work.
But if it was running on her Roku It would also try to connect to a local host for 4 6 6 which is going
to fail.
In reality we want to use the exact same endpoint you are else that we set up in our config files for
Dev We want to connect it to this one for production on Heroku.
We want to connect to this one and we're going to go ahead and get that done by using these exact same
files and our exact same values.
In the end instead of having a string right here we're going to use an environment variable instead
to start.
Let's go ahead and move in to package Jason.
And the reason that this file is interesting for our purposes is that this file is what Heroku uses
to one know that we're running a node app and two to figure out how to install our dependencies and
start things up.
So in this case Heroku is going to install all of our dependencies and then it's going to run the start
script.
The one that has start as the script name.
Now the problem with this is that this is not the script we want to run in production.
And if you're asking why the answer is because we use gnomon So it's going to try to refresh gnomon
is not suited for production.
This is really for development purposes only.
So we're going to make a few small changes.
First up we're going to add a new script right here and I'm going to call this script dev.
This is what we're going to run when we want to start our application for local development and we're
just going to cut out the exact contents of the start script above and move them down below.
Now we can actually create a start script that makes sense for us and for Heroku before we worry about
the start script.
Let's go ahead and at least get our local development environment working after swapping this out for
an environment variable.
So what we're going to end up doing right here is removing the string value for End Point and replacing
it with process a dot NVI dot and the variable name is going to be whatever we have in dev and Prod.
which is Prisma endpoint in uppercase with an underscore separating them.
So over here Prisma underscore endpoint perfect.
So now the Prisma file is at least in its final state.
All we have to do is make sure that our dev config file actually gets loaded whenever we run the dev
script.
Otherwise when this file executes there is going to be no environment variable and things are going
to fail to load in that Devcon NV file.
We're going to use a very simple library that makes this possible.
You can find the library by googling NVI hyphen ACMD.
It is an NPM package and if we head over to the get hub repository page for that library we can take
a quick peek at how it works down below.
We have some example usage and in this case they're even showing it right inside of an NPM script.
A test script.
So we start with Envy's CMT.
Within the link to the file we want to load in.
Then we add what ever else we are trying to do.
So let's go ahead and install it down below in the terminal.
We're going to run NPM install We are going to install NVI hyphen ACMD and we're going to grab the latest
version which is version 8 point zero point two.
Perfect.
Now once that is installed we'll be able to actually take advantage of it inside of our scripts and
for the moment we're going to add it to that Dev script to make sure that these environment variables
load which is going to ensure that when the Prisma js file runs it can still connect to our local instance.
All right.
The module is installed an over in package.
Jason we're ready to use it exactly like they use it right here.
We start with envy.
Hyphen ACMD then a space then we link to our config file from the package date Jason File.
So for us that's going to be daat forward slash in that route to the project we have the config folder
in the config folder we have dev Dom.
Ian V then after a space we get everything we want to do next which we already have in place and there
we go.
Now our application is at least going to work in development when we run the dev script.
It's going to load in this file and that's going to make sure that when the app actually runs it has
a valid value for Prisma endpoint so it can connect to the endpoint correctly.
All right.
Now that we have this in place what we're going to do is test out our development script to make sure
we can still run our app locally from the terminal.
I am going to clear the terminal output and run NPM run dev which is our new script but we want to run
the app locally.
This is going to make sure to load in the environment variables and run things through babbel and gnomon.
If I fire this off we should see the same output we saw before and our server should still be up on
localhost 4000.
So if I go over to localhost 4000 and give things a refresh the graph UL playground instance should
still load.
And if I fire off one of my operations I should still get data back which I am.
The fact that I'm able to do those two things proves that this is still going to work for development
and it also proves that this is going to still work for development.
Now at this point we've started to make some changes to our app but we haven't really set it up to actually
run on Heroku at the start script is empty.
And that's a problem.
That's what we're going to end up addressing in the next video.
So let's take just a quick moment to recap what we did because I know these development production videos
can be a bit confusing.
So in short all we did in this video is we first installed get and Heroku logging in to the Heroku command
line interface.
Then we edited index dot J S making sure that when we eventually send the code to Heroku it can run
on the correct port locally we still use port 4000.
From there we updated Prisma dot J S instead of having a static end point.
We now have a dynamic one coming from an environment variable in development.
We use this one in production.
We'll end up using this one.
All of that is going to get wired up in packaged Jason.
Currently we just have the dev script to complete.
Let's go ahead and jump right in to the next video and focus on that start script and getting things
up and running on Heroku.