In the last video we made some great progress towards getting our app Heroku ready.
Things are working in development which is good at least it's not broken there.
And in this one we're going to finish up the process actually getting our app deployed live to the Web.
So what's the first thing we're going to do.
Well the first thing we're going to do is talk about the scripts that Heroku is going to run in the
end of the day Heroku is going to run the start script.
That's what's going to start up our app and we want to use node to run our application.
We want to make sure that index dot J s executes so it can get everything started.
The other thing that we can do though is use a series of other scripts that Heroku supports to do things
like run babbel to make sure all of that is in order as well.
There are actually plenty of scripts that Heroku supports and it allows you to tap in to the lifecycle
of your application.
And we can find those by googling Heroku node G-S support and the article we're looking for is titled
No JS support Heroku no js support is right here and we're looking for these scripts related to Heroku.
Now if we scroll down the list we are looking for customizing the build process.
If I click that it brings us to various scripts we can use the ones that we're going to talk about our
down below just a little bit.
We have Heroku pre-build and Heroku post build.
We want to use Heroku post build.
This is going to fire just before NPM start runs.
So it is a great place to run babbel so over inside of package Scott Jason we're going to add that into
the mix as well just below our start script.
We're going to set up a new one.
The name for this script needs to be Heroku hyphen post build.
Exactly.
If there are any typos inside of their Heroku is going to think you didn't provide it and it's not going
to run but we end up putting in the script.
So in summary this script is going to run our code through Babel and this script is actually going to
start up the node application.
Now for the Heroku post build script we're not actually going to use Babel node babbel node is great
for local development purposes but as the babbel team will tell you themselves that's not suited for
production.
So right here we're going to just use Babel which we already have installed since we've installed babbel
down below.
We have access to both of these.
Now we are going to use babbel providing a series of arguments.
The first thing we do is list out where our code lives.
In this case it is in the source directory.
Next up we have to list out where we want to put the output.
So Babel is going to take all of our files and transform them.
When those files are transformed where do they go.
So unlike babbel node which just runs our app on the fly.
The battle command actually doesn't run our app.
It just transforms the files so the input is the source directory.
Right here we use hyphen hyphen out.
Hi Van Der.
And then we provide the output directory.
I'm just going to call that d'Este.
So at this point Babel would read our source directory.
It would run everything through all of the presets and plug ins we've installed and it would spit those
files out into the disk directory.
Let's go ahead and actually see that in action.
So I'm going to save package dot Jason.
Closing down all directories and opening up graft.
Well Prisma from the terminal all we're going to do is run NPM run Heroku hyphen post build.
And when we do this it is indeed going to run babbel and we'll notice that there is a single new directory
the dist folder this contains all of our javascript files and if we were to crack just one of them open
we can see that they have indeed been transformed.
This looks nothing like the code we wrote.
So in the end of the day this is the directory that we are going to run from Heroku.
Now the only thing you'll notice is that some files are missing files that aren't G-S related don't
get processed by babbel and are actually getting skipped here.
We can fix that by using the hyphen hyphen Copie hyphen files flag.
This is going to make sure to copy all files even if it's not getting processed.
This is going to include our graph Cuil files like schema dot graft well and our generated graphics
file.
Now that save package data Jason and run that exact same script again this time around we're still going
to have that disk directory.
But you'll notice we have some newcomer's We do indeed have our schema file and we also now have our
generated directory.
So this contains everything that node needs to run our application and we have to do to startup the
app is use node and run a file from the disk directory called index dot J ass.
Now we are going to test this out so let's go ahead and toss Ian V.
CM d up front.
And for this we are going to load in our production file that's dot forward slash config forwards slash
Prod. dot E and V.
Perfect.
And if we actually run this it's gonna fail and we're going to talk about why I'm going to go down to
the terminal and run NPM start.
This is going to try to start everything up.
But we are going to be greeted with an error and if we scroll up we can look at the error.
Right here we have our message or reference error a regenerator runtime is not defined.
So this is something that's provided when we use babbel node but it's not provided when we just use
babbel we can use Babel node in development.
We can't use it in production which means that we have to make a small change to our app.
And I promise this one is also pretty easy to address.
So babbel has a whole bunch of different things.
If we go over to babbel J as I go we can go ahead and take a look at what they have and if we go to
the docs.
One of the things they offer us is a poly fell down in the side bar there is babbel poly fell this adds
a whole bunch of stuff that's necessary and on the first line you can see it includes a custom regenerator
runtime that allows us to use advanced features like a sink and a weight down below you'll notice it
explicitly says this poly Thale is automatically included when you're using babbel node.
That's why we didn't run into this issue earlier.
In reality salving it is very simple.
We install something then down below we simply require it or inport it.
That's all we have to do to get this to work.
So let's do it.
We are going to go ahead and move into the terminal and install it using the command we have right here.
I'm going to clear the output and run NPM install the module we're installing is at Babel forward slash
poly Phil and we're gonna grab the latest version.
So at seven point zero point zero perfect.
Now when we install this to get things to work all we need to do is make a microscopic change to index
Dhananjay ass not the one in d'Este remember that's auto generated.
We can actually just remove that directory altogether.
For the moment we need to make a small change to index data and J.S. in the source folder up top.
We're going to do is load in that Polly fill and we want to do it before any of our code we can even
put it as the top line in the file right here.
We are going to import the following file.
We don't need anything from it.
So we can go right to our quotes that is at Babel forward slash poly fill.
Perfect.
So now our project is going to work with or without babbel node which is great.
It's a little more robust now.
From the terminal we can rerun our commands and make sure that things working right here.
NPM run Heroku hyphen.
Post build.
So we are going to rebuild our application generating a nudist directory and here it is.
Next up we are going to use NPM start or NPM run start.
They're both the exact same thing.
This previously failed but this time around it should indeed work.
And right here we have our message.
The server is up.
So now our scripts are good to go.
We are all set for Heroku.
I'm going to shut down our server and from the terminal run clear the goal from here on out is to get
everything in a get repository.
We're then going to send that repository with all of our code off to Heroku and Heroku is going to be
able to use that to run our application.
Heroku is going to run this script.
It knows about it.
It's a custom script supported by them.
Then it's going to run this script to startup the app.
So let's go ahead and get started.
First up we have to create a new get repository.
So once again it is a requirement for this course.
I'm not going to cover all the commands in detail but we will go one at a time from the root of our
project.
We're going to run it get in it.
It is super important that you run this from the root of our project not the root of the Course folder
and not some nested directory like the Prisma directory which we have been switching in and out of throughout
the class.
So before you hit enter just confirm you're in the right folder then we can run the command now from
here I am getting a few messages sent Visual Studio code has built in get support.
I'm just going to close that down and we're going to run and get status to get the status of our repository.
Right here we have a whole bunch of files in red under the header untracked files.
This is everything in our application and we want to track them.
But not all of them.
There are two directories we're going to ignore.
There's two directories we're not going to send to Heroku.
The first is node modules Heroku is going to run NPM install anyways and it's going to find all of the
dependencies we have listed here.
It can regenerate that folder no problem.
The other is the config directory which contains secrets and confidential information.
It's a best practice to avoid committing these to your repository.
So we want to leave those off as well to leave off both of those folders.
We're going to create a good ignore file in the root of our project in the graph.
Q El Prisma folder.
That file is called Gadot get ignore and we are going to ignore those two folders first up we have node
underscore modules.
Second up we have config.
Now if we save this file and to rerun the exact same get status command we can see the those two folders
are gone which is a good thing.
Now there's another directory We want to ignore as well and that's the dist folder for almost all purposes.
We're never going to have this locally.
We only have it locally because we were testing out the scripts that Heroku is going to run.
But since there is a chance it could exist.
Let's go ahead and ignore that as well.
Awesome.
So now we've ignored everything we wanted to ignore.
And we can go ahead and actually commit our code.
I'm going to start by running get ad dot.
This is going to add all of those untracked files to the staging area.
They're going to be committed the next time I make a commit and if I rerun get status we can see that
here we have a list of all files in the staging area under the header changes to be committed.
Now let's go ahead and actually create that first commit commit with the flag which is short for a message
and inside of a set of quotes we're going to provide the typical first commit message in it.
Commit.
Excellent.
Now we can fire this off.
And what do we have.
We have code committed to our repository.
Now you'll notice that inside of package dot Jason we're using the config file and I told you that this
script is going to be executed by Heroku.
But we've also just ignored that folder.
So the folder isn't actually going to get sent to Heroku and to address this all we're going to do is
remove ENVI CMT as well as the path to that file we'll be configuring the environment variable for our
Heroku app via the Heroku command line interface so we can just bring it back to what we had before
node running the index file in the disk folder.
Perfect.
I'm going to save that file and that calls for a nother commit.
So right here get status.
We have that one modified file get commit with the AM flag a is going to add all of my changed files
to the commit and and allows me to provide that message.
I can just say something like updated or excuse me update start script for Heroku and commit that.
Now I'm ready to create the Heroku application.
Now we could create the Heroku app via the web site but we can also just do it right here inside of
the terminal.
So I am going to clear the terminal output and run Heroku create to create our application.
This is only going to take about a second.
And there are three useful pieces of information that are going to get spit out.
One we have our application.
This is useful for finding it inside of the web app version of Heroku.
We also have that you Arel where our code will eventually be visible.
So whatever our app does can be found here.
Now I could alt click it right now.
Check out the keyboard shortcut for your operating system and when I get brought to is just an empty
page it's saying welcome to your new app but it's not showing our app because we haven't pushed our
code up now.
Just before we push our code we need to make sure that all of the environment variables that are code
or relies on are actually set.
We have to in index.
Yes we have port.
This is automatically set by Heroku.
We don't have to do anything to get support for this.
The other one though.
Inside of Prisma dot ingenius is something we want to configure.
We want to configure a value for Prisma end point.
So in this code runs it actually uses the correct string.
Now over inside of Prod..
Ian VI we have that strength.
We can actually take this entire line copy it to the clipboard and we're going to use it in a terminal
command down below that command is Heroku config Colan set.
Here we can set key value pairs using key equals value.
We are just going to paste in what we copied from the file up above.
I'm going to paste it in.
Hit enter.
And that is going to set the environment variable on Heroku.
Now if I were to run something like Heroku config we would be able to view all of the environment variables
that are set by us and right here we do indeed have the one we just set which is fantastic none the
last piece of information from that Heroku create command was actually the repository you Arel and Heroku
create automatically adds that as a get remote.
So if I run get remote with the V flag which is short for verbose we can see all of the remotes set
up.
We have set up none but Heroku did set up one called Heroku.
That's what we're going to push too.
So he can push to it using get push Heroku which is the remote name Master which is the default brand
name.
If we fire this off it's actually going to send all of the committed code up to her Roku Heroku is then
going to install our modules.
It's going to run the code through Babel and it's going to start up our application.
Now the process for deploying can take anywhere from maybe 20 to 40 seconds.
So I'm just going to kill some time by saying some words until the process completes.
So right here we can see that the modules were installed.
It's now running our command we can see all of the files being copied and everything is done.
The last step is compression.
The app should indeed be deployed in just a few moments.
And it's important to note that once the app is deployed it can typically take three to five seconds
for it to show up.
So when I refresh the page we might have to wait just a little bit of time but that's only for the first
time you deploy.
If I were to refresh again it would load instantly right here what do we have.
We have a graph Well playground instance.
This is a production version of our node app connected to the production version of our Prisma application.
What does that mean.
Well that means we should be able to access that one user we created.
Remember this guy I'm going to go ahead and do just that.
So for him or her Roku app you RL I am going to use a query.
Now I have access to any of the queries we've set up for our node app right over here we can see we
have a few different options.
I'm just going to use the user's query to try to match that one user that I know lives in our production
database right here.
Users.
The selection set will just grab the id the name and the email for every user.
And if I fire that off what do we get back.
We get back the idea in the name and we don't get back the e-mail sends we're not authenticated.
And there we go.
We now have the production version of our Prisma service our database and our Heroku app up and running
which takes care of all three things we wanted to accomplish.
Now that does not mean we're done yet.
There are a few other things I want to talk about in this section and some are super important related
to security.
I mentioned that we should include that config directory because it contains sensitive information but
we still have sensitive information in our project.
For example inside of our Prisma file we have our secret.
That's definitely something we want to pull out into an environment variable and handle more securely.
We're going to knock out that as well as other topics throughout the rest of this section.
So stay tuned and I will see you soon.
Oh quick reminder that PTF guide contains all of these steps.
So you probably went along as you watch the videos if you deploy again and you forget don't watch the
videos again.
Just go back to the PTF guide and work through the steps from there.
The process will be way quicker.
All right.
C-A.