In this video we're going to continue to extract sensitive information out of our codebase and inject
those values via environment variables instead.
Now that's not to say this is a bullet proof method but our code base is going to get passed around
quite a bit.
We send it off to Heroku we send it to get hub.
Maybe we share it with others to collaborate on the project.
And it's just a best practice to keep sensitive information like secrets out of your codebase and use
environment variables instead.
It also makes it much easier to change those values because you can just change the config instead of
having to dig through your code and find all the places it's used.
So right here we have the secret and we have the actual string written out.
We're going to go ahead and start by pulling the secret out of our code base.
So I'm going to delete the string and we're going to end up referencing an environment variable instead.
So that's process.
Ian V dot and here we can pick a name since it's not set up yet.
I'm going to use something like Prisma in uppercase which is merely a convention then underscore then
secret.
So following the same pattern from Prisma and point perfect.
Now it's important to remember that this was not the only place we used the secret in our code base.
We also used it in the Prisma y AML configuration file.
Here we have the secret listed out as well.
We have the full text instead.
We want to reference an environment variable just like we did for the End Point up above.
So right here dollar sign curly braces NVI colon followed by the name.
In this case we just picked Prisma underscore secret.
Excellent.
So now the secret is no longer in the code base but to make sure our project still works.
We have to inject that value for both development and production to get that done over in dev Dom envy.
I'm going to set up the environment variable for the development environment.
All we have to do is add a second line to the file setting the name to Prisma underscores secret and
setting the value equal to whatever secret value we want to use.
I'm just going to use a series of characters and numbers you can come up with something completely random
on your own or you could use some sort of secure password generator.
Perfect.
Now we're going to end up doing the exact same thing for Prod. envy because remember this file is used
when we deploy our Prisma application so we need to make sure the variable is in here as well.
Otherwise no secret is going to get set when this file has the variables injected so over and prod NV
We're also going to add a second line.
Setting up Prisma underscore secret.
Giving a value equal to whatever we want.
Once again I'm just going to come up with a completely different random set of characters.
Perfect.
Now this is not the only place we have to set the prod environment variable because remember this file
on our machine is going to help us with this.
But this file is not getting sent to Heroku So we also want to configure Prisma secret on Heroku with
the same value.
So down below we can go ahead and get that done.
If you remember from the last video that is Heroku space config Colon's set followed by that key value
pair.
I can just copy the one we have above taking this second line for the production file.
Pasting it down below.
And if I hit enter that environment variable will get set.
We can always confirm that it is indeed set correctly by using Heroku config to pull out all of our
environment variables.
And here are the two listed.
Match up with the two we have in this file which is exactly what we want.
Now we can actually test our work.
I'm going to start by testing things out locally then we'll worry about testing things in production.
So in the terminal I can clear my output and I am going to CD into the Prisma directory and from there
we're going to deploy it to development.
That would be Prisma deploy with the E flag then we provide the path to that file from the Prisma folder.
That's dot dot forward slash config forward slash dev dot NV.
And if I fire that off it should go through the deployment process.
Now it's not going to update any of our fields since we don't have any fields changing but it is still
going to deploy because the secret did indeed change.
Now that it's deployed in development let's go ahead and run our application and make sure the connection
still works.
To do that I am going to CD out of the Prisma folder and use the script we created earlier.
Our dev script.
So right here that would be NPM a run Dev that is going to start up our server on localhost 4000 and
as long as we're able to pull some data out of the database we know the secret is indeed working for
both Prisma and for our node app.
So I'm going to go ahead and move over to graph Q L playground at localhost 4000 and I'm just going
to fire off a query.
Any request works right here.
This query for users would work just fine and then do indeed come back.
I can always change the data we select just to confirm we are actually seeing changes.
Perfect.
So now things are working locally in development and the secret has been extracted from the code base.
So let's go ahead and push things up to Heroku and confirm it works there as well.
Before we do you'll notice we have a new warning down below related to Babel Polly.
It's telling us that we've loaded babbel poly fell more than once in development and that's true.
Remember babbel node includes Babel.
Polly Phil and we've also included it in index Dhananjay s.
Then there's a very easy solution to remove this warning.
It's a warning not an error but we can still address it.
All we do is change our imports statement.
That's at Babel forward slash Pylea Phil put forward slash.
No conflict.
This is going to avoid conflicts.
Just loading the original version and not trying to load the library again.
Now if we actually save index dot J as the app restarts and the warning is gone.
Perfect This is still going to load in production though so don't worry about that.
We're still going to have what we need when we deploy to Heroku.
Let's go ahead and do just that.
I'm going to shut down our server.
Clear the output and run and get status so we can see the changes we've made.
We changed these three files and that is indeed correct.
Let's go ahead and commit them.
Get commit with the AM flag and we're gonna pick a message for this extract Prisma secret to environment
variable.
Perfect.
I'm going to make that commit.
Then we're going to deploy.
By pushing that up to her Roku so get push Heroku master the same command we ran in the last video.
Now once again when we push this up Heroku is going to take the new code.
It is going to install any new dependencies.
It is then going to go through the process of running our code through babbel and starting up the application.
And you'll notice that typically the second deployment goes a little quicker than the first deployment.
And right here it looks like we are past the Babble's stage and it is now starting up our application
all we're going to do once it's up is make sure that it's still working.
I want to make sure that I can still communicate between my production node app and my production Prisma
instance down below I can see that the application has indeed been launched.
We're now ready to test things out.
So what am I going to do.
Well I also have to deploy my Prisma project to production.
So right here all we have to do is use Prisma deploy from the Prisma directory.
So that would be CD Prisma then we run Prisma deploy with the E flag dot dot forward slash config forward
slash Prod. dot e and B.
Once that's done which it should just take a few seconds to do we'll be ready to actually test things
out.
All right.
Right here I can see that the production deployment has completed we're getting essentially the same
output from when we deployed to development a couple of minutes ago and now over in the browser.
I'm going to pull up my production instance of the node app so that's the Heroku app you are out right
here.
I'm going to give things a refresh and we should still see our instance.
And as long as I can communicate with the server.
I know that the secret is still configured correctly.
So all I'm going to do is update my queries so he can see the changing data.
I'm going to fire it off and we're going to see what we get back right here.
We have our data showing up.
So there we go.
We've successfully extracted that secret out of our code base using environment variables instead.
Now it's your turn to do something similar as your challenge for this video is I'm going to start by
closing down all open files and collapsing all expanded directories and we're going to focus on a different
area of our project where we currently have some sensitive information right in the code base.
If I go into the source resolvers directory excuse me the source you tills directory.
We have some code that is currently using JWT daat sign and the secret is right in line.
So this is a another example of a value that we want to pull out into an environment variable instead.
And we also use that over and get user ID to verify the J.
W.T. that gets sent from the client.
So here we create it here we verify it.
In both cases we want to use an environment variable down below and some very high level comments to
guide you in the right direction goal pole JWT secret out of code and into ENVI VAR for Dev and production.
You're going to reference those variables in the node application where ever we currently have the secret
in line.
You're then going to add the environment variables into our config files and on the Heroku application
for production.
And finally you're going to deploy and test so to test your work.
All you need to do is log in or sign up and make a secure request if you can do that that we know our
J.W. are still working and you're going to test things in development and in production.
So take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Don't forget to test your work then come back and click play
how that go let's go ahead and kick things off by first pulling those strings out of our code.
So I'm going to remove the string.
This is a secret and replace it with process.
Dot Ian V dot something.
I'm going to use JWT secret for this.
Now we can do the exact same thing in generate token where that same string was also used instead of
the string.
We're just going to reference the same environment variable process.
Ian V dot JWT secret.
Perfect.
So that takes care of step 1.
We have our secret in both places.
Now we need to actually add an environment variable called JWT secret.
So the code still works in the config directory.
We're going to set that up in our ENVI files right here for dev dot envy.
We're going to add a third line and JWT secret equals and we can pick once again any sort of random
value we like.
And inside of product EMV We're also going to add J.
W.T. secret sending an equal to some sort of random series of characters.
Perfect last up we also have to set the production value on Heroku.
So I'm going to take this and use the Heroku config set command from the terminal I am going to clear
the output and use C.D dot dot to go back to the root project and from here that will be Heroku config
Colon's set.
Pasting in the line I just copied.
I can fire that off and now we have the environment variable set everywhere.
This brings us to step three which is actually to deploy and test our work.
I'm going to go ahead and remove the challenge comments at this point since we are going to end up committing
our changes before we bother to commit though let's test things out locally by running our application
in development.
Now for this particular environment variable it's actually not necessary to redeploy Prisma because
Prisma doesn't use it.
It's only our node J.S. app.
So we only have to deploy our node.
JS app with Prisma secret.
It was used in our Noad app and in our Prisma project.
That's not the case here.
So all I'm going to do is run the app in development from the terminal.
That would be NPM run dev.
And we're going to make sure that I can still log in and then make a secure request if I can.
We're good to go.
So the server is up and running.
I'm going to switch over to a local host 4000 and I'll go over to my log in request.
Let's go ahead and log in as Sarah.
I get a token I'm going to copy that and then we'll use this token to get her profile so right here
I can just use the query which requires authentication.
Down below I'm going to swap out the old barer token with the new one.
I'm going to fire off the request.
And what do I get.
I get the data back which is fantastic.
So by doing those two things we've confirmed that the J W T secret is indeed being injected correctly.
Now we're ready to commit and deploy to production.
So down below I am going to shut down the local development server and I'll just run get status to make
sure everything looks semi-normal and it does we just have changes to the two files.
We actually changed so we can go ahead and use get commit with the M flag to provide our message right
here something along the lines of pull JWT secret out of code.
Perfect.
Now we can use it get push Heroku master to deploy our application and once the app is deployed over
going to do is test it once again.
So from the production node app I'm just going to log in then I'll go ahead and try to make a secure
request.
Right here we can see the process should be done in just a moment.
I'm going to cut the video to when deployment is complete.
All right.
The app is deployed.
Let's test things out.
I'm going to move over to the graphic and playground instance for the production node app and I'm going
to create a new user.
We do have that one user in the production database but remember we created them without hashing the
password since we bypassed node just to make sure that Prisma was working.
So we're going to create a new one right here and nutation.
I'm going to use create user and we're going to provide the necessary arguments.
We just need to provide data with the name email and password for here.
Let's set up all three name.
I will use less USERRA for this then the email I'll stick with Sarah at example dot com followed finally
by the password and I'll just use read one two three four five once again.
Perfect.
Now we also have to provide our selections set and in this case I'm just going to grab the token that
comes back I could grab some information about the user too but that's not necessary for our purposes.
So I fire that off.
Sarah gets created and I get her off token.
All we have to do is make sure it works.
So for my other tab I'm going to use the query query me.
I'll just grab the id the name and the email of whoever were authenticated as and down below I am going
to set up the headers to actually be authenticated.
So I set up my Jason object I am going to provide just a single key value pair the header name is authorization
and the value is barer space followed by the token that was generated.
Now if I fire this off we should be able to see Serra's details and that is exactly what we end up getting
back which is great.
We've now proven that our change works both locally and in production and we are all done extracting
that.
Jason Webb tokin throughout the process of pulling values out into environment variables We've also
broken the script in packaged Jason get schema this looks in the Prisma ADOT why a file to figure out
exactly what it's supposed to do.
But that file doesn't really contain hardcoded values anymore more it contains environment variable
references and those environment variables currently aren't getting loaded in.
Which means that this script is going to fail down below if I run it using NPM run then you get hyphen
schema.
We can see that it is indeed going to crash.
Right now it's trying to communicate and it does indeed fail.
All we have to do to fix that is add a dot envy argument on and provide a path to our dev configuration.
So right here that would be config forward slash dev dot NV.
Just providing a path to this file that's going to actually inject those environment variables.
And if we save package Jason things should be working.
Once again I'll rerun the exact same script from down below using the up arrow key.
And this time we can see that it did indeed work.
No changes were recorded but that was expected.
The goal was to just make sure it could communicate successfully.
That's where we're going to stop for this video and that's where we're going to stop for this section.
We have our production database up and running.
We have the production version of our Prisma project and we have the production version of our node
J.S. app so that handles everything we need to get our apps securely deployed in the next section we're
going to cover testing.
I'm super excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.