In the last section we spend all of our time looking at one of the three operations that graph you all
supports.
We were looking at the query operation as mentioned in this section we're going to be focusing on the
mutation operation which allows us to change data on the server so we can create data.
We could update data or we could delete data.
Now the end goal of all of this is to be able to perform mutations from our graph client and actually
perform operations like signing up a user.
So remember the graft you client could be a web app a mobile app or in this case just graphed Well playground
if it was a web or mobile app I'd be getting some data from a form like a sign up form and they would
need a way to actually pass that to the server.
Then the server needs to respond accordingly.
It's probably going to do a little bit of validation on that data for example making sure the email
is not already in use by another user and then it's going to respond accordingly either sending back
some success message or sending back an error message letting the client know that things didn't go
correctly.
So all of this is possible with mutations and we're going to start as I mentioned with that sign of
mutation.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by moving down to our type definitions.
This is where we're going to define all of the mutations we want to support just like we have defined
all of the queries we want to support.
So right here after queery though it could be before or at the very end we are going to set up a new
type definition for another built in type mutation then we're going to set up our curly braces and in
here we define all of the mutations we want our server to be able to perform.
What's nice about defining a mutation is that it's basically the exact same thing as defining a query.
So we're going to be able to reuse a lot of what we already covered in the last section.
The syntax here is going to look very familiar.
Let's go ahead and start by naming the operation.
So we're going to have a few mutations by the time we're done here.
I'm going to call this first one something like create user now create user is indeed going to require
some arguments.
If you are going to create a user the client is going to have to send some data across in this case
you have to send a name and an e-mail and.
You could also send an age.
So we have to set up some arguments exactly like we did for our queries right here.
I'm going to set up my arguments list the first one can be name which will be a required string.
The second one can be email which will also be a required string.
And lastly we're going to have age which will be an optional event so you'll notice that the actual
type definitions for all three match up with the type definitions down below.
For the user type now that we have our operation name and the set of arguments the operation supports
we have to provide the value that the operation returns.
So right here when you create a new user what are you going to get back.
You're going to get back the user that you created.
So right here we have a non nullable user as the resolved value.
Now this is the final mutation definition there's nothing left to do here.
The next step is to actually define a resolver for create user much like we defined resolver for every
single query we set up.
So once again we're going to move down below and create a brand new method down below what we're going
to end up doing is creating a new property on the resolvers object called mutation and adding a new
method into that object create user.
Now I understand that for the moment everything is in one file and this one file is starting to get
a bit long.
We are going to introduce a more real world directory structure very shortly.
For the moment though we're going to stick with our one file solution.
So down below a new root property right alongside of query and our other properties I'm going to add
this right after the query property.
So a new property called nutation with a capital M.
We're going to set that object up and toss a comma at the end and inside of here we need just that one
method for our one mutation.
I'm going to be calling this one create user now like with every other resolver function we've created
whether it's for a mutation or one of our custom object types we're going to get those same four arguments
we're going to get the parent We're going to get our args.
We're going to get the context and we're going to get the info and inside of here what do we do.
We do something similar to what we would do for a query with a query we are just concerned with fetching
data for a mutation.
We're concerned with actually creating updating or deleting some data and then responding accordingly.
So in this case we know we're going to get some values passed in via that args argument.
That's where we're going to have access to the e-mail and the name which are required and the age which
is completely optional to start.
All I want to do is use console dialog or to dump the args argument to the council and then going to
save this file expand the terminal so we can actually see the log.
And we're going to run our very first nutation operation from graft UL playground for the moment.
We're not actually creating a new user and we're not returning the data that create user expects to
get back a user object.
But that's OK.
This will still work for the most part over engraft UL playground.
We're going to create a brand new tab for our very first mutation and we start off with the mutation
keyword just like we do with queries.
So right here we define the mutation.
We set up our curly braces and in here we list out the mutation we want to run in this case we only
have one it's called create user.
Now the syntax for all of this is going to look so similar to the syntax we saw when we worked with
a query that took an argument.
I know we have one somewhere here.
Here we go.
So it's going to look very similar to what we have here where we pass those arguments in right after
we name the mutation operation we're trying to perform.
That means over and the create user tab we can set up our parentheses and we can provide all of the
arguments that create user expects.
Now we know it expects the name and the email and optional.
It could also get the age.
For now let's just provide a name in the email so name call and space equals I'll use my name Andrew.
Then I'll set up an email as well.
Email that value is also a string.
I'll use something like testing an example dot com.
Perfect.
So here we have our arguments list and the next thing we're going to do is provide our selections set
just like we did for a query.
So what comes back from create user will a user comes back and this is where we can get all of the data
for the new user.
So right here for the moment let's go ahead and grab its ID.
We're going to grab its name its e-mail.
And finally the age now this query is indeed going to fail it's going to fail because create user does
not respond with a user.
But we can still go ahead and run this to see our log print.
So over here in the terminal Yes we do have a very long error message but just above that we have our
console log.
It is indeed printing an object with the name and the e-mail that we're passed along with the mutation.
So there we go.
We have our very first mutation set up engraft UL playground.
What we want to continue to do is actually wire up the back and actually perform the correct tasks.
What we're going to do here is a couple of things we're going to see if the e-mails unique.
We're then going to create a new user object with a randomly generated ID.
We'll add it to the array and we'll return the new user.
Let's go ahead and take this all off by talking about the one NPM library we're going to need to install
to get this done.
That is the ideal library.
If you've taken any of my other courses you've probably used this before.
It's my favorite library for generating random ideas.
You can find it by googling NPM.
You you ID right here we can find the page for it.
You can find either the NPM package page or the hub repository.
I'm going to head over to the get hub repository and here you can learn all about how to use you you
I.D. to generate random IDs and the end of the day what it really gives you is just a function you can
call to generate a new random ID as a string.
We're going to go ahead and install this and then use it to actually generate the new ID for this new
user we're creating.
So down below in the terminal I am going to use Control C to shut down node man and then NPM install
right here.
We are going to provide the module name.
It is a you ID right here.
Will be using the latest version at three point three point two.
Now once this is installed we can just run NPM start again to restart our server then we'll actually
use this library to generate the random ID.
I'm going to use the up arrow key twice to cycle through to the command.
I ran two commands ago which was indeed and start we can run them I can collapse the terminal and we
can actually use this library.
Now the ID library comes with five different functions we can use to generate random IDs.
Excuse me it's actually just four.
There is a V-1 the three the four and V five.
Now the newest version isn't necessarily the best.
Each version just has a different way.
It generates randomness.
So in the case of the first one it's time stamp based version 3 is namespace based version 4 is random.
And version 5 is an alternative name specced version.
We're going to be using version for the completely random one.
So there are two steps to actually using this.
First we import it up above then we actually call the method we've imported so up at the very top of
the file let's just add our import statement right here.
We are importing.
And in the case of this library it is a default export we're trying to grab it so I'll name that right
here.
I'm going to call you you ID the for then we grab it from the following you you ID forward slash V for.
And now we can actually use this function down below to get a random ID back.
So let's go ahead and start the process of filling out the create user method to actually do something
meaningful to start.
What we're going to do is create a new constant.
A variable called email.
Take it email take and it's going to end up being true if the email this person is trying to register
with is already in use it will be false.
If the email is not already in use and to determine whether the e-mail is in use or not will be using
users dot some these some array method is great for exactly what we're trying to do.
It's going to return true if some of the users have that e-mail in return false.
If none of the users have that e-mail which is exactly what we want.
So like most of our array methods we provide a callback function.
This function gets called one time for every single array in the list that gets called with the individual
a right item.
We have an array of users so I'll call this one user and this is just one of the objects stored in that
user's array.
So one of the objects we have up above like this first one with these four properties.
So now down below it is the job of this callback function to return true if the email is indeed already
in use.
So if user dot email equals the email they're trying to register with which is our exact email.
So if they are equal this will be true and we return true if they're not equal.
This will be false and we return false.
So as long as one of these return true then some of them do.
An e-mail taken will be true.
Now as always we can simplify this.
We can use the shorthand for the arrow function right here I can remove the curly braces and just implicitly
return user dot e-mail equals args dot email.
Excellent.
So we have this first line in place and now what we can do is actually throw an error if the e-mail
is taken.
So right here if we're going to check if the e-mail taken variable is true.
If it is true what are we going to do.
I'm going to throw a new error throw new error.
So here we are just throwing a brand new javascript error and we can provide an error message which
will actually get sent back to the client.
So we need to be specific and actually say what happened.
I'm going to use e-mail taken as my message.
Perfect.
So now that we are checking if the e-mail is indeed registered or not and we're already handling that
all of the code down below is only going to run if the email is not taken and we can actually create
this brand new user.
So let's go ahead and start that process off by creating a new object called user.
And on here we are going to do a few things.
First up we are going to generate a new random ID then we're going to pull all of the arguments and
add those on as properties.
So right here ID equals we're going to call are you you ID the for function to generate a new string
ID then we're going to set up the other properties necessary.
So right here there are three other ones on args and we're just going to pass all of them through to
this object.
So we have name args dot name.
Then we have email args dot email.
And then finally we have name excuse me age args dot age.
From here we have our user object all set up and we have to do two more things.
First we're going to quote unquote save it by just adding it to that array.
So I will use users don't push it to add this new object onto the end.
And then finally we are going to return the user object.
So the client can actually get some values off of it.
Now in this case three of the values that come back are things that are actually sent to us.
But it would be nice to be able to get the ID of the user that was just created and by returning the
user we allow the client to be able to get that data.
Now that we have a valid create user method let's go ahead and actually run that query again over here.
I'm going to move to the graph Well playground and we're not going to change anything about the mutation
we already had set up.
All I'm going to do is fire this off again.
And what do I get back I get back data that matches up with my structure over here.
So on the data property we have a property for the nutation name.
Create user.
Then we have all of the data we chose to select from that user.
In this case we chose to select all four fields and we're getting all four back for ID we have our randomly
generated ID which is awesome.
Then we have h.
Excuse me name and for name we have the name we passed across for email we also have the value we passed
across.
We did not provide an age so no age was actually set up.
And what are we getting back.
We're getting back an age value of NULL.
Now if I were to rerun this operation once again this time around we do get the error.
So here the data property is empty and we have this new errors property which is an array of all of
the errors that occurred in this case we just have one and the message for that is the exact message
that we set up e-mail taken.
So we just registered with this e-mail a few moments ago when we reran the query we tried to register
with it again and that failed because the code in our function actually checks the user's array.
Now for the moment if I were to actually change something like I'm moving this period from the error
message and I were to save the file again all of the data gets reset.
So this user that we just created no longer exists because the server restarts and the users array contains
just the things hardcoded above.
So after saving the data I can indeed rerun this operation and it works.
But once again if I rerun it a second time it does indeed fail.
We'll fix all of that when we actually start saving the data to a real database.
That's why I like to start for this one.
Let's take a quick moment to recap what we learned.
We learned that like with a query there are two sides to any mutation.
There is the client operation and there is the server definition.
So if I want to support a mutation I have to actually define it on the server then it can be used from
the client.
Now for the definition of a mutation it was actually super similar to a query.
We define a new mutation type and we list out all of the mutations we want to support.
We give them a name.
We set up the arguments and we set up the return value down below.
We define a resolver method just like we did for any of our queries here.
We take in the input via the args argument and we return whatever data the mutation expects to return.
In this case we decided that a user was the appropriate return value.
Now from the client's perspective it actually also looks very similar to a query instead of query we
have nutation and instead of one of our queries we have one of our mutations.
So here we have the create user a mutation which takes in some arguments and then returns that user.
So we can provide the selection set.
We actually want know once again I don't have to grab everything.
Maybe I just want to grab the ID for the newly created user.
That would be fine as well.
I can also choose to grab something like the posts and send this particular user has no posts since
they just got created.
We'll get an empty array back.
So all of this is possible with mutations and in the next video we're going to continue to explore mutations
and also be a challenge.
You'll be required to create a mutation of your very own.
I'm excited to continue on with this section.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next video.