In this video we're going to continue to talk mutations together.
We'll be creating a mutation called create post for adding a new post.
And as your challenge for the video you'll be creating a third mutation called create content which
will allow someone to add a comment onto a post together that we are going to start with that create
post mutation and we're also going to explore a couple other features of graft Well that make working
with our mutations just a little bit easier.
Up above though we are going to start by setting up the definition for create post right here after.
Create user will be setting up the Create post mutation and once again we need a set of arguments and
we have to determine what data comes back what's going to come back from Create post will indeed be
a post.
So we'll set that up first.
Now it's time to determine what values we actually need to create a new post.
What we don't need an ID that's going to be randomly generated we need a title we need a body we need
published and we also need to know which author this post should be associated with.
So I actually need a user id passed along with Create post and any create post resolver method.
We're going to verify that that user ID actually matches up with one of our users.
So right here.
Let's go ahead and list all of that out.
We're going to have title as a non nullable string.
After that we're going to go ahead and have a body once again a non nullable string.
Then we're going to have published this will be a non nullable boolean.
And then finally we have author which will be a non nullable ID.
So there we go.
We have the mutation definition all set up for create post and down below.
We can actually set up the resolver method for it.
So down here along side of create user right after it I'll add a comma a new line and we'll set up create
post and will also define all of the arguments for this one.
So we have our parent we have args we have context and we have info.
Once again we only know about a couple of these we will learn about the other ones as we progress through
the class.
But for the moment they're not particularly useful but we're actually trying to do.
So the first thing we're going to do inside of Kreep post is make sure that the author ID they gave
us actually matches up with the ID for one of our users.
The code for getting this done is going to look pretty similar to what we have up above though the opposite.
Instead of trying to make sure there is no person with that email we're going to try to make sure that
there is a person with that ID.
So right here a variable a constant something along the lines of user exists will get the job done.
And once again we'll be using the same method on our users array.
So users dot some.
Now we set up our callback function where we get access to the individual user and we are going to return
true if the user's ID matches up with the args dot author value.
If they do match up then we know we have found a match.
And as long as one of these match some will return TRUE meaning that the user does indeed exist.
Now in this case we do still want to throw an error related to this variable but we only want to throw
an error when the user does not exist.
So here we set up our IF statement if user exists is the opposite of what we want.
So I will flip that using the logical operator then we can add our code.
And in this case the code can once again just throw an error.
So throw in new error and we can say something like.
User not found.
Awesome.
So now all of the code down below this if statement is only going to run if we actually did find a matching
user.
Well we can do now is similar to what we did right here.
We're going to create a new post.
We're going to save it by pushing it onto that array.
And finally we are going to return the post object.
I'm going to start by creating a new constant called post.
This will be the object and we are going to generate a random ID for this post.
So ID equals we will be using a u u ID V for a function to generate that brand new ID.
And once we have it generated we're going to provide the other values necessary.
So we have tidal which lives on args title we have a body which lives on args dot body.
And then finally we have published which lives on args dot published.
I said finally but there actually is one more we can't forget.
Author also necessary author lives on args dot author.
Now we're going to learn how to clean all of this up with the object spread operator in the next video.
But before we actually add support for that syntax with babble This is indeed going to get the job done.
Now what do we do.
We push that on to our array.
So we have our posts array.
I'm going to use push to add it.
And what are we going to push.
We're going to push that object.
And finally we will return the post and there we go our create post mutation is all done.
Let's go ahead and actually test this out by moving over to graphical playground.
So the first thing we have to do is decide which user we want to add this post for.
I'm going to go ahead and create a new user adding the post for them since I just saved the project
file.
All of the old users have been reset.
I can create a new user with this data.
And what do I get back I get back the ID.
I'm going to copy that to the clipboard because we're going to use this value in our create post mutation.
We can create a nother tab for that sitting right here and we're going to start off by setting up the
mutation and we are going to be using the Create post mutation right here.
We're going to set up our arguments and we're going to set up our selection set.
Now when you have a lot of arguments you can actually break those onto multiple lines.
It's common to hit enter right here and define all of your arguments on their own lines that would look
a little bit like the following.
We'll start off with the title which every create post mutation has to have.
Right here we have our title.
I will use my new post after the title we can add the body in for this one.
Let's say I just started and I haven't actually written anything yet.
Then we can set up published.
Since I haven't written anything yet let's get published.
Equal to false.
And lastly we have to provide the author value.
Who wrote this post.
And in this case I copied that so right inside of quotes I'm going to paste the ID I copy to the clipboard.
Now down below.
We can actually determine what we want and get back for each post.
Let's go ahead and grab the ID.
I'm also going to grab the title I'll grab the body I'll grab a published and we can actually grab related
data as well so I could choose to grab something about the author if I wanted to.
For example I can grab the author's name.
And lastly I'll also grab the comments just to show you that that would work well even though no comments
exist since the post is about to get created.
So right here I could say I want the ID for every single comment for example.
So with this operation in place let's go ahead and actually run things when I do what happens well our
create post mutation runs.
We have our data property with the Create post property in there we have all of the data we selected
about this newly created post.
I have the ID title body published and I have related data in this case I have the author name Andrew
which is indeed correct.
That is the exact name I used over here.
And I also have my comments array since the post was just created.
It has no comments but that's OK.
Now if we try to create a post using an ID that didn't match a user we would get an error.
So let's go ahead and add just a couple of characters up front if I rerun the exact same operation this
time around I get user not found it sends this ID does not match up with any user in the database.
Now we were able to successfully add at least one post.
That means that if I run the Post's query I should see that one is showing up.
Let's switch over to the other tab where we use the Post's query here grabbing the id the title and
the author's name.
If I actually run the same exact operation we can see we have our initials 3.
Then down below we have the one that we just created with the title my new post.
So there we go.
We have the Create post mutation.
All done.
It's now working really well.
We have create user we have create post.
It is going to be your challenge for this video to add create comment.
Let's go ahead and move into the challenge portion of this video and up above at the very top of the
file.
I'm going to outline the exact steps I'd like you to take to knock this one out.
Right here we have all of the steps necessary but in the end of the day the big picture goal is to just
allow clients to create new comments.
So let's talk about all the steps necessary to get this done.
Step one is to define a new create commnet mutation.
So this mutation should take three arguments.
We're going to have the actual comment text.
So what are you trying to say.
We're also going to have the authors ID.
So which user is actually trying to leave this comment.
And we additionally need the post ID right here we need this so we know what post we're commenting on.
So with Create post we had a single ID argument.
That was author with create comment.
We're going to have to we need the author and we need the post in order to create the comment.
Now the comment is going to end up returning a comment just like we have done for the other mutations
create user returns and user create post returns a post.
So that brings us to step 2 which is to actually define the resolver method for create comment right
here to start.
What you have to do is make sure that the user actually exists.
So when they call create comment they are passing in an author ID.
You have to verify the author Id actually matches up with a user.
If it does not you're going to throw an error.
Additionally you also want to make sure that the post exists and that it is published.
So you want to try to find a post in that array whose I.D. matches up with the post argument and whose
published value is true.
If you do not find the post and it's not published you also want to throw an error.
Now if you find the user and you find the published post.
Lastly you will create the comment and return it steps 3 and 4 involve testing your work.
So for Step three you're going to run the mutation and actually add a new comment for a given author
on a given post and for Step 4 you're just going to use the comments query to fetch all of the comments
and make sure that the one you created actually shows up.
So take as much time as you need to knock this one out.
It's slightly more complex than the resolvers we've created so far because there are two checks you
have to make.
But you know how to get that done.
You just have to do the same thing twice.
Feel free to use the code down below any videos so far in the course to knock this out.
Take as much time as you need when you're done come back and click play.
All right let's get to it.
We're going to start with step one.
We have to define our mutation before we can create that resolver function.
So right here we have our type definitions.
I'm going to be adding a new one after create user and after create Post called create comment we're
going to set up the arguments and our return value which as I mentioned will just be a comment.
We need three arguments for create comment.
First up we have to know the comment text.
What exactly are you trying to say with this new comment.
This will be a required string.
Then we're going to have the two IDs necessary.
We need the author right here a non nullable ID.
And we also need to know the posts Id right here.
Another non nullable ID and there we go.
That is all you had to do for step 1.
That brings us to step 2.
We want to go ahead and define that resolver method and set up all of the logic necessary to verify
that the user exists and that the published post exists.
We're going to knock that down below.
Now this is one of those situations where there are plenty of different valid ways you could have solved
this problem.
There are basically an endless number of solutions to some of these challenges.
And that's OK.
So if your solutions not character for character the same as mine don't stress out about it.
If you have any questions or you're concerned that you might be missing some sort of edge case just
crack open a new question in the Q&amp;A and post your solution there.
We'll be happy to take a look and make sure there isn't anything that could potentially cause problems.
So right here we are going to create the Create comment method setting up those four arguments.
We have our parent we have arx we have context and we have info excellence inside of here.
The first thing we're going to do is verify that the user exists and that the published post exists.
I'm going to start by verifying that the user exists.
So right here a Konst user exists will get the job done like it did before.
I'll also use users got some passing in that callback function where we get access to the individual
user.
I'm going to return TRUE saying we've found a match if the user's I.D. matches up with the args dot
author property.
Now we can do the exact same thing for the post sir right here.
Conc post exists.
We are going to use posts dot some to try to find that match.
And this one is going to be slightly different.
So we're going to verify that not only we can find the post by ID but also that the post is published
so we get access to the Post's argument right here and we can return the following.
We're going to use the logical and operator.
So I want to confirm that the post I.D. matches up with the exact post property.
That's step one.
But I also only want to return true if in this case if the Post dot published property is indeed true.
So I only want to return true if the post is published now sends this value is going to be either true
or false.
We can actually remove the equality operator and just use that boolean value directly.
This is the exact same functionality.
And now that we've written this out I am going to convert it to the shorthand so I'll take everything
that we return.
Copy it to the clipboard.
Remove the curly braces and then just implicitly return it.
So this is the same functionality just with the shorthand syntax.
Now we can use an IF statement to actually throw an error if something's not quite right.
Now you might have used one if statement for each.
For the user and the post I'm going to go ahead and just add one totals are not one each.
Right here if and what we're going to do is check if there was no user.
So if there is no user exists here using the logical operator to flip the boolean value.
So if there was no user or there wasn't a post so right here if there was no post referencing the post
exists variable.
If there was no user or there was no post we want to throw an error right here throw new error.
We can print whatever message we see fit.
I'll just say unable to find user and post and now down below.
We can write the code for when we do find the user and we do find that published post right here.
Let's go ahead and actually knock that out.
We're going to create our common object so Konst comment equals a brand new object and we're gonna set
up the four properties we need.
The first being our randomly generated ID which we get by calling the u you ID V for function.
Excellent.
All of the other three come right off of args so we have text which comes from args dot text.
I have author which comes from args dot author.
And finally we also have posts which comes from args dot post.
Now we can go ahead and push this object on to the comments array and return it right here.
Comments.
Drop.
Push pushing on the brand new comment.
In effect saving it and then finally return comment.
Excellent.
So this is just one way you could have solved step 2.
Maybe you've created three variables up here.
Maybe you used multiple if statements.
All of that is perfectly fine.
You do not need to match me character for character.
What you need to match me for is the functionality.
So let's go ahead and save this file.
And that brings us to steps 3 and 4 which we're actually going to do over engraft you playground.
We want to create a brand new comment and then we want to verify it was actually created by using the
comments query.
Now what we're going to need a user ID and a post ID to create that comment.
I could create a user and create a post with my two mutations.
I'm going to go ahead though and just use some of the static data.
I'm going to say that this third user with an ID of 3 is leaving a comment on this last post with an
ID of 12.
So those are the two IDs I'm going to use.
We can now create a new tab engraft UL playground and set up our create comment mutation.
So right here it is a mutation operation and we are using the Create comment mutation and we are going
to provide a list of arguments.
I'm going to use one line for each argument and we're also going to provide our selection set.
Let's go ahead and set up our arguments.
First we need the text but say I'll say something like.
You should check out David cutter music.
You actually should check that out.
Some of my favorite programming music is completely instrumental and it has a really nice vibe to it.
I'm also going to provide the author and the post ID so for author.
I said it was three I believe.
And then for a post.
Let's go ahead and double check.
I believe it was 13.
Nope it was 12.
So let's go ahead and use that ID right here.
Now we have all of the arguments set up and the last thing we have to do is provide our selection set.
So I'm going to grab the idea I'm going to grab the text and I'll also grab some related data.
I'll grab the author's name and I'll also choose to grab the post's title right here post title perfect
with all of this set up we can refresh the schema see that we have a completely valid operation and
actually fire this off.
I'm going to go ahead and create it.
And what do I see.
Unable to find user and post wups.
I actually think I picked a post that was not published.
Yes I did only the first post is published so I'm going to go ahead and just SWIP excuse me swap this
published value from false to true.
And we'll go ahead and try that again.
So I'll save index dot J s over here I'm going to rerun the same operation and this time it is indeed
working.
So we've already verified that our published check is indeed working correctly.
So right here what do we have.
We have our data.
We have our create common data.
We have the ID for the comment.
We have the common text.
The comment was left by Mike and it was left on a post called programming music.
All of that is indeed correct.
The last step is to run that comments query and make sure it was actually saved.
I have the comments queries sitting right over here.
I'm going to run that I get my static comment and then at the bottom what do I get.
I get my newly generated comment from the Create comment.
Mutation.
I have all of the same data I had over there because in the end of the day the selection set is identical.
I'm getting the author's name and I am getting the Post's title.
So there we go.
We've learned a bit more about how to use mutations when working with related data.
We now have mutations for creating a user for creating a post end for creating a comment.
What I'd like to spend the next couple of videos on are a few optimizations allowing us to improve our
arguments for mutations and allowing us to improve the actual code right inside in the next video we're
going to set up support for the object spread operator in our project allowing us to simplify the code
in these resolver methods.
I'm super excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right into the next one after saving index dot J as.