In this video as promised you're going to learn how to set up your application to support the object
spread operator.
So we're going to be installing a new NPM module.
We're going to be configuring it with babbel and then we'll explore how this operator works.
The operator is super useful making it really easy to copy object properties from one object to another.
Now before we actually install anything or change our babbel RC file I just want to pull out the module
page in Google so you know where it lives.
You can find it by googling NPM babble plugin transform object rest.
Spratt that is quite a mouthful but once you actually search for it it should bring you over to the
NPM package page.
Here you can learn exactly how it works and how the object respite operator works.
But we'll be covering all of that in just a little bit for the moment.
We're going to go ahead and actually install this plug in and configure babbel to use it.
So over inside a visual studio code I'm going to bring up the terminal I'm going to go ahead and shut
things down and use clear to clear the terminal output from here.
You're going to run NPM install and we're going to be installing that module.
So that's babbel hyphen plug in Haifa and it transform haif an object hyphen or arrest hyphens spread
it quite a few words there.
And we are going to specify the latest version that is six point twenty six point zero.
Awesome.
If we go ahead and actually run this command what do we do.
We go through the installation process and once that's done we're going to be able to change Babel RC
and we only have to make a three line change to this file when we install a plug in and we have to actually
tell babbel to use it much like when we install the preset we have to tell Babolat to use that as well.
We set up the plug ins that Babel should use by adding a new route propertied to our babbel configuration
file.
You can call this one plug ins and this is just an array of all of the plug ins you want to use.
So right here it's an array of strings.
Now you leave off the babble plug and prefix.
So the actual plug in name is this part right here.
So all I'm going to do is type transform object arrest spread and there we go.
Babbel is now all configured to use this brand new syntax.
From here we can save the babbel configuration file and I can rerun NPM is start from the terminal starting
up the application once again and down below or actually going to take advantage of this syntax I'm
going to take advantage of it right here inside of the create user mutation method.
As I mentioned earlier the whole goal with the object spread operator is to be able to easily copy properties
from one object to another.
That's exactly something we're doing manually throughout our mutation methods right here for example
we have the args object with various properties on it and we copy all of them to the user object.
But we have to do that manually which can be a bit cumbersome hairshirt sure it's only three lines for
three properties.
But as we had more properties it requires more manual work.
We do the exact same thing with Create post copying for properties from the args object and we also
do it with create comment the object spread operator gives us a better way to get this done.
So let's take a look at how it works.
First we need two objects.
I'm going to define a couple here for example purposes only so we can have Konst object one and we have
a another one Konst to also an object.
And we're just going to add some properties onto this first one.
I'll use something like name and I'll set the name equal to my current location Philadelphia and then
on the second object we're going to define a couple of other values.
Let's go ahead and do something like population and I believe the population is about 1.5 million at
the moment.
So we'll do one million five hundred thousand people in Philadelphia but now we decided we also want
all of the properties from one on it to.
So we have a couple of options.
Sure we can manually copy them over like we're doing with ours down below.
Or we can use the spread operator which is the following dot dot dot followed by the object we want
to spread out.
This has the effect of copying all properties from one over to two.
So now we have two objects.
The first object has a single property name and the second object has two properties it has population
and it has a name.
If we add more properties up here let's go ahead and put something in like Country USA.
Now two properties are going to be copied from one down to two.
So being able to easily copy all of the properties on a given object to another object is a very useful
thing to be able to do.
And we're going to use that right here instead of listing out all of these manually.
All I'm going to do is spread out using dot dot dot the args object.
Now we can do the exact same thing down below for our other mutations right here for create post instead
of listing out title body published and author manually.
I am just going to spread out the args object and I'll do the same thing down below for comment.
Try moving text author and post in just spreading out args once again.
Now we have a slightly easier way to maintain our code something that scales a bit better as args has
more properties on it.
If we actually save our program we can see that in the terminal.
Nothing's going wrong.
There is no error.
The program isn't crashing.
If you did not set up the plug in we just set up or you configured it incorrectly.
You would actually see an error at this point where a node would not know what to do with this operator
since we have configured everything correctly.
We are seeing that the server is up and it's just waiting for operations to be performed on the graph.
Well Back-End Let's go ahead and collapse the terminal and actually test our work.
So over here engraft UL playground.
All I'm going to do is fire off the three mutations we had before I fire off the first one and I get
my user.
I can then go ahead and create a post.
I'm going to create a post using the same mutation right here that works as well.
And finally we have create comment right here.
The comment was indeed created.
So we're getting the exact same functionality but using this object spread operator and that's where
I'd like to stop for this one in the next video we're going to continue learning about graft.
Well we're going to come up with a better way to structure the arguments for all of our operations.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.