In this video you're going to learn about a more real world and more advanced way to structure your
operation.
Arguments engraft Well when we were just working with the query operation we didn't really run into
a problem with argument structuring because we had at most one argument but with our mutations we're
going to end up having more and more arguments like with Create post where we have what for almost running
off the screen.
Well we're going to do in this video is come up with a better way to structure these.
We're not changing the applications functionality.
We're just learning about a new feature of graft.
Well allowing us to create more complex applications without more complex code.
Currently all of our arguments are of a scalar type so up above we have a couple of strings down below
we have plenty of strings as well but we also have ideas we have booleans and we have ints and we could
have used floats if they made sense for application.
So any of our five scalar types.
Well we can also set up operation arguments whose values are objects but it is going to require us to
learn about one new thing the input type.
So let's say that we don't want to pass in three arguments to create user.
We just want to pass in one an object called user who has all of these as properties.
To get that done what we can't do is something like the following user equals an object where we define
the properties.
This is not the syntax for creating an object argument.
Instead what we do is define an input type and then we are referencing the arguments list.
So I'm going to do undo all those changes.
Bringing us back to what we had in the beginning and then down below.
What we're going to do is define an input type which lists out all of the arguments for this mutation.
So right here what does that look like.
Well we start with the key word input followed by a generic name that we choose for these inputs.
I'm going to go ahead and call Vess create user input.
It's typical to follow a convention similar to this.
We have the action then we have the actual object we're acting on.
And then finally we have input just making it easy to know that this is of the input type.
Now what do we do from here.
Well we go ahead and set up the curly braces and inside of these curly braces we define all of the properties
that could exist on this input.
So on the arguments that we're setting up goes inside of here is going to match up one to one with the
arguments we actually need.
So I can start off with the name whose value is a non indelible string that will also add an email a
non nullable string.
And finally we have age and double it.
So right here.
Ange ant now all we can actually use to create user input inside of the arguments list up above.
So right here I can remove all of the three individual arguments and then I can create a single argument
whose type is going to be create user input.
Now you can call this whatever you like.
You could call it something like user but in general I always call mine data.
So what is the core data for this mutation.
And then the type for this one is going to be the input type we created below.
So right here create user input.
Now it's important to note that if you want to reference a typewrite year it has to be an input type.
It could not be one of our custom object types like user post or comment those cannot be referenced
in an argument list.
Why is that.
It is because your input types can only have scalar values so I could not have a custom object type
inside of here.
Everything listed inside of the input type needs to be a scalar.
That's exactly what we have here.
Using just string and INT.
Now down below we can make a small change to the create user mutation.
So we have our resolver function under resolvers we have mutation we have create user and we reference
the args argument right here we use our X-Com email for example but we now have args dot data dot email
and down below we have args dot data.
So right here this is what we're going to stick with going forward using the data object on ARX.
Now it might seem like we're not getting a ton of value here.
The value is going to be more and more obvious as we start to create other mutations.
For example when we update a user we have two distinct sets of data one being the idea of the user we
want to update and the other being an object with all of the properties we actually want to change using
the input type we can create our inputs in a way that's just a bit more organized.
So once again this is not a magic silver bullet allowing you to do anything you couldn't already do
with craft.
Well it is just a better way to organize our applications listing out all of the arguments for a given
operation separately from the operation definition itself.
Now that we have this in place with one of our three mutations we're going to go ahead and go through
the same process for the other two before we do let's go ahead and test our work and make sure that
our current changes haven't broken anything.
I'm going to save index dot J s over inside of the create user mutation.
Well we're going to do is remove our individual arguments and we're going to replace them with a single
argument right here matching up with the one we chose.
I chose data you might have picked something else.
Now data is indeed an object.
So we're going to set it up as such.
And now we have to set this object up to conform to the input type we created.
So I need a name and I need e-mail and optional.
I could include H so for name I'll pick something like Jess.
Then for email I'll pick something like Jess at example dot com.
And then I can also choose to put the age in there.
Let's go ahead and say that Jess is 39.
So now we have a completely valid mutation.
I can always go ahead and refresh the schema to get the latest changes.
If I then go ahead and actually run this operation it should still create a brand new user right here
no errors.
A new user was created and we can always test that the new user was created successfully by fetching
them using one of our queries.
I have the users query over here.
I could go ahead and refresh the schema run the operation and down below I should see Jess and there
she is.
I have Jess showing up as my fourth and final user.
So now that we have a better way to structure and organize our arguments for create user let's do the
same thing for the other two mutations starting with Create post.
This is actually going to be your challenge for the video so I will paste in the challenge comments
up top right here.
The big picture goal is to create input types for create post and create comment.
So step one is to create the input type for create post with the same fields and for the name like we
did you could use data or you could use something more specific to that particular mutation like post
then you're going to update and create posts resolver to use the new object you've created.
Step three is to verify the application still works by creating a post and then fetching it using one
of our queries.
Moving on to Step 4 we start changing create comet Sorba.
Here you are going to create an input type for create comment with the same fields using data or comment
as the argument name.
Then you're going to update the Create comment resolver to use the new object.
And finally you will verify that the application still works by creating a comment and then fetching
it.
So take some time to knock out all six of these steps and feel free to refer to anything we've covered
in this video.
Any other video or anything you find on the web.
All right.
Pause the video.
Knock this out.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play.
How'd you do.
We're going to go ahead and move through this process together starting by changing create post.
So down below we need to change our type definitions.
We're going to set up a new input type for create post input.
I'll call this something like create post input and then we're going to set up all of the actual properties
we want on that object.
So once again there are four right here.
We have title being a non-global string.
We have body being a non nullable string.
I have published being a non nullable boolean.
And finally we have author of being a non nullable idea.
So in this case all four are required now that we have the input type created we can change the Create
post mutation definition.
I'm going to remove the individual arguments.
I'll create just one something like data or post then I will reference that input to type.
So right here create post input.
Now both of these should have been non nullable like this.
Sorry for the confusion there.
If you didn't add that in that's fine too but we're going to go ahead and make that change.
Meaning that the argument is always required when the mutation is executed.
So what do we have.
We have create user don't we have create Post done for the most part.
Besides changing the resolver Let's go ahead and knock that out.
Down below create post we reference ARGs in a couple of different places here and here.
All we're going to do is change that to args dot data dot author.
And then below we're going to spread out args dot data.
Excellent.
That should be it for create post.
I'm going to save index dot J S and we can actually test this out.
So over here we have the Create post mutation but I'm going to do is go ahead and refresh that schema
then we're going to set up create post with the data argument.
So data.
And then we need all four things that data expects We have our title.
I can use something like my new post again.
We're going to have the body which I'll leave empty.
We're going to have a publish which I'll set to false.
And finally we need one of the author ideas.
I'm going to go ahead and use three which I believe belongs to Michael.
Now if we go ahead and actually run this operation what happens.
A new post gets created.
We have our new ID we have our post data and we can see the author's name is Mike.
Finally if I actually go ahead and try to fetch all of the posts I should see the new one added and
down below.
It has indeed been added.
So there we go.
That is steps 1 through three.
All done.
We're now going to move on two steps four through six.
Doing the same thing for create comment.
So down here we have our mutation for create comment I'm going to create an input type input.
We're going to call this one create comment input and we will set up all of the fields necessary we
have the text being a non nullable string.
Then we have author and being a non nullable ID.
And finally we have post whose value is also a non nullable idea.
We can now reference that up above right here.
Data referencing our new input type create Calment input.
Excellent.
That brings us to step fiber we can actually change the resolver.
So down below we have our last mutation for create comment we are referencing ARGs in a few different
places all of which now need to change.
We have args dot data dot author.
Then down below that we have args dot data dot post.
And finally we spread out args dot data.
Excellent.
The last thing to do is to move on to Step 6 and actually verify that we can still create and fetch
comments.
I'm going to save index Dhananjay as over inside of graph.
Well playground we can switch over to the Create comment tab and refresh the schema and then we're going
to set up the one argument for create comment and I'll use the same author and post value.
I mean try to remember those three and 12.
So right here we have data inside of data we need text we need author and we need the actual post ID
via post and we're going to use 12:4 the post ID.
We're going to use three for the author ID and I will stick with a comment like this was a great read
and now we can go ahead and actually create that comment.
I'm going to run the operation right here we get our comment and successfully created.
And if I actually fetch it using the comments query it should be showing up as the last one down below
at the bottom of our list.
What do we have.
We have our comment created by Mike on the programming music post.
So there we go.
We have now converted all of our three mutations to use a custom input type for our arguments.
Now as we've seen we haven't changed the functionality of our application at all but we now have a simpler
mutation definition and we now have these input types which can be reused across other operations creating
just a better structured application.
That's where we're going to stop for this one in the next couple of videos.
We're going to focus on mutations that delete data.
So we're going to figure out how we can create mutations that delete users delete posts and delete comments.
I'm real excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in that to the next video.