In this video we're going to continue to explore mutations and we're going to turn our attention towards
creating mutations that delete data in this video in particular we'll be creating a delete user mutation
which deletes a user in the next video will be creating the delete posts and delete comment.
Mutation and of course there will be a challenge requiring you to use what you've learned here.
Let's go ahead and kick things off though by figuring out what it would take to delete a user when deleting
data.
It's important to be mindful of not just the actual thing you're trying to delete but also associated
So let's say we're trying to delete this first user with the idea of one.
Yes we can remove this object from the array but we should also be removing all posts created by that
user and all comments created by that user.
Otherwise we're going to have some invalid data.
We would have something like this post which tries to reference this author but that author would no
longer exist.
Assuming we actually deleted this object here so well it is a pretty straightforward process.
We do have to be considerate of the other data in our application.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by creating the new mutation down below just below.
Create user.
I'm going to create the mutation and delete user.
We're going to set up the arguments for this and we're also going to set up our return type.
What I'm going to do is just return the user that was deleted and the only thing we need to delete a
user is the user's ID.
So right here we only need a single argument ID of the type ID and will make that a non nullable argument.
You have to provide it in order for us to do anything.
So now that we have the delete user mutation defined we can actually create the resolver down below.
Right here we have create user just below it.
I'm going to add delete user.
We're going to set up all four arguments.
This method is still going to get called with all four.
We have parent args context and info and now what we're going to do is use args dot ID to successfully
clear everything out and then we're going to return the user that was actually deleted the first thing
we want to do is try to find the user that's supposed to be deleted.
If there is no user to actually delete We want to throw an error because we're not going to have a user
to return from this operation.
So right here I am going to start by getting the index of the user using the find index array method.
So we have Konst.
I'll call this one something like user index and find index method is identical to find although find
returns the actual element in the array find index returns the index of that element in the array.
So right here I am going to call users dot find index to find the index and in this case we are going
to pass in our callback function and we're going to return true when we actually find the match.
So we get this call for each individual user and I am going to return true if the user's ID equals the
args ID.
If those are equal We're going to return TRUE saying we've found the match and the index will be stored
here.
If there is no match user index ends up being negative 1.
So it's actually very similar to the index of method we can use on something like a string.
Now I'm going to go ahead and take this cut it out and I am going to use the shorthand syntax for the
arrow function.
And now what we're going to do is check if we actually found a users.
So if our condition.
And in this case we want this code to run if no user was found.
So we're going to check if user index equals minus one.
Perfect.
If you want to learn a bit more about find index you can always google and DN find index to find the
Mozilla developer network documentation page.
And if we pull that up we can learn all about how it works.
In this case you can see they're using find index to get the index of a specific number inside of this
array.
They're actually looking for the first one that's greater than 13.
Is this greater than 13.
No.
Is this.
Nope.
Yes.
What's the index for that.
Well the index is three.
Remember indexes are zero based.
So 0 1 2 3 and that is exactly what comes back from find index.
So in our case we are going to match one of those users if the args don't ID property will be one that
it would match that first user right here.
And the index would be zero if we passed in three as that value the idea of three it would match this
third user with the index of two.
So we want to keep that in mind as we continue working through this mutation.
So if the user index is indeed minus one we never found a match and we can go ahead and throw an error.
So throw new error and we're going to say something like a user not found.
Awesome.
Now the code down below is only going to run if we actually found a user to delete.
So what are we going to do.
We're going to start by deleting that user then we're going to delete all of their posts and all of
their comments to remove the user from the array.
We could use something like the filter array method.
But I'm going to be using the splice array method since we already have the users index right here.
If you've never used splice before you can find it over at and D-n splice.
So we're just googling those two words and right here we have the splice method documentation.
You call it on the array and you pass two two arguments.
The first is the index where you want to start removing items and the second is the number of items
you'd like to remove so we can go ahead and use that to remove one item starting at this index where
we actually found the user.
So right here I'm going to call users dot splice and I am going to call it with two arguments.
The first is going to be the value we got in user index.
So maybe it 0.
Maybe it's 1 or maybe it's 2 depending on which user we chose to delete out of the three above.
And the second argument value is the number of items you want to remove.
I'm going to just use a single one.
So we don't want to remove one item.
Now the cool thing about splice is that all of the removed items actually come back in an array as the
return value.
So Konst something like deleted users would be appropriate.
Now in this case we're just deleting one user but the return value is still an array.
So in this case it is just an array of one object and the only reason I'm even naming this as an argument
is so I can return it as the return value for delete user sends member in our typedef.
I do expect to get a user back.
So before we actually return that user there are two other things we have to do.
We have to remove all associated posts and we have to remove all associated comments.
Now we can actually see what would happen if we did not do this.
So right here.
Let's return that first and only deleted user.
So we're going to access deleted user
deleted users and we're gonna grab the first item with the index of 0.
I'm going to save index dot J S and we're going to test this mutation out over in playground.
I'm going to create a nother tab right here.
We're going to set up the mutation for delete user and I am going to pass in the ID value equal to one
to Dr. delete that first user.
Andrew and right here we will ask for some data back as well.
I'm going to go ahead and ask for just the ID of the user that was deleted if I refresh the schema this
should become a valid operation if I fire it off we can see that the actual operation completed.
We have delete user and we have our ID right there.
Now if I were to run users I should see that the item has been removed.
Right here I just have Sarah and Mike Andrew is gone.
The problem though is that if I tried to query for posts we're going to get an error the message cannot
return NULL for non nullable field Post author.
What this is saying is that it tried it to find the author for that post but it couldn't.
And this is a problem because any type definitions.
We said that author was a non nullable field.
So to fix this we can either make it a nullable field which we don't want to do or we can actually clean
up the posts and comments which is what we are going to do.
So right here let's go ahead and knock that process out.
I'm going to delete all of the posts in all of the comments for this user.
Now if you remember when we first created those three arrays we use the Konst variable definition.
I am going to be reassigning these values.
So let's go ahead and switch them over to let.
I'm going to switch comments posts and up above.
I will switch users over as well.
Now we can actually reassign these array values.
Something we're going to need to do throughout this section down below.
We can head back to the delete user mutation and we can go ahead and knock this out by adding two more
lines here.
We are going to use the array filter method to filter out all of the comments and posts that belonged
to this user.
Right here let's start with posts.
So I'm going to be assigning a new value to posts which I can do because I just switched it from being
a contest to being left and right here we are going to still use an array as the value the array is
going to come back from post.com filter though we're only going to keep the posts that did not belong
to this user.
Now right here we are going to set up a tried and true full arrow function we're not going to use the
shorthand syntax because there is a bit more we need to actually accomplish.
We don't just want to delete posts if we delete a post.
We also have to delete any comments for that post.
So once again what we're working with is relational data.
It's a good thing because it allows us to perform some flexible queries but as we can see on the backend
things are getting a bit complex.
If you're noticing that it's a good thing we're going to address this a little bit later in the class.
So right here what are we going to do.
Well we're going to get access to the individual post and step one is to determine if this post is a
match.
Was this post created by the user that we just deleted.
We can actually perform that check storing the value in a variable like match.
Right here counts to match equals.
We're going to look at the post's author value and check if it equals args ID.
If it does equal match will be true.
Now in the end of the day we are still going to return a boolean filter.
Right here I am going to return not match but the opposite of match.
So we want to return true when we did not find a match.
Keeping that post we want to return false when we did find a match making sure that post gets filtered
out and the last thing we have to do and an important step in the process is to add an if statement.
Right here is this post a match.
Is this post about to get deleted.
If it is we have to delete all of its comments.
So right here comments equals we are going to remove some comments.
Let's go ahead and knock this out.
Using comments dot filter we are going to set up our callback function where we get access to the individual
comment.
We're going to return true if it's a comment we want to keep and we're going to return false otherwise
I'm going to return it true when the comment is done.
Post field is not equal to the post ID.
So if we are looking at a comment and that comment doesn't belong to the post that we just deleted it
can stay.
If it does belong to that post it's got to get deleted.
Now I'm going to use the shorthand syntax here as well.
Removing the curly braces and everything inside and putting the value I want to return right here and
that brings us to the last line we need.
And the last line involves us actually removing all comments that the user created.
Whether it's on it's own posts in which case they've already been cleaned up or whether it's on other
posts by other users which aren't getting deleted.
So comments equals common stock filter.
We are going to get the individual comment and we are going to return it.
True keeping the item when the comment author was not equal to the author we just removed.
So right here using the inequality operator and I'm going to use that with args dot ID.
Awesome.
Now we have everything in place handling all of those edge cases.
Yes this is a bit complex but yes we will also look at a better way to handle this relational data a
bit later in the class so we can avoid all of this manual cleaning up of data.
We'll come up with a way to automatically do all of this allowing us to vastly simplify the code necessary
for the moment though this is a great way to explore how all of this related data works inside of graft.
Well now what we're going to do is actually delete one of the users and make sure everything gets cleaned
up successfully.
So up above we're going to have this as our starting data and I'm going to delete this first user with
the idea of one.
So in the end of the day this user should get deleted but the posts it created should also get removed
which would be the first two posts since the author value is one for each down below.
I would also expect the comments for the posts they created and B comments they created on other posts
to be deleted.
So if you notice all of these comments are on either post 10 or post 11 so they're all going to get
deleted because they all belong to posts that are going to get deleted.
Now I'm going to change this up just a little bit.
I'm going to take this last comment written by our author and I'm going to change it to a post that's
not going to get removed.
This one written by Sarah with the idea of 12 now on the end of the day this comment should still get
removed but very different reason.
It should get removed because it's a comment by that user not because it's a comment on a post that
the user wrote.
So that's just going to allow us to test both of those situations.
These three comments should get deleted because they belong to posts that are getting deleted.
This last comment should get deleted because it was created by the user who got deleted.
A slight difference between the two but also important for testing that our code works as expected.
Now what am I going to do while I'm going to go ahead and save the file head over to graft UL playground
and actually test this out.
Step one over here.
Delete user.
I'm going to delete the user with an ID of one and it does appear to have worked.
Now we're going to run our three queries user's posts and comments and make sure everything seems right.
If I run users what do I get I get.
Just my two users back Sarah and Mike.
Andrew has indeed been removed.
If I run posts what do I get back I get back.
Just programming music.
The other two posts graphed you well 101 and graphed Well 201 have indeed been deleted as expected.
If I run the comments operation you can see that I actually get no comments back because all of the
comments either belonged to posts that got deleted or it belong to the user who got removed.
So there we go.
We now have a way to delete data.
It might not be as straightforward as you were hoping for but it is indeed a great start.
I will we will address the complexity of this a bit later in the class.
For now though it is really important to see that when we're working with data engraft Well we can't
just focus on the individual thing.
In this case the individual user.
We have to also focus on that graph of data what data belongs to this user.
Is it OK to leave that around or should that get deleted too.
And we saw that in this case.
Posts and comments need to get cleaned up.
Just like users needs to get cleaned up in order to remove a user in the next video we're going to do
the same thing for deleting a post and for deleting comments though the process for both of those will
be a bit easier.
And then from there we're going to continue on looking at how we can update data.
I'm excited to continue on with the rest of the course.
So let's go ahead and jump right into the next one and continue exploring.
Mutations.