Now that we have the mutation for deleting a user in place it's going to be your challenge.
In this video to create the mutation for deleting a post now when deleting a post there is still the
concern of relational data that needs to be cleaned up but it's not nearly as complex as with deleting
a user.
We just need to clean up the comments for the post that's getting removed.
Up above let's go ahead and talk about what exactly I'd like you to do.
I have the challenge comments for this one right here and remember in the end of the day the big picture
goal is to set up a mutation that deletes a post.
Step one is to define the mutation.
Now this mutation needs to take in the post ID the idea of the post we're trying to delete and it should
also return the deleted post much like delete user return the deleted user.
Step two is to define the resolver for the nutation This is where most of your time is going to be spent.
There are a few things to keep in mind related to this resolver method.
First up you want to check that the post that they're trying to delete actually exists.
If it does not exist you want to throw an error saying something like post not bound.
You also want to remove that post and actually return the post object as the return value for the resolver
to actually fulfill the value we've set up.
That should come back from the operation.
The last thing to do inside of this mutation resolver is to actually remove all of the comments belonging
to the post.
If we are going to remove a given post like this one we do not need to delete the user.
That doesn't make sense but we do need to delete all of the comments associated with that post regardless
of who created them whether it was the Post author or someone else.
All those comments need to go where the post property value is in this case 11.
Now that brings us to the final step which is to test your work.
Run a brand new mutation.
Mutation and not queery to delete a post.
Then verify that the actual post and all of its comments have been removed.
Once again take as much time as you need to knock this one out.
When you're done test your work.
Pause the video come back in click play when you're ready to look at the solution.
How did you do.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with step 1 which is to just define that mutation.
You want to take in the post ID and we want to get that deleted post back.
So down below we have our type.
Daffs we are going to set that up anywhere works.
I'm just going to keep things organized putting delete post right after Create post.
Now we want to take in just that one argument the ID of the post to remove.
Which will be non-IT nullable you have to provide it and will also set up the non nullable return value.
You are going to get a post back.
Perfect.
So that is it for step 1.
We're now going to move on to Step 2.
Actually creating that resolver function.
So down below we have all of our mutations create user delete user than we have create post right after
Create post.
I am going to set up delete post.
We're going to have all of those arguments.
We got parent.
We have args we have a context we have info and inside of this method we have to go through those steps
and the first thing we're going to do is try to verify that the post exists and I'm going to do this
exactly the same way I did it up above.
We're going to start by fetching its index using find index will throw an error if we don't find one.
Otherwise we'll actually move through the deletion process.
So let's kick things off right here.
Konst post index is going to get the job done and once again I will be using the find index method.
This time though on the Post's array.
So post-START find index and we are going to pass in that callback function.
We get the individual post and we find a match when we return it.
True we're going to return true if the posts ID so post dot ID matches up with args ID the ID of the
post they want to delete.
Now we can actually set up our if statement to throw an error if no post was found.
If and we'll be checking if Post index equals minus one.
If it does equal minus one then we know we have not found a post and we want to throw an error throw.
New error with a message.
Something along the lines of.
Post not found would be clear enough.
Now we can move on to the next steps we have to complete inside of delete post.
We have to actually delete the post but we also have to delete all of the comments associated with that
post.
Let's start by deleting the post itself using Once again the splice array method.
So right here I'm going to create a variable called deleted posts much like we did above for deleted
comments right here excuse me deleted users then we're going to set this equal to and we're going to
call posts dot splice.
So I want to remove some items from that Post's array.
I already have the index.
I want to start at in the post index variable.
So I'll just reference that.
The second argument and the number of items I want to remove.
I just want to remove one now and the end of the day we are going to return the first and only item
in this array.
So right here return deleted posts grabbing the first item by its index 0.
But we're not quite done yet because we still have to delete old comments belonging to that post that
we just removed.
So right here we're going to set comments equal to a brand new value the value that will come back from
comments dot filter and we're going to pass in our filter callback function.
We get access to the individual comment.
It's our job to return true if we want to keep it and false otherwise we're going to return true.
When the comments don't post property is not equal to the actual post.
We just deleted args.
ID is where we can get that ID.
So this is going to return true for comments not belonging to this post meaning they'll be kept in the
array which is good.
It's going to return false for comments belonging to the deleted post which is great.
Those ones are going to get removed now that we have all of this in place.
We can actually save this file and test our work.
We can move on to Step 3 and verify that all the code we wrote is actually working.
Up above let's go ahead and pick which post we want to remove.
I'm going to remove this post right here with the idea of 11.
That should remove this post from the array.
It shouldn't touch the users or Ray at all but it should indeed touch the comments array.
Removing any comments made on this post.
We just have one right here.
This did not work.
That should be not.
Not no but I'll just leave it there.
This one should indeed get removed since it belongs to the post that I'm going to end up deleting.
All right let's go ahead and jump into graphical playground and get this done.
I'm going to create a new tab.
We're going to set up our mutation.
We'll be using the new delete post operation passing in the ID.
I am willing to delete the post with the ID of 11.
This guy right here.
Now we can actually go ahead and set up those curly braces and the selection set for this one will just
be the ID.
I'll describe the idea of the post that was removed.
If I go ahead and run this operation what do I get.
I get a successful operation.
If I were to run it a second time.
You'll notice the second time it fails since there is no longer a post without ID which is also great.
We can verify that things were deleted correctly including the comments by running our posts and comments
queries.
I'm going to start with posts if I run this.
What do I get.
I get graphed UL 101 and programming music as the only posts that exist.
That's great.
The post with the idea of 11 was deleted.
If I go ahead and run the comments query what do I get back I get back.
Three comments.
The one that saying that the actual solution didn't work for them has been deleted because that was
associated with the post that is now removed.
So there we go.
Everything is done for the delete post mutation.
That brings us to what I'd like to do to wrap up this video which is one more challenge requiring you
to set up a much easier delete comment mutation.
Right here the big picture goal is to set up a mutation for deleting a comment with this one.
There is no need to worry about related data.
You can just delete the comment don't have to touch that user who created the comment and you don't
have to touch the post that the comment belongs to either.
So step 1 define the mutation.
Take any comment Id return the deleted comment step to define the resolver for that nutation check if
the comment exists.
Otherwise there are an error and then remove and return the comment and step 3.
Test your work by running the mutation to delete the comment and verifying that the comment was removed
by using something like.
Our comments query.
This is exactly what you did last time though.
Slightly easier since there is no concern of relational data.
Take some time to knock this one out when you're done come back and click play
How'd that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with step 1.
We're going to define that mutation.
I'm going to put it right below create comment or call delete comment and we're going to set it up to
take just that one argument.
The idea of the item we're trying to delete right here the return value will be removed.
Comment perfect.
That brings us to step 2.
Setting up the resolver method for delete comment that's going to go down here below.
Create comment I'll call delete comment matching up with the operation name we just created and we'll
set up those four arguments.
We got parent args context info and then from here we can actually worry about our functionality.
So step 1 does that comment exist.
We got to figure that out first.
Once again I will be using find index so Konst.
I'm going to call this one.
Comment index equals.
I'll be calling comments dot.
Find index to try to get the index and we will pass in our callback function.
We could access to the individual comment and we're going to consider it a match.
If the comments ID matches up with the argument ID on args I'd be perfect.
Now we can actually perform the check seeing if there was no comment.
So if comment index is indeed equal to minus one.
Then we have a problem.
There is no comment to remove.
So what are we going to do.
We're just going to throw an error throw new error alerting the user along the lines of a comment not
found perfect.
Now all we need to do is return the comment that we actually delete.
So while you splice once again Konst the deleted comments equals I'm going to call comments dot splice.
I'm going to remove starting the following index.
Whatever is stored in comment index and I am going to remove just a single item.
Then we can go ahead and return right here.
The first item in deleted comments deleted comments is only ever going to have a single item inside
of it.
So right here deleted comments.
Accessing it by index.
Perfect.
Now with this in place.
All that's left to do is verify that our code is working as expected.
We can go ahead and knock that out by picking one of the comments to remove.
It doesn't really matter for this example since there's no relational data.
We have to worry about.
I'm going to go ahead and just remove this first comment right here with the ID of 1 0 2.
Let's go ahead and get that done over inside of graph.
You playground will be creating a brand new mutation right here.
A mutation.
I'm going to call this one delete comment.
We're going to pass in that ID.
I already forget the idea I said I'd use 1 0 2 and we'll just ask for the ID of the deleted comment
back.
Now if I go ahead and actually refresh the schema there should be a valid operation and if I run it
any comment should get deleted.
And right here it is indeed removed.
We can verify that we're not just seeing a false positive by running that comments query.
I'm going to run it and do we see 102.
No we do not.
That comment has indeed successfully been removed.
And there we go.
We now have Duleep mutations for all of our data.
We can delete users we can delete posts and we can delete comments and we also have taken into account
the fact that we have a lot of related data here.
So those considerations are taken care of as well.
That brings us to the end of our little two part series on deleting data with mutations.
Now at this point we have one really really really really long file.
And for the moment it hasn't been much of a burden.
But as we continue to add code it's just going to get annoying.
So in the next video we're going to start to explore how we can better structure our projects will be
breaking up this application from one big file to many smaller files with folders and directory structures
to keep us organized.
I'm really excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.