In this video we're going to talk about how we can better structure our graphics applications.
Now we're not just going to talk about it we're actually going to do it.
So we're going to take index dot J S from being what about 300 lines of code to being about 10 or 20
lines of code.
Now at the end of the day what we do in this video will not change the functionality of the application
in any meaningful way.
The goal of this one is to give us a better directory structure so it's easier to continue to expand
on our app as files get really really long and it's really really hard to find things.
We want a better file and folder structure making it easy to stay organized even as our app gets big
to kick off our project refactoring.
What I'd like to do is take our type definitions and break them out into their very own graph to l file
allowing us to manage them on their own with things like syntax highlighting opposed to just having
them in a string like we currently do.
So what are we going to do to get that done.
Well step one is to create a new file to put all of this stuff.
We're going to make a brand new one right in the source directory and it's common to call this file
schema dot graft.
Well then once again you're free to call it whatever you'd like.
Now what goes inside of here well what goes inside of here is Graff.
Q Well code if you installed one of the many vs C graph you all plug ins like I mentioned earlier in
the class you are going to get things like syntax highlighting in this file.
Let's go ahead and actually see that by taking R-Type type definitions and copying them over.
So we're going to take everything inside of the template string all the way down from the closing curly
brace for the comment type all the way up to our definition of the query type.
I'm going to cut that out.
Go over to the new file and paste it in.
All I have to do is unindexed things one time and there we go.
We now have a graph.
Q Well file that contains our application schema exactly like we had it before but now lives in its
own separate place.
Much easier to find manage and work with.
Now at this point we can't just save our files and have our apps still work.
Because over here we have an empty type definitions straight.
So how are we going to fix that.
Well it's a fix that we're actually going to remove the type deps variable altogether.
And down below we're going to change how we can figure our graph Well yoga server at the very bottom
of the file.
Currently we're using the type deps variable that no longer exists.
So we can no longer use our shorthand.
What we're gonna do instead is set type deaths equal to a string and the string value here is the path
relative to the root of your application.
So for our purposes that would be daat forward slash.
Now the route would be the graph BASIX folder.
So we would go to the source directory forward slash and then we have to find digraph file that contains
our schema that is schema dot graph.
Q L excellent.
So now what we have is a separate schema file though our application is still going to work as expected.
If I go ahead and expand the terminal we can see that things did restart and we're not getting any error.
The application is still functioning.
And if I actually went ahead and ran one of our queries we can see it's still working over there as
well.
Now by breaking this out into its own file we've actually also broken node one currently gnomon is not
going to automatically restart our application when we make changes to this separate graph file because
it does not watch files with the graphical extension by default.
So if I change age from being in int to being a float and I save the file we can see that Nordman didn't
do anything.
It has not restarted.
So that's obviously a problem for us.
I do want our application to restart when I change the schema file.
We can actually fix this by using one of the arguments that node supports.
Let's head over to the browser real quick and go over to the gnomon Web site.
Let's get have dot com forward slash Remmy forward slash gnomon.
This is where we were earlier in the class and if we scroll down on the home page there are a few different
ways we can actually configure this tool.
And one of the ways we can configure it is by specifying the extensions we want to support.
So right here specifying extenstion watchlist now by default gnomon is going to watch the following
files with these extensions.
But we can also specify our own using the either or the x t argument.
So over here all we need to do is change package.
Jason a little bit.
I'm going to add on the extension argument and we're gonna provide the file extensions we want gnomon
to watch the first of course being the javascript file extension and the second being the graph.
Q Well extension.
Now if we save package dot Jason we are indeed going to need to restart things but once we restart things
no demand is going to pay attention to changes in our graph file.
I'm going to go ahead and make that same change.
I'm going to switch this back to a float save the file and this time around we can see gnomon did indeed
restart which is awesome.
And if I were to change it back to it.
And it's going to restart again.
So now we have a separate schema file and we also have it working with gnomon.
So we have our first refactoring step down and there's still a lot of stuff in index Dhananjay S..
So let's continue to work through some of this.
And the next thing I'd like to do is take our temporary data and break that out into its own file as
well.
To start I'm going to remove this comment right here about demo user data and I'm also going to remove
these Scheller types comment which has been around for a bit too long.
And the goal is to take these three arrays users posts and comments and find a better place for them.
Now what we're going to do here where we're going to put these is not just going to work for static
data like this.
It's also going to be exactly what we end up using when we wire up graphs ul to work with a real world
production ready database.
Step one is going to be to create a new file in the source directory and this will be the last file
that we actually put right in the source folder will be creating subdirectories for everything else.
We're going to call this one db dot J.
And this file is going to be around even when we no longer just work with static data.
It's going to be an important piece to the puzzle in the future as well.
For the moment though what we're going to do is take our three arrays so users posts and then down below
comments we are going to cut them out of this file and we're going to paste them over in Dot J S and
then we're going to create one object that holds all three.
We'll export it and we'll be able to use that elsewhere in the application.
So Konst DBI for example is going to equal an object and right here this object is going to have users
on it.
So we're setting the users property equal to the users variable.
Value will do the same thing for posts.
And finally for comments as well that means we can actually switch all three of these back to being
Constans since they're no longer going to get reassigned in the same way they were before.
So right here users posts and comments can all be constants once again.
And the last thing we're going to do in this file is just export D-B as either unnamed export or the
default line.
And I'll just go with the default one.
So export D-B as default.
Perfect.
So that is actually it for DB J s.
But this brings up another problem.
How exactly do we take advantage of what we just did.
Now it might seem easy it might seem like we can just import the DB variable into this file and then
access db users instead of just users and you would be correct.
The problem though is that all of this stuff on resolvers isn't going to live here either.
Not all of these methods are going to live in the same file.
We're going to break our queries out into their own file.
Mutations are going to have their own folder with various files.
Our other custom resolvers for our object types are going to live in their own files so we're not going
to have just one place for all of this lives and to solve this.
What I want to talk about is this third argument that gets passed to all of our resolver methods.
This is the context the context is something that we can set so we can set up some context for our API
and the context which is just an object with a set of properties will get passed to every single resolver
method.
So what we can do is set up that DBI object over here to be part of our context and that DBI object
will get passed to every single resolver method regardless of where it's actually defined.
That's exactly what we're going to end up doing and to start this process off all we really need to
do is add one new property onto our GRATHWOHL yoga configuration down below.
So down here we're going to add something additional into the mix and this one appropriately is called
context.
No context is going to be an object and on there we're going to define the things we want to set up
on context so we can choose to pass in whatever values we happen to need.
Well later on we're going to pass in our database connection.
We're also going to use this for authentication passing and things like the authentication token the
user used.
Context is a very useful and important feature of graft.
Well and the graphical yoga server and well we're going to do here is inport the database and then we're
going to set it up on the context object.
So up above let's go ahead and start with the inport.
Now typically I like to add my third party inputs first and then my custom imports.
Second so right here I am going to import D-B which we set up as the default export from the following
file.
Now if you remember from earlier in the course when we are trying to load in a file in our application
we go ahead and start with daat forward slash to specify the relative path.
And right here the file is in the same folder.
So we can just use DBI.
No need to add the Java extension.
You could indeed do that.
Both would be fine.
So we have the db object and down below all we're going to do is set up a DB property giving it the
value of DB and we can just use the shorthand syntax for that.
So now in effect we are passing that database object to every single one of the resolvers for our application
regardless of where these resolvers actually live.
This is going to give us a ton of flexibility allowing us to move these around to different files and
folders.
Which is exactly what we're going to end up doing.
We want to be able to structure our application in a way that doesn't constrain us as our application
grows.
And context is a big part of that.
All of our resolver methods now have an object stored on context and that object has a single property
D.B and the db object has three properties users posts and comments.
Which means that we can now take advantage of all of those inside of our resolvers.
So right here we return users instead of just users.
It would be context dot D-B dot users just like this.
And we could even structure this argument to grab DB directly.
A very popular thing to do.
So instead of grabbing the context argument we can go ahead and destructuring adding curly braces right
here and we can say we just want the DB property off of that third argument.
Now we can shorten this accessing just D-B dot users.
So this is a very popular approach when working with context.
It's something we'll be doing throughout the applications or we have DB users down below.
We are going to have DB users again anywhere in our resolvers where we're accessing users posts or comments
we want to switch this up and this process is going to take a few minutes and that's going to be a slightly
boring few minutes but that's OK because it is going to set us up for success in the future.
So just bear with me as we work through this refactoring right here.
Once again I am going to deep structure grabbing just the DB property off of that context object.
We have posts we want D-B posts down here we have posts that filter I want D-B dot posts dot filter
and inside of our filter callback below we have no users of either 3.
So we can continue on.
I'm going to deep structure D-B right here and use DBI data comments as the return value Myan post can
stay as they are.
Those are currently still just static data will actually work on those as we start to set up things
like authentication a bit later in the class.
That brings us to our mutations where we definitely use this data.
So right here for create user I'm going to destructor the database we use D-B dot users dot some right
here.
Next up we have users don't push.
So D-B dot users dot push and that is it for create user damage so that we have delete user We also
need to do the same process.
So this is where things start to get a little boring.
D.B dot and I'm actually just going to copy D-B dot to the clipboard so we can go ahead and just paste
that in where needed.
Right here we splice the users I'm going to paste D-B dot beforehand right here we filter the posts
down below we filter our comments and we set a new value for comments.
So we have to do the same thing for posts right here.
So we set DB up posts equal to whatever comes back from DB posts dot filter and we'll do the same thing
for comments adding it before comments in both locations.
Perfect.
Next up Dambulla we have the same thing for comments once again.
And that wraps up the changes necessary for delete user.
After that we have create post so right here I will deep structure the database property.
We have users data some will add DB in front of that.
Then down below we have posts that push.
I will add DBI in front of that as well.
That brings us to the delete push resolver method.
I'm going to go ahead and D structure the database put DBI data in front of posts there Double-O we
slice our posts.
We need divi dot in front of that.
And the same thing for comments twice once here and once here that brings us to create comment.
We're getting close to the end.
We need to access that DBI argument.
And what are we going to do with the D-B argument.
Well I'm going to access it in a couple of places.
We have two instances right here where we check if the users and the posts exist then Double-O.
We have one more instance where we add something on it to the comments array that brings us to delete
comment.
Our last nutation right here we need that DB argument.
We're going to use it for comments right here and we're also going to use it down below where we use
comments dot splice.
That brings us to our custom object resolvers we have post right here I am going to do structure d.b.
We have users dat find that's going to be D-B dot users dot find for comments we have comments filter.
I'm going to restructure D.B and change that do DB comments.
Builder and we have the same thing for our other four methods right here destructuring the D-B adding
it up front.
Same thing for the comment post method.
Then we have the same thing for user posts.
And finally we have the same thing for user comments.
So thanks for bearing with me.
I know that wasn't the most fun three minutes of that course but what we have now is actually really
special.
We have a setup where our resolver methods don't rely on that global D-B variable it gets passed in
via the context.
So it's now going to be very easy to break these methods out into their own files.
We're going to talk about exactly how we can do that in the next video.
So let's take a quick moment to recap just how far we've gotten.
We started off this video by breaking our type definitions out into their very own file in the source
folders schema digraph QOL.
We were able to load those in by providing the path as the value for type depths when setting up our
server.
So we can either provide our type definitions in line like we were previously doing or we can break
them out into their own file which is the preferred approach for a real world production grade graph.
Q Well API the next thing we did is we set up context for the application context is going to have values
that are pretty universal things that should be shared across your app and in the case of a real graphical
API one of those is the database connection.
All of our method should be able to use the database connection to do things like read write update
and create data.
So what are we going to do for that.
Well we're going to pass the db in currently just a static set of arrays and that gives us access to
it in all of our resolver methods like the user comments method right here where we can access it in
that third argument.
So all of this has set us up for the next video where we're going to continue to refactor.
We're going to take everything on this resolvers object which is the last big thing inside of this file
and we're going to break it out into its own set of folders and files.
I'm really excited to get to that and to finish up this graphical application architecture.
So let's jump right in to the very next video.