In this video we're going to finish our application refactoring by refactoring the resolvers object.
We're going to one break it out of this file and to break it up into many smaller files as opposed to
one or really long one.
Kind of like what we have already when we started refactoring in the last video the index database file
was sitting at about 320 lines of code.
We're currently at 192.
And by the end of this video we should be just shy of 20.
So we've made some pretty good progress so far but there's still a lot more progress to be made.
Now we're not going to be adding any more files into the source directory.
What we are going to do though is add a new folder.
This folder is going to be called resolvers and I'm creating a folder and not a file because I don't
want all of these to sit in the same location.
So instead we're going to have a resolvers folder and we're going to have files for each root property.
So I'm going to have a file where I just had my queries.
I'll have another file where I just have my mutations and down below.
We're going to have three more files one for post one for comment.
And finally one for user that's going to allow all of our files to stay nice and organized.
Preventing the bloat that we're currently suffering from.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by creating those five files in the resolvers folder.
So I'm going to add one called queery Dhananjay.
And this is a capital Q Just to match up with the property name.
It's not necessary to use a capital letter it's just a convention after resolvers we are going to add
one in for mutation so mutation.
J S.
Then we're going to add three for our three custom types.
So we have the user so user Dhananjay as we have the post.
So right here a Forth file Post dot J s.
And then finally we have the comments.
I'm going to add in just one more comment.
Dot J.
S awesome.
So now we have files for each of those root properties and what we're going to focus on is shifting
code away from index dot J S and into those files.
And let's go ahead and start with the first one right here.
The query object we need to do is take this object and move it over to the file we just created for
queries.
So right here I'm going to copy everything from the opening curly brace to the closing curly brace.
Actually instead of copying it I'm just going to cut it out and then I'm going to take it over to this
file and create a new object for it.
So right here Konst will create a new variable query.
I'll set it equal to and then all I have to do is paste in the object.
I just cut out.
So now we have a file that defines a single variable queery which is the object with all of the actual
query methods we need from here.
All we need to do is export that as the default export.
So that is going to be export in our curly braces exporting query as the default.
And there we go.
We are done with queery dot J ass.
Now we'll talk about how to load this in in a second.
But currently it needs nothing else.
I don't need to import anything and because it doesn't require any of those third party modules over
here what did we have.
We had D-B which is not needed because it's accessed via the context.
We don't need the ID library that was mainly used for our creation.
Mutations and graphical server is also not necessary since we're not actually creating a server over
here.
So this file is done and now we can go through a similar though not quite identical process for our
other four files.
I'm going to save this one over an index just as I am temporarily going to delete this line.
And we're going to move down to the mutation so our mutation object is a bit longer but we're still
going to take that.
I'm going to cut out the entire object then I'm going to move over to our mutation jast file and create
a new variable for it counts.
Mutation setting is equal to the object.
I just cut out once again we are going to export this as the default.
So export in curly braces mutation as default.
Now do we need any of our imports for this one and the answer is yes indexed at J S.
The only time we were actually using you you ID before was in our mutations.
So this line no longer serves a purpose in this file.
I can cut it out of index dot J S and I can add it in to mutation and Dot J s up at the top.
So now a mutation that J S has everything it needs.
Just this one library and we can move on to our other three files all of which are much simpler.
Once again I am going to temporarily remove the mutation property and we will shift our attention towards
Osca with user next so we have the user file.
We're going to need that user object.
I'm going to cut it out.
Then over inside of user Dom J S.
I'm going to create a variable for it.
Konst user equals that object.
And finally I will export it export user as default.
We're going to wrap this up by doing the same thing for other two files.
I'll delete the user property and we can focus on comment.
I will cut that object out bring it over to comment that J S create a new variable for it called comment
said that variable equal to the object and then export it export we're going to export comment as default
and then finally the last one we have to shift around is post.
So right here I'm going to grab that post object.
I'm going to remove all of the object properties for resolvers and then over here where we have post
we will create a variable for Konst post set it equal to that object and export the object export post
as default.
So now we have all of our objects set up in these other files.
What we need to do is bring them all together.
Right here now let's go ahead and actually knock that out.
By adding a few inport statements into the mix up above we're going to go ahead and import all five
of those.
I am going to start by importing my query.
That is the default export called query from right here daat forward slash.
We have to go into the resolvers folder and in there we have queery J atts.
So there we go.
We have queries set up.
We can do the same thing for the other five.
Next up import nutation from.
We have that path too.
That is forward slash resolvers forward slash mutation then we're going to grab user post and comment.
So inport user from Duck forward slash resolvers forward slash user uppercase you of course then we
have a post inport post from that forward slash resolvers forward slash post.
And finally we have comet.
So once again in porting something we're going to call it comment and we're going to grab it from at
DOT forward slash resolvers forward slash comment.
Now that we have all five of these defined we can actually use them right here so I can go ahead and
set that up or I can even just set them up down below so I could set resolvers equal to an object then
on this object I can set up query I can set up mutation.
I can go ahead and set up user post and finally comment and there we go.
We now have our resolvers broken out into their very own files.
Each one containing just one of the root properties we had.
If I go ahead and save index dot J s saving all of the other files of course our application is now
completely refactored.
Now index Dhananjay is a much more focused file it's focused just on bootstrapping our application.
It's not focused on actually defining things so we don't define our temporary data here.
We don't define our resolvers in this file and we don't define our schema.
Those are all defined in other files.
The goal of index j s is to just load those in and bootstrap our application.
So now that we have the new directory and structure in place what I want to do is continue on to the
next two videos where we're going to focus on mutations that update data.
So we want a way to update a user's e-mail or change the body of a post or change what we wrote in a
comment that we regret leaving regardless of what we want to update we can do all of that with mutations.
I'm excited to talk about how we can get that done in the next video.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.