In this video we're going to turn our attention back towards actually creating mutations.
We're going to focus on creating mutations for updating data.
We need three in this video we'll be creating a mutation for updating our users in the next video will
be creating mutations for updating posts and comments.
So to kick things off let's go ahead and close all of the open files and just crack open the files we're
actually going to use.
I'm going to open mutation.
J S.
I'm going to open schema graft UL and also keep D-B dot J.S. open so it can refer to the actual object
structure in case we forget.
Now as always we're still going to start by updating our type definitions just because things are in
a different file doesn't mean we don't follow the same process.
We're still going to define the mutation first then we'll define the resolver for that mutation then
we'll actually test things out.
I'm going to go ahead and create our mutation right here and I'll call it something like.
Update user will set up the arguments in just a moment.
And this one like with our other two user related mutations is going to return a user is going to return
the user with those updated properties in place.
Now it comes to the actual arguments for update user and we're actually going to have to the first argument
is going to be the ID of the user you're trying to update.
And the second argument is going to be an object with all of the fields that you can actually update
and all of them are going to be optional.
So when you're updating a user you could choose to update their name.
Maybe you want to just update the email or the age or maybe you want to update all three.
So let's go ahead and actually set that up.
So this first argument ID is just going to have a scalar type.
Very easy to set up.
The second one though we're going to call something like data and the type for this is going to be one
of our custom input types.
Now unfortunately we can't reuse create user input exactly because name and email are both required.
If someone wants to update their age I don't want to force them to also update their name and email.
So we're going to modify this slightly below.
We're going to create a new input.
I'm going to call this one update user input and what we will have the same three fields all are going
to be completely optional.
So when you're updating share you could update the name if you do it's got to be a string.
If not that's fine too.
Same thing is true with e-mail.
And lastly of course with age which is always optional anyways.
So now we can actually use this input type as our type for data.
So right here we will reference that update user input making that a and nullable type.
So now we have this update user input mutation in place.
We can now go ahead and actually move to the mutation.
J.S. biol an anti resolver method for it over here.
I'm going to add that just below where we delete a user.
So right here we have create user then delete user just to keep things organized.
I will add update user right here and we're going to have all four of those arguments like we have for
every one of our resolver functions.
We have parent we have args which is going to be useful that contains both the ID and our data argument.
Then we have the context argument which we can just restructure to get the database.
And finally we have info.
The only one of these three arguments we haven't discussed at all but which will become very important
in just a couple of sections so now is our job to do a couple of things.
First up I want to locate that user so we can actually update things if we don't find a user with ID.
We're going to throw an error saying that the user you're trying to update does not exist to start we
can create a user variable where we're going to store the user we find if any and to grab the user we
will be calling find on D-B dot users.
So DB users dot find passing in our callback.
We get the individual user we return true when we find a match.
So right here that would be when the user's ID equals our args ID.
Excellent.
Now I've seen people create resolver functions where they never touch args and just reference it like
this.
Armscye ID.
I've also worked on projects where they do structure args so I might grab ID directly off of it.
I could also grab data if I wanted to.
In reality you can really go either way it's personally up to you it's a stylistic choice.
There is no right or wrong answer.
I've also seen folks leave ARGs in place like this and then deep structure it down below.
So I will create a contest.
I will structure both ID and data from args.
This works just fine as well.
There are three options.
Fauria and they're all perfectly fine.
Just to switch things up and explore other ways we can solve problems.
I'm going to stick with this approach.
So right here I will reference ID directly instead of needing to grab it off of args just making life
a little bit easier.
Now what we can do is check if there was no users.
If we did not find a match if no user what are we going to do.
As always we're just going to throw an error.
So throw new error.
User not found the exact message we printed when we didn't find a user when we tried to create a post
or when we tried to delete a user up above.
So now everything down below is only going to run when we actually found a user to update.
The next thing we're going to do is look at data to see which properties they actually want to update
and we're going to update them.
We'll start with the e-mail so if and then we're going to check if the type of data dot e-mail is indeed
equal to a string.
So we're going to make sure that it was actually provided and if it was provided the code inside of
here will make sure that the user object gets updated correctly.
Now for our other properties name and age there's nothing special we have to do but for email we are
going to verify that there is no other user that has the e-mail they're trying to switch to.
So to do that and we're going to add a little bit of duplicate code and we will clean this up very shortly.
So for the moment let's go ahead and check if the e-mail is taken.
Konst e-mail taken all I'm going to do is iterate over all of my users that's D-B dot users and I'm
going to use some to figure out if at least one of those users has that e-mail.
So right here we have our callback function.
We get that user and we're going to return true saying that the e-mail is taken if the users e-mail
equals data email the email they're trying to switch to.
Now we can add a little bit of conditional logic if e-mail taken is a truthy value so e-mail taken is
either true or false.
What are we going to do.
We're going to throw an error saying you cannot use that e-mail.
So right here throw new error I'll just say something along the lines of e-mail taken or email in use.
Now the code down below this will only run if there was no match.
So if the e-mail is not taken and in that case we're just going to set users on e-mail equal to data
dot e-mail.
Now we can move on to our other two properties which will be much easier to set up.
Let's do the name next.
So if type of data dot name is indeed equal to a string then we know it was provided and we can go ahead
and update it.
And for this one there is no additional verification that we actually have to go through.
All we need to do is set the users name property equal to data that name sir.
Here user name equals data dot name.
That brings us to the final property that you can update on the user which is indeed the age and with
the age.
There is another consideration to take into account.
Age can be null so we do want the user to be able to set it to either a number like 27 or 54 but we
also want them to be able to clear it setting an equal to null.
Both are valid.
So we're actually going to change our conditional logic a little bit.
We're still going to have an if statement and when this statement runs I'm still going to set user data
age equal to the data age value.
The difference is exactly when we do that.
So right here the condition of logic is checking the type of data age and only running this code when
it is not equal to undefined.
So if I leave age off of the data argument we're not going to do anything if I set it equal to null
or a number though this code will actually run updating the age appropriately.
Now you might say well could an ice set age equal to something other than an integer and null like a
string.
And the answer is no because the schema is going to invalidate that request before this resolver ever
even runs.
Now down below all we have to do is return the user and there we go.
We now have our update user mutation.
All done.
We have our actual mutation definition in typedef.
And we've created and filled out our resolver method.
The last thing to do is to actually update one of our users over NDB.
J.S. I'm going to go ahead and update this first user with the idea of one.
We'll run a few different updates updating various properties to make sure the method is actually working
as expected.
I'm going to switch over to Grath playground and we're going to create a nother tab.
Now if you're getting a little concerned about the vast number of times we have a little bit later in
the class we'll explore another tool that allows us to stay a bit more organized.
But for the moment this is still going to work.
I'm going to create a new tab and we'll run our update mutation.
So a new mutation we are going to use the new one we just created update user.
Now currently that's invalid.
If we refresh the schema it will become valid and we're going to provide the arguments it expects.
And we're also going to provide our selection set.
I'm going to grab the ID for the user the name the email and the age all of its scalar values.
Now we can choose to update it.
So remember there are two arguments we have our ID.
I'm going to update the user with the idea of one and we have our data which is an object on here we
can provide whatever fields we want.
Now currently we have a valid mutation I don't have to provide any of the fields in data.
I could run this.
And what happens well nothing happens.
Nothing gets updated but I get back is the exact same user that exists over here in the static data.
What's cool though is now we can start changing things so I'm going to change the name.
For example I will change the name to my full name and I'll also wipe the h.
So I'll set age equal to.
No.
Now if we run this new operation we can see we have those changes.
The users name is now an jimmied and their age has been cleared.
And we would see the exact same data if we ran one of our other queries like the users query.
Here I'm going to query for all of the users our first user has those changes.
We can see the name right here and jimmied and if I did add email and age in to the query what do we
get.
We get those back with the correct values age being NULL.
So now we have our update user mutation all set up.
We can update whatever we want whenever we want.
Let's go ahead and wrap testing up by trying to change the e-mail subject here.
I'm going to go ahead and change the e-mail to something like.
Test an example dot com.
This should work since no other user has that e-mail.
But if I tried to change it to something like Mike at example dot com it should fail since that email
is taken.
I'm going to switch it over to Mike an example dot com rerun our operation and what happens.
We get our error which is correct.
We get e-mail taken printing to the screen.
So there we go update user is indeed working as expected.
We have one of our three update mutations in place.
Now let's go into the next video where we're going to set up the other two including a challenge where
you're going to have to use what you've learned here.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's jump right in to the next one.