In this video which is the last video for this section on mutations we're going to go ahead and create
two final mutations one for updating the post and another for updating the comment once that's done
we'll have all of the basic Krout operations for all of our data we'll be able to create data we'll
be able to read data.
We'll be able to update data and delete data we already have the c the R and the D complete the U.
For update is partially complete but by the end we'll have it all finished.
So let's go ahead and talk about exactly how we're going to accomplish this.
Both of them are going to be challenges for you to build on your own but we'll do them one at a time.
I'm going to start by copying and pasting the challenge comments over in the top of the mutation not
J.S. file.
So right here we're going to start with just one mutation.
Let's take things one step at a time.
The goal for this one is to set up a mutation for updating a post.
Let's walk through all three steps which are essentially what we did for user in the last video.
So step one you've got to define that mutation and your type deaths.
We want to support two arguments ID and data where ID is the idea of the post you're trying to update
and data is an object containing all of the actual fields you'd like to update.
Now when it comes to updateable fields and data you should support Title body and published all three
of those should be something that any user can actually update about one of their posts.
And also we're going to set up a return type for this one just like when we updated a user we got the
user back when we update a post.
We should get the post back.
That brings us to step 2 actually creating the resolver method that fulfills this mutation.
First up we want to verify that that post exists we have to fetch it.
If it doesn't exist we're going to throw an error.
And then once we get the post we're going to go property one at a time and we're going to update each
other like we did for a user with our IF statements we're going to check if title is a string.
If body is a string and if published is a Boolean you don't have to worry about the situation we ran
into with age when we updated a user because there are no optional fields for a post title body and
published all have to be provided much like name and email were required for users.
So once you have that in place that brings you to step three to verify your work by updating all of
the properties for a given post.
So pick one of the three posts we have over in our sample data and try to update it try to update its
title try to update the body or try to update the published value when it comes to updating we're not
going to be able to update things like the post's author or the comments author or the post that a comment
has been made on that doesn't really make sense.
If I made a comment on a post and I wanted to change it to a different post.
I don't know of a single web site that would let me do that without just deleting the comment and creating
a new comment for the other post.
So once again it's really up to us to determine what fields someone should be able to update and in
the case of the post.
It's just going to be these three.
All right.
Take as much time as you need to knock that one out and feel free to refer to everything we did in the
last video where we discussed how to update a user positive video.
Knock this out.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play
how that one go.
I'm going to kick things off over in schema.
Graft you well where we're going to set up our mutation so right here we have mutations.
We have our two for post.
I'm going to add a third one just below for updating a post.
And we're going to set up those arguments.
We need the ID of the type ID.
And we also need data.
Data is going to be of the type update post input something we'll define in just a moment.
Now the return value for this one is just going to be a post much like we have for delete post and create
post up above.
Let's go ahead and define update.
Post input down below.
We have create post input.
I'm going to define the new one just below input update post input.
And we're going to set up those three fields.
I talked about title which is totally optional.
You do not have to update the title every time you update something else.
Then we're going to have the body.
Also something you don't have to update all the time.
And finally we're going to have whether or not the post is published.
This is a boolean.
And once again like the other two it can be null.
That's ok we just won't update anything.
Now that we have the schema graphed you l file all knocked out.
We can actually go ahead and save things and move into mutation J ass and move on to Step 2 where we
create the resolver method for this new mutation.
Dambulla we have our user mutations than we have are post mutations.
I'm going to add this one in order update post and we're going to go ahead and set up all of those arguments
right here will start with parent.
Then we have ARGs that our D structure context to get the database and finally info in here.
Just like I did for updating a user.
I am going to start by destructuring args.
I'm going to grab both the ID and data off of there right here getting them both from the args object.
So what's the step one here.
The step one is to get that post we want to make sure that post actually exists.
Otherwise there's nothing to update.
So Konst post equals D-B dot posts dot find we had to find that guy and right here we are going to set
up our callback function where we get the individual post and we'll say we found a match when the individual
posts Id matches up with the ID that was passed in to our arguments.
Perfect.
Now the next thing to do is to throw an error if there was no post.
So if there was no post found that's OK.
We're just going to tell you we can't update anything so throw new error saying something like.
Post not found.
Now everything down below only runs when we did find a post and this is where we're going to go through
those properties one at a time updating them if they were provided.
So we're going to add three more if statements.
First up if the type of.
And we'll start off with the title.
So we're going to check the type of.
In this case data.
Title.
Is that a string.
If it is great we're going to go ahead and actually update the post title properties so post title equals
data title.
Next up we're going to be doing something very similar for bodies.
Let's check the type of data dot body is that equal to a string.
If so that's great right here.
We will set post.com body equal to the value provided on data.
Body and last up we have our published property which is a boolean.
So if type of data are not published equals a boolean.
What are we going to do.
Well we're going to go ahead and set post-cart published equal to whatever value is passed in postop
published equals data not published.
And the last thing to do is to just return that updated post so return post.
And there we go.
Update post is all done now from here.
What we need to do is test our work and make sure we can actually update all of these things.
We have a few posts we can pick from.
I'm going to go ahead and update this first post right here.
The graph Q L 101 post with the ID of 10.
We can test all of this out over inside of graft and playground.
I'm going to add one more tab on to the end.
This one is for our update post mutation.
Mutation update post and I will refresh that schema real quick.
And then we can actually set up the arguments and what we want to select.
Once again I'm just going to select these scalar values.
So I grab the posts ID.
I'll grab the title.
I'll grab the post body and I'll also go ahead and grab the published status from here we can now pass.
Any idea of the post we want to update Sarette here.
ID equals.
I already forgot what I said.
I said 10 then we're going to provide the data as well.
So right here data setting that equal to an object and I should be able to call it like this without
any issues.
What do we get.
We get a post that looks exactly like it did before the data matches up perfectly.
Let's go ahead and change this around a little bit.
I'm going to go ahead and say that I don't really like what I've written I'm going to start from scratch
so I'm going to wipe the body setting body equal to an empty string and then I'm going to unpublished
it.
So I'll set published equal to false.
I go ahead and do that.
And what do I get back I get back exactly what I had before then let's say I also want to change the
title with a different operation.
I could update the title saying something like how to graph Q out if I go ahead and run that.
That data changes as well.
And if I were to run any other operation that interacted with posts I would see the changed data so
I can run the Post's query.
And what do I get.
I get my post changed as expected.
So now we have one of our two mutations in place.
Let's go ahead and move on to the second challenge for updating the comment above.
We have challenge comments for this one as well.
And they're basically identical to what we already had there for the post.
Right here we have the exact same thing we just had for a post though with the word posts swapped out
for comment.
For the most part so I'm not going to spend a ton of time going over this.
Once again start by defining your mutation.
We want ID and data as arguments and the only field we can actually add on data is text since that's
the only thing that can be updated for a comment.
You're also going to actually return the updated comment.
Then step 2 create that resolver method verify the comment exists.
Otherwise throw an error and update the comment properties one at a time.
There happens to only be one.
Lastly verify your work by trying to update a comment changing its text.
Take as much time as you need to knock this one out.
Test your work.
Pause the video and when you're done click play.
How that go.
I'm going to kick things off over in a schema.
Graft.
Well right here we're going to define update comment.
We need the ID and we also need our update data.
I'm going to call the input for this something like.
Update comment input and then we'll set up the value that comes back which will just be a comment.
Now we do need to define update comment input which will be non nullable and right here we're going
to do that down below.
So we have the input for updating a post then for creating a comment.
I'll put it just after creating a comment input update comment input and once again we only have the
text so we have our text and this is an optional string.
Now you might say why create the data object if we only have one field.
Well it's good to stick with a standard set of practices so here we're using ID and data for all of
our updates.
That also gives us a very easy way to expand our code.
If we do add other properties on to comments later down the line we want to restructure a ton of stuff
because it's already set up to scale.
Well now we can save schema digraphs well with everything in place and actually create the resolver
method for updating a comment over and mutation.
J S.
I'm going to put that way down at the bottom as the last method on here update comment we're going to
set up those arguments.
We got parent we got our books we have our DS structured context where we get the database and we have
info inside of here.
We're going to start the same way we did for all of our other ones.
We're going to first deep structure idea and data totally optional.
It's OK if you did not do that then we're going to try to find the comment.
So Konst comment equals D-B comments dot find.
Let's go ahead and track it down.
Right here we have our callback function which gets called with the individual comment and we know we
found it.
If one of those individual comments has an ID value that is equal to the ID argument passed.
And now we didn't find a comment.
We are going to throw that error is standard practice for us if there is no comment.
We'll throw a new error and we'll just say something along the lines of comment not found.
Now all we have to do is update the one property which is the text so I'm going to set that up whoops
down below of course I have that new Mac book with a bigger trackpad and sometimes the palm of my hand
actually moves the mouse around a little bit annoying but right here anyways we are going to check if
and we're going to look at the type of data don't text it that is indeed a string that we are going
to go ahead and apply that as an update changing comment text over to the value stored on data dot text.
And the last thing to do in this file is to return the comment we've just updated.
Now we can actually remove the challenge comments up above and save this file.
We can move on to step three which of course is to verify our work.
A very important step in the process over engraft UL playground.
We're going to create one final tab for our last mutation.
So right here we are going to perform a mutation.
This one is called update comment.
We're going to provide our arguments.
We're going to provide our selection set for this.
I'll just grab the idea and the text are two scalar values.
And before I set up my arguments I am going to refresh the schema.
Now what do we need.
Well we need to pick a comment to update.
I got a couple of comments to choose from.
I'm going to go ahead and grab the comment for this one right here.
So I actually made a typo when I typed this one.
This did no work.
It should be this did not work.
I'm actually going to change that using my mutation so that is the idea of 104 right here.
Id equals 104.
Then data is an object.
And we're just going to provide a single property text.
Once again we should be able to run it with no properties.
Right here we get the original unchanged comment.
I'm going to set text equal to the correct string.
This did not work.
And when I run it what do I get.
I get my changed comment back.
Now as always we can verify that things were saved correctly by fetching that data.
I'm just going to fetch all of the comments and if I scroll down I should see it changed.
And I do the comment with the idea of 1 0 4.
Now has this did not work spelled correctly.
Now that we have this in place we are all done with our final two mutations.
We now have mutations for creating all of our data whether it's a post a user or a comment.
We have mutations for updating all of our data and we have mutations for deleting all of our data.
So we now have support for all of those basic crud operations.
Engraft UL which is an awesome first step.
Now there are still a few basic features of graphics you want to cover before we worry about setting
up a real production ready database.
What I'd like to talk about in the next video is the third operation we can use engraft ul.
This is the subscription which allows us to perform real time communication between the client and the
server the client can say something like Hey I want to subscribe to all comments and the server will
automatically update them any time a new comment comes in.
It's a very cool feature of the language.
So let's go ahead and jump right into the next section and learn all about subscriptions.