Welcome to Section 5 and to the start of part two and part one we looked at the basics of graft.
Well all of the fundamentals you learned about things like this schema and our three operations the
query the mutation and the subscription.
In this part part two we're going to start to focus on all of the features you would expect in a real
application things like database storage authentication testing and deployment.
Now that's all part two in this section in particular we're going to focus on data storage using a very
exciting tool called Prisma Prisma is kind of like an alarm but it comes with a ton of great features
specific to graft well making it really easy to integrate into your application.
And the next video we're going to talk about exactly what Prisma is then we'll set it up throughout
the section getting our data stored in a database as opposed to accessing it from that D-B dot G-S file.
All right let's go ahead and jump right in.