In this video you're going to start to learn about Prisma Prisma is the tool that we'll be focusing
on in this section and in the next several sections.
We're going to be using Prisma to connect our back end no J as to the real database that we're going
to be using and Prisma works with a wide variety of databases which we'll talk about a bit later.
So the primary focus in this video is to figure out one what Prisma does and to where it fits into our
application architecture.
Once we have a general idea of what prison was good for we can actually move on to the next video and
start exploring how we can set it up in our projects to kick things off.
I actually want to go through the visualization we've already been through before.
It's one of the very first things we actually did in this class if you remember on the left hand side
we had our clients on the right hand side we had our server in the middle we started off with a rest
API connecting the two.
And later on we swapped that out for a graphical API.
We learned what graft stands for and we learned that it can work with any back end and any front end.
Now this is all indeed true I did not tell you any lies but I did leave out some of the truth.
There's a bit more complexity to what happens on the back end than meets the eye.
So what I want to do is go ahead and reduce the size of this visualization making room for one more
node over here.
In reality the server is just going to make up our back and programming language.
So for our purposes that is any language.
So once again it could be Python it could be java or in our case the server is written in node j.
S now as a separate node we have our database and once again this still can be any database we'd like
we could use my ask you well post gress or mango D-B.
Any database can get the job done.
The question.
And what I want to focus on in this video is how do we connect our back end node j s with the database
of choice.
We need a tool to actually facilitate that communication.
So when someone sends a mutation off to the server the server instead of modifying one of the arrays
like it currently does needs to actually write to the database when someone sends a query asking for
data the server needs to actually read from the database as opposed to just reading from one of our
static arrays.
So how exactly do we get that done will we have a few options one of them being Prisma the first option
we have is to use a native driver.
So all popular databases like my.
Q Well Mongo DB or post grass have native drivers for node.
J S.
These are essentially NPM libraries that make it really easy for us to connect our backend in node to
those databases.
Now native drivers are very bare bones implementations we can perform all of the queries necessary to
read and write data but we do not get any nice to have features we typically don't get things like migrations
data validation and we don't get a way to actually map our models setting up relationships between our
data.
So in the end of the day if we were to go with a native driver we would end up doing away more work
than is really necessary.
The next step up from the native driver is typically some sort of OUR am now O R M stands for object
relational mapping and a couple of examples of these would be sequel eyes or mongoose sequel eyes is
a great node j s o r n for connecting node to an s ul database like Manusky well or post gresse.
Mongoose is a great no.
J.S. Oh r.m for connecting No J.S. to Mongo D-B.
Now when we start to get into LRM territory we do start to get those nice to have features we can actually
model our data things like users and posts where a user has many posts.
We can set up validations saying that the password field needs to have at least 6 characters and we
can also migrate our data over time adding and removing fields as our data structures change.
All of these are possible with open arms and this is typically what we end up using.
If you've taken my node J.S. course we used the mongoose LRM in that class to connect node j s to a
mongo D-B back end.
Now the tool that we're going to be using Prisma is indeed an alarm.
So we still get all of those nice to have features we can model our data setting up things like users
in posts.
We can describe the relationships between our data we can set up migrations for the data we can perform
validation.
We can do anything one of those other forums can do.
But it comes with a ton of nice to have features that really make it a standout choice.
One of the great features of Prisma is that it is database agnostic.
So if you're using the sequel AIs library you have to use an s ul database.
If you're using the mongoose library you have to use the Mongo D-B database.
And if you decide you want to switch from Mongo DB to post postgresql you have to rewrite most of your
application since the two libraries are so different.
With Prisma we don't have to do that.
Prisma supports every major database out there.
It currently has support for my Eskil post grass and mango D-B and they're working on adding support
for others like elastics search and Casandra.
That means we can easily pick the database we want or switch between databases without needing to change
any code.
Well you have to change some code.
It's about six lines of these six lines we set up to connect to the particular database.
Now all of this works because Prisma wraps our database up and exposes it as a graphical API so it exposes
a graphical API that can be used to read and write from the actual database regardless of what database
we're using whether we're using Eskew L.A.'s UL or whatever.
Now that means our node J.S. back end can read and write from the database using you guessed it graph.
Q Well so Prisma sits right here between our back end and the database.
And you'll notice at this point any time we have communication between different layers it's graphed
Well if the client wants to communicate with no J.S. it's graphed well and if no J.S. wants to communicate
with the database it's graphical as well.
So if no genius wants to read data from the database it sends off a graph.
Well query if no genius wants to write data to our database it sends off a mutation and if no genius
wants to watch the database for changes.
You guessed it.
It sets up a subscription because we're using graphs well between the client and the server and between
the server and the database the server itself actually becomes a whole lot less important.
There's not as much to actually do there which is a good thing.
It allows us to reduce the amount of code and the complexity of that code.
It really just serves as a thin layer between the client and the database.
So it's almost like the client has direct access to the database though the server is still very important
for things like authentication and data authorization.
So we still want to make sure that someone can only read data.
They should actually be able to read.
And we want to make sure that someone can only write data they should be able to write after of course
that data has been sanitized and validated.
So it's not like Noad no longer serves a purpose.
It just serves less of a purpose.
It's more of a thin layer of communication between the client and the database.
So let's take a look at a real world example.
Imagine I had a client and I wanted to get all of the posts I would generate my operation and I'd send
it off to node What does No do node does not write a nother operation to send to the Prisma.
Graft UL API.
It just takes the same one and passes it through Prisma gets the data and the node passes that data
back to the client.
So node really does not do a whole lot.
Now if it came to a mutation I would first make sure that they were authenticated and that the data
was valid.
But then once again I'd still pass that operation from the client right off to Prisma to perform that
right.
And when the data came back I would just send it back through.
Now I don't expect your mind to be blown yet.
I'll be honest when I first heard about Prisma my mind was not blown.
I almost considered not using it in this class.
It wasn't until I actually got into the code and saw how Prisma worked and how it helped me reduce the
amount of code I had to manage that I got really excited.
So that's enough of this visualization.
We're going to continue on to the next video and start setting Prizm up.
If you learned nothing else in this video it should just be this Prisma is an alarm.
It works with all databases and it makes it really easy for us to expose access to the database to a
client and a secure and efficient way.
All right I'll see you next time.