In this video you're going to start to set up your local machine to work with Prisma.
There are a few tools we're going to be installing and configuring to get everything up and running
and then we'll actually be able to learn how this tool works with our graphs.
Well application.
Now the catch here is that the process for installing and setting all of this up is a little different
for each operating system.
So I've actually created three separate installation videos.
This video shows you how to set everything up for Mac.
The next video shows you how to set up everything for Windows and the video after that shows you how
to set everything up for a aboon do you do not need to watch all three just pick the installation video
for the operating system you're currently working on.
All right.
If you're still watching this video I am going to assume you're using a Mac.
So let's go ahead and get things set up.
The first thing I'd like to do is get us set up with a database and the database we're going to be using
is post-grads post-crash is an S Q L database and it pairs really well with graft Well Eskew all databases
in general pair really well with graphics.
Well because with graft you well you have to be explicit about the exact fields and type definitions
for those fields making it an easy match later on in the course I will show you how to set up Prisma
with Mongo D-B if that's your cup of tea.
Honestly any database you can pick works because in the end of the day Prisma abstracts that database
away anyways.
For now though let's go ahead and grab a post gresse.
Heading over to Heroku dot com.
And there are plenty of places where you can get a post gresse database and you do not have to use Heroku.
I use Heroku because they have a free tier for what we're about to do.
So you actually don't need to pay in order to get a basic database up and running for your sample application.
So take a moment to log in if you have an account and sign up.
If you don't I'm going to go ahead and log in to my existing account and once we're in we should see
a dashboard.
Now if you're creating your new account it's likely going to send you through some new customer flow
or it asks you to create an app and that's good because that's exactly what we're going to do.
I'm going to create a new application and we're going to give it a name.
I'm going to start with my last name and all lower case letters.
Now there's no spaces allowed.
So I will use hyphens to separate my words.
That is Mead hyphen Prisma hyphen dev server.
Awesome.
Now we don't need to touch the region.
You likely have a default region.
Good for your location around the world.
You could customize it to Europe if you wanted to but since I am in the US I'll stick with that and
I'm not going to touch the pipeline at all over going to do is create the application.
And once the application is created it's going to bring us to a set of steps describing how we can start
to deploy things.
Now there are plenty of features for Heroku but we're actually not going to need in this class.
We really only need a very small subset of them and we can get started by heading to the overview tab
for our application.
But we're concerned about is installing Add-Ons there's one for a postgresql database.
So let's head over to the configure add ons page and from here we can search all of the available add
ons you want to search for Heroku post graphs.
Now there is a free tier for that.
So once we click on Heroku postgresql it's going to allow us to pick the option we want everything from
free to $12000 a month.
Let's go ahead and start with that free plan.
I am going to provision this which is going to create the database and once the database is created
We're going to be able to click that in our add ons list.
It's going to bring us over to the page where we can learn a little bit more about our database.
One important thing we need from here are the credentials.
The credentials that allow us to connect to the database.
You can find those over in these settings tab.
Right here we have the database credentials area and we can view our credentials.
And this is the information that we're going to need to connect to this newly created database from
the outside world.
Now with your seeing credentials for your database you're all done with Heroku.
We're not going to be using any other features of it.
We're just here for the database and if we have our credentials then we're all set.
The database is created and we can now connect to it.
The next tool that we're going to install is called PGE admin and that's going to allow us to manage
our postgresql database via a GUI.
So we're going to be able to view our data making changes to it like it was in an Excel file without
needing to use code to interact with the database.
Of course our code is going to interact with the database but it is nice to see what data you're working
with and how data is changing over time.
You can find the gooey that we're going to be using by googling PGE admin B-G admin is probably the
most popular one out there.
It might not be the sleekest looking tool but it does get the job done.
It's super stable.
If you head over to PGE admin dot org we can download the version necessary for us for Mac users.
Now D.G. admin is available for pretty much everything out there which is why it's a great choice.
We're going to grab the Mac specific one right here just grabbing whatever the latest version is.
You don't need to match up your version with my version.
It's perfectly fine to just use the latest stable release.
Right here we have the DMG file that is what we need.
When I click that and it is going to start the installation down below perfect.
Now the installer for PGE admin is one of those click next installer.
You don't have to do anything fancy.
You're not running any commands from the command prompt.
All you're doing is cracking it open clicking next and giving permission for it to install something
on your machine.
Now I already have PGE admin installed so all you need to do is wait for the download to complete and
run through the installation and then once it's installed.
Go ahead and crack it open.
You should be able to find it in your Applications folder.
So I have my finder right here if I head over to applications and go down to the right here I have P.G.
admin for all I'm going to do is click that it is going to start up P.G. admin.
And in the end of the day what it's going to do is open up a new browser tab.
So take some time to pause the video until you've got everything installed when you're seeing the PGE
admin tab in your browser like I'm seeing here.
You can go ahead and comeback and follow along.
All right.
I'm going to assume at this point you are seeing what I'm seeing.
We're going to do is add a new server.
This is going to allow us to set up the connection to the database that we just created.
And I'm going to match up the name here with the name I picked for my Heroku app that was Mead hyphen
Prisma hyphen dev hyphen server.
It does not need to match up just matching it up because that's logical.
It's going to make it easy to find this server.
From here we have to move over to the connection tab.
And this is where we put in all of the connection details that Heroku spit out.
We're going to start with the host.
You can find the host right here.
We have to copy that value and paste it over.
Then after that what do we have.
Well we have our database.
This is the actual database that's been given to us.
So I'm going to grab that and bring that over as well right here to the maintenance database tab.
Then we have a user and password we have to grab both of those as well.
We have user right here.
I'm going to paste that in the User Name field and then down below we have password.
The last field we need we can bring that over as well.
And I am going to check that save password checkbox.
I don't want to have to enter the password every single time I want to connect from P.G. adamant.
Now what we can actually save the connection from here we should be able to expand the new connection
we've just created and go under databases.
Now this is where things get a little bit tricky.
What you see here is every single database on this shared cluster.
So it's not just yours now just because I can see them all listed doesn't mean I can actually access
them if I try to expand one of these databases you can see I get an error saying permission denied.
So there are a lot of databases listed here but in reality only one of them is the database we can actually
use out of what 2000 databases to easily find it.
All I do is I just grab the database name over here copy it to the clipboard use find on page in the
browser to search for that database by name.
And here it is.
And you can see that this one does not have that little X next to it.
That's because this is a database.
We can actually connect to if I expand it.
You can see we have a few different options under here.
And for the moment we're actually going to ignore all of these.
We'll talk a bit more about why P.G. admen is a useful tool.
Once we get Prisma set up and we are actually working with some data.
So for now we have our Heroku database set up and we have a way to connect to it from a gooey.
This is a great first step.
The next thing we're going to do before we actually install Prisma is to go ahead and install a tool
called docker so we can find this by heading over to Dr. dot com.
This is a dependency it's something that we have to have installed on our machines in order to use Prisma.
If you've never used or worked with Daker before that's perfectly fine.
We're going to be using a very small amount of Dakar in this class Daker can be a complex tool in the
whole dev ops space and there are literally entire You Tommy courses that just cover Dharker we don't
need to worry about all of that.
We're using a very very small subset of its features.
Now what is Dakar.
Well it's part of this whole containerisation and virtual machine movement.
So if I'm building up an application I have my application code and I have my dependencies.
Let's say I need to run on Linux.
And I also need get and node.
Yes and stop.
Now I have a couple of options I could choose to allow people who want to run the application to actually
install all of those things then I could cross my fingers and hope it works on their environment or
I can bundle it all up into a container.
The container which in essence is a little virtual machine can then be executed from anywhere Dharker
is supported.
And the good news is that docker is supported pretty much everywhere whether it's Mac Linux or Windows.
You can run docker containers regardless of what tools or dependencies they need.
You don't have to slow down and install a whole bunch of stuff on your machine.
For every application instead you just run the container.
It's very easy to stop containers to delete them and to free up all of that space without trying to
remember all of the dependencies you had to install.
It's just a better way to manage apps.
Now there are two sides to docker.
There is the person creating the application and creating the container and there's the person who's
using the container to run the application.
That's the side we're on.
So we're not going to learn about the ins and outs of docker because in reality we're just a user of
a docker trying to run a container provided by somebody else.
Now we're here just to install it.
We can find the installation stuff over at Docker dot com forward slash get hyphen docker and there
are versions available for all operating systems.
We're going to be using the free community edition.
We do have to head over to what's called the docker store.
Don't worry you don't actually check out or buy anything.
It's totally free.
Right here we have versions for all operating systems and set ups.
We're going to be using the version for Mac and once we're here you are going to have to log in.
So you're not going to see the get darker button you're going to see a button saying you need to lock
in what you have to do is create an account and then verify your email.
That'll bring you back to this page and you'll actually be able to click get docker to download the
tool.
Now once that tool is downloaded it's one of those click next installer's.
So take some time to actually go through the process of installing Dharker.
Obviously you have to wait for it to finish downloading and then when you have it installed you can
come back and click play.
All right.
At this point in going to assume that you have docker installed once you have it installed all you have
to do is open it up in your finder.
So I'm going to go over to my applications folder.
I'm going to go down to D.
I have Dharker sitting right here and I'm going to double click it.
Now when we click Dakar and we actually open it up we're not going to see anything visually on our machine
though it did indeed start the docker process.
You should be able to view that up in your menu bar.
You should see this little half well with the little containers on it and if you actually click that
you can get the status of docker.
Now the first time you start it it's going to say something like Dharker is starting up with a little
orange icon right here.
It will take anywhere from 20 seconds to a minute to actually get it started up.
You just want to wait until you see Dharker is running.
If you're seeing docker is running then you're all done with this video.
You have a post database you have PGE admins set up and you have docker up and running which means that
you have everything installed necessary to use Prisma.
Now remember the next two videos are installation videos for my windows and for my Linux users you can
skip both of those and move on to the video after those that were actually going to start the process
of installing and running.
Our very first Prisma application.
I am beyond excited to get to it.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.