In this video you're going to be setting up your machine to work with Prisma.
Now as I mentioned in the last video there is a separate installation video for each operating system.
This video is for my Windows users.
If you're working on a Mac the last video was for you.
If you're working on aboon to the next video is for you.
So if you're still watching I am going to assume that you're on Windows and for the moment we're going
to stick with the Mac screen recording and a little bit later.
In about three minutes we'll switch over to Windows when we have to perform some Windows specific things.
All right my Windows users.
Let's go ahead and set up our machines for Prisma.
The first thing I'd like to do is get us set up with a database and the database we're going to be using
is post-grads.
Grass is an S Q L database and it pairs really well with graft Well Eskew all databases in general pair
really well with graphics.
Well because with graphite you well you have to be explicit about the exact fields and type definitions
for those fields making it an easy match.
Later on in the course I will show you how to set up Prisma with Mongo D-B if that's your cup of tea.
Honestly any database you can pick works because in the end of the day Prisma abstracts that database
away anyways.
For now though let's go ahead and grab a post gresse.
Heading over to Heroku dot com.
Now there are plenty of places where you can get a post gresse database and you do not have to use Heroku.
I use Heroku because they have a free tier for what we're about to do.
So you actually don't need to pay in order to get a basic database up and running for your sample application.
So take a moment to log in if you have an account and sign up.
If you don't I'm going to go ahead and log in to my existing account and once we're in we should see
a dashboard.
Now if you're creating your new account it's likely going to send you through some new customer flow
or it asks you to create an app and that's good because that's exactly what we're going to do.
I'm going to create a new application and we're going to give it a name.
I'm going to start with my last name and all lower case letters.
No there's no spaces allowed.
So I will use hyphens to separate my words.
That is Mead hyphen Prisma hyphen dev server.
Awesome.
Now we don't need to touch the region.
You likely have a default region.
Good for your location around the world.
You could customize it to Europe if you wanted to but since I am in the US I'll stick with that and
I'm not going to touch the pipeline at all over going to do is create the application.
And once the application is created it's going to bring us to a set of steps describing how we can start
to deploy things.
Now there are plenty of features for Heroku but we're actually not going to need in this class.
We really only need a very small subset of them and we can get started by heading to the overview tab
for our application.
But we're concerned about is installing Add-Ons there's one for a postgresql database.
So let's head over to the configure add ons page and from here we can search all of the available add
ons you want to search for Heroku post graphs.
Now there is a free tier for that.
So once we click on Heroku postgresql it's going to allow us to pick the option we want everything from
free to $12000 a month.
Let's go ahead and start with that free plan.
I am going to provision this which is going to create the database and once the database is created
We're going to be able to click that in our add ons list.
It's going to bring us over to the page where we can learn a little bit more about our database.
One important thing we need from here are the credentials.
The credentials that allow us to connect to the database you can find those over in these settings tab.
Right here we have the database credentials area and we can view our credentials.
And this is the information that we're going to need to connect to this newly created database from
the outside world.
Now we're over on my Windows machine and what we're going to do is install the next tool we need.
This one is PGE admen and this is a post Gras database gooey.
It's a tool that's going to allow us to connect to our database and manage our data.
So we'll be able to create data update data delete data and read all of our data in an Excel like table.
It's a fantastic companion.
When working with post graphs so share our code is going to connect it to the database and it is going
to read and write to the database.
But it's also nice to have this gooey so we can track how our data is changing over time.
We can find this tool and install it by heading over to PGE admin dot org.
Here we can go to the downloads page and we can find the download for our operating system which is
Windows and we can just grab the latest release.
You don't need to match up with my version.
You can grab the latest version available.
So I'm going to go ahead and download version three point two by grabbing the s e right here.
Now take some time to download the file so we don't have to watch and sit here while I download the
file I've actually downloaded it in advance.
I have the text file that would get downloaded right here.
And all we're going to do is install it.
So if your file is downloaded we can run through the installer together.
Right here it's one of those click next installers so we don't have to do anything fancy.
We don't have to run any commands.
All we have to do is agree to their terms.
Pick a destination for our installation.
We can go ahead and actually create a shortcut if we want to.
And then it just confirms our options and we run the installer.
Now once this is done we're going to run it PGE admen that is going to allow us to connect to our database.
So what we're going to do is provide these credentials to PGE admin so it can actually make this connection
securely.
From there we'll just make sure that the connection is all set up then we'll be done with PGE and then
for the moment and we'll continue to use it as we progress through the course in the background the
installer is almost done.
I'm going to go ahead and cut the video to when the installer is complete.
Welcome back the installer is complete I'm going to go ahead and launch PGE admin for right here.
The tool is starting up and then the end of the day what's going to happen is that it is going to crack
open a browser tab.
And that's where we're going to interact with the tool itself.
All we're going to do is copy those credentials over so we can actually connect to the database.
So let's take a quick moment to let this tool start up.
Then we'll come back together right here we have our new tab for the admin application and now on the
left hand side we have a list of all of the servers that we've set up connections for and currently
you can see there are none.
So before we can actually do anything with this tool we have to go ahead and create a brand new server.
So right here we have to provide some details in the name field.
We're going to go ahead and pick a name for this.
It can be whatever you'd like.
I'm going to use something like Heroku PGE as an example.
Then we have to move over to the connection tab.
And this is where we provide all of the connection details we have over inside of our Heroku dashboard.
The first thing I'm going to do is grab the host value copying that to the clipboard and bringing it
over to PGE admin.
We're at a pace that in right here.
Next up is the port that is the value 5 4 3 2.
That's the default post gresse port and you can see it's used over here as well.
So there's no need to change anything.
Next up we have our database itself Amen copy this to the clipboard.
Then over here I'm going to paste that in under maintenance database.
After that we have the username and password.
We have both of those over here.
I'm going to grab the user I'm going to bring that over and paste it in.
And I'm also going to grab the password.
So let's take a moment to grab that password.
Copy it to the clipboard paste it in and I'm going to choose to check the save password button so I
don't have to re-enter the password every single time I want to connect.
Now we're actually done.
We can go ahead and save this connection and it's going to test the connection and right over here we
can now actually expand that server.
We can view our database by expanding databases.
And the first thing you'll notice is that there is way more than just our database.
There are actually maybe a couple of thousand different databases running on this server.
Now that doesn't mean we can actually access them.
If I were to try to expand one of these other databases with a little red mark what do I get.
I get an error saying that I do not have permission to connect to that database.
And that's a good thing.
Now we have a really long list of databases here.
It can be a burden to scroll through and find yours.
So what I like to do is just copy the database name to the clipboard.
Then use control after bring up my search on page I paste that database value in and it shows it right
here.
Here we can see this database shown in gold is something we can connect to and if I expand it we're
going to be able to dive in to exactly what that database contains.
Now this is actually where we're going to stop with P.G. and then for the moment once we actually get
Prisma set up we'll dive into here and explore our data.
But for now there's actually nothing in here worth looking at though we do have PGE admin set up and
connecting to the database which is a fantastic first step.
There is just one more thing we have to grab before we're done with this video.
And that is a tool called docker.
We can find that by cracking open a new tab and heading over to Dr. dot com if you've never used or
worked with Daker before that's perfectly fine.
We're going to be using a very small amount of Dakar in this class.
DAKAR can be a complex tool in the whole debt ops space and there are literally entire You Tommy courses
that just cover Dharker.
We don't need to worry about all of that.
We're using a very very small subset of its features.
Now what is Dakar.
Well it's part of this whole containerisation and virtual machine movement.
So if I'm building up an application I have my application code and I have my dependencies.
Let's say I need to run on Linux.
And I also need get a. node Yes and stop.
Now I have a couple of options I could choose to allow people who want to run the application to actually
install all of those things that I could cross my fingers and hope it works on their environment.
Or I can bundle it all up into a container the container which in essence is a little virtual machine
can then be executed from anywhere docker is supported and the good news is that docker is supported
pretty much everywhere whether it's Mac Linux or Windows.
You can run Doctor containers regardless of what tools or dependencies they need.
You don't have to slow down and install a whole bunch of stuff on your machine.
For every application instead you just run the container.
It's very easy to stop containers to delete them and to free up all of that space without trying to
remember all of the dependencies you had to install.
It's just a better way to manage apps.
Now there are two sides to docker.
There is the person creating the application and creating the container and there's the person who's
using the container to run the application.
That's the side we're on.
So we're not going to learn about the ins and outs of docker because in reality we're just a user of
docker trying to run a container provided by somebody else.
Let's go ahead and download and install this tool we can find it by heading over to the get started
button.
If that button has been moved for some reason you can just go to Dr dot com forward slash and get started.
And if I scroll down under the developer tab we have our download for Windows button.
Now there are a few different versions of docker for Windows we want the docker toolbox.
There's a link to that right over here on the right hand side.
The docker tool box is going to allow us to do exactly what we want to do which is use it as the dependency
for Prisma.
Perfect.
Now we do have to go ahead and actually download and install this.
So let's go ahead and do just that.
If I scroll down on this page we can grab the Windows installation.
This is going to download an XP and to save us all a bunch of time.
I've downloaded this ahead of time so take a moment to allow that download to finish then come back
and click play and we'll go through the installation process all right at this point.
I am going to assume you have a docker tool box downloaded.
All we need to do is give that a double click to start the installation process much like we saw with
PGE admin.
This is going to be one of those click next type installers.
We need to pick the location to install the tool we want to leave all of the options at their default.
So here we are installing everything which is good.
Then from there we're going to leave the next pages options as default as well.
Finally it's going to ask us to confirm everything which we will.
And now it's going to run through the installation process once Dharker is actually installed to wrap
up the video.
We're just going to run it and make sure that it's running correctly.
As long as it's running correctly then we'll be able to be done with this video and continue on to the
next one.
Actually setting up and using Prisma from here I just have to confirm that I want to install everything
and that should wrap up the installation process right here.
It's all done.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and click Finish.
That is going to wrap up the installation.
And we're going to go ahead and actually start up Dr Mary.
Here we can see we have a couple of options.
We want to double click.
Dr. QuickStart terminal this is going to crack open a terminal style window and it is going to start
up the docker application.
And this is something that we're going to leave running in the background for as long as we're using
docker.
Now if you restart your machine you can always just start up the docker QuickStart terminal again to
get darker up and running once again.
But once again it is important to leave this window running.
As we progress through the course now on initial booting it's going to take about 30 seconds for it
to go through the process.
And once the process is complete you'll know because it's going to show you a big message in green.
So we're just going to wait here for a couple of moments clicking yes to confirm that we do actually
want to set up Daker the way that doctor wants to set itself up.
And once this is done we'll be done.
All right.
Here we are.
This is what we are looking for.
This is the screen that lets us know that docker started up successfully and right here it's showing
us the local IP address where docker can be used.
It's important to keep the screen up and make note of this address because you as Windows users are
going to need to use this a bit later on.
So that's it for this video.
We have three things set up.
We created a brand new post database using Heroku.
That's where all of our data is going to be stored for our local development app as well as our real
world production application.
We also installed PGE admen which is going to allow us to interact with our database from a gooey.
And finally we installed docker which is what's going to let us run the Prisma application.
All right.
That is it for the Windows specific installation video.
The next video is for our Linux users so you can go ahead and skip that video and jump right back in
to the rest of the course.
I'll see you there.