In this video you're going to be setting up your aboon machine to work with Prisma.
So there are a few dependencies we have to install before we can actually explore Prisma itself.
If you're on Mac or Windows your installation videos were the past two videos.
This one is only for my a boon to users so if you're still watching I am going to assume you are using
the aboon two operating system and we're going to kick things off by actually just sticking with my
Mac screen share.
Then we'll switch over to aboon do in about three minutes.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.
The first thing I'd like to do is get us set up with a database and the database we're going to be using
is post-grads post-crash is an S Q L database and it pairs really well with graft Well Eskew all databases
in general pair really well with well because with graphs you well you have to be explicit about the
exact fields and type definitions for those fields making it an easy match later on in the course I
will show you how to set up Prisma with Mongo D-B if that's your cup of tea.
Honestly any database you can pick works because in the end of the day Prisma abstracts that database
away anyways.
For now though let's go ahead and grab a post gresse.
Heading over to Heroku dot com.
Now there are plenty of places where you can get a post gresse database and you do not have to use Heroku.
I use Heroku because they have a free tier for what we're about to do.
So you actually don't need to pay in order to get a basic database up and running for your sample application.
So take a moment to log in if you have an account and sign up.
If you don't I'm going to go ahead and log in to my existing account and once we're in we should see
a dashboard.
Now if you're creating your new account it's likely going to send you through some new customer flow
or it asks you to create an app and that's good because that's exactly what we're going to do.
I'm going to create a new application and we're going to give it a name.
I'm going to start with my last name and all lower case letters.
No there's no spaces allowed.
So I will use hyphens to separate my words.
That is Mead hyphen Prisma hyphen dev server.
Awesome.
Now we don't need to touch the region.
You likely have a default region.
Good for your location around the world.
You could customize it to Europe if you wanted to but since I am in the US I'll stick with that and
I'm not going to touch the pipeline at all.
All we're going to do is create the application.
And once the application is created it's going to bring us to a set of steps describing how we can start
to deploy things.
Now there are plenty of features for Heroku we're actually not going to need in this class.
We really only need a very small subset of them and we can get started by heading to the overview tab
for our application.
But we're concerned about is installing Add-Ons.
There's one for a post gresse database.
So let's head over to the configure add ons page and from here we can search all of the available add
ons you want to search for Heroku post graphs.
Now there is a free tier for that.
So once we click on Heroku post grass it's going to allow us to pick the option we want everything from
free to $12000 a month.
Let's go ahead and start with that free plan.
I am going to provision this which is going to create the database and once the database is created
We're going to be able to click that in our add ons list.
It's going to bring us over to the page where we can learn a little bit more about our database.
One important thing we need from here are the credentials.
The credentials that allow us to connect to the database.
You can find those over in these settings tab.
Right here we have the database credentials area and we can view our credentials.
And this is the information that we're going to need to connect to this newly created database from
the outside world.
There now are over on my REAL a Bundu machine and we're going to go through the setup process and the
next tool that we're going to be installing is PGE admin PGE admin is a post grass database.
So it's going to give us a graphic user interface to interact with our database.
We can create data update data delete data or read our data all from an excel like view.
Now this is a really great tool.
Obviously we are still going to connect to our database using code that's coming but the Guly is just
going to make it easier for us to track our data over time.
Now for aboon do what we're going to be installing is PGE admin NPG admin is the same tool we're installing
on Windows and Mac.
The only difference is that currently even the latest version of aboon do doesn't support the latest
version of PGE admin.
So to talk about this let's go ahead and crack open the Ubuntu installer.
Right here we are going to search for PGE admin.
We are looking for at PGE admin.
Version 3 that's currently the only version available version 4 is out.
It's essentially the same thing.
It just looks a little bit nicer So this tool is still going to work just great though.
So I'm going to go ahead and install this one.
I'll authenticate myself and it will start off that installation process.
Now once this tool is installed we're actually going to connect to our postgresql database using it.
Once we have that connection set up will be all done since the installation has completed.
I am going to launch the application in the background.
We now have PGE admin version 3 and we are going to connect to our server now by default.
Over here we have NOS servers so we need to create a new one and we do that using this little guy right
here.
This allows us to add a connection and then we have to fill out the connection details step 1.
We can just pick some sort of name that makes sense.
You could use for example Heroku PGE anything would work.
Does it need to be specific to your credentials.
Next up we have our host and this is where we start to pull some database information from our credentials
page.
So right here I am going to grab that host value copy it to the clipboard bring it over to PGE admin
and paste it in.
Next up we have the port the default port for post gresse is 5 4 3 2 and the same thing is true over
here so there is no need to make any change.
Next up we have maintenance DB.
We are going to change that to be our database.
So right here I'm going to copy that database value.
I'm going to paste it in as the value for maintenance DBI.
Then we're going to move on to the user name and the password.
Both also values we have over here.
So first up I have the user.
I'm going to copy that and paste it in and then after user I have the password I'm going to copy that
as well.
Pasting that in to the application.
So from here we have all of our information set up we don't have to worry about any of the other tabs
and we can now go ahead and actually create this connection.
It's going to warn us about saving passwords.
We do indeed want to save the password to prevent us from having to provide it every single time we
want to connect.
Now once we actually do get through that process under server groups we're going to have a single one.
We have our Heroku post gress server and we can go ahead and actually connect to it.
Which is exactly what I'm going to end up doing.
Now here we have a few different views.
What we're concerned with is the databases.
Now you'll notice that there is about 2000 2042 to be exact.
Different databases on this one server.
Now we can't access all of them.
We can only access the ones we've been given privileges to access So for example if I try to click any
random old database we're going to get an error.
Permission denied.
Which is a good thing.
Any database that has that little red X to it is not something that we're going to be able to access.
What we're going to do though is scroll down and find ours.
Our starts with D 6 3.
So let's go ahead and work our way through this list.
I have Diwan did two three four five D6 should be coming up real soon here and right here we have D6
and we have a single database.
Without that red mark next to it.
This is the one we can actually connect to and if I click it and connect we can see the connection was
indeed successful and now I can expand that database and start taking a look at things like it's data.
Now currently there is nothing worth looking at inside of here because we haven't added any data to
the database but once we connect Prisma and start manipulating the data we'll be able to view it over
here.
So for now that's all we're going to do for PGE admin.
We installed the tool.
We connected it to our postgresql database that Heroku gave us and now it's time to move on to the second
thing we have to configure which is Daker.
We can learn a bit more about docker by heading over to the browser and going to dr.
Dot com if you've never used or worked with Daker before that's perfectly fine.
We're going to be using a very small amount of Dakar in this class.
DAKAR can be a complex tool in the whole dev ops space and there are literally entire To me courses
that just cover docker.
We don't need to worry about all of that.
We're using a very very small subset of its features.
Now what is Dakar.
Well it's part of this whole containerisation and virtual machine movement.
So if I'm building up an application I have my application code and I have my dependencies.
Let's say I need to run on Linux.
And I also need get a. node Yes and stop.
Now I have a couple of options I could choose to allow people who want to run the application to actually
install all of those things that I could cross my fingers and hope it works on their environment or
I can bundle it all up into a container.
The container which in essence is a little virtual machine can then be executed from anywhere docker
is supported and the good news is that docker is supported pretty much everywhere whether it's Mac Linux
or Windows.
You can run Daker containers regardless of what tools or dependencies they need.
You don't have to slow down and install a whole bunch of stuff on your machine.
For every application instead you just run the container.
It's very easy to stop containers to delete them and to free up all of that space without trying to
remember all of the dependencies you had to install.
It's just a better way to manage apps.
Now there are two sides to docker.
There is the person creating the application and creating the container and there's the person who's
using the container to run the application.
That's the side we're on.
So we're not going to learn about the ins and outs of docker because in reality we're just a user of
docker trying to run a container provided by somebody else.
Now we're here just to install it to install Dharker on aboon do we have to work through a very manual
process so long story short we're going to be running a bunch of commands from the terminal.
Now there are two articles we need in order to get the correct commands.
First up we are going to Google get darker.
E that stands for community edition for Ubuntu.
The community edition is the free edition that we can use to work with docker outside of an enterprise
environment.
Now the first one is the one we're looking for.
So make sure the u r l matches up.
This is what's going to allow us to install docker and there is just one more article that we're going
to work through as well.
I'm going to pull that up right here.
That one is called install a docker compose.
If we Google that the first result is the one we're looking for docs dot dot dot dot com forward slash
compose board slash install.
This is a nother utility that we're gonna need to actually take the Prisma application and get it deployed
which will work through in the coming up videos.
For now though we have to install these tools and we are going to work through this article.
Get Dankers CD for aboon do if you want to go on your own that's perfectly fine.
Long story short we're gonna be running every single command shown in this article so let's get to it.
The first one is going to uninstall potentially old versions of things we have on our machine.
Now you might not have anything that you remember but it's always a good idea to run it just in case.
Perfect.
And once that's done we are just going to move down the list so down below.
We can go ahead and install using these steps for Bundu 16 and newer.
I'm running on eighteen point in 0.4 so this is what I want and there are a bunch of commands down below.
First up we're going to make sure everything is up to date.
Using apt get update.
That might take a little while depending on how long you've gone between running it and once that's
complete We're going to move on.
To actually allow ourselves to install from.
H t t p s.
So here we're going to copy that command to.
We're going to fire that off.
And once that's done we'll be able to continue on down below.
We are going to configure ourselves with docker.
We had to run this command to get the official GOP key and after that what do we do.
Well we're going to go ahead and set up our fingerprint I'm going to grab that command I'm going to
run it.
Excellent.
Now after that we moved down below.
And here we are actually configuring ourselves with the repository for docker.
This is where we can grab the stuff that we're about to install.
So we're going to grab that command.
Run it from the terminal as always and wait for it to finish.
Once again a very straightforward process.
Now once this is done we're actually going to be able to install Thakurs community edition down below.
Installed Dockers see we can update one more time.
Once that's done we are going to run the installation command for Daker hyphen C E which is what we
want.
Let's go ahead and fire that off right here.
I'm going to fire that off.
And this could take a significant amount of time depending on your network speed and environment.
Now after we have the docker community edition installed we can go ahead and choose to install a specific
version which we're not going to do.
We're just going to install the latest version that you could run a command to get that done.
So we can actually skip step three entirely and move on to Step Four.
Now this is their way of verifying that things are working correctly.
We could go ahead and do this though it's not necessary the way that we can verify is by running.
Dr hyphen hyphen version if this prince a valid version.
No we know we've installed things correctly.
If you get some output like command not bound then things didn't install correctly but don't worry you
can always open up a new question in the Q&amp;A and I'll work with you to get unstuck.
This installation method isn't ideal but it is all we have for our Linux based operating systems.
So thanks for bearing with me as we ran through all of those comments on Mac and Windows.
It's much easier.
Click next type installer.
But to each their own.
Now next up we have the second article which is much quicker.
We're going to install doc or compose which we need as well.
We can pick our path we are using Linux and all we have to do is run a couple of commands so right here
we are going to fetch what we need.
Make sure to grab the entire command even what's not shown without scrolling.
I'm going to fire that one off.
And once that's done we're actually going to mark that as executable using our seamount command.
Excuse me S.H. mad.
I never said some of this stuff out loud so sorry if there is an official pronunciation for that.
I don't come from the aboon do world.
But I did want to make an installation video showing you how to get everything set up.
So I'm going to run that over here marking the file as executable.
And then what are we going to do.
Well we're going to execute it.
So right here we can run Dakar compose with the version flag to make sure that it was installed successfully.
If you're seeing a version print then you're all done.
If you're seeing an error like docker compose command not found then something went wrong and once again
just crack open a question in the Q&amp;A.
So there we go.
We now have everything we need to actually continue on to the next video.
Keep in mind that when you're running on aboon do you are likely going to need to use sudo before all
of the darker and darker compose commands we run.
I'll remind you in the future but this is a quick reminder right now.
So we are all set up.
We have our database.
The database has our credentials and we connect to the database already using PGE admin.
The gooey.
We're going to use throughout this course.
Now aside from getting the database and installing and configuring PGE admin We also just installed
and configured docker which is going to allow us to run Prisma.
That's the topic of the next video.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.