Welcome back.
In this video we're actually going to install and create our very first Prisma project which I am super
excited about now at this point we're all coming back together.
So regardless of your operating system this video is for you at this point you should have your post
gresse database set up.
You should have P.G. admin running and you should have a connection to the database.
And finally you should have installed and started up Daker.
That's what we covered in all three installation videos.
The first one for Mac.
The second one for Windows and the third one for Linux.
If you did not go through those steps you're not going to be able to continue on.
If anything went wrong during those steps just crack open a question in the Q&amp;A and we'll work with
you to get unstuck and back on track.
All right at this point I am going to assume you have everything is set up and to kick things off we're
going to go over to the Prisma Web site what you can find at Prisma dot I.
Oh here you can learn more about how this tool works and all of the features it offers.
They also have a fantastic set of documentation.
It's a combination of guides telling you how to do specific things like deploy Prisma to Digital Ocean
for example in reference docs showing you exactly how various methods and utilities actually work.
Now if we go back there's only one more page here I want to show you.
That is the community page.
The Prisma community has a great slack channel.
It's a great place to talk with others about how to use Prisma you can help others you can get a bit
of help yourself.
It's a nice community.
So let's go ahead and join there as well.
You can just toss your e-mail in there and click.
Join us on slack now don't use that as a place to just pester them for help.
If you have a real problem it's best to try to work through it on your own and improve your understanding.
Though the community is there for help and it's also there for you to help others with what you actually
know.
All right that's it for the Web site.
I just wanted to point you in this direction.
So you know where to go if you want to learn more.
Or if you forget how something works for our purposes what we're going to do is install this and we
install it as an NPM module.
So over in Visual Studio code I'm going to crack open the terminal for the first time in a while I'm
going to use Control-C to shut things down.
And what we're going to do is run NPM install with the G flag.
We're going to be installing this module globally.
It's called As you probably guessed a Prisma and we're going to install the latest version.
So Prisma at one point twelve point zero.
Perfect.
Now we can actually run this installer and it's going to go through the process of getting everything
set up on our machines.
It might take a little while to actually install.
So what I'm going to do here is cut the video and I'll come back once the installation process is finished.
Take a moment to pause the video yourself and just click play.
Once the installation is complete.
All right.
How'd that go.
Hopefully you were able to get everything installed as expected.
I'm going to clear the terminal output and I can test that things were installed correctly by running.
Prisma with the flag.
This is going to print the version of Prisma installed.
If you do get a version.
Great things have been installed successfully.
If you get an error along the lines of command not found that means things were not installed correctly.
You can just crack open a question in the Q&amp;A and we'll work with you to get unstuck and back on track.
Now from here we're going to be using that Prisma command to initialize a new project and we're actually
going to create a new folder engraft Cuil course.
So we're not ditching everything.
We created engraft UL basic's we're not throwing all of that code away.
All I'd like to do is create a new directory for this phase two of our project I want to leave this
barebones version in place as a reference for the future.
So right here what am I going to do.
I'm going to create a new folder inside of here.
We're going to give a name to this project I'll call it graph Cuil hyphen Prisma.
And now what we're going to do is use C-D to switch into that folder.
So from the terminal C-D dot dot to get out of graph you basics then forward slash graphical haif and
Prisma to get into the new folder we justified.
Once we're in there we're going to be using Prisma in it.
Now Prisma it does take an argument it takes the name for your project and we're going to call our Prisma.
So that's Prisma in it.
Prisma we can actually go ahead and run this and this is going to go through the process of setting
up the project.
Now if we actually crack open graph Q L hyphen Prisma we can see it's created a new folder with the
same name as the project that we just set up.
We passed in that third argument Prisma we have a folder called Prisma.
Currently it has no files inside of there.
And that's because Prisma is asking us some questions about our project.
The first question is whether or not we have an existing database so we can either create a new one
or use an existing one.
We don't want to create a new one because of the way it actually creates it.
We want to use the existing external production ready database that we've already created.
So we're going to use the arrow keys to cycle through the options and pick use existing database.
From there it's going to access the type we are using.
I'm using POST graphs and then the last question for the moment is does our database contain existing
data.
Now there's experimental support for migrations but we don't have data so we can pick.
No we have an empty database from here.
All it needs is our connection information.
So the same information we provided to P G admin I could head over to that Heroku tab once again and
grab those values.
First up is the host value.
I'm going to copy that pasted in and hit enter.
Next up is the port.
The port is.
Excuse me 5 4 3 2 which is indeed the default value.
So I can just hit enter to use the default value.
Next up the database user right here we have our user name.
I'm going to copy that.
I'm going to pace it over and hit enter.
Then we have our database password.
I'm going to grab that copy it and paste it over and then finally we have our database name.
That's right here next to a database.
I'm going to paste that in and hit enter.
The last question is whether or not we want to use S S L external connections for Heroku require SSL
so you have to hit.
Yes here you have to type in uppercase why then we can enter and we can choose a name for our existing
schema.
We're going to call it what we've been calling it before schema dot graph.
Well and there we go.
We're all done.
Now what exactly did that do.
Well it actually did a few things.
First up it created three files in the Prisma directory which we'll be exploring in just a moment.
It also shows us the steps to actually get things set up.
These are steps we're going to take in just a second after we actually go ahead and explore the files
that it created.
What I'd like to take a moment to do is open up all three files and familiarize ourselves with this
little project structure.
We're not going to dive into the details of all three right now.
I just want to get a quick overview though don't worry we will be working with all three extensively
making changes to them as we progress through the course first step.
We have a data model dot graph QOL data model graphed UL is nothing more than a set of type definitions
for graph.
Q Well similar to what we have in schema data.
Well in here we have all of the things that make up our application.
We have users posts and comments and eventually we're going to have something similar in data model
that graphical as well.
The cool thing about this file though is that Prisma uses this when it determines your database structure.
So for us Prisma is going to create a new table for all of our custom object types.
So it's going to create a new table for all of our users and it's going to add columns to each user
ID and name.
So the graphical type definitions end up changing the structure of what our database looks like.
Now if it wasn't for this code right here we would know exactly what the spiled does at Unique is something
we'll talk about later.
We'll talk about exactly what this syntax is and what it's doing for us.
For the moment though we're just going to continue on to the other two files the next file.
I'd like to talk about is Prisma.
Y.M. Well this is a YAML file and YAML is similar to Jason.
It is just a set of key value pairs.
And in the end of the day it's a great language when it comes to configuration.
So we're going to see a bit of YAML in this course.
Essentially we have the key Kolins space.
The value here we have just some default configuration.
We have the end point which we will eventually be able to use to access our instance and we have a link
to the data model we want to use for the database here.
It's just data model linking to the file that we just explored.
Now there's only one more file but it's by far the most complex that is docker compose.
Dot why now.
This is the file that's actually going to start up the docker container.
And you'll notice it contains some of our personal details down below.
We have all of the connection information for our database.
Let's briefly go over this file.
First up we have the version for the or composed file.
You can think of this kind of like your TNL document.
It describes the version you want to use.
In this case we are using the syntax for version 3.
So the version allows us to determine what fields we can actually set.
Next up we have services and we just have a single service Prisma.
Now for Yamhill you can think of this kind of like a property whose value is an object and on that object
we have a property Prisma.
Now inside of Prisma is where everything interesting lives.
First up we have the image.
So this is the Dakar container that someone else created that we are going to use it specifies the container
name as well as the version here.
One point one too.
Next up we have restart always.
Which just makes sure that the process restarts when we deploy new changes to it.
And we have the ports we're going to use just 4 4 6 6 down below that we have environment.
And this is where we set up our Prisma config to configure how Prisma works.
We have our port once again.
And the other thing we have in here is our database so we just have a single default database and we
have all of the connection details we provided.
Now we do have to make a couple of small changes to this file before we actually deploy.
Right here we're going to remove the schema property.
It's not necessary.
We will actually leave that off and we're going to be adding in a new property as well setting that
to true.
Now if you remember when we went through the little prompts from Prisma in it we did say we wanted to
use SSL for one reason or another though it doesn't actually save that information into the dock or
compose file.
Maybe they'll change that in the future.
So if you see SSL there already there's no need to add it again.
But you do need to make sure it exists.
Otherwise we're not going to be able to connect to the Heroku postgresql database.
All right.
That is it for changes to this file.
Let's go ahead and actually deploy our app.
So what is it telling us to do we have to CD into that new folder.
We have to run one command to start up docker and another command to actually deploy what's in our little
Prisma folder.
So I'm going to use CD Prisma to navigate into that new directory.
Then we're going to use one of maybe two docker commands will ever use Dr hyphen compose up with the
D flag.
Remember that if you are running on aboon do you are going to have to use sudo before all of our docker
commands that includes darker and darker compose.
Let's go ahead and run the command and the first thing it's going to do is grab all of the code necessary
to actually run Prisma then it's going to start on the Prisma application in our little virtual machine.
Now this process is actually not deploying our code in any way whatsoever.
We have to run that separate command in order to actually deploy our changes to the process.
For now though we really just need to sit and wait for it to complete.
It should just take a few moments.
Perfect.
The next thing we're going to do and the last command we're going to run for now is Prisma deploy.
This is actually going to deploy your latest change in so as I make changes to my schema for example
adding new types or changing the fields for types we are going to need to deploy for Prisma to actually
reflect those in the database.
Right here though we can run it Prisma deploy and this command is known to fail if you run it too quickly
after actually creating that Daker instance.
So if it does fail just go ahead and run it again maybe count to 10 then run it again and you should
see what I see here.
Here we can see exactly what it did.
It started by deploying that default service.
And then what did it do.
It went through the process of actually creating everything necessary based off of our schema.
Now in this case we just had a user and we had two fields ID and name.
And that also created two fields for us updated at and created at allowing us to keep track of when
the given record whether it's a user a post or a comment was created and updated.
A super useful thing to be able to do.
Now what can we do when we can actually pull things up in the browser.
Everything is deployed.
We can head over to the browser and go to a local host colon four four six six.
Now if you're on Mac or Linux this should be the correct.
You are Al.
If you're on Windows you need to find the IP address that the docker toolbox spit out so you could open
up that terminal which should be running in the background somewhere there's an IP you want to replace
local host with that IP.
You still want to add the port on to the end if we actually visit as you are l.
What do we get.
We get another instance of graph Al playground.
This time though the graphics playground is connected to the graphics API provided by Prisma itself.
That means if we were to use a mutation it would actually write data to our postgresql database.
If I was to use a query it would be reading data from that database.
Now the nice news is that Prisma does all of the heavy lifting for us.
All we need to do is define in data model the various types and fields we want Prisma goes through the
process of automatically creating the mutations the queries and the subscriptions necessary to get everything
working with the database we've chosen.
Now if we actually go back over to the browser we can open up the schema and we can see there are plenty
of queries mutations and subscriptions that we had no part in creating.
We have users for fetching users we have user prefetching an individual user.
We have create user update user and delete user.
And we even have subscriptions allowing us to watch user data for changes.
They noticed that everything here is related to user.
And that's because it's the only type we defined as we define more types Prisma is automatically going
to generate other queries mutations and subscriptions allowing us to easily work with those types.
Now in this video we're not actually going to perform any operations just yet.
That's going to be the topic of the next one.
That's where we're going to stop for this one.
So let's take a quick moment to recap.
Aside from installing Prisma what we really did in this video is we created a new Prisma project and
we deployed our first Prisma project.
We created the new Prisma project using Prisma in it and then asked us to a bunch of questions about
our project and it allowed it to automatically generate these three files.
Data Model Prisma and Dakar compose.
Now it's important to note that I could have generated these three files on my own.
The only reason we use the little wizard is because it makes it way easier to get up and running with
Prisma.
In the end of the day I could have typed out every single character and gotten the same result.
That's just way more tedious and quite frankly way more error prone.
So it's always a good idea to use Prisma in it when you're getting started.
Now all of the real work was done when we used the docker compose command to start up the Prisma service
and then Prisma deploy to actually deploy our data model to that service.
The end result was that we can see well play ground over in the browser.
Now this is great because in the very next video we're going to use graph Q playground to interact with
our database.
Then after that video we're going to start using it inside of node j ass so we can actually read and
write to the database from our project itself.
I'm excited to continue on talking about Prisma.
So let's go ahead and jump into the next video and take a look at all of the queries mutations and subscriptions
that are provided to us.