If you've made it this far into this action I've got some great news which is that there's no more installation
or configuration left.
We have everything set up.
Prisma is up and running and it's time to start taking advantage of what it has to offer.
Well we're going to start to do and this video is explore anti-graft UL Prisma API.
This is auto generated for us and it allows us to interact with our database.
So as we perform mutations we're actually writing to our database as we perform queries and subscriptions.
We're actually reading from the database.
Now all of these get automatically generated based off of the contents of a data model dot graph.
Well so you'll notice that all of these are user related because the only model we actually have is
a user.
If we were to add other ones like comments and posts we would see auto generated queries mutations and
subscriptions for those as well.
So briefly under queries we have a way to fetch multiple users and a way to fetch a single user under
mutations we have ways to create update and delete our users as well as a couple of other ways we can
mutate our users.
And finally we have a user subscription allowing us to subscribe to user changes whether a user gets
created updated or deleted to kick things off.
Let's go ahead and write to our database by using the create user nutation.
And if we actually click on that we can learn how to create user works create user takes a single argument
data and it sends back the user itself.
So we know what to do when we get a user back.
We're going to select the fields we want but what exactly do we pass in the data we pass in an instance
of user create input.
So down below under arguments we can actually click data to view what user create input takes.
Right here we can see it just takes a string.
So on the data argument we have to provide a name field of the type string.
That's all we need to actually create the user and to write some data to the database.
So let's go ahead and kick things off.
I'm going to collapse the schema and we're actually going to use create user right here a new mutation.
We are going to create user then we're going to pass in our arguments and set up our selection set.
I'm just going to grab the ID and the name of the user.
We create the two fields we actually have listed.
Now we do have to provide our argument.
So let's set that up as well.
We're going to provide data.
The one and only argument we need and we know the only field we have to provide on data is name where
we set up our string name.
I'm going to go ahead and just use my name I'll use Andrew Mead.
Perfect.
And there we go.
Now we can actually fire off this mutation.
Let get back the data we probably expected.
We have our route data property.
We then have create user which matches up with the mutation name in there.
We have all of the data we asked for about the user we just created.
What's cool though is that the data is not just living in some array or something like local storage.
It's actually being stored in our post gress database.
So let's go ahead and move over to PGE admin and actually view this data.
I'm going to crack open PGE admin and right here I have the database you should have your database already
expanded.
We did that in the installation video.
And the only one we care about under our database is schema It's now the data has changed since we first
opened PGE admin admen since we have executed Prisma.
We need to refresh our schemas to see the latest changes right here.
You can just right click schema and click refresh and we all need to do that when we actually make a
change to that data structure.
Now if we expand this we can view all of the various schemas we have and by default our data is stored
under default dollar sign default.
So we're going to open that up in there.
We are interested in exploring the tables.
That is where our data lives.
So down below we have tables and we have a table for every single model we define.
So here we defined one type user and we have a table that stores all of our users and we can actually
view the data in a nice way by right clicking that table name going to view data and just selecting
all roads here as a sort of Excel sheet.
We're going to be able to view all of the data in our database.
We have just one row one user we have the ID value under the ID header.
We have name under name Andrew mead and I also have updated and created at.
Which are automatically added by Prisma itself.
We'll learn more about these and how we can actually use them a bit later created at get set once when
the record is first created and updated and gets updated.
Anytime we change our data in this case the only thing we can change is name.
So any time the name changed updated at will be updated to reflect the time stamp when the name was
actually changed.
All right.
So we have all of our data are right here.
This is a great first step.
We can clearly see that with Prisma we're able to manipulate our database using a graphical API.
Let's go ahead and add a user into the mix.
I'm going to pick a random name for this user I'll use victim and we're going to run that.
And now we should see vigorous showing up in the database as well.
Over here I can refresh the data being shown by clicking this little lightning bolt.
Not exactly the clearest icon but it will indeed make another query for your data.
And now we can see we have two records showing up.
Now we can also fetch our data using the Graph API provided by Prisma right here for example there are
a few different ways to get that done.
We have a user's query to fetch multiple users and we have a user query to fetch a single user.
Let's go ahead and mess around with users for the moment.
Now users does take some arguments but they're all completely optional so we can just grab all of our
users deciding what data we want from each.
I'm going to set that up right here.
A query operation we are using the user's query that requires no arguments so we're not going to provide
any.
You can take my word for that and then we're going to define what we want off of each user.
We'll just grab everything the name and the ID.
Excellent.
Now if we actually fire this off what do we get.
We get all of our users back.
I have jimmied as the first one and Vikram as the second one.
All of these live under the users are array stored on our route data property.
And this is exactly the sort of structure we would have expected.
And its a sort of structure.
We actually see with our very own application.
So theres nothing magical about exactly how Prisma sends data back it's going to look the same as it
looked when we were using graph playground with our own app.
What's nice though is we do not need to create the mutations the queries or the subscriptions Prisma
does that for us.
All right let's go ahead and explore one more together than I'll give you a challenge.
All you have to use one on your own right here.
We're going to go ahead and use update user to change the name for one of our users.
Now if we look at Update user we can see it takes a few different arguments.
And this is where you're going to start to get a bit more familiar with the definitions for various
operations.
So it's necessary to actually dig into the schema and see how things work.
Right here we can see that with Update user we get a user back as expected.
And we can see that it takes two arguments it takes data where we provide the things we want to change
and it takes a where argument.
This is where we define which user We're trying to update.
If we look at data we can see the only thing we can change is the name.
Obviously that makes a lot of sense if we open up where though we can see the only thing we can search
by is the ID.
So we have to provide the ID for the user We're trying to change.
And we also have to provide the data we're trying to change.
Let's go ahead and actually knock that out by creating a new mutation right here another mutation I'm
going to set this up and I'll call it update user.
This one does take arguments so we have to provide them.
We have to provide Where where is an object.
And we have to provide the ID so we can filter users by their ID.
And I'm going to go ahead and update one of these users I'll update the user that I created for myself
and I'm just going to change the name.
Removing the last name if I copy the ID I can bring it over to this tab and paste it right there between
the quotes for the ID property.
Next up we have to define data as well so comma enter.
Setting up data that also equals an object.
On here we can determine what exactly we'd like to update.
There's only one thing to update currently and it's name.
I'm going to change it to Andrew removing the last name.
Last up we have to provide our selection set.
So we get a user back.
What do we want to know about that user we just changed.
I'm going to grab their ID and I'm going to grab the name if we actually fire off this operation we
can see that when we get back.
Looks like a success.
We have our data update user properties and we have the data.
We've actually changed with the name being the new version.
I can go ahead and rerun that user's query to see the exact same thing.
And finally if I refreshed the data in PGE admin I can see that the last name has been removed from
that very first user.
Now that we've messed around with a couple of these queries mutations and subscriptions together.
Well I'd like you to do is figure out how to use delete user.
I want you to delete the second user we created.
So in this case I want to delete Vikram.
You might have a different name.
Either way you want to figure out how to use delete user by exploring this schema and actually knocked
that out to delete one.
Then go ahead and rerun the user's query to make sure it's gone and refreshed.
PGE admin to make sure it's removed from there as well.
Take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Dig into the documentation to figure out how it works or move the record.
Test your work and when you're done click play
all right how that one go hopefully you were able to get everything up and running without too much
trouble.
I'm going to start by digging into the documentation there's no better way to learn how something works.
Right here we have delete user for deleting users and we can see that it returns the user that was deleted
and it takes a single argument where it's of the type user where unique input.
And we can explore what exactly it lives on there down below.
The only thing we can delete a user by is their ID which is great.
That's exactly what we're going to end up doing.
So right here what do we do.
First we need the idea of the user.
We're trying to remove.
I have that sitting right here so I'm going to copy it to the clipboard then we're going to move over
to a new tab and set up our delete user mutation.
So we have a mutation operation.
The mutation is called Delete user.
We are indeed going to be providing some arguments just where that's an object.
We set up the id property on that object setting the value equal to the ID we just copied.
You can break this onto multiple lines if you like.
You can leave it as a single line too.
Typically though if I do have objects I like to break things onto multiple lines like you've been doing
previously throughout the course from here we have to provide our selection set.
So what do we get back.
We get back that deleted user and I am going to grab the ID and the name for the user that was removed.
If I go ahead and fire off this operation what do I get.
Right here I get the data property I have delete user on there and I have the information that I selected
for the deleted user.
Now if I rerun that user's query I should no longer see that second record.
And I can see that has been removed.
And lastly if I refreshed the data view over NPG admin I can see it's been removed from there as well.
And this is fantastic.
We now have a way to perform all of those crud operations using the auto generated graphics API provided
by Prisma we can create data we can read data we can update data and we can delete data.
Now we've gotten a little taste of what the API actually provides.
Clearly there are plenty of things we have not used but what's great is that the queries mutations and
subscriptions would be the same even if we were using a different database.
If I switched over to my ESC well or mango D-B we wouldn't need to change any of our code.
It could all stay exactly the same.
So Prisma abstracts away the implementation details of our database allowing us to just focus on what
our application needs to do and that is a huge bonus.
Now from here what are we going to do.
Well we're going to learn how to set up a more realistic data model inside of Prisma.
Right now we just have users and they only have two fields and one of them has something that we don't
even know about in the next video.
We're going to spend a lot of time in this file making it look a lot more like the schema we had set
up previously.
We're going to have users.
We're going to have posts and we're going to have comments.
All right.
That is it for now.
Let's go ahead and jump right into the next one and make some changes to data model skycraft.