In the last video you saw just how important the data model got graph you el file is.
This file is used by Prisma to determine two very important things.
First this file is used to determine the database structure.
So I have a user type here and that is the only reason why I have a user table down below on that user
type we've determined we want an idea and a name and that is the only reason I have an ID and a name
field for each user.
Now yes we do have updated and created out.
We'll learn a bit more about those later in the class.
Now the other important thing that this file is used for is for generating the graphs Well API as schema
as we saw all of our queries.
Mutations and subscriptions are all related to users and that's because it's the only type we have to
find.
If we were to define other types we would have other queries mutations and subscriptions for those other
types as well.
So in this video we're going to do two things.
One we're going to make some changes to our user type and two we're going to add together a post type
in the next video.
It will be your challenge to add the comment type.
So let's go ahead and get started by making some changes to the user type.
Now everything we're seeing here was automatically generated as part of the default Prisma project.
Now we do still want a user type in our application but it's missing some fields.
If we go over to schema digraphs Well obviously we're missing posts and comments but we don't even have
those related types set up.
So let's not worry about them for now we'll just worry about our scalar fields.
We already have ID we already have name we don't have email and we don't have age.
Now we're actually going to ditch age at this point age was added to give us a bit more variety using
other types as we explored how graphical works.
But for the final version of this blog app we're not going to track the age for each user though we
definitely will be tracking their e-mails.
And later on in the course we'll be adding on other fields like password as we start to get into authentication.
For now though let's just add that email field into the mix.
So over in data model dot graph.
Well I am going to list email out setting it up as a non nullable string.
We can save the file and now all we need to do is rerun Prisma deploy.
That's going to read the contents of this file.
It is going to update both the database structure and the graph API to work with this brand new field.
So down below we can just run Prisma deploy from inside of our project.
Now here's the catch.
When we run this it's actually going to fail and the error message is going to shed some light on what's
going on.
So we have an error.
The error is of course related to the user the only thing we have and the message is the following.
You are creating a required field but there are already knows present that would violate that constraint.
So it's complaining about email.
We've set up e-mail to be a field that every user has to have.
Now what it says node's really just means data.
It's talking about our existing users.
If I go over to the database it's saying that it can't automatically update this record because it's
not going to be able to add a value for e-mail which means that this user would be invalid for the moment.
We can work around this just by deleting the record and starting from scratch.
So what I'm going to do is delete our one and only user wiping this table out completely.
Then we should be able to rerun Prisma deploy but this time around we should not be getting any errors.
We should actually see that everything went correctly and that even describes all of the changes that
were made.
Right here we can see that one of the changes made to user was that an email field was created and it
has the correct type right here.
Now this means two things.
It means one that our database structure has changed.
If I refreshed the page we can see that email has been added and 2 two it means that our graph QOL API
has changed as well.
If I refreshed the schema here and open up the documentation for create user which we can already see
is currently invalid.
We have our data argument.
This time it does still take name and that is still required but it now also takes email which is also
required.
So the previous create user call we had is no longer valid because there is no e-mail provided.
Let's go ahead and set one up sir right here.
E-mail sending an equal to.
I'm going to use Vikram at example dot com.
Perfect.
Now we can actually go ahead and run this operation and when we do it's going to succeed.
So right here we can see that the new user was created.
Now in that case I didn't ask for their email back which is why I did not get their e-mail.
Well we can always fetch that.
Using the user's query to make sure it's showing up.
So right here for each user I'll grab their id rather name and I'll grab their e-mail if I fire this
one off we can see we have that data showing up which is fantastic.
Now of course over NPG admin We want to make sure things are looking good here.
If I refreshed the page we do have victim at example dot com as the value for our email field.
Perfect.
So with this in place the last thing I want to talk about related to the user is what we have right
here the unique that comes after our ID field definition.
What we have right here is a graph Q El directive.
A directive is a way to modify the behavior of the field.
Now directives are usually something that we need to create and then use but clearly we haven't created
anything called unique in our code.
This one is actually coming from Prisma.
So Prisma provides us with various things to make our life a little bit easier.
It gives us custom types we'll be talking about soon.
It gives us things like directives and more and the unique directive as the name suggests makes a given
field unique.
Now the syntax for this is the following after the field definition.
Obviously we don't need a directive.
But if we want to use one we start with the at sign then we provide the directive name.
In this case providing unique directives as we'll see later can also take arguments unique does not.
So we're going to leave those off just setting it up exactly like we had it before.
Now what does this do well makes sure that for every user out there none of them have the same idea.
So we want to make sure the ID is unique for all users stored in the database.
Now this is great for some fields and it's useless for others.
For example the name the name doesn't need to be unique.
There are other Andrew Mead's out there.
I'm not that special so I'm not going to put that unique on there.
I want everyone to be able to use whatever name they like email on the other hand is something that
should be unique to each user so we can actually enforce that by using the at Unique directive.
Perfect.
Now we have the user definition that's way more real world.
I'm going to save data model Dohm graph well and I am going to redeploy the application.
Once again it is going to show us all of the changes it made.
And right here there is just one.
It's updated the email field the field has become unique.
Perfect Now that we have the user type definition in place let's go ahead and actually create a user
with an e-mail before we move on and worry about our other types like post and comment.
So I'm going to head over into graft.
Playground we have that sitting right here for the Prisma graph API.
I'm going to refresh that schema.
And over here for create user what I'm going to do is try to create a user with the e-mail that I've
already set up now this should fail because once again this email already exists.
I've already added that user it's sitting right here.
So if I were to rerun this what do I get.
I get an error.
A unique constraint would be violated on user.
And that tells us the exact field that's talking about it's talking about the email field.
So this error tells us that we cannot create a user with this e-mail because it already exists for a
different user and all emails must be unique.
Perfect.
So now we have a way to really structure and manage our users.
Obviously this user could change their email to victim to at example dot com.
And then once again it would work as expected.
As long as they're not exact matches.
The last thing I want to do in this video is set up a nother type.
We're going to set up and configure the post type then we'll be all done and we'll move on to the next
video will you.
We'll set up and configure the comment type so pay close attention because you're essentially going
to be doing what I do from here to the end.
In the next video over in the old schema engraft you file we have our post typed down below and to start
we're just going to worry about the fields with scalar types so we have ID title body and published.
We want to bring all four of those over to the brand new files are right here and new type posts like
we had before.
We're going to have idea of the type ID and we will use the unique directive here to make that unique
for IDs you have to use at Unique with Prisma.
Otherwise you'll get an error and then we're going to set up a title that will be a noun and nullable
string.
There's no need to use at unique here that doesn't really make much sense and we have body a non-negligible
string once again not using unique.
And finally we have published.
So we have published and I'm going to have that be a non nullable boolean also.
So these are all the fields with scalar types.
Now we can actually focus on setting up relationships.
I can set up the comments relationship because the comments type doesn't exist.
You'll create that in the next video.
But I can set up the relationship between the post and the user.
So let's get that done.
We're going to be setting up a post's field on user and R.A.F. posts and we're going to be setting up
the author field on the post which has links to a user.
So over here we're going to have the exact same stuff on the user we want posts it is going to be an
array and non indelible array and the elements inside of there will be non nullable posts and then down
below for posts.
We are going to add the author field that a link to a non nullable user.
Excellent.
So now that we have all of this in place we have users set up we have post completely set up and we
have the relationship between them defined.
Now notice we didn't do anything special here to set up that relationship.
We used the exact tools that we already know about.
I'm going to save data model dot graph QOL and we're going to go ahead and deploy our application once
again right here.
We're going to get way more changes that we've gotten in the past.
So if I scroll up real quick we can see exactly what this deployment did for post it first created the
post and then it created all of the fields associated with the post for user.
It just set up that relationship right here.
It created that post field.
Now you'll notice that for a post and for user we have type next.
Each of them down below.
We also have this other thing post to user and this has relationship excuse me relation instead of type
so post to user is automatically generated by Prisma allowing it to set up the necessary tables to create
a relationship between users and post.
Let's see what all of that looks like by grabbing all the new tables over inside of PGE admin.
So over NPG admin I'm going to right click tables for our database.
I'm going to refresh and we're going to see that two new tables have been created.
First up we have as you might have expected the post table the post table contains all of the data for
the individual post but we also have this underscore post to user table.
This was automatically generated and this is where it stores the IDs that link posts to users so we
can say that post with the ID of one is associated with the user of the idea of three by storing those
right inside of here.
Now what I'd like to do is actually test all of this out by creating a new post for this user.
So I'm going to grab this user's I.D. I can just double click the field to bring up the little editor
I'm going to copy it to the clipboard and hit cancel since I don't actually want to change the fields
value.
Then we're going to move over to graft Well playground.
I'm going to refresh that schema and we can explore all of the new stuff available to us.
So right here under queries we have a query for getting multiple posts and a query forgetting individual
posts under mutations.
We have all of the new mutations for our post.
We have create post update posts delete posts and others.
And finally under subscriptions we have one new post subscription.
So just like with user all of these were auto rated for us based solely off this very small what 8 line
type definition.
All right let's go ahead and actually use one of those mutations.
We're going to use create post.
Now this is where things start to get a bit interesting.
We can see that with Create post we get a post back that's expected we get back the new post we create.
But when it comes to the data we can see that yes we have titlebar and published all there as expected.
We also have author though.
So author is where we set up the relationship.
So all posts have to have an author that wrote then.
So we need to set up this relationship when creating a post just like we did before.
But if we actually click this we can see that it results in us either creating a new user when we create
this post or connecting it to an existing user.
So right here what we're going to do is use connect to connect it to an existing user.
Now we can connect it to an existing user by anything that makes that user unique.
So I could create a new post and say I want it to go to the user with the idea of 4 or I could create
a new post and say it belongs to the user with an email of Andrew an example doc.
Anything that makes the user unique.
So not their name.
For example.
Now let's go ahead and actually use all of this.
It can be really tricky to navigate the schema documentation especially when we have to click so far
and we get really nested.
But when you see it in action it's really not going to be that much different from what we're already
comfortable doing.
So it's not that out right here we're going to create a new tab.
This is where we will define our new post.
It is a mutation we will use the Create post mutation that has just been auto generated for us.
We are indeed going to set up arguments as it takes them and we will also set up our selection set for
the newly created post.
I'm going to grab its ID.
I'm going to grab the title and I'm also going to grab the other fields body published and I'll even
grab something from the author.
I'll grab the author's ID and I'll grab the author's name.
Perfect.
Now when it comes to the arguments why do we have to provide We have to provide that one argument data.
This is indeed an object and we're going to start by setting up the things that are required.
We have to provide the title body and published.
Let's start there.
Title equals Prisma post.
Then we have body.
Body can be empty.
And finally we have published published is going to be either true or false.
I'm going to leave this one unpublished so I'll use falls from here.
Once again we have to provide author which we saw over in the schema author itself is an object.
So we're going to set it up as such in here we can now either create or we can connect.
We are going to connect to an existing user by setting up on Connect either the ID or the email field.
I'm going to link by ID since that's what I copy to the clipboard so I'll set up ID right here.
Passing any ID value as a string.
Excellent.
Now all of this might seem like a little much.
It's quite a bit of work to provide author then connect then Id It would be nicer if there is something
like Author ID.
Don't worry about that just yet because we're not actually going to be making almost any graph QOL API
requests from GRATHWOHL playground like this.
We'll be using a tool that makes this a bit easier when it comes to interacting with Prisma from no
J.S..
For now though let's go ahead and run this and make sure it's at least working at a basic level.
If I fire off this operation what do I get.
I have data.
I have create posts and I have everything I asked for about that post.
Abbott's idea.
I have the title.
I have the body I have the published status I have the author's ID and I have the author's name.
Now let's go ahead and explore the data just to get an idea for what this data structure looks like.
Over in PGE admin We are going to crack open that posts tables.
I'm just going to write click it with a view at it.
Data.
I'm going to view all rows and what do I have here.
I'm going to end up having a single row and you can see we have the ID of the title.
We have a body and we have published all as expected.
Now when it comes to linking the two linking the user with the post that happens in post to user.
So let's view that table as well.
I'm going to Right-Click it go to view edit data and view all rows and here we're gonna see that we
just have one record.
We have an ID for this record.
Then we have the A and B values.
This is the post ID.
This is the user ID.
Actually I believe it's the other way around.
Either way by just using these two values it creates a relationship between those two entities.
Between a post and a user.
So at this point I don't expect all of this relational data to make sense with Prisma just yet.
And if you start to explore some of the other mutations you're going to see that things can get pretty
complex pretty quickly.
Don't worry we're going to dive into how all of this works in detail well for an hour just going through
the process of setting up the basic types we need before we can even really play around with how Prisma
functions and why it's useful.
So that's where we're going to stop for this one.
We've set up our user type and we set up the post type in the next video it's going to be up to you
to set up the comment type and that will be a challenge video.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.