In this challenge video it's going to be up to you to integrate comments into the Prisma API.
So just like we did for posts in the last video we're going to be bringing that type definition over
to the spiled deploying the changes and then messing around with it inside of graphical playground down
below.
The few challenge comments that outline exactly what I'd like you to do.
And once again the big picture goal is to add comments to the Prisma API.
Well let's go through all three steps.
Step one is to copy the comment type definition over from schema dot graphical.
And once again remember you have to mark the idea as unique.
Everything else can stay the same.
We already have the relationships set up so we can just bring those fields over.
Step two is to redeploy the Prisma application.
So we've made changes to this file from step 1.
We have to use the correct command from the command line to actually deploy those changes.
Step three is probably where you're going to spend the most time.
This is where we're actually going to test things out.
So I've broken this into four little pieces.
First part if we're going to make a comment on a post that post has to be published.
So step A.
Update our only post to be published then for forby what I want you to do is create a new user this
new user is going to leave a comment on that one and only post.
We actually have.
And in order to explore the new mutations given to you remember you can just refer to the schema for
usage.
It's really important to get comfortable navigating the schema and actually being able to use it to
generate your operations so you get a little more practice with this in the challenge as well.
And finally we have part D you want to fetch all of the comments.
In this case you only created one.
The one comment you created in step C. But you should indeed see that comment showing up and for each
comment just include the comment text and also grab the author's name.
All right.
Take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Feel free to refer to anything we did in the last video since we went through a very similar process.
When you're done do make sure to test your work.
That's actually one of the bigger pieces to this challenge.
So once again upon the video when you're done click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with step 1.
We're going to grab our comment type from schema data graph.
Well I have that sitting right here.
I'm going to grab all six lines exactly as they are.
Copy them to the clipboard and bring them over to our data model file.
I'll paste it right down below the post type and the only change we need to make is to the ID field.
Remember all of our IDs in Prisma need to be marked as unique using the at Unique directive.
Excellent.
All of the other three fields can stay the same text is still going to be a string author is still going
to link to a user and post is still going to link to a post.
Now that brings us to step 2 the easiest of all of the steps.
All we need to do for this one is to one save our file and to run Prisma deploy from inside of the project.
This is going to make sure that the database gets updated to conform to the schema that we've currently
created.
So right here we've added comment on.
And I would expect all of the changes to be related to that down below under changes.
I have a bunch of changes related to the comment type since we're creating it for the first time.
And they also have other changes that are related to the associations with comment end users and then
down below comment and posts now that we've deployed the application we can move on to step three which
is actually where we're going to spend most of our time working with graphs.
Well playground to perform a series of steps.
Step one we want to update our only post to be published.
We can currently get the post ID using either the users or the post query right here I have users all
set up.
I could choose to just grab the posts for a user as well.
And in this case I could just grab the ID for all of the posts and if I run that I can see we have the
one post for our first user.
This is the only post we have and this is the one that we're going to be updating to published and it's
the one we're going to be leaving a comment on.
Now I don't have a update post mutation so I can go ahead and create one right here under a new tab.
Nutation update post.
And in order to figure out what update post takes we're going to go ahead and move into the schema for
the moment though down below we know we're probably going to get a post back so we can grab the ID for
that post.
I'm also going to grab the title the body and of course the published status.
Now we can open up the schema and figure out what it takes to use that update post mutation it's sitting
right here.
Update post I'm going to click that we can see pass it two arguments.
Data which includes the updates and where which allows us to figure out which post we want to update.
And we saw the exact same thing when we worked with Update user data took in the fields you wanted to
change.
In this case we changed the name and where it took in the ID of the user.
We were trying to alter.
So let's do the same thing for our posts right here.
I am going to pass in a where this is an object we're going to filter by id and I've already copied
that ID to the clipboard.
The other thing we're going to provide is data.
Data also an object takes all of the fields that we want to change.
And in this case we are just going to change the published field.
I'm going to change published from false over to true.
Excellent.
Now we can actually go ahead and run things some of that click that play button we can see that the
post was indeed published and now we're ready to move on to part B here we're going to create a new
user and that user is going to end up leaving a comment on this post.
I already have a create user mutation sitting over here on the left.
Oh I'm going to do is change the name and the e-mail.
I'm going to use myself so I'll use Andrew as the name then down below for the email I'll use Andrew
an example dot com if I actually fire this off it should work as expected and perfect.
We now have the user created this can bring us on to part C we want to create a comment for that one
post.
So how are we going to do that.
Well we're going to do that with discreate comment nutation.
So overunder our mutations list we have create comment though I do need to refresh the schema first.
Now if I open it up we should have create comment and it is indeed sitting right here and we can see
exactly what it takes to create a comet.
We pass in the data object we get back the comment.
And if we expand data we can see that we need to pass and obviously the text.
But I also have to pass an author and post fields.
This comment needs to be associated with an author and the comment needs to be made on a particular
post.
Now for author.
Once again we can create an author or connect an existing one and the same thing is true with post.
I can create a post or connect an existing one.
We're going to be using connect for both.
Since you've already created the user and you've already created the post so let's go ahead and actually
knock this out.
One last stab right here.
We're going to set up a mutation and this one is for create comment.
Now create comment is going to take the data arguments I'm going to set that up.
I don't actually break it out onto its own line down below just to keep things nice and organized.
This is indeed an object and on here we're going to add and all of those fields.
First up what is the comment text.
Well for this one I can just say something simple like a comment from Prisma graphic.
Well perfect.
Now we have to provide the author field end of the post field.
So for author which is an object.
What I'm going to do is set up the connect property connect takes an object and there provide the ID
of the author.
We want to link to.
So right here we already have that ID.
That's the one I copied to the clipboard from our create user mutation.
It's the ID right here.
I'm going to paste that in.
And then we can add another field alongside of text and alongside of author.
This one to link to the correct post.
So we're going to have post which is also going to be an object in there we also have Connect which
is an object.
And then in here this is where we have the ID of the post.
We want to link to now for our purposes we did indeed grab that post ID.
It's sitting right over here so I'm going to copy that to the clipboard.
Bring it over to our create comment mutation and paste it right in.
Now the only thing we have to do is provide our selection set.
So we get a comment back.
Let's go ahead and get some stuff related to that comment.
I'm going to grab the comments ID.
I'm going to grab the text for the comment and I will also grab some information about the author.
I'll grab the author's ID and the author's name.
Perfect.
No I know that's quite the mutation.
There's a lot going on there and it seems way more complex than it needs to be once again.
Just bear with me for the next several videos when we actually integrate this into node.
The syntax we used will become a whole lot simpler.
For the moment though we do want to test that this actually works.
I'm going to click that play button and there we go.
We can see that the comment was indeed created.
We have our comment Id and the comment text.
And we also have the information expected about the comment author.
That brings us to the final step.
D.
Fetch all comments include their text and the author's name.
So I'm going to go ahead and knock that out with one final operation over here.
We're going to add a new tab into the mix.
I'm going to set up a query in for this one we're going to be using one of our queries if we want to
fetch all of the comments we're going to be using the comments query.
Now the comments does indeed take a whole bunch of arguments but they're all completely optional.
You'll notice there is no exclamation mark after the types for any of them so none are required.
And we're not going to provide any.
All we're going to do is set up the operation in name then we're going to go right into our selection
set.
What do we want from each comment.
I'm going to grab the ID.
I'm going to grab the text field and then I'll grab some information about the author the ID and the
name.
Perfect.
If we fire this off we should get the expected data back right here.
Everything looks good.
We have our data property on that object we have our comments property.
And this is an array of objects since we only have one comment in the database we only have one object
showing up.
We have our ID and text and we also have some of the associated data.
So there we go.
We now have a way to store real data in the database using graphs.
Q Well we've seen this work with not just individual types but also with relationships between our types.
And we've also explored the Prisma API that's provided to us.
Now here's the interesting thing.
So far we've only interacted with Prisma via graphical playground.
But when it comes to actually integrating this into node j s we're not going to need to manually type
all of this stuff out.
We're going to start to see how that's possible in the very next video which I am super excited to get
to for the moment though let's go ahead and one delete all of those challenge comments end to save the
file.
All right.
That is it for this video.
Let's start taking some concrete steps towards using the Prisma API from a node.
J.S. Back-End.