In this video you're going to start integrating noted at J S and Prisma together.
Remember the big picture goal here is to allow our node J.S. application to read and write from the
post gresse database.
Currently the Prisma Graph API can indeed read and write from the post gresse database.
So all we need to do is figure out how to allow node to interact with this API once node can interact
with this API node will be able to read and write from the post gresse database.
Now to get all of this done we are going to have to do a little bit of configuration.
So that's what we're going to spend this video on.
Then in the following videos we'll actually see how we can perform all of these operations from node
J.S. itself.
I'm excited to get to it.
So let's get started configuring our app to start with what I'm going to do is close all of my open
editors and collapse all of my uncollapsed directories.
Now here we have our graphical basic's folder and we have our graph Cuil Prisma folder.
What we're going to do is copy everything inside of graph.
Well basics into the well Prisma folder.
So I want to add these five things along side of the Prisma directory itself.
We're not going to be making any further changes to the graphics Well BASIX project because I want to
leave that as a reference for us in the future.
So what are we going to do.
I'm going to start with packaged at Jason Billal and then going to shift click up to node modules.
I can right click and copy them then down below.
We're going to right click the well Prisma folder itself and paste those in.
Now we can close all of the open editors and collapse all of our directories once again and inside of
you well basics we should now have the node modules folder are Prisma project folder which we had before
the source directory with all of our other files and folders.
The DOT babbel RC config file package lock Jason and package Jason itself.
If you have all of these 6 showing up inside of graph Prisma then you're ready to continue on from here
what I'd like to do is pull up the documentation for one of the two libraries that we're going to be
setting up and configuring in this video.
The first library that I want to talk about I'm going to Google in a new tab.
It is called Prisma hyphen binding Prisma binding gives us bindings for node j.
S..
So in essence it gives us a set of node J.S. methods that we can use to interact with our Prisma graphical
API.
So if we actually click on this first result which is the repository page we can take a look at one
of the examples they have in the read me file down below.
If I scroll down a little bit on this page I'm looking for the slightly longer example here they do
two things.
First up they can figure there are no japes application to actually link to that end point.
We'll talk about how to do that very shortly then what they do is they actually interact with the API.
So here you can see they're using methods like Prisma dot queried dot user and Prisma dot nutation.
Create user to interact with the Prisma graphical API every time they do this from node they're actually
reading and writing from the database itself.
This is exactly what we want to do.
Now the Prisma binding library is created by the same folks who created Prisma itself and it is a must
have tool when working with Prisma and node j.
S..
So what we're going to start with is the process of actually installing and setting this up.
Let's head over to Visual Studio code and install this tool down below.
I'm going to start by using C.D to switch into the graphical hyphen Prisma folder.
Make sure that if you are already in the Prisma directory use C-D dot dot to come up a folder to this
directory.
And from here we're going to use NPM install to install this library.
So we're going to be installing Prisma hyphen binding at the latest version which is indeed two point
one.
Point one.
Perfect.
Now we can actually run this installation command and once it's done.
Well actually before it's even done what we're going to do is create one new file in the source directory.
We're going to call this one Prisma dot J.
S. And this is where we're going to store all of the code required to actually connect our node j s
app to the Prisma graphical API.
Now we can actually inport the library we just installed and start connecting to the Prisma API.
So to start let's use an import statement.
The one thing we're going to be grabbing off the Prisma binding library is a named export and it's called
uppercase P Prisma.
This is a constructor function we can use to create a connection to a Prisma and point.
Next up we're grabbing that from the library we just installed that is Prisma hyphen binding.
Excellent.
And now down below what we can do is actually create that connection.
So what we're going to do is call this constructor function and we want to store the return values to
ongoing to create a lower case P Prisma constant right here.
Lowercase P Prisma as a cost.
And then what we do is we call that constructor function with of course the new operator.
So that is new Prisma this time referencing the thing we imported.
And this is nothing more than a constructor function that takes a single object argument.
This is our options object and this is where we configure no J.S. to connect it to the correct Prisma
endpoint.
And there are two things that we have to provide.
The first thing that we have to provide is the type deaths.
So we need to provide the type definitions for the end point that we're connecting to.
This is necessary so the Prisma binding library can generate all of the various methods needed.
So it doesn't always come with create user.
It only has create user if you actually have a user type that Prisma is going to interact with.
If we have comments we'll also have a create comment method on Prisma dot notation and if we add posts
into the mix we'll also have things like Prisma mutation Dom create post update post and delete post
all of the same stuff we're seeing in graphical playground so we'll learn how to provide that in just
a second.
The other thing we have to provide is also the end point and point also provided as a string specifies
the actual u r l where the Prisma graphical API lives.
Now the end point is the easy one right here.
We can just provide local host Colan for 4 6 6.
You're going to want to use the correct end point for you.
That is whatever you have over here.
If you have the IP address because you're on Windows you also want to provide that over here when setting
up the endpoint property.
Now the other thing we need to provide the typedef is a bit more complex for this one we actually need
to introduce that second tool I mentioned.
We would be installing and configuring.
Now it's a common mistake to try to use the Prisma data model diagram graph Q L file as the value for
typedef.
But this is not quite correct because think about it.
We know that with our Prisma graphical API we have the comments queery accessible.
We were able to run that and actually get our data back.
Do you see the comments queery listed anywhere inside of here.
And the answer is no.
This just represents our data model.
It does not contain all of our type definitions.
That is auto generated by Prisma based off of the contents of data model Dohm graphs.
Well the only reason the comments queery even exists is because we have the comment type defined inside
of here so it's actually a different file and what we're going to do is configure a tool that's going
to fetch that file.
Then we can just reference that file by its path right here and we'll be all connected to the Prisma
API.
Let's go ahead and pull up the repository page for this second tool as well.
The second one we're going to be installing and configuring is called a graph Cuil hyphen see ally.
And this is just a little command line interface.
It gives us about a dozen or so different commands for performing common tasks and one of those common
tasks is fetching the schema for a given API.
We need to do that so we can provide it right inside of our Prisma configuration object.
Now how are we going to do that.
Well we're going to do the exact same thing that Kraft UL playground does.
GRATHWOHL playground is clearly able to fetch the application schema since it's showing all of the queries
all of the mutations and all of the subscriptions we just need a way to be able to do that from our
project itself.
And this tool provides that in one of the commands it offers.
If we scroll down just a little bit we can see all of the commands.
It gives us the only one we care about is this one right here.
It is the graph.
Q Well get schema command.
This is what's going to allow us to fetch the schema and save it as a file in our project.
Let's go ahead and actually install this tool from the command line.
I'll start by clearing the output.
Then we're going to run NPM install with the library name once again that's graphical hyphen see Ally
and we'll be grabbing the latest version at two point sixteen point four.
Excellent.
I'm going to go ahead and fire that installation command off and once it's done there are two things
that we're going to end up doing.
We're going to add a single new file into the project and we're going to set up a single new script
in package Donte.
Jason the script is going to be very simple or it is going to run that and get schema command and the
file we create is going to be a little configuration file telling get schema where it can find the schema
that it should be fetching and where in the project it should be saving that file.
Now you'll notice that in newer versions of NPM we get all sorts of great information about the vulnerabilities
of the modules we installed.
And this is just an example of one.
A lot of the other modules are going to have something similar.
You can see we have one moderate and one critical vulnerability.
Currently there's nothing we can do about these.
The graphical see Ally is not indeed responsible for these directly.
These come from subdue so dependencies of our dependencies and they'll get fixed once those sub dependencies
actually update.
For now there's nothing to worry about with these.
Well we're going to do from here is follow those two steps that I just outlined.
We are going to create that file and then we're going to set up that new script.
Let's go ahead and start by creating that file.
Now this file needs to live in the root of our project.
So in the root of the graph.
Well hyphen Prisma directory AMANOR right click that folder create new file and this one is called Dot
graphic QOL config.
This is going to be a Jason configuration file where we provide those two pieces of information.
Where does this schema live and where should it be saved.
Now before I add anything inside of this file I do want to tell Visual Studio code that this file should
indeed be treated as Jason when it comes to syntax highlighting and formatting.
You can do that via the command palette if you forget the keyboard shortcut to bring that up it's always
right here.
View command palette and you should be able to find the keyboard shortcut for your operating system.
Once you have the command palette open with this file indeed in focus and the background you can search
for language.
And what we're looking for is this first one change language mode.
It might not be the first one for you but that is the one we want to run.
And when we click that it's going to ask us to pick the language from a list of languages.
There are all sorts of different languages that are currently supported in Visual Studio code.
We are going to pick Jason that is the format we are currently working with from here.
We're going to create that root object and now we can start the configuration process.
So the first thing we're going to do is set up a root property called projects.
We only have one project but we're still required to set up this project's object on here.
We define the name for just that one project we have.
I'm going to call this Prisma and then we define the actual configuration for that project.
So the first thing we're going to provide is the schema a path property this is going to be the path
where the file should be saved.
Now in this case we currently don't have a decent place for that.
What's common though is to create a new folder in the source directory.
This new folder ends up getting called generated and this is where we store generated code like the
File we're about to download.
This is a practice you'll see amongst a wide range of different graphs you present projects.
So we're going to stick with that same approach right here.
We have to provide that path from the root of our project.
So we start by going into the source folder then a forward slash generated then forward slash we can
pick a file name it's common to call this one Prisma dot graph.
Well this is where we're going to have the actual type definitions saved and this path is the same path.
We'll end up using over here in just a few moments.
Now that's not all we have to configure inside of here.
We also have to specify the end point in this case.
For us it has localhost 4 4 6 6.
If you're on Windows you might have an IP address right here.
We need to provide that over in our configuration as well.
And to do that we start with an extensions property.
So right here alongside of schema path extensions now extensions itself allows us to define all sorts
of things we are looking to define our end points.
So we set up an end points property and then inside of endpoints we define an end point for our default
project.
So default is the property name and the actual You Arel is that you are well we have over here now you
do have to specify the protocol.
So for us we are currently working in just HTP not HTP as colon.
Forward slash forward slash and then for me it is a local host Colan 4 4 6 6.
Perfect.
And there we go.
This file is now all configured.
We can save that and we're not going to be touching this one for a while if ever over inside of Prisma
J.S. we now have to link to that file that was just saved.
So it's going to end up being the same exact path we have source a forward slash generated then a forward
slash Prisma dot graph.
Q Well excellent.
And there we go.
Everything is now configured.
The last step to the process is to set up that script in package datt.
Jason so over here we are going to create a new script.
I'm going to call this script something along the lines of get schema so get hyphen schema and the actual
command we're going to run as a command provided by graft.
You will see ally right here.
We start with graft Cuil then a space we are going to be using the Get hyphen schema command they provide
and we do have to provide the name of the project.
Now once again we only have a single project Prisma.
So that is the name we're going to provide that happens via the p argument.
So right here Prisma excellent.
Now what we're going to do is actually run this script and we're going to see the schema stored in the
generated directory down below.
I am going to use clear to clear the terminal output than NPM run followed by the script name that is
get heighth and schema exactly as we specified right here.
When I run this it's going to connect to that end point.
It's going to fetch the schema and it is going to store it in our application file and we can see that
a new file was indeed generated and I actually expand this.
We can take a look and we can see that this file is much bigger than the data model that graph you Al
file we created everything necessary for the Prisma graph Q L API to work lives inside of here.
So for example we have a create user nutation that's defined over here.
We have the users query that's defined in this file as well.
And if you scroll through it you can see it's a lot of auto generated code and we're never going to
make changes to this file.
This is not a file that we ever edit.
The only time this file changes is if we rerun that script and fetch the latest schema.
So if I were to make a change to the Prisma API for example adding another type into the mix or maybe
adding a field onto one of these types we would deploy using Prisma deploy and then we would actually
fetch the updated schema running the get schema script again.
And nowhere you don't have to memorize that process.
As always we are going to move through that process in the course.
For now everything is completely set up.
We have Prisma binding installed.
It has everything it needs to actually connect it to the API and in the next video we're going to go
through some various examples of how we can now interact with the graph Cual API provided by Prisma
right from inside of our node.
JS file that's the topic of the next video.
So let's get to it.
I'll see you in the next one.