You now have Prisma binding all set up and in this video we're actually going to read and write from
the database right here inside of Node.
Jay ass so we're going to spend some time looking at what exactly comes back on this Prisma object.
We'll see how we can use that to perform all of the graphical operations.
We want to.
Now the cool thing is that all of this is actually going to read and write from the database for the
moment.
We're going to work through some examples in this file just right down below.
But once we understand how it works we'll actually be integrating it into our resolvers for both queries
and subscriptions as well as mutations.
Now in this video we are going to start to use asynchronous javascript which is listed as a pre-req
for this class.
So remember in order to take this course you need to know about node and javascript that includes Asynchronous
JavaScript So things like callbacks things like promises and things like async Oh wait if you don't
know about these three things you should go ahead and learn about them before continuing on with the
Course because I am going to assume that you understand how they work.
Now maybe you've read a book or a blog post on them.
That's fine.
Maybe you took my beginner Noad course which covers all three.
That's fine too.
Or maybe you took a different course by a different instructor and learned about these.
That's also OK.
As you know about them and then you're ready to continue on.
Now I know someone's going to ask why not cover them here.
The point is that all three of these are fundamental javascript features.
They're not specific to graph Q L in any way and I don't want to take away from time spent on graphs
to cover basic javascript so that's why I've made the choice to not cover them here and list them as
pre-req for the class instead.
Now that's not to say I'm not going to talk about how we're using them.
As always I'm going to describe what I'm doing in the code in great detail.
I'm just not going to talk about their core underlying functionality.
All right let's go ahead and jump in on this.
Prisma object.
There are four key properties that we're going to be using.
We have Prisma dot queery.
This contains all of the queries we have access to.
We have a Prisma dot mutation.
This contains all of the mutations we have access to.
And we also have a Prisma daat subscription which as you can probably guess contains all of the subscriptions
we have access to.
There's also one more.
This is Prisma that exists.
This contains some handy utility methods which we'll be exploring later in this section in this video
in particular where it is going to start with square one.
We're going to start by exploring Prisma query and figuring out how we can fetch data from the database
right here inside of no.
J.S. Prisma dumb query itself is nothing more than an object on that object.
There are a set of methods available to you.
There is one method for every query that the API supports.
So for example if I go over to grab Q Well playground and open up the schema there is a method on that
Prisma query object for all of these queries and we access it by name.
So if I want to fetch the comments I can use the comments method if I want to fetch an individual post.
I can use the post method I want to go ahead and fetch some users.
So right here I will use Prisma dot query dot users where the method name matches up exactly with the
query name.
So I have users sitting right here now with this in place we can go ahead and call it as a function
since it is one and we can talk about the arguments that users accepts all of our Prisma methods take
two arguments.
The first are your operation arguments and the second is your selection set.
Now we know that for some operations like our mutations they do require operation arguments.
We have to provide data when creating a user but for our users query the operation arguments are completely
optional.
So we are going to go ahead and ignore them by not passing any in.
So right here as the first argument I am going to pass in null.
Now the second argument to all of our Prisma binding methods is the selection set.
So I'm asking for all of the users.
But what do I want about each user over here for example.
We're getting the user's ID their name their email and the idea of any posts they're associated with.
We can go ahead and provide our selection set as the second argument and this is represented as a string.
In here we open and close a set of curly braces and we list out all of the things we want just like
we list them out in the curly braces.
Over here we can do all of this on a single line so I can say that for each user I want their ID and
their name.
For example I can also choose to grab their email.
So now we have a completely valid operation.
We are asking for the users and we've provided our selection set for each user We want all of their
scalar fields ID name and email.
Now what comes back from the user's function.
Well what comes back is actually a promise.
Which means that need to use either then or catch to wait for the promise to resolve.
This is an asynchronous operation so it takes time to go off and make a request to the graph queue out
Prisma API and it takes time for a Prisma to make a request to the underlying database.
So we do not get the data back right here.
Konst users equals whatever comes back.
This is not going to work as expected.
We actually get a promise back so we are going to wait for this promise to resolve by using the then
method.
So right here then passing in our callback function.
This is the function that's going to get called when the user's query is done and it gets called with
a single argument.
The data that came back from the query.
So the data argument is basically the same as what we see on the right hand side over here.
It represents the response from the API.
So for our purposes let's go ahead and just dump this day that to the council.
Although later on we'll be integrating all of this into our resolvers files console dialog and data
is going to get the job done.
Now before we actually run the project we have to make a couple of small changes.
First up the protocol is required with the end point.
So we want to put HTP colon forward slash forward slash upfront.
The other quick change we need to make is to index Dhananjay.
Because currently this file isn't even going to run.
So in index dot J.S. I'm going to inport Prisma Dhananjay s just so the file actually executes right
here.
I'm going to add an import statement on we're not grabbing any default or named exports so we can leave
off our exports list and the from keyword.
We can just go right to the file name the file We're trying to import is in the same directory as indexed.
J S.
So don't forward slash Prisma is going to get the job done.
Now this in effect is just running the file and that's all we want.
We just want misfiled to run.
So it actually executes our query and dumps our data to the console with those changes in place.
We can now head over to the terminal and drawn NPM start to actually get our program up and running.
I'm going to go ahead and fire that off.
The program has started and right here what do we have.
We have an array of objects.
So since we have queried for users we're going to get an array back and each object represents a user.
So we have victim 1 victim 2 and Andrew.
Each object has those three properties we have ID we have name and we have e-mail.
Now we could also change up our selection set to change the values that come back.
For example if I remove email and save the file gnomon is going to restart and we're going to see that
property is now got for each user We just have the ID and the name.
So the selection set is very important.
It determines the structure of the data that comes back which is exactly what we saw over and graphical
playground as well.
So there we go.
We now have our very first query in place actually fetching data out of the post gress database right
inside of our node.
J.S. app..
We can also query for related data.
For example I can grab some information about the posts for all of these users just like we do over
here.
Here we grabbed the ID for every post that belongs to a user.
Let's do the same thing in no.
J.S..
So we grab ID we grab name then we grab posts right after posts.
We have to open and close a another set of curly braces and in here we provide the selection set for
posts.
Let's say that we wanted the ID and the title for every post that belongs to the user.
Now if we go ahead and save Prisma dot J as we're going to see our data structure changes a little bit
down below for the first user we have the posts array.
It does indeed have an object inside of there and for the second and third users we can see that they
have an empty array since they have no posts which is indeed correct.
The reason that we're not seeing the actual object data for this post is because the council is just
hiding some of the output to prevent it from becoming too complex.
We can fix that by switching up our console dialog call right here inside of the arguments list for
console dialog.
I'm going to call Jason in upper case dot string if I.
This is an easy way to convert a javascript object or array into Jason data.
And that's going to allow us to customize how it's formatted in the output we pass in three arguments.
The first is the data.
So we have our data object.
The second is what's called a replacer function.
This allows us to remove and replace properties.
We don't want to do any of that.
We just want to see our data as is.
So we can pass in undefined for that second argument and the third argument allows us to determine how
many spaces we want to use when indenting our Jason common values would be 2 or 4.
I'm just going to stick with for now if we save Prisma.
J.S. once again we're going to see that our data is much easier to read.
Here we have our second and third users neither of them having any posts and if I roll up we have our
first user.
This one does have that Post's property and there is a single post inside of there.
That post has the ID and title exactly as specified over here.
So using Prisma binding from node j as we can do anything we would be able to do from graft.
Playground.
The advantage though is that it's actually inside of our code so we can actually use it to build out
our app.
That's where we're going to stop for this video before we go.
I do want you to run through a quick challenge querying for some other data down below.
Your challenge is to use Prisma binding to fetch all of the comments in the database right here big
picture goal fecche comments using Prisma binding.
Step 1 you want to use the comments query right inside of Node.
J.S. to fetch all of the comments for each comment.
Grab the ID and the text and also grab some of the associated data grab some information about the comment
author.
In this case the ID and the name will suffice.
Step two test your work by saving this file and making sure you actually see the data down below.
You can use the same trick I used here with Jason docstring if I to format the data and make it easier
to see those nested data structures.
All right.
Take some time to knock that out.
Test your work when you're done come back and click play
how that go let's go ahead and kick things off up above by using Prisma dot queery dot right here comments.
So we have that comments a query in our schema which means we have a comments method on the query object.
Now we know that comments doesn't require any operation arguments.
I'm going to pass in Knol though we know we do have to provide our selection set.
What do we want about each commet.
I'm going to go ahead and provide my selection set right here in curly braces.
I want the comment Id I want the text value for the comment and I also want some information about the
comments author.
I'm going to choose to grab the ID and the name for the author.
Perfect.
Now with this in place we do have to use the then method to actually wait for the data to come back.
We provide our callback function and then we get the data as the first and only argument from here.
We're just going to dump it to the console so console dot log.
I'll use Jason docstring if I once again passing in those three arguments.
We have our data we have undefined for the second argument and we have our indentation for the third.
I'm going to indent by two spaces once again.
And now we should actually be able to test our work.
I'm going to save the file and view the terminal output.
Now we're going to have two separate values printing right.
Here we have our array for comments.
So I have my one comment.
The text for the comment was a comment from a Prisma graph.
Well I had my ID and I also have the author property with some information about the author.
Here I have the authors ID and name all as expected based off of these selections set I provided.
So there we go.
We now know how to query data right inside of node j ass.
We're going to continue on in the next video by looking at how we can use Prisma mutation and we're
going to explore how we can pass in operation arguments.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.