With Prisma Dom queery out of the way in this video you're going to learn how to use the methods available
on Prisma dot notation to perform mutations from right here inside of node j ass allowing you to create
update and delete data stored in the database.
So to kick things off let's go ahead and comment out the two queery calls we already have.
I am going to leave the code in place to serve as a reference but I don't want it to print every single
time we run the program.
The output is already going to be hard enough to actually read through.
So let's go ahead and kick things off by using Prisma dot mutation.
Now just like Prisma queery Prisma Dopp mutation is an object on there we have a method for every single
mutation available to you if you forget exactly what you have access to.
You can always pull up the schema in graphical playground.
Here we have mutations for creating Common's users in posts for updating comments users in posts and
for deleting comments users and posts so we can use any of these from right inside of our application
to actually make data changes.
For this example I'm going to go ahead and use create post to create a brand new post for a given user.
The arguments that get passed into your nutation methods are the same as the arguments that get passed
into your query methods.
The first argument is where we put our operation arguments.
The second argument is where we put our selection set.
Now we know that with the queries we did not need to provide any operation arguments and we know that
with our mutations we typically do.
For example if I want to create a user I have to provide some data about the user to be created and
if I want to create a post I have to provide some data about the post itself and some data about the
author that should own this post.
So we need to do all of that same stuff over here while we pass in to the first argument is an object.
This object is where we provide all of our operation arguments.
Now in the end of the day we're going to have one root argument data and we're going to have all of
our scalar fields right on there so we can set up a title for this new post.
I'll call this something along the lines of my new graph Cuil post is live.
Then we can set up the body for this particular post and for the body we are going to have a string
value as well and I'll use something like.
You can find the new course here.
After that we're going to set up the published value.
Should this post be published or not.
I'm going to go ahead and say that it is published so well set published to true.
And the last thing we have to provide is the author property.
So we have to determine if we want to create a new author.
That is the owner of this post.
Or be connected to an existing author.
And that's the approach we're going to take.
We'll be using correct and we are connecting it by id and then right here we are going to paste in the
ID for an author.
Now down below I actually have an idea for an author in the output.
I have the ID for the author with my name Andrew.
So I am going to grab this ID copy it to the clipboard and paste that right here as the string value.
You're more than welcome to use what ever author ID you like.
Feel free to grab any from your database and use that.
Now this takes care of the first argument.
We have all of the operation arguments expected.
We still have to provide that second argument though.
What comes back is a post to the new post that was created and we have to determine what data we want
related to that post.
We can grab things from the post itself.
We can also grab related data whether it's comments which doesn't make sense because no comments would
exist yet or some information about the author.
Let's go out and just grab some information about the post right here inside of curly braces.
I'm going to grab the posts ID.
I'm going to also grab the posts title the post body and the Post published status.
Excellent.
And now we have a very complete call to create post.
Now remember just like our queery methods the return value of create post is not the new post itself.
It's actually a promise.
So we have to once again use then to be able to do something when the promise resolves when it actually
one communicates with the Prisma API and to Prisma has time to communicate with the database only once
everything happens.
Do we want misfunction to run and when it runs we are going to get the data.
This is where we have the data that we've chosen to select for the moment.
Let's just go ahead and dump it to the console console dot log right here.
I'm going to log that out.
Printing the data object.
Excellent.
Now we can go ahead and save the file and check out the output in the console down below.
Here the program is restarting it in just a few moments.
We should have some data about our new post and there it is.
We have our auto generated post ID and then we have the title of the body and the published status that
we actually set.
Now from here we could fetch all of the posts for a user again and we should see the new posts showing
up.
So let's go ahead and do just that.
I am going to comment out the new create post method call down below.
Since I don't want to create a nother post when the file re runs and up above I am going to comment
our users query where we happen to fetch all of the posts for each user.
Grabbing the post ID and the post title.
I'm going to save the file.
The browser is restarting excuse me the terminal is restarting and right here you can see that for that
third user whose name is Andrew.
We have the new post that we just created.
We have our ID and we have our title.
My new graphic post is live.
So there we go.
We now have a way to mutate and data right inside of Node.
Jay asks what I want to take a moment to talk about is how we can actually change some of these calls
together.
Doing one thing after or before I do something else Sendero working with promises for all of them.
We can use promise chaining to get that done.
So let's demonstrate this by and commenting our create post call.
We're going to go ahead and actually run this the next time the file runs and then we're going to take
our users query and we're going to move that down below.
So let's do a bit of restructuring right here what we're going to do is after our call to data we are
going to make a nother call to Prisma.
Queery dot users.
Here we are going to pass in any operation arguments and we're going to provide the same selection set
we had up above.
So right here I can go ahead and provide my curly braces in there I can ask for the ID the name the
posts and for each post I can go ahead and grab the ID and the title exactly like I did up above.
Now since I am trying to use promise chaining I am going to return this promise from my then callback
method allowing me to add on a nother then method and this one is going to fire.
When our second promise is complete.
So right here we pass in our callback function we get our data and this will contain the output results.
Right here I am going to use the Jason docstring ify method to correctly allow that nested data to actually
show up.
So console dialog.
Jason docstring ify passing in our data.
Undefined and a number like two or four.
So there we go.
Now the first thing that's going to happen is that this code is going to run it's going to create the
post then this callback will run we'll dump the data to the console and only after Create post finishes
we will start the process of querying for all users and getting all of their posts which should include
that newly created post.
Then down below there we dump all of the user's data to the console.
So let's go ahead and comment out the one call up above.
We're not going to need to run that since we're running the exact same operation down below.
And from here I'm just going to change the actual contents of the post a little bit.
I'm going to wipe the body.
I'll just leave that empty.
I'm going to set this post to have a published value of false and I'll change up the title as well.
Let's say something like 101 graphical Well graphical 101 to be exact.
Perfect.
Now if we go ahead and save Prisma dot J.S. it should go through the process of performing those two
operations.
It should be one creating that new post into fetching all of the users along with their posts.
If I scroll up we can search for that green text which is where the new instance of our application
running starts we see the server is up.
Then what do we get.
We get our new post data coming from line 30.
Right here we have our ID.
We have our title our empty body and our published status of false down below that we have all of their
users as well as the posts for each.
Our first user victim has one post.
The second user the other victim has zero posts and now Andrew has two posts the one we created a few
minutes ago and the new one that we just set up.
So using promise chaining we can do one thing after another.
Now it's Challenge time for this challenge you're going to have to use both a mutation and a query.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by commenting out the code we have so far.
This did indeed run but I don't want it to run every single time I save the file down below.
I'm going to paste in the challenge comments.
So the big picture goal is to mess around with mutations like we did here.
You're going to first perform a mutation then perform a query.
What you're going to do is update that newly created post changing its body and then marking it as published.
So I created this post with the title of graph.
Well 101 I gave it an empty body and I marked it as not published.
You're going to be updating it marking it as published and changing its body text value.
Now from there what are you going to do.
Well that brings us to step 2.
You are going to fetch all posts scribing the ID title body and published values for each and you're
going to print them to the console and step three save the file and look at the output in the terminal
down below.
You want to view that list of posts and confirm that the post you changed actually had its body and
published values changed accordingly.
All right take some time to knock that one out.
And for this challenge I would like you to use a promise chaining exactly like we did up above.
We want to first actually update that post in only once the post has been updated.
Do we actually want to fetch post data.
All right.
Pause the video.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
Hopefully you were able to knock that out without too much trouble.
We're going to kick things off with step 1.
Our mutation so I'll be using a Prisma dot mutation and for this one we will be using the update post
mutation.
Now we have to provide those two arguments are operation arguments and are selections set and we know
that when we're updating we do have to provide operation arguments in the case of updating a post which
we've explored already.
We have to first specify where to determine which post we actually want to update.
Then we specify data where we outline the data we would like to change.
We have to do the same thing over here.
Now I have the post ID sitting down below inside of the terminal though I could have also gone over
to the admin to grab that data.
I'm going to copy it to the clipboard since I'll be using it in a moment.
I'll be setting up an object for our operation arguments.
We are going to set up both where and then after where data and in where we are going to search by ID
sir right here in the ID of the post we're looking for is the one I just copied to the clipboard.
Now when it comes to what we want to change we pretty much want to change everything but the post title
I want to change the Post body I can change it to anything I'd like.
I'll say this is how to get started.
With graphics graphic well dot dot dot.
And I'm also going to change the published status so I am going to set published equal to true.
Excellent.
Now we can provide our selection set.
This comes back with the updated post so we can choose to grab whatever we like.
All I'm going to grab is just the idea of the post.
Perfect.
I didn't mention that you needed to grab anything or print anything so it's completely up to you.
What you ended up putting in there.
Next up we are going to use dot then to run some code after the post has been updated.
Right here we are going to get the post data back.
We could choose to print it to the console but that was by no means required.
From here we move on to Step 2 where we use a query to fetch all posts.
So I am going to use Prisma dot queery dot posts and I am going to return this promise so we can actually
chain them together.
Now I am going to call posts as a function which it is.
I'm going to pass a null for the operation arguments since we don't need to do anything special like
filter or sort.
The list of posts and then as the selection set I'm going to grab all of these scalar values listed
here.
So I want first up the ID then I'd like the title the body and the published value.
The last thing to do was to go ahead and use dot.
Then once again to run some code after that query has been completed and in our case what are we going
to do.
Well we're just going to get that data.
The list of posts and dump it to the console by dumping it to the council will actually be able to perform
in step 3 where we view the list of posts in the terminal and confirm that the post we changed actually
had those values updated.
Excellent.
Now with this in place our code is all done.
I can go ahead and save Prisma dot J.
S.
This is going to restart the application down below we can see a couple of different things happen.
The app restarted we got the server is up then we got our list of posts printing down below we have
our latest post.
This is the one we actually changed.
We have our brand new body.
This is how to get started with graphics.
Well and we have a published value of true Asso.
So using mutations inside of node j s is exactly the same as using mutations inside of Grath QOL playground
in the next video we're going to quickly convert this to use async await to make it much easier to do
one thing after another.
Since all of these Prisma methods support promises the conversion process is going to be very simple.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.