In this video you're going to learn how to use a single weight with our Prisma methods.
So we'll be able to use them with our mutations and with our queries since all of those methods return
promises and we can use async await any where promises are used.
Now as a reminder.
Understanding the basics of a sink and a weight is indeed a pre-req for the class.
So make sure that you understand how those two things work before continuing on with the Course.
To kick things off what I want to do is comment out the code you wrote as the challenge for the last
video.
I am going to leave it in place though as you'll be referencing it a bit later than I'm going to delete
the challenge comments for the last video and scroll up.
We have three examples we have are two separate queries and we have our one set of code that first creates
the post and then fetches all of the users we're going to leave this one in place.
But I am going to delete the other two.
We're going to end up replacing both of those with a single async function and this async function that
we're going to create together is going to have two responsibilities.
The first thing this function should be able to do is create a new post is going to take some post data
in as function arguments.
The second thing that this function should be able to do is fetch all of the info
about the user also known as the author.
So after I create the post I want to get all of the details about the person who created the post.
Things like their name their email and other posts they've created.
Now once again like we saw down below it's important that one operation happens before a nother operation.
So in this case we do still want one to start and finish before we ever start number two.
Let's go ahead and knock that out.
By creating a new function right here I am going to create a contest for this one.
We can call this something like create a post for a user and we are going to set this up as a function.
We could use a standard E-S five function like so or we could use an arrow function.
I'm partial to the arrow function so I'll stick with that as the value for create post for user.
Now we are going to be taking advantage of async and await after all that is the whole point of this
video.
So right here before our arguments list we are indeed going to mark this as an async function and we
are also going to take some arguments in.
We need to take in all the information about not just the Post but also the author that this post should
be associated with the first argument is going to contain the author ID so I'll call that one author
ID and then the second argument is going to be an object that has all of the post fields we need.
Like the title the body and the published value.
I'll call this one something like data.
Now down below we can actually go through the process of creating a post.
So what we're going to do right here is create a concept called post and this is going to store the
post data that comes back from calling create post and we're going to set it equal to.
And here we are going to use a wait.
So we're going to await the promise we are going to await the promise that comes back from Create post
and we're going to get the resolved value.
So instead of having to attach the then method to get the resolved value we can grab it right here as
long as we're using a sink and a weight.
Now what do we do.
Well we just call Prisma dot nutation dot create post.
Then we go ahead and pass in all of the necessary data.
So I'm going to set up my object.
We're going to have our data property on here.
We need to add all of those data fields we need to spread out that data object.
I can actually just use dot dot dot data to get that done.
That's going to spread out tidal body and published all of which are going to live on this argument
from there all we have to do is set up the author ID so I can add another property onto the data object.
Author is an object on there we have Connect which is also an object on there we have ID and that value
comes from author ID up above.
Perfect down below.
All we have to provide is that second argument our selection set.
What do we want to grab about the newly created post.
I'm just going to grab the posts ID.
Now we can move on to the next statement in this function and this is where we are going to fetch the
users are right here.
A new Konst user.
And once again we're going to be using a wait this time with a query Prisma dot queery dot user.
So we're using the singular user to fetch an individual user as opposed to what we've already explored
which was users to fetch an array of users.
Now if we pull up the documentation for the user query we can see that we actually do have to provide
a single argument.
This is not marked as nullable it's marked as non nullable So it has to exist.
The user query returns the individual user and the where argument is where we determine how we want
to find this user.
We can search for an individual user by any of the fields that make it unique whether it's the ID or
the email.
Now we already have the author ID as an argument for this function so that seems like a pretty good
place to start right here.
I am going to set up the arguments necessary.
We have our object we have the where argument we are going to search by id and we have ID on the author
ID variable name below as the second argument to the user method we can pass in our selection set.
What do we want about the user we find.
Well I'm going to go ahead and grab a couple of things right here.
I am going to grab the ID for that user.
I'll grab their name.
I'll grab their e-mail.
And I'm also going to as I mentioned up above fetch some information about the posts.
So right here I'll grab the posts and for each one I will grab the ID I will grab the title and I'll
grab the published stats I could grab body if I wanted to I'm just leaving that off for this example.
Now down below we can actually do something with the information we've compiled so far.
We have access to the post variable which contains the post ID and we have access to the user variable
which contains a lot of information about the author.
Let's set up a return value for this function right here.
I am going to return the user information so I will return it user.
Now we can actually remove these comments outlining what we were going to do because it's already done
and we can call create post for user down below down here we are going to call it with the necessary
arguments create post for a user.
We are going to pass in and the author ID and some post data I have to grab an author ID so I can make
a user's query from graft Cuil playground and I already have posts for that first user and for the last
one I'm going to add a post for the second victim.
So right here I will grab his ID.
We're going to use that as the first argument value for create post so as a string.
I'll paste it right in.
That brings us to the second argument.
The data for our post so we need the title we need the body and we need the published value right here.
I can set up an object for that title.
Could be something like.
Great books to read for the body.
We can go ahead and make a recommendation.
I'll go ahead and recommend something like the war of art and then we can determine whether or not this
post should be published and I will set published equal to true.
So we have our function call in place that's going to ensure that all of this code actually runs.
The last thing to do before we save the file is set things up so we can grab that user information.
Now remember async functions always always always return a promise and the resolved value of that promise
is whatever you return.
So in this case we can add on a single dot then call right here we can grab the user which is exactly
what was returned and we can print it to the council.
So I am going to use Jason docstring if I for this one so cancel that log.
Jason docstring ify passing in those three arguments we have the user itself undefined for our replacer
function and to for our indentation.
Now let's go ahead and save Prisma Dhananjay ass and see what we get down in the terminal.
The app is restarting and here we go.
We have some information about that users and information about victim 2.
We have their ID name and e-mail.
We also have their array of posts.
They had zero posts before and since we just added one and we can now see we have a single post in place.
We have the ID the title and the published status.
Exactly what was selected up above.
Now we've seen how we can use sink a weight with all of our Prisma binding methods.
This makes managing our asynchronous code a lot easier because we can do one thing right after another
without having to use nested callbacks.
And more than a single event the method call now that we've done this once together it's going to be
your challenge to do it down below before we move into the challenge comments and talk about what I'd
like you to do I am going to comment out our call to create post for user.
We don't want to actually run that every single time the file executes.
And I'm also going to remove the code block down below since it's been repurposed in a nicer way with
Create post for user up above.
So right here we can remove this code block where we create the post and then fetch the user.
Now the last code block in this file is the one that you're going to be altering to use async.
Wait and I'm going to paste the challenge comments right here.
The big picture goal is to use async await with the Prisma binding library.
Now step one for this is going to be to create an update post for user function that accepts the post
ID and the data to update.
So we have two arguments.
We have post ideas a string and data to update as an object.
Next up you're actually going to fill out the function itself and update the post.
So this is the first asynchronous thing you're going to do.
You're going to use a weight along with the correct mutation to update the post.
And the only data you need to get back about the updated post is the author IDs.
So grab that relational data.
The next step step three is where you're going to use an ID to fetch the user.
So you're going to use one of the queries to grab that user.
And for the user I want you to grab the same fields you grabbed up above with Create post for user.
So you're going to grab the ID name and email and you're going to grab the ID title and publish values
for each post.
Now you want to return the user data as the return value for update post for user and that brings us
to step 4.
You're going to call the newly created function passing in an ID for a post and the data you want to
update for the moment stick with an ID that actually has a post with the same ID.
Don't use an ID that isn't associated with a post.
Although in the very next video we'll learn how to check if some data exists before trying to make changes
to it.
For now though do use an actual valid post ID one that exists in the database.
So you're going to call that function with those two arguments and you are going to use the then method
call to do something when all of the operations are complete and all you're going to do is dump the
user to the console and make sure you see everything show up.
You should see the user data as well as their posts including the post you updated with the correct
new values.
So in the end of the day the post call would look like this.
We would call update post for user.
I could pass in something like the ID my ID and I can pass in the data.
Maybe I just want to publish the post so I'll set published equal to true for example.
All right.
Take some time to actually create the function that I've called right here and fill it out.
Then add the then method call on and verify everything worked as expected.
Pause the video.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
I'm going to kick things off with step one.
We are going to create our new function so a contest update post for user.
And once again the reason we're creating these little functions in Prisma dot J.S. is to get familiar
with how Prisma binding works.
Before we actually integrate it into the graft project itself.
So right here we are going to create this as an async function does this function except arguments.
Yes it does.
I need the post ID and I also need the data to update I could call that data or data update or post
data or pretty much anything.
Now we move on to the actual function body itself step to update the post.
We want to use our update post.
Mutations are right here.
We are going to create a variable to store the data that comes back.
I can call that something like post.
We will then await the following mutation.
Prisma dot mutation dot update post exactly what we used.
Down below.
And just like down below we have to set up the correct arguments.
The first argument our operations argument object needs where end data for where we are going to search
for the post by its ID.
I have post ID as an argument alongside of where we have to add data and since we already have a data
object up above we're good to go.
We can use the object property shorthand syntax.
Now in terms of the selections set I mentioned that I wanted you to grab the author ID.
So right here is the second argument I'm going to pass in a string.
We'll set up our curly braces and I'm not going to grab anything about the post itself.
I'm just going to grab something from the author.
I'm going to grab the ID and there we go.
That's all we have to do.
Now down below we can move on to Step Three and use the user query to grab some information about that
user.
So Konst user equals we are going to await Prisma dot queried dot user.
We are going to pass in the correct arguments for this one we just have to provide where we are searching
for the user by ID and I have the ID stored up above.
We have it on post dot author dot ID.
Excellent.
Down below we're going to provide the selection set for our user query right here.
I'm going to go ahead and choose to grab some information about the user id name and email as well as
information about their posts for each post.
I will grab as mentioned the id the title and the published value.
Perfect.
Now with this in place the last thing left to do is to return the user from update post for user.
Next up we can move on to Step 4 and actually set up our call.
So I already have the basic structure down below but I do need to use a valid post ID.
I'm going to grab the post ID from the terminal output and paste that in.
From here we can also change how we're updating the post.
Since this post is already published I'm going to unpublished it by setting published equal to false.
Next up we can add our Venn method to call and pass in our callback function which is going to run when
all of these operations actually complete.
We're going to get access to whatever got returned.
In this case it's the user.
I could call it data I could call it user I could call the argument whenever I want.
In the end of the day it's an object that has those user fields on it and we're just going to dump them
to the console so cancel that log using Jason docstring ify passing in those three arguments if you
want to print the user object.
I'll pass an undefined for our replacer since we don't want to manipulate the object in any way and
I'll pass in two as the spacing for this.
With this in place we can move on to Step 5 where we actually run things and make sure they work as
expected.
I'm going to save Prisma J.
S. down below.
The application is going to restart.
And what do we get.
We get our one user vicar him too.
This time we have our post with the published value correctly set to false.
Which is fantastic.
We now have a way to use async and to wait with Prisma allowing us to vastly simplify that async code.
To wrap this video up we can go ahead and remove the old example down below.
And I'm also going to comment out our update post for user call up above.
We can remove the challenge comments as well and now we have those two functions in place as promised
in the next video you're going to learn how to use a nother Prisma property.
We're going to be using Prisma exists to help us figure out if something exists.
So for example am I trying to create a post for a user where there is no user with this ID.
Or am I trying to update a post where this post ID doesn't even exist.
In any case it Prisma exists can help us figure out if data exists or not.
Let's go ahead and jump right into the next video and dive in to that.