In this video as promised you're going to learn all about Prisma.
Exists this comes with some handy utility functions that make it really easy for us to determine if
there is a record of a given type.
For example we can check if a given user exists or a given post exists or a given comment exists.
And this has real world practical uses in create post for user.
For example we create a post for this user with this ID without ever checking that the user is actually
in the database.
We do the same thing down below in update posts for user.
We take this post ID in and we blindly try to update the post without ever verifying that there actually
is a post with that I.D. It being able to use exists to verify data exists is very useful.
So let's go ahead and actually see how this works.
Right here we're going to mess around with it then we'll integrate it into the two functions down below.
Let's use Prisma and Dot exists and we're going to start by checking if a given comment exists now.
Just like Prisma dot query and Prisma dot mutation we have a dynamic set of methods available to us.
We have one method for every single type and the method name is the type name.
So if I want to check that a user exists I used upper case user if I want to check that a post exists
upper case P post if I want to check that a comment exists.
You guessed it uppercase C comment.
Now what we can pass to this.
Everything that exists expects and the arguments for this are a bit different than the query and mutation
method arguments.
And now all of these exists methods.
They take a single argument.
The value is an object.
And here we provide all of the properties that we want to verify about the comment we're looking for.
So if I want to verify that a comment exists with a given ID.
All I do is provide ID.
And I said it's value equal to the value I'm searching for.
So if I type in ABC 1 2 3 I'm in effect trying to determine whether or not a comment exists that has
the ID value of ABC 1 2 3.
Clearly the answer is no.
Now in the end of the day all of these exists methods return a promise and that promise resolves to
the boolean value true or false.
The thing you're looking for either exists or it doesn't.
So let's go ahead and use the event method on our promise.
We're going to get the resolved value.
I'll call that something like exists.
It's going to be either true or false.
And for the moment we will just print it to the con..
So down below cancel dot log dumping exists to the terminal.
Excellent.
If I save the file we should see our bullion value printing.
And for this data I would expect it to be false and that is exactly what we end up getting.
We have the boolean false printing.
Now let's grab the ID for a that that actually exists.
If I head over to graph you our playground I can use the comments queery for example and if I fire that
off I can see we just have a single comment across all of our posts.
All I need is this ID.
I'm going to grab it copy it to the clipboard bring it over to Visual Studio code and add that as the
ID we're looking for.
Now if I save a Prisma J.S. Once again I would expect to see the boolean true.
And that is exactly what we end up getting as well.
Now we can perform more complex assertions I code for example verify something about the comment text
as well.
I could check if the comment text equals For example my first name it doesn't.
So I would expect to see false.
It's really up to you to add as much criteria as you actually need though commonly you just provide
the ID for the record you're looking for.
You can even provide associated assertions.
So for example I can grab the author ID and I can use that over and exists as well right here.
I can verify that there is a comment with this ID and that it was created by the following author.
So author setting that up as an object and outing the id property on.
Now we should see true because there is indeed a comment with this ID that has an author with that ID.
So he can get as complex or as simple as we happen to need.
Now that we've seen this in action let's go ahead and integrate it into create post for user down below
down here.
We are going to verify that that user actually exists before we tried to add a post for that user.
All right.
Here I am going to create a concept called user exists and then I'm going to set it equal to.
And we are going to await the promise that comes back from Prisma and exists dot.
And in this case we're searching for a user.
So we use UPPER CASE YOU user.
Now from here we provide the object argument and we determine what criteria we want to use to search.
In this case we just care about the idea of the user.
We want to make sure the ID equals the value passed in as author ID if we did find a user.
This will be true if we didn't find a user.
This is going to end up being false down below.
We can now use that.
So if there is no user I can do something like throw an error immediately stopping the execution of
this function right here.
If I'm going to flip that boolean using the logical NOT operator.
So now this condition is going to be true if there is no user and it'll be false if there is a user.
So right here we know that this code is only going to run if no user was found and we can throw a new
error.
We can pass to the error constructor function whatever message we'd like to use something like user
and not found it would get the job done.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can go ahead and make a small modification to how we call create post
for user down below down here we can uncomment our call and we can go ahead and add on a catch method
to the end of our chain.
This is going to fire if we get any errors.
We are going to get the error as the first and only argument and then we're just going to dump it to
the councils are right here.
Dot Lague printing the error object to the screen.
Excellent.
So now that we have this in place let's go ahead and actually test out its functionality.
The first thing I'm going to do is remove my call up above where I check if a comment exists then I'm
going to leave the Create post for user arguments exactly as they were.
This user still exists.
So this code should work and then the end of the day I should get the user information printing this
callback is going to run.
This one is not.
Let's go ahead and prove that by saving Prisma.
Jay x.
This is going to execute our file and what do we get.
We get the user information with our new post added.
Now if we were to mess up this ID changing it to something like 0 9 8 for example there is not going
to be a user associated with that ID and our code is going to throw an error resulting in this function
running.
And right here you can see we've printed our error to the console using console dialog and we have our
message user not found if we want to limit this to just the message.
We can always use error message accessing the message property.
That is where the string error message exists.
And this time around we get that simplified output.
So there we go.
We've made a change to our create post for user function making it a little more robust we're actually
checking the data that gets passed in before just blindly passing it along assuming the user exists.
Now if you've been paying close attention so far you might have realized that this query is actually
completely redundant and not required.
If I wanted information about the user associated with that post I could actually add that in to the
selection set right here.
There's nothing stopping me from grabbing fields about the author and then also grabbing their posts
getting the exact same data but without having to perform another operation.
And you're right.
We can indeed do that.
The reason I originally didn't do that is because I wanted to have two asynchronous things that we could
use with a wait.
But now that we have exists in place we can go ahead and simplify our code.
So right here what am I going to do.
I'm just going to change the selection set for our create post nutation.
Yes we're gonna grab the ID of that post though it's actually not required so we could even leave that
up.
We're going to grab some information about the author for the author.
What am I gonna grab.
Well I'm going to grab everything we have below.
I'm going to grab the id the name and the email and I'm going to grab the author's posts on the posts.
I want to grab a few fields as well.
I'll grab ID.
Title and published.
Awesome.
So now we're getting the exact same data back.
But we can actually delete this altogether from here.
All we have to do is make a small change to the return value.
Since user no longer exists the user data actually needs to come from Post.
We now have Post dot author.
That is where all of those user fields can be found.
Now let's go ahead and actually get this to work once again we're going to verify our work by first
reverting back to the correct ID over here.
I can go ahead and grab that ID.
I have an author ID right here for example.
Any author ID will work doesn't have to be the same one we had before.
And if I go ahead and paste that in and save the file I should see not my error but my success message
and that is exactly what I end up getting.
And I still get all of the same data.
I have everything about the user including all of its posts including the brand new post that was just
added sitting right here.
So now that we've improved in simplified create post for user.
It's going to be your job to do the exact same thing down below.
So down here let's go ahead and talk about what I'd like you to do for the challenge.
First up I am going to comment out our call to create post for user so that doesn't run when you're
actually working through your challenge solution.
Right here the big picture goal is to improve update post for user down below.
Just like we improved the Create post for user function up above.
So what does that entail.
First up you are going to use Prisma and exists to verify that the post you're trying to update actually
exists.
If there is no post with that ID I'd like you to do is just throw an error.
Step 2 you're going to remove the unnecessary user query by updating the selection set for update post.
So everything we're getting right here can actually be received by making a few modifications to the
selection set for our first operation.
Right here making this one completely useless.
It can actually be removed completely and that's what I'd like you to do.
Step 3 Add a catch method call to actually catch and print those errors.
You're going to do that down below in the usage and step 4.
Test your work tried to update a post that does exist.
Make sure that still works.
Then try to update a post that does not exist and make sure you get the correct error message printing.
All right.
Take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Don't forget to actually test your work.
Come back when you're done and click play
how that go on and kick things off by adding my exists method call right here.
So I'm going to check if the post exists.
I can create a concert called post exists for that I'm going to set it equal to and we're going to await
the promise that comes back from Prisma data exists.
And right here it is the model name so uppercase you user excuse me upper case P post since we're verifying
that a given post exists.
Now we passed to this an object.
And the only thing we're trying to actually filter by is the ID.
So I set up that Id property making sure it equals post ID.
The argument passed in.
So this will be true if there is a post with this ID that will be false otherwise.
That brings us to the second part of step 1.
Throw an error if there is no post right here if we're going to set up our IF statement if there is
no post.
So if post exists when fliped is indeed true we want to throw an error right here throw new error printing
a message like post not found excellent from here we know that everything that runs down below is only
going to run if there actually was a post which is great.
And this brings us to step two.
We want to remove the unnecessary user query by updating the selection set for update post.
So we want to be able to get rid of this entirely and we're going to do that by asking for more fields.
We don't just want the author ID.
I also want their name I want their email and I want the posts for each post.
But what I like.
I would like the ID and the title and the published values.
Now down below we can remove that extra query and instead of returning user we will return post dot
author which contains in the end of the day the exact same information that brings us to step 3.
Add a catch call to print those errors.
So down below I'm going to uncomment our usage.
I'm going to add on a catch call right here.
We are going to pass in the callback function.
This is only going to get called if the promises reject.
And right here what are we going to do.
I am going to grab the error and print it so cancel dot log.
And I'll just print the message.
So error datt message.
Excellent.
From here we move on to Step 4.
I want to verify this function by providing both a valid and invalid post ID.
Now we can go ahead and do that by saving the file in its current state.
I already have an ID sitting right there and I can see it is indeed a valid one down below.
I have that post unpublished.
I can go ahead and switch it over to true to make sure it actually changes.
Right here we should see the same post what they published value of true.
So everything seems to be working really well so far.
I'm then going to change this ID to the ID that does not exist for a post.
I'll use a power.
There is no post with an ID of power.
And if I go ahead and save the file and rerun things I can get the post not found error.
So there we go.
We now know how to use Prisma dot exists to search our data for various records.
That's where we're going to stop for this one.
Down below I am going to comment out our call to update post for user.
Then up above I am going to go ahead and remove those challenge comments.
I'm excited to continue talking about Prisma in the next video we're going to focus on customizing our
relationships.
So we're going to learn how we can customize exactly how the relationships between our types function.
Let's jump right in to that.