In this video we're going to focus on what happens when we try to remove data from the Prisma database
using the graphical API.
And we're going to talk about how we can override that default behavior by making a few changes to data
model graph.
Q Well to kick off this discussion I want to start by actually trying to delete some data and we're
just going to make a few requests from graphical playground over here I'm going to create a brand new
tab and we're going to use one of our delete mutations to remove some data.
And for this example let's go ahead and try to remove a user.
Now in that previous tab right here I was fetching all of the comments and I was fetching the author
for all of those comments.
I have a single comment written by this author.
This is the user that I'm going to try to delete.
And I'd like you to also try to delete a user that does indeed have a comment.
Now let's go back over to that tab and set up the mutation.
So over in our schema documentation we can see that under mutations we do indeed have delete comment
delete user and delete posts.
We're going to be using the delete user mutation it takes in a single argument where and it gets the
user back that user that was removed.
Now the where argument allows us to target our user but anything that makes it unique.
What you remember is the ID or the e-mail.
In this case we're just going to use the ID.
So let's set this up.
It is indeed a mutation operation delete user passing in all of the arguments that it expects.
That's just one where it's an object and we pass in either the idea of the user We're trying to remove
or the email of the user We're trying to remove in this case I already have the ID copy to the clipboard
as I'm going to paste that in right here.
Now we have to provide our selection set to what fields do we want back about the user that got deleted.
I'm going to say that I'd like back the ID.
I'd also like back the name and the e-mail so all of these scalar fields are available if we fire off
this operation we are actually not going to get the result we might expect right here in the response.
We have two properties we have data and we have errors for data we have just delete user but the value
is actually null.
This is because no user was removed.
Now to figure out why no user was removed we can refer to the errors array down below.
There is just one object in the errors array and the actual error message on that object is the following.
The change you are trying to make would violate the required relation comment to user between comment.
End user.
Now it's referring to are two types the user type and the comment type that we've defined over in data
model graph.
Well when the user gets removed it actually makes the comment invalid.
So all of our comments have that author field which needs to link to a user.
We've made this type non nullable.
All comments have to have an associated user in the author field.
And if the user gets deleted then the comments become invalid.
That is why Prisma isn't letting us delete the user.
The good news though is that we can override this behavior.
We can set up some on delete behavior to solve this issue.
And if you remember it we ran into the same problem when we created our graphical API using just arrays
for storage when we deleted the user.
We also had to delete all of their posts and all of their comments were going to do the same thing here
with Prisma.
But the actual process of setting it up is going to be much much easier.
And now when we brought over all of our types to data model dot graphics Well we never reconfigured
the comments field on user and post.
Let's go ahead and add that real quick.
It hasn't mattered so far but it's going to be important in this video.
So comments on the user type is indeed a non-negligible array where all of the elements are of the type
comment and the same thing is true with a post.
So right here we are going to have our comments field with the exact same type as up above a non-null
label array and all of the array elements are of the type comment.
Excellent.
So now that we have our types correctly configured we can talk about how we can configure what happens
when a given record gets deleted.
And of Prisma gives us two options.
There is the default option and there is one additional option we can set up.
Let's go ahead and talk about both of those.
The first option we can use when deleting a record is known as set null.
This is the default option and we'll talk about exactly what that means in a second.
And the other option we have available to us is known as cascade.
We're going to be using this as well.
So sometimes we're going to rely on that default behavior using set no.
Other times we're going to override that default behavior and use the cascade option instead.
Now a sentinel and Cascade become relevant when we have types that link to other types.
So a user links to post via posts and to comment via comments.
Post links to user via author and comment via comments and finally comment links to user via author
and post via post.
So in all six of those situations we can customize what happens to the other records when a given record
gets removed.
So what happens when a user gets deleted.
Well right now for all of the posts for example we use the set all behavior which is default so it tries
to set the field on the post to null.
In this case the author field.
Now clearly this is not allowed.
We set this up as a non mailable type.
We need an author record and that's what's causing the error we're seeing.
We're trying to delete a user that has a comment but in the case of a comment as well.
This is also non nullable.
So the set null behavior is trying to keep the comment around setting this field to knowl that's not
allowed.
Based off of our definition of these types and this is where the error comes from.
Now in our case we determine that we don't want to keep posts around or comments around.
If the user itself has been removed we want to delete those records.
So set NULL is not what we're looking for in these cases.
We're looking for cascade.
So let's bring this back to our user type when we have a user deleted.
We could set up the Post's relationship to use cascade instead of set.
In that case it's actually going to delete all post records associated with that user and we could do
the exact same thing for comment.
So when a user gets removed we remove all of their posts and all of their comments.
You could even set that up for post as well.
When a post gets removed we can have all of the comments for that post get deleted.
So let's go ahead and see how we can actually configure this Prisma provides us with one more directive
we can use like unique allowing us to customize the relationships between our types.
The directive is called relation and we can use it on our field that end up linking to other types like
the posts field on user at relation.
We are going to set up our arguments list and we are going to provide it.
We're gonna set up a name which is going to be a string.
Will give this relation a name in just a second and the second one is on delete.
Right here we provide either set all which is the default behavior or cascade.
So when a user gets deleted what do we want to have happen to the users posts.
We want them to get deleted so we will be using the cascade option in all uppercase.
Excellent.
Now when it comes to picking a name we can go ahead and use something that describes this relationship.
I am going to use post to the user but in reality any single value would work something that's descriptive
is best though because this is going to end up getting used a bit later down below.
We want to do the same thing for our other fields.
So right here we have comments at relation.
We are going to set up our relationships we want name right here.
Well pick a name and a second we want.
On delete right here.
When a user gets deleted we want to cascade remove all of their comments.
So once again I will be using that cascade value.
Then we can set up the name value for this one.
I'm going to use comment to user perfect Dambulla we have our post type let's knock out our relationship
down there as well.
We have author and we have comments now for author.
We will use our relation once again.
We're going to set up those arguments we have name and we have on delete for undelete What do we want
to do when a post gets deleted.
I do not want to remove the author so I'm actually going to stick with the default behavior using Set
knowl.
Now we have to match up the name with the relationship.
On the other end.
So when we link a user to a post what do we use.
We used post to user.
So we want to do the same thing down here post to user.
Perfect.
Now that relationship is completed on both sides we can set up a relation for comments our relation.
Setting up our arguments list we pass in that name we can give this one a name like comment to a post
and for the on.
Delete value we can choose to use cascade.
So when a post gets deleted.
Yes I do want to delete all comments associated with that post from here.
Post is all done and we can move on to comment itself down below.
We have author so relation we have to provide both.
We're going to set up a name right here.
The name for this one already exists elsewhere.
We already have a relationship between a comment and a user.
We call that comment to user.
So I will use comment to user right here.
Then we can set up on delete when a comment gets deleted we don't want to touch the user itself.
So we will continue to use set Knol for that.
Down below we have just one more relation.
We are going to set up a name equal to the relationship we've already created comment to post then we
are going to set up on delete as well on delete for the situation will once again also be set.
No.
Perfect.
So we have six different usages of this at relation directive.
We have three different values for name.
We have post to user used here and down below we have comment to user used here.
And down below.
And we have a comment to post used here and down below.
We've also customize the on delete option for each setting everything up correctly.
Let's go ahead and actually remove the comment up above.
Save this file deploy the application and see how this affects the behavior.
First up I did notice I added a stray closing parentheses right here that was added by accident.
It has become part of our posts.
Feel the definition so we can remove that and save the file from here we're actually going to shut down
NPM start altogether and what we're going to do is CD into the Prisma directory so we can redeploy our
application.
I'm going to use clear to clear the terminal output and then have Prisma deploy to deploy our changes.
Now once the changes are deployed we should be able to run the exact same command over here but this
time instead of seeing an issue saying that we can't actually delete the user because the user has a
comment we should see a success.
The user should get deleted and their comment should get deleted as well.
If I actually go ahead and run this what happens exactly what I said happened happened.
We get our user back and the comment has been removed.
If that particular user had any posts associated with them those posts would have been removed as well.
And any comments on that post any of those posts that got deleted by other users would have been deleted
too.
So remember user has its posts and comments removed since we're removing posts all of the posts comments
are removed as well.
This is the same behavior we had before when we created our applications storing data in arrays.
The only difference is that previously we had to manually delete all of those things.
It was a real pain this time.
Prisma does all of that automatically by modifying six lines of code in our data model.
Damn graphical file.
No there is no challenge for you to use the admiration directive in this video.
It's kind of a tricky situation because we needed all six lines in order to get everything to work so
it was very much an all or nothing scenario.
In the next video though we're going to start a challenge to wrap up this section where you're going
to have to create a separate Prisma project with a different data model for a different type of application.
You have to set up all of the types for the application and you have to set up the relationship between
all of those types.
That's going to give you a lot of real world experience.
Setting up a data model file for all sorts of different data structures.
Not just a blogging application.
All right let's jump right into that.
It is coming up next.