It is a challenge time and in this video we're going to go through the setup process.
I'll describe what I'd like you to do.
And in the next video you're actually going to get it done.
Now don't skip through this video because I do still cover a few new pieces of information that are
going to be really important when it comes to getting this challenge done successfully in the end of
the day though the big picture goal is to create a new Prisma project and model the data for a different
application.
So instead of modeling what would be necessary for a blogging Web site you're going to end up modeling
what's needed for a review Web site.
So that could be a book review Web site that could be a computer his review website or a course Review
Web site and we'll dive deep into exactly what you should be modeling with the visualization which is
coming up in a few minutes.
For the moment what I want to do is set up that separate Prisma project because there are a few new
pieces of information that you're going to need to actually get that done to kick things off.
What I want to do is duplicate the Prisma directory.
Now if you install the duplicate action vs C extension you can actually right click the folder and use
duplicate file or directory.
Unfortunately Visual Studio code currently does not even have that feature built in.
Seems like a real missed opportunity for a basic feature.
I'm going to call this one something different like Prisma hyphen and I'll call this review Web site.
You could call it whatever you like.
And the end goal is to just have a copy of our Prisma directory.
This is the one that you're actually going to be modifying for the challenge.
So let's start things off by closing all of the open editors and we're going to crack open some of the
files in this directory and make a few changes before I set you off on your own to kick things off.
We're actually going to be deleting the Daker compose file in our new directory.
We only need a single Daker container running Prisma to deploy multiple Prisma projects to it so there
is no need to create a whole new container to actually get this completely separate project up and running.
That's nice because it means we can use the same database so there's no need to create a new database
and set up new connection details to configure this as a new project.
All we need to do is make a change to the end point value in Prisma dot wya.
Now our Prisma YAML configuration file in here.
We're going to be adding something on to the end.
Now when we deploy a Prisma project if we just have a u r l like this it ends up determining two things.
It ends up setting what's known as the service name to default and it sets the stage name to default.
This is actually why we see default default over here inside of PGE admin.
It is the default service and the default stage because none were provided.
In our Prisma YAML file we can go ahead and actually customize them now by default.
It's like having the following default forward slash default but we could change that to anything we
like.
So for our project maybe we have a dev stage maybe we have a test stage separate data store as we can
actually use for our purposes though what we're going to do is create a new service so when I say service.
Think of it like a new project we have our blog project.
We have our review Web site project.
So right here I'm going to call this reviews by giving it a name so forward slash reviews forward slash.
And for this stage we can indeed stick with default.
Now that we have this in place when we actually deploy in a little bit with Prisma deploy it'll be creating
a whole new space to store the reviews data.
That's not going to in any way conflict with the blog data we already have set up.
So once again this is the service name.
Think of it like the project name.
This is the stage name.
Both can be anything you like are completely arbitrary.
The only thing is if you don't pick any default is used for both.
So we are going to keep ours in place reviews as the service name and default as the stage name.
Now we don't have to make any changes to anything else in this file so we can save the Prisma why Amell
file.
And we're going to move into data model ZCom graph.
Which once again is just a duplicate of the data model we had before.
For the moment let's completely remove the comment and post type.
Those are not going to be a part of the new application we're creating.
And then what we're going to do is wipe everything from user except for ID.
So we are still going to have users in this new application as we well with most applications and users
are still going to have IDs so this will be our little dummy starter so we can actually deploy our project
and that's what we're going to do right now.
So I just want to show you how this deployment goes with that second project.
Then we'll talk about what exactly it's your job to do.
So right here down below all we're going to do is use CD dot dot to get out of the rectory and we're
going to go into our new folder using CD Prisma hyphen review hyphen a Web site from they're all we
do is run Prisma deploy exactly like we would of for the previous project.
This time though when we deploy.
It's going to be creating that brand new service here.
We can see the user has been created now and the end of the day the deployment went well and if we head
over to PGE Admin we can actually Right-Click schemas click refresh and you should see a new one showing
up down below we have reviews dollar sign default.
So this is the reviews service on our default stage.
This is a separate place where we're going to have all of the data for this review Web site application
down below.
We have our tables completely separate from the tables for the blogging application but all under the
exact same database.
Now you can access the graph API at the New You RL So that still localhost 4 4 6 6 Remember use your
IP if you've been using one so far.
If you're on Windows then it's forward slash.
Now if we wanted to get to our blogging API we could obviously use just this.
That's what we've done so far.
But we could also use default a forward slash default if we do this.
It's going to be just like we had before we open up the schema.
And what do we see.
We see things related to users posts and comments.
If we change up that you are Eldo to forward slash revues forward slash default this is going to bring
us to a graph.
Q Well playground instance that allows us to work with our new application.
So right here what do we have.
We just have information related to users since we just have users in the data model file.
All right that's enough set up.
Let's go ahead and talk about what I'd like you to do.
And I have a quick visualization for that.
All right let's go ahead and talk about exactly what I want you to do.
So right here we're going to go through the different types in the different fields we need in order
to get all of this done.
Now this is for a book review web site but you could also review something else maybe like vacation
destinations.
So the first type we need is for the thing we're reviewing.
In this case we're reviewing books so we're going to create a book type.
Now users leave reviews.
So we need a user type as well.
And the final type will end up creating is a review type which contains the actual review information.
Now for the book we're going to have some fields that make sense for a book I've picked for we need
an ID a title author and ISBN and we'll say that all of these fields are non nullable.
So you have to provide a value for all of them.
Next up we have the user type.
This one is going to be really simple.
All we need is an ID and a user name the user name for the person leaving that review.
Now you can make both of these non nullable as well.
You obviously have to have an ID.
And we're also going to say that you need to provide a user name.
Let's also go ahead and make that username unique.
Next up we have our review type the review type has a few fields of its own.
We're going to have ideas.
We're going to have text so you can leave a text review in and we're going to have ratings so you can
leave a rating anywhere from one to five stars.
So this will be stored as an integer.
You can make this non nullable So you have to provide a rating but you could choose to make the text
field completely optional.
It would be perfectly fine to leave a review like a five star rating without saying why.
Now there's also relationships between these types.
So we're going to have a relationship between book and review book is going to have a revues field which
links to all of the reviews made for that book and then review is going to have a book field which links
to the book that's being reviewed.
There's also going to be a relationship between the review type and the user type right year a review
is going to have an author property that points to the user who left the review.
And every user has a collection of reviews on the reviews field.
So if I have 16 reviews I could find them all there.
So the end of the day this is the data model we're working towards.
Now let's go through the steps necessary to actually get that done.
Once again the big picture goal model a review website using Prisma.
Step one we're going to define all of the types we talked about as well as their scalar fields.
All of that is happening in data model graphs.
Well from there you're going to configure the relationships between our types which we've outlined here
and we also want to customize the relation using at relation the directive.
If someone deletes a book it should do the reviews for that book.
If a user gets deleted it should delete all reviews left by that user.
So you want to make sure to set up that as well using one we learned a couple of videos ago.
From there you're going to deploy the application using Prisma deploy.
And the last step is to test things out.
So for this Web site to test things out I might one create a book then to create two users.
From there I would have each of the users leave a review on the book then I could fetch the data to
make sure everything is working well then I can test out my removals by deleting a user and ensuring
that its review gets deleted that I could delete a book and make sure the other review goes away.
So all of this is going to allow us to just test that the functionality is working as expected.
And there's no need to do this from javascript.
You can just knock this out from.
Playground itself the real goal of the challenge is for you to correctly set up the data model in data
model aircraft.
Q Well all right.
That is it for these set up.
The actual solution is coming up in the next video.
So take some time to knock this out.
Test your work and when you're done jump right in to the next lecture.