Welcome back how do I go.
Who are going to go ahead and move through all four steps.
Step one is to set up all of our types with their scalar fields.
You shouldn't have run into too much trouble there.
Bullets do the process.
Nonetheless I'm going to kick things off with the first one we have our book.
So we have our type book sitting right here.
Then we're going to set up all of the fields for a book.
We are going to have an idea of the ID type and we do have to use at Unique for IDS in a Prisma.
Excellent.
And from there we can set up the book's title.
I'll set that up as a non nullable string as shown in the graphic then we can move on to the author.
Also a non nullable string.
And the last one we're going to have is I s b n that is also going to be a string that must be provided.
So that is it for these scalar fields.
Next up we have our user let's knock out those two fields and we already have one done the only one
we still need is a user name right here user name setting not equal to a string.
Perfect.
I also want to make this unique so I will use at Unique on the users user name field.
The last type we need is our review type we have an ID and a rating field which are both required and
an optional text field.
So let's set all three up over here type review.
Setting up first ID.
There's nothing special there will be setting it up with our unique directive.
Next up we're going to have our text.
This is indeed going to be a string but it's going to be a nullable string.
So it's perfectly fine if you don't want to provide any sort of text based reason for why you're leaving
a review.
After that we are going to have the orating field and this will indeed be a required integer and there's
no need to worry about determining if the end is between 1 or 5 for the moment.
That wasn't the point of this particular challenge.
So from here we have Step 1 done.
We've defined are three types.
And we set up all of their scalar fields as shown in the visualization.
From there we want to configure the relationship between the types.
So I want revues book author and reviews all set up.
Let's go ahead and move from top to bottom.
Starting with book so book should be able to link to all of the reviews for that book using a revues
field.
This is going to be an array like we've done before and the individual elements in the array will just
be individual reviews.
Nothing too shocking there.
Next up we have the user.
Now the user also has a link to reviews.
So right here we have to configure that as well.
We're going to have reviews as an array and the elements for that will also be of the review type.
And that brings us to the last type we have review review needs to link to both the book and to the
user.
So right here we are going to set up a book field which will link to the book and then we are going
to set up an author field or maybe you called it user or something similar linking to the user that
actually left the review.
Now I mentioned that I also wanted you to use that at relation directive to set up a relationship between
all of these things and configure undelete to cascade.
So when a book gets deleted all of the reviews for that book should go away.
And when a user gets deleted all of the reviews for that user should end up getting deleted as well.
I'm going to go ahead and kick things off right here with the reviews field for book.
All right here at in relation we are going to set up those arguments.
We're going to provide both name.
Setting that equal to a string and we're going to provide undelete setting that equal to in this particular
case cascade because that is the behavior we're looking for.
And we can use whatever name we like.
I'm going to go ahead and use review to book perfect now that we have that in place we can move on to
the next relational field we have which is the reviews field on the user.
Right here something very similar at relation.
We're going to pass in those arguments and we can use a name or something along the lines of review
to user then we're going to pass in on and delete.
And for this one we also want to configure it to cascade delete.
So if a user does get deleted We also want to remove any of their reviews.
Now Dambulla we can configure the review type itself.
We have two fields to configure book and author.
Both of these are going to use set Nall as opposed to cascade.
If we delete a review I do not want to remove the book and I do not want to remove the author so at
relation.
Setting that up passing in a name value.
Now in this case we already have the other side of this relationship set up.
We have that book up above and I called it review to book.
So right here.
Review 2 book.
Matching up exactly.
Then we provide on delete.
Setting this particular one equal to set underscore null.
Excellent.
Then we're going to do basically the same thing below with a different name.
So at relation passing in a name setting the name equal to the name we have right here that is review
into a user and then providing are on delete value on delete for this particular case will also be set
Knol perfect.
So this actually wraps up step two.
We have everything done inside of data model Dom graft UL and we can go ahead and deploy our changes.
So down below all we have to do is run Prisma deploy from our Prisma review Web site directory.
I'm going to fire that command off.
This is going to make all of the necessary changes to our data store and once it's done we can move
on to Step Four and actually test things out.
All right.
Deployment done.
Let's go ahead and verify that things are working over here inside of graft.
Playground at forward slash revues forward slash default we should be able to see our new schema.
I'm going to refresh the schema.
Crack open that tab and now we have all of our queries mutations and subscriptions related to books
users and reviews.
Let's actually use them to get something meaningful done.
First up as mentioned I'm going to create a book so down below I have a create book mutation which I
can use to get that done.
Now I know that with the create both mutation I'm going to have to pass in all of the data necessary
for the book.
So in this case that would be my title my author and my ISBN number and I get the book back.
So let's go ahead and use that over here for the first tab we're going to set up a mutation.
We'll be using create book passing in all of the data necessary on the data argument.
I'm going to pass in a title for the book.
Let me go ahead and pick a book from my shelf.
I'll go ahead and use.
Rest a book about taking breaks and working at a reasonable pace as opposed to burning the midnight
oil.
Now this book was written by an author.
So let's set up the author field as well the author for this one is Alex Pang.
And we're also going to add in the ISBN number.
Now I don't know what it is and I'm not going to look it up so let's just use ABC.
One two three.
Perfect.
We can also provide a selection set getting some information back about the book that was created.
I'm just going to grab the idea.
The title The author and I will also grab the ISBN.
We could also choose to grab the reviews but remember there aren't going to be any reviews since the
book is getting created right now I am going to grab that though just to prove the point.
I'll grab the ID for each review the text fields for each review and the rating for each one.
Now if I fire that off what happens while the book does indeed get created and as expected we have our
ID.
Our other scalar fields and we have reviews as an empty array since no reviews had been created on the
book just yet.
Next up let's add some users into the mix using the create user mutation.
So I'm going to use that to add a couple of different users.
Once again we get the user back as the response value and we pass in as the data.
Just the user name it's the only field necessary to create a user.
I'm going to create a new tab to knock this out.
We have a mutation.
We'll be using create a user over here.
We're going to set up that data argument passing in the user name the user name can be anything in the
world we like.
I am going to use a sleepy guy as the first user.
And now we can move on to our selection set.
So right here I can grab the ID and I can grab the user name.
Perfect.
So I am going to fire off this mutation to create that first user.
And I'm also going to create a second user.
I'll go ahead and have this one be.
Sleepy girl.
Perfect.
Now we have two users in the database and we have one book.
The last thing left to do in terms of creating data is to create some reviews.
So let's knock that out as well.
Over in the schema we can figure out how to use this.
If you can't guess based off of the structure of past requests by going to the Create review mutation
right here we have to pass some information on that data argument.
We have to pass in not just the optional text and required rating but also of the connection to the
existing book and author.
So for both book and author we can choose to create the entity or connect it to an existing one.
I am obviously going to connect to our existing users in our existing book.
Let's go ahead and actually knock all of that out in a brand new tab.
I'm going to perform a nother mutation our last mutation tab.
This one will be using create review which we just created and we are going to set up the arguments
here.
So we need data.
And this one is going to be a bit more complex.
I can provide a text feel like it was a good read.
Then we can choose to provide a rating.
Actually we have to provide a rating.
I'll go ahead and rate this one five stars.
And from here we need to link in the book we're reviewing and the user who's leaving the review.
So I already have the book idea sitting over here.
I can just copy that to the clipboard and bring it over to create review and link that up.
I'm going to add book in this case we are connecting to an existing book.
So I use connect and I am connecting by the only thing that makes that book unique it's ID.
So right here I'll paste the idea in.
Next up we can go ahead and actually specify alongside of book the user.
So right here that is known as author.
We are going to provide connect to connect to an existing author and we are going to provide the ID
for that author.
Let's go ahead and actually grab one over in the other tab.
I have the idea for sleepy gal so I'll copy that to the clipboard and use that when I create this first
review.
I'm going to paste that in.
And perfect.
Now we're all done.
We can add a selection set on it to grab some information about the review we're creating.
I'm just going to grab the ID.
I'll grab the text and I'll also grab the rating.
Perfect.
If we fire off this operation we should see that our review was indeed left successfully.
And now what I want to do is leave a nother review by the other user.
Now I don't remember what the other users I.D. was.
So I can always take advantage of something like the user's query.
I'm going to query for all users grabbing the ID and the user name for each if I fire that off.
I have the ID for a sleepy guy right here.
I can bring that I.D. over to my Create view mutation.
I'm going to swap out the old author ID with the new one.
And for this review I'm going to go ahead and toss it four stars.
And I'm not going to provide any reason for why I'm giving it four stars if I fire off this operation.
What do I get back.
I get back exactly what I would have expected.
I have all of the information about my new review.
The text value is indeed null which is OK.
None was provided.
And that's fine because the data model allows that it's OK to leave the text off.
So from here all I want to do is actually verify that one everything got created successfully then I'm
going to delete stuff and make sure all of our cascade deletions are working.
So for example what I can do is create another query I'm going to grab all of the books for each book.
What am I going to do.
I will grab its ID its title.
Also grab the author and the ISBN and I'm going to grab all of its related data as well.
So I am going to grab the reviews for the book and for each review I am going to get all of these scalar
fields ID the optional text and the rating.
And I'm also going to grad the user name of the person who left the review.
So right here we are going to grab on each review the author field and in that case I will grab my ID
and username.
So that is quite the operation but its going to allow us to see everything that was created and if I
actually fire that off what do we get.
We get our one book back we have the book rest by Alex paying.
It looks like I actually forgot to leave the title and the title is just head and down below there it
is.
There is the ISBN as well.
Then we have that revues property and we have our two reviews the first one.
It was a good read five stars by sleepy gal.
The second one no reason why it was a four star rating by sleepy guy.
Perfect.
Let's wrap things up by deleting some data.
We're going to delete one of those users and make sure its review goes away.
Then we're going to delete the book and make sure the other review goes away.
I'll start by deleting the sleepy guy user so I have his ID right here.
I'm going to grab that and over here I will use the delete user mutation.
Delete user we are going to pass in the necessary arguments which for deleting is just where we can
delete a user by its user name which is unique or it's ID which is unique.
I am going to delete it by its ID and I will just grab the ID and the user name of the person I've removed.
If I fire this operation off I can see right here that the user was indeed deleted.
And if I refresh my request over here I should see there's only one review for the book.
Right here I fire it off.
And now there is only one review of both the user and that user's reviews were correctly deleted.
The last thing I want to do is delete the book and make sure the last review gets removed.
So I'm going to set up one more tab mutation.
I'm going to delete the book we're going to pass in all of the necessary arguments where as an object
where we provide the ID of the book to remove I have that I.D. sitting right in the output over here
I'll pass that in as the value.
And then in terms of the response I'm just going to grab the ID and the title of the book that was deleted
and if I fire this operation off right here I can see the book was deleted.
The last thing to do is make sure there are now zero reviews.
There are plenty of ways I could test that I can use P.G. admin or create a query.
I'm going to go with the query approach.
I will set up a query operation right here.
We are just going to ask for the reviews and for each review.
All I want is the ID.
So right here ID I fire that off and what do I get back.
I get back an empty array because there are no reviews in the database.
So there we go.
This challenge was designed to get you thinking about how you might model other applications using Prisma
or more generally using graphs.
Well we can model whenever we want maybe I'm creating a Web site for managing flights.
I can model all of that with graphs.
Well I can have a flight type I can have a customers type.
I might even have a type for staff members who are going to be on that flight whether they're pilots
or whether they are stewardesses.
So all sorts of that stuff can be modeled using what we have here.
You can also model something like Air B and B I can have rooms I can have reviews I can have bookings
I can have users.
All of that can be modeled using type definitions and relationships between those types.
All right.
That's where we're going to stop for this section.
The whole goal of this section was to just get us up and running with Prisma in the next section.
We're actually going to integrate this into our node API and we're going to start focusing on features
like authentication to create that real world app.
We're working towards it for now we can close all of the open files and we can collapse that Prisma
Review Web site directory.
We're not going to be working with that directly for a little while though there might be a challenge
later where I ask you to expand on that.
All right let's jump into the next video which is the section intro for the next section.