Welcome to section number 10 we spent this class creating our application from scratch.
We built it up over time integrating new tools along the way.
We started with graphical yoga.
Then we introduced tools like Prisma Heroku jast Apollo and more.
Now what if we're ready to start a second project what do we do.
Do we create an empty folder and configure all of these again and getting them to play nice together.
The answer is no we don't.
We already did that.
All of these tools are set up and configured in our blogging application.
But we're going to do in this section is create a boilerplate version of that.
So we're going to get all of the blogging specific stuff leaving you with a nice boilerplate project
you can use as a starting place in the future.
Then in the second video I'll show you how to actually use this.
So we'll go through the process of cloning the boiler plate and getting it set up in development test
and production.
I'm excited to get to this as it's going to give you a great way to get started with future projects.
Let's go ahead and jump right in.