We've spent this course building out a blogging application using graft.
Well but what happens when we're ready to build our next app.
Do we start from square one with an empty directory and start installing and configuring things.
And the answer is No.
We've already done all of the heavy lifting and to get graphed you Ellen Prisma playing nice together.
And we're not going to throw that away.
Instead what we're going to end up doing is duplicating the graph.
Q El Prisma directory then we're going to remove everything from it.
That's specific to a blogging application and we'll leave in place just a bare bones project that we
can build from.
So we're going to end up removing features like comments and posts which are pretty specific to a blogging
app and we'll end up keeping things like users and authentication which we're likely going to need no
matter what application we're building.
In the end we're going to have something that we can still run deploy and test.
It's just not going to be as full featured but it'll give us a good starting point for a new distinct
app.
So first things first.
Let's go ahead and close all files and collapse all directories and we're not going to touch the graphic.
Well Prisma folder at all that's still going to contain our blogging app.
What I'm going to do is create a new directory a copy of our project and I'll go ahead and call this
something like graft UL hyphen Prisma hyphen boilerplate.
This is going to be the folder we can copy when we're ready to start a new project.
This is going to contain everything that our application needs to get up and running.
It looks like a couple of them files are lagging behind.
They should be loaded in in a moment.
And in essence what we're going to do is go through all of our source code files one by one getting
things that we no longer want is actually not going to be that painful of a process as we're mostly
just going to be removing things all of the folders are here.
So we're just going to go top to bottom throughout the video.
But make sure you are deleting things from well Prisma boilerplate and not from your graphics.
Well Prisma project as always you can grab the final boilerplate in the lecture zip for this one the
configure your factory can stay exactly the same.
We have configuration files for our three environments and none of these contain anything specific to
the blogging app.
So we're going to leave that in place and the disk folder and the node modules folder those are both
generated directories and there is no need to copy those over to the new project as we can just regenerate
them by running our NPM scripts.
Next up we have the Prisma folder.
And in this folder there are some files we're going to end up changing actually.
Just one the data model file.
So docker can pose can stay exactly as it is.
So can Prisma dot why I smell the only file We're going to change is data model data graph.
Well this does contain things specific to the blogging app like post and comment definitions.
What I'm going to do is delete the comment and delete posts from there.
We're going to modify user all of the fields can stay in place except for posts and comments which now
need to go since those types have been removed.
I'm going to delete those two fields leaving things like ID name email and password in place.
And now we have the final version of our data model file.
From here we can close down all of those files were actually all done with the Prisma directory and
that's going to bring us to the next folder Prisma it Review Web site.
If you remember you created this a long time ago when we first explored Prisma as a challenge.
This already exists in the graph.
Prisma folder.
There's no need to have it in both places and it's not going to be part of our boilerplate so I'm going
to go ahead and delete that file perfect from there.
That brings us to the source directory and we have a lot of code inside of here and we want to move
delicately.
We want to extract the things we don't want while still leaving the things we do want in place the generated
directory can stay in place.
We can always generate a new Prisma digraph file using our NPM script but the folder should indeed stay
the resolvers folder contains a bunch of stuff which needs to change.
First off we actually want to delete the comment dot J S file completely.
And we're also going to delete post.com J as we are indeed going to leave the other files including
user data.
J.S. in place for the moment.
I'm going to shut down the test suite just so that doesn't run in the background that's going to start
running as we change files and we won't be done all of the changes so obviously things will fail we'll
start that up near the end.
To make sure that everything's still working the first file we have in here is index not J S in here.
All I need to do is remove the imports for a post and comment which no longer exists.
And then I'm also going to remove those two properties on the resolvers object just leaving these for
queery nutation subscription end user.
We can save this file and move on to the next one.
That is mutation.
J S.
Now in here we have a bunch of imports.
None of these are comment or post specific.
They are all related to users and authentication.
So we're going to leave those.
We're also going to leave create user log in delete user and update user.
The last six are going to go.
I'm going to start with the comma.
We're going to delete create post delete post update post as well as create comment delete comment an
update comment.
All of those are going to go.
The last mutation listed should be update user.
Assuming your stuff was in the same order as mine.
Now everything inside of here is user specific.
We want to keep that functionality.
There is nothing related to posts and comments so we're good to go.
I'm going to save this file and move on to queery.
Jay ass in here we have some queries that do indeed need to get deleted.
First up we have users that can stay.
We have my posts that's going to go we also have post which needs to go.
Then we have comment which needs to go.
We then have.
Me and me can stay.
So at this point we have users then a comma and then me after me what do we have.
We have a post that's going to go and that's the last one.
So let's remove it and there we go.
This leaves two properties on our queery object users and to me now that we have this in place we can
go ahead and save the query dot J ass I'm going to close this file down and we're going to move on to
subscription and Dot Jay ass in here.
We have a couple of subscriptions comment post and my post.
All of these are specific to the blogging app and I'm actually going to delete all three that's going
to leave us with an empty subscription object and you might say well why not just get rid of this altogether
if it's an empty object.
And remember the whole point is to give us a boilerplate we can build off of if we want new subscriptions.
In our next project it's going to be really easy to do.
If the file is already in place in linkup So we're going to keep it.
Next up we have user datt Jay ass.
There are two custom resolvers we have here.
One for the Post's field and one for the e-mail field.
We are going to delete the one for the posts field altogether.
That's going to leave one property on user email that can indeed stay exactly as it is.
Next up we have the utils directory and the utos directory is already good to go.
All of that is utility functions for working with authentication and users.
So there's no need to delete anything there.
Next up after you tells We have DBI.
Jay asks.
We haven't used this file in for ever.
This was created earlier in the course before we were even saving our data with Prisma.
This can indeed be deleted and next on our list.
We have indexed.
J s index yes is very generic and can stay as it is.
After that we have Prisma ADOT J s Prisma J ass.
Also has code that's going to stay as is but we have down below a whole bunch of comments from when
we first learned how to use Prisma.
These can indeed be removed.
I'm going to delete everything.
Wrapping up the file with our Prisma export.
Perfect after Prisma we have schema dot graph.
Q Well this contains queries mutation subscriptions and type definitions for things that we now want
to remove.
First up on line 1 we import post order by input and comment order by input.
Those are no longer going to exist in the new Prisma project.
So right here we're just going to import user order by input.
Perfect.
Now for our queries we have a user end to me which are going to stay.
Post is going to end up going so well posts my posts and comments so I'm going to take a moment to delete
those three.
This leaves just two.
Excellent.
Next up we have our mutations create user log delete user and update user can stay.
These last 6 there are going to go ahead and get deleted just like we deleted them from our file earlier
in this video that leads just those four matching up with the four we have over in the mutation.
J.S..
File 1 2 3 4.
Next up we have our subscriptions and we deleted all of those.
So we're going to delete them all from here as well and after that we have some in types.
We have auth payload that's going to stay.
We have create user input logon user input update user input.
Those are going to stay then we have create post input update post input and then we have the same thing
for comment.
Those four are going to end up getting deleted since they are no longer necessary.
That brings us to our type definitions.
We are going to remove comment and post altogether and on user We're going to remove the comments and
posts field.
We have our mutation type next that can stay.
Then we have our subscriptions.
Those got deleted so we can delete the payloads as well.
There we go.
Schema diagram is all done.
Next up we have server dot J as the final file in the source directory.
Here we do a few things.
One being importing DBI.
I'm going to remove the import and we were using it right here.
Passing it onto the context but we actually weren't using that property from the context any more.
We refactored that out some time ago so we can delete that save the file.
And that wraps up the changes necessary for the source directory.
I'm going to go ahead and close all open files and we're going to move on to the tasks directory where
once again will mostly be deleting stuff.
The changes to the test directory are going to be much smaller.
Let's go ahead and start with geste.
That's just a start up and a shut down of the server that's going to happen no matter what app or building
under utils we have get clients that can stay exactly as it is.
We have the old get client as well.
Now we also have operations and seed database and operations.
We're going to remove operations unrelated to users so create user get users log in get profile.
Those can stay.
We're gonna remove get posts.
We're also going to remove my posts.
Update post create posts delete posts delete comment subscribe to comment and subscribe to posts so
all of those are gonna go.
And then we're also going to remove their exports as well leaving just in my case the first for the
same exports as constants.
We left up above.
All right that is it for the operations file.
The next file we have in the mix is see database.
Now we do still want to see the database with some users so we can still test the user related functionality.
Posts and comments though those are going to go.
I'll be removing comment to comment one post to and post one leaving just user one end user to in place
down below.
There is no longer a need to delete many comments or to delete many posts as those are no longer going
to exist after we create the first two users we can remove everything else.
Here we do create post 1 Excuse me.
Then we create post 2.
Then we create comment 1 and we create comment to all of that was great while we were building out that
app but now it doesn't serve much of a purpose.
The last line in the file is where we have our exports.
We removed these four variables which means we have to remove the export as well.
Excellent.
Next up on our list are the individual test suites.
The comment test suite that's just going to get trashed.
No need to keep that file in place the same thing is true with the post test suite that can go their
users to test suite that contains all of the test cases associated with user related functionality.
And if you look at the imports of what we're testing it's just the four things we left and we're not
even importing comment or post from the C database file.
So this file can stay as is.
No need to change anything.
The last change that's necessary is a big picture change.
If you remember in the schema graphs you all file in the source directory.
We got rid of all of our subscriptions.
Having a type like this with nothing defined is actually invalid.
If we're going to define the subscription type we have to set up at least one that we don't need any.
So we're just going to comment this code out.
Removing the subscription type completely if we are copying this boilerplate to create a new project
in the future we would just uncomment this and add our subscription in.
Now if we are removing the subscription type from graph Q L we also have to remove it from all resolvers.
Now I'm not going to delete the file because once again we want to make it easy to get started in the
future.
All I'm going to do is comment out this one line right here where the subscription property gets set
up so we're no longer passing subscription into graph.
Q L yoga and we no longer have the subscription type and there we go.
We are all done.
We have a complete boilerplate project that could easily be duplicated as we want to work on something
new.
The last thing we're going to do is put it under version control.
Now it is indeed under version control but we're going to wipe that repository and start with a nice
clean one for the new boilerplate code to do this from the terminal.
I'm going to CD out of the graph Q prism folder and into graft.
Well Prisma boiler plate perfect once we're in there.
I'm going to clear the output and we're going to use a few commands to wipe the old repository completely
and then create a new one committing the boilerplate code right here.
We can use the R M command to remove the repository.
So our.
With the RF flag that's going to recursively delete a directory as well as all of its contents and the
folder we're trying to delete is dot get that's where the get repository is stored.
Now it's important to run this command exactly as typed from this exact folder.
Otherwise you might delete something you actually want to keep around in this case.
We are indeed safe by running it from this directory and once it's done we no longer have a repository
from there we're going to create a new one with a get in it.
We are going to use get at with DOT to add all of the files to the repositories staging area to be committed.
Now once again we already have good ignore in place so will be ignoring the dist config and node modules
folder down below.
You can always run a command like get status just to make sure everything looks right before committing.
Here we have files from the tests the source and the Prisma directories and we also have our root files
about 5 of them.
Everything looks good so let's go ahead and commit.
I'm going to use.
Get commit with the M flag to set up my message inside of quotes.
Let's use init commit and we are done.
We now have a complete get repository that we can use associated with our boilerplate project.
If you're wondering how exactly we're going to use the boiler plate project Well lucky you we're going
to cover the entire setup process in the next one.
You'll learn exactly what steps you need to take to use the boiler plate to start up a brand new project.
I'm excited to get to it.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.