We have our boilerplate project directory.
And in this video we're going to learn how to use that.
So we're going to duplicate it and we're going to get it set up as the starting point for some other
dummy project.
Let's go ahead and do just that right here I'll kick things off by duplicating the directory.
We don't want to modify the boilerplate directly for our new application.
That defeats the purpose.
The goal is to keep that around as an easy starting point.
I'm going to duplicate it and I'll call this something like books from boiler plate.
Perfect just a name that suggests exactly what it is.
A little books app based off of the boiler plate.
And we're going to go ahead and spend our time in this folder and to kick things off.
Let's go ahead and change directories into that folder.
I'm going to use C.D dot dot to get out of the boilerplate folder then CD books hyphen from hyphen boiler
plate.
Perfect from here.
The first thing we're going to do is make sure that Prisma is up and running and we're going to start
by deploying Prisma to both the dev and test environment.
So in the config directory we're going to be cracking open the DEF file and the test file.
Let's go ahead and start with the dev file.
What we need to do is update the endpoint.
We're going to deploy to our local docker instance right here.
Default default that's already taken.
So I'm going to use something like.
Forward slash I'll use food as the service name and then whatever I want for the stage name in this
case I can use dev over and test.
Ian V I am going to use forward slash food so I'm using the exact same service name and for the stage
name I'll use test.
So we have the food app in a test environment and we have the food app in a development environment.
Now we can actually deploy both of those by changing directories into the Prisma folder and running
Prisma deploy it twice.
I'm going to run Prisma deploy with the flag providing a path to the config file.
Let's start with the dev environment.
So dot dot to get out of the Prisma folder.
Forward slash config forward slash right here dev dot envy.
Now if we actually run this it's going to go through the real deployment process.
It's going to set up the new service and new stage.
And if I scroll up through the success output for here deploying a service food to stage Dev and we
can see that our user type was created which is a great start.
The next thing we're going to do is deploy the test so I can just reload the same command using the
up arrow key.
I'll switch over the file name from dev NV to test dock EMV to deploy to the test environment as well.
Once that's done we're ready to do something a bit more interesting.
So I'm going to CD out of the Prisma folder and use clear and the go from here is to actually get our
app up and running in both the dev and test environments.
First things first.
Let's go ahead and run NPM install to actually install all of our dependencies remember.
We did not include those in the boilerplate since they can just be generated by running the install
command.
Now once that's done the next thing we're going to do is get a correct generated file.
So we're going to get a new version of source generated Prisma graph.
And remember we have a package Jason's script.
We can run to get that done.
So the process isn't going to be too bad.
I'm going to take a moment to cut the video to when the modules are installed.
Now that everything is installed we can go ahead and use our get schema script but remember that's going
to grab the L from the dot graphical config file.
We're going to switch that over to the correct one for our dev environment.
That's food dev.
So right here localhost 4 4 6 6 forward slash food forward slash dev.
Once we have that small change made we can now run that script NPM run get a hyphen schema that is going
to fetch the brand new schema making sure that we can actually use that right here.
We can see the source was indeed updated which is a good thing.
I would expect some changes since the last time we ran that command we also had the comment and post
types in place.
Now we can clear the terminal output and we're going to go ahead and get our app running in the test
environment to do that.
All we have to do is run NPM run test.
We're going to start up the test suite now when just runs it might not actually run any test cases.
It's saying that no files have changed.
So why would the output change.
And it's right we can always use a task force just to rerun things and for our own sanity we can make
sure that everything is set up correct.
Right here we have five passing tests which is fantastic.
Now what I'm going to do is shut down the test suite.
That's how you would start it up if you were building out this app.
And we are going to start up the development environment.
So right here.
Let's go ahead and get that done.
That would be NPM a run at Dev like we've done plenty of times before.
Hopefully our app starts up correctly and it looks like the server is up and if we were to head over
to localhost 4000 and give things a refresh I would expect to see our updated schema we have our two
queries we have our four mutations and our subscriptions are completely gone.
So it looks like the development version of the app is working really well too and I could go ahead
and fire something off just to verify that I'm going to remove the auth headers for the users query
I'll fire that off.
And what do we get back.
We get back an empty array as expected.
So that's the process to get the death and test environment up and running when working with the boiler
plate project.
Now let's get things up and running in production since we've knocked out Devyn test first up.
We're going to make a small change to prod EMV like we did for Devyn test.
The stage can stay the same as Prod. but right here the service name.
I'm going to swap out for something new.
I'll call this once again food which is what I used for Dev and test that you r l itself can stay exactly
the same.
Use the same server that we set up previously in the class.
You could always create a new one if you wanted to via Prisma cloud.
Now I'm going to go ahead and save product envy.
We're going to navigate back into the Prisma directory and deploy to production.
So CD Prisma then after that I'll use clear just to bring things up off the bottom of the screen and
I'll be using it Prisma deploy it with the E flag dot dot forward slash config forward slash Prod. dot
envy.
This is going to deploy our Prisma books back end if we go ahead and run it.
It's going to move through that process and in just a few moments we should see the brand new service
and stage set up up above we can see the user was created the service food and the stage Prod. that
now lives over in Prisma cloud.
From here the last thing to do now that the Prisma app is deployed is to deploy our node app and it
will go through that process quickly using the Heroku command line interface so we're going to create
a new app.
We're going to set up the environment variables and we're going to push our code up.
First things first we'll be seeing out of the Prisma folder or getting back to the root of our books
project then we'll use Heroku create to create a new Heroku application.
Once the app is up and running we're going to have to get all of these environment variables set on
Heroku.
I'll start by using Heroku config Colon's set like we've done before and we're just going to copy them
over.
I'm going to grab the first line.
I'll paste that in with a space between set and P in Prisma.
Then after that I'll type another space.
I can grab the second one and paste that in.
And finally the third one are JWT secret.
I will add a space and paste that in.
Now if we run that it's going to set all of those environment variables and we could always use Heroku
config just to confirm they got set as expected.
Here we have all three.
Next up we're going to go ahead and actually commit all of our changes so we can do that by running.
Get commit with the AM flag to commit our changes right here I am going to type in set up book project.
So it's basically the initial commit for the book project and once we have that in place we can push
it up to Heroku.
Now Heroku when we ran Heroku create automatically created that remote get remote.
Is going to reveal that to us it's always called Heroku and to deploy it we'll be using get push Heroku
master to push our code up.
Right here it is indeed pushing the code up to the Heroku remote.
It's going through the deployment process and once it's done we should be able to visit our app you
Arel and see the production version of our little book application.
Now we haven't added anything specific to books to the app but this would be the starting point.
That was everything necessary to get dev test and prod configured.
I'm going to go ahead and cut the video to when the Heroku deployment is done.
All right.
Everything is done.
I have the app you are all right here.
I am going to click that to bring me over to the Heroku app.
And what do we get.
We get our version of graph Q Al playground for the book's production app right here.
I can see my schema I'd be able to fire off the queries and mutations that I'd be able to fire off in
dev or test.
So there we go in just a matter of a few minutes.
We got up and running with the graph.
Q Well project from here we can add new features add new test cases and build out our graphic application
to fit our needs.
I am going to leave the little books from a boiler plate project inside of here and you can always download
it by downloading the lecture zip for this one.
That's going to contain everything we've written in the course so far including the code for the books
example.
All right.
That's it for this video.
I'll see you in the next one.