Welcome to Section 9 in this section you're finally going to learn how to interact with your graphics
API from outside of just graphical playground.
That's going to allow us to do a couple of very exciting things.
Number one you're going to learn how to interact with your application from the browser.
So we'll see what it takes to do something like fetch a list of posts and render those to the screen.
That's going to allow you to build out a front end for your graph QOL applications.
The other exciting thing we're going to talk about is setting up an automatic test suite.
So you're going to learn how to write test cases for your graphic app that verify it's always working
as expected.
This is going to prevent bugs from getting into production and messing with real user data.
I'm excited to get to all of this.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the very first video.