It's time to start setting up our automated test suite for our graphical application.
Now in this video in particular we're going to focus on creating a third environment so we have a development
environment.
We have a production environment and if we're going to be setting up an automated test suite we also
want a test environment in place.
Now if you're wondering why we need a test environment and a separate place in the database for our
test data it's because our test suite this automatic process that we're going to set up it's going to
be interacting with the database quite a bit.
We're going to be setting up dummy test data so that the code we run can actually get data back and
we can assert that everything is working correctly.
This is going to happen over and over again and we're going to be manipulating the database a whole
bunch.
So it's best to not interfere with our production or our development data.
Now the good news is that deploying is going to be a super simple process.
We're going to make a new environment very similar to the dev environment.
So let's go ahead and kick things off by creating a new file in the config directory called Test dot
NVI.
Now to start we can actually just grab the contents of dev Dom Ian V.
So I'm going to copy these three lines to the clipboard.
I'm going to bring them over to the test environment file.
And the only line we're going to change is the Prisma endpoint.
Now if you remember from much earlier in the class there's actually two things that the Prisma endpoint
specifies.
Aside from the actual You Arel the service end of the stage and by default both are default.
That's why we see default dollar sign default in our development database.
This is the default service and the default stage what we're going to do is override those values.
So for Devcon EMV as an example I could set up a forward slash default for the service name then forward
slash default for the stage name.
And this would be exactly the same as the code we have right here.
These are identical because default is the default over intestate envy.
I'm going to use forward slash default.
So we'll stick with the default service name.
But then for the stage name I'll switch that up.
Calling it something like Test.
So now we have two separate places in the database.
One for development data and one for test data.
And this is a good thing.
Now that's the only change we actually need to make it to the test NVI file.
From here we're actually ready to deploy our test environment to Prisma.
So from the terminal Let's go ahead and use the CD command to navigate into the Prisma directory.
And from here we're going to use Prisma deploy.
That's going to be Prisma the deploy we are going to provide the e argument so we can provide the path
to the configuration file we want to use which is this one.
So that would be a dot dot to get out of the Prisma folder.
Forward slash config to go into that directory then forward slash.
Test dot envie.
Excellent.
Let's go ahead and actually round this to deploy the test environment.
As always it's going to go through the process of communicating to our Prisma server.
Right here we can see all of the stuff it did and sense it is a brand new stage.
We can see that it created everything that's necessary and down at the bottom.
Everything went well it successfully applied those changes.
And over inside of PGE admin.
If I right click the schemas list and click refresh.
We now have a new one.
We had default dollar sign test.
This is where we're going to have all of our test data.
That data is going to be manipulated automatically via code and that code is something we're going to
work on creating next in the next video will configure that tool will be using for our test suite.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.