In this video you're going to be installing and exploring just the testing framework that we're going
to be using throughout this section.
We'll talk more about what exactly a test framework is.
But in short it's going to give us all of the tools we need to make it really easy to write test cases.
And in this video you'll learn what those are to by writing our very first test cases.
Now these initial test cases are going to test our graft application.
We're just going to explore how things work with geste.
Then as the section progresses we'll actually start to test our.
Well queries mutations and subscriptions to kick things off.
Let's go ahead and pull up the website for the just testing framework.
We can find that by heading over to the browser and going to just J s dot.
So here there is a bunch of great resources for using the tool.
The two main pages are docs and API docs contains a lot of guides showing you how to do specific things
with jast.
They will be covering much of this in the D.S. itself and the API page contains all of the various methods
and tools that Jeste provides.
And this is a page you will be referring to throughout this section as we explore new features.
For now though we can go ahead and install geste and geste installs as a module.
So from our project all we're going to do is run NPM install wups.
Let's go ahead and CD to the root of the project first.
NPM install then the module itself which is just at twenty three point five point zero which is the
latest version.
And it just is going to be a local module only not something that's needed in production.
So I can use the save dev flag to save that as a development dependency package.
Jason So this is going to go through the installation process.
Grabbing everything the framework has to offer.
And over in Patrick Gadot Jason we'll see that gests dependency show up in just a moment.
Once we have just installed we're going to go through the basic process of creating a test suite from
scratch.
So down below everything went well and we had it listed as a dev dependency.
But we're going to do now is create a test script now by default package.
Jason gives us a test script and it just dumps a message to the terminal when you run it saying that
there is no test suite specified.
We're going to go ahead and fix that by running just instead.
So there's nothing fancy we have to provide after just oh we will explore some arguments later.
For now it's enough to simply run the just command.
Let's go ahead and see what happens when we run the test script down below in the terminal.
I'm going to use clear to clear the terminal output and then I'm going to run NPM run test to fire off
our test script.
This is going to run geste and jestice going to try to run the test suite but we haven't created one
yet.
So it's going to fail and that's OK.
Let's go ahead and run it and see what errors we get.
Right here we do indeed have an error.
And if I scroll way up to the top we can see where it ran are just command.
And the first thing just said is that no tests have been found and that's true just it uses a specific
pattern to look for test files in our application and we haven't created any.
Let's go ahead and create one.
So just can actually detect it.
What we're going to do is make a new jur rectory in the root of our graph.
Well Prisma project.
So right here along side of the source directory and the Prisma directory.
I'm going to make a new one called tests and this folder name is specific.
Gest is specifically looking for a folder that has the tests name and in there we're going to end up
putting all of our test files.
So let's go ahead and create our very first one.
Now there's also a method to naming your test file so geste can detect it.
This is done by adding the dot test and Dot JSE extension onto the end so we can call our file as an
example user dot test dot J as we could call it something like post dot test dot J.S. or something like
order dot test dot J ass right here.
Let's go ahead and stick with that initial one user dot test dot Jay ass.
This is going to be the test file that contains individual test cases for user related functionality
so things like signing up and logging in and fetching your profile and updating your email.
Now we have a single test suite in place and our test suite is nothing more than a file with that correct
extension in the correct directory.
A test suite is a file that just is going to detect Down below.
I'm going to run the exact same command I ran before.
I'm going to run NPM run test.
This is going to fire off just again.
And well things are still going to fail.
They're going to fail with a different message if I scroll up.
We have the part where they originally ran the Jeste command.
Then we have a failure and it's related to the user dot test that J S file.
So this already is a big step in the right direction.
Gest was indeed able to detect our test suite because of the naming conventions we used down below.
We have an error test suite failed to run your test suite must contain at least one test.
Right now we have an empty file we definitely don't have a test so let's go ahead and fix that.
Adding our very first test case now jest it detects and executes our test file.
It's injecting a whole bunch of just specific stuff that we can use to build up our test suite.
And one of them is a function called test that allows us to define individual test cases.
And it's a function we'll be calling over and over again.
It's injected as a global.
So we'll call it like this.
And we passed to just two important pieces of information.
The first is a strain.
This is the name for our test case.
It describes exactly what we're trying to test.
We're going to be writing dozens of test cases.
So it's important to stay organized.
And the second argument we passed to the test function is a function.
We're going to pass in a function and this is the function that runs some code and makes sure that code
worked as expected.
So in this function for example I might fetch all of my draft posts and make sure I got the correct
number back for the moment.
Let's go ahead and create a dummy test case.
I'm going to set up a name for this one.
This is my first test case.
Then we're going to save the test suite and down below in the terminal.
Once again I will be executing NPM run test this time around the test suite is going to work we're not
going to get an error.
And right here we have the output.
This is the beginning where it ran the Jeste command and we can see that our test suite the file user
test.
J.S. it is indeed passing which means that all of the test cases inside of it succeeded and those are
listed out as well.
Right here we have just one.
This is my first test case.
It passed and it took just one millisecond to do so.
Down below at the bottom we have some input about the entire process.
All of our test suites they all passed all of the individual test cases we just have one and it passed
then we have snapshots which we're not going to be using.
That's more for our user interface development.
And finally we have the total time that it took to start up run and finish the test suite just 1.5 seconds.
Now at this point we have a test case in place and we've already ran to the NPM test script multiple
times.
There's actually an option we can use on our just command that's going to cause the geste sweet to rerun
as our files change.
This is the hyphen hyphen watch option and that is going to make sure that when our test files change
or when the code we're testing changes that everything restarts.
So now what do we do.
Well we can go ahead and talk about where the documentation for Watch lives over inside of the geste
API page where we were before.
If I scroll way to the bottom there are just CLID options.
That's actually an entire page on its own.
And in the sidebar there are all sorts of options we can use most.
Not particularly useful for our purposes but down below we do indeed have the watch option and we can
see exactly what that does.
Watches are files for changes and then reruns the correct tests.
So now that we have that in place we can go ahead and run the test suite again.
NPM run test this time around.
So it's not going to finish.
We're not going to be brought back to the command prompt.
It's going to sit and wait.
Right here we can see that things still succeeded and down below we can see we now have a whole bunch
of options.
So I can use the key for example to rerun all of the test cases again.
I can use w to show more options and use a different option.
I can use some of these to filter and run just a specific set of my test cases.
All sorts of interesting things.
But in general we're not going to be using these watch options.
We're just using it so that when we do make changes to our test file the test suite reruns for example
I'm going to go ahead and just add a little line in here one plus two.
I'm going to save the file down below the test suite Re-Read.
And we do indeed still have a single passing test case.
Now it's Challenge time it's going to be up to you to create a new test case and this is an easy one.
But I wanted to give you a little experience working with that test function.
So you're going to create a second test case by using the test function.
You're going to pass in a name for your test.
You can use anything you like and you're going to pass in the function argument and you can just leave
that empty.
Then I'd like you to save the file and ensure that your second test case shows up in the output and
that it is indeed passing.
So take some time to knock that one out and when you're done come back and click play
how that go let's go ahead and kick this one off by calling test.
So up above or down below.
Order doesn't matter.
I am going to call test with the two arguments we have to provide.
First up a string name and second up a function to run and we can pick whatever name we like for this
test case.
I'll just say my second test ever.
Perfect.
Now we can actually save the file.
And down below we have new information under our test suite.
We have two test cases.
Down below we have one test suite passing.
We only have one test file and we have two individual test cases.
And now at this point you're probably wondering what exactly we put inside of our test functions and
you might even be wondering why these test cases are passing if they're not really doing anything.
We're going to talk about all of that and more in the very next video.
We're actually going to be testing some functions that will create I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.