In this video you're going to learn how to test real Javascript functions using jest.
So the focus is going to be on these test cases.
We're going to talk about what exactly you're supposed to do inside of them and how exactly everything
related to this test function works.
We'll figure out how to make a test fail and how to make a test pass allowing us to assert that the
code we're testing is actually working as expected.
Now if we're going to write some test cases we actually need some code to test and for the moment we're
going to continue to hold off on testing our actual graph application.
There's a bit more that's going to go into that setup process and don't worry we will get to that soon.
For now we're just going to create some new functions and write test cases for those over in the source
directory.
Let's go ahead and make a new file in the Utilities folder and I'm going to call this something like
user Dhananjay ass.
And then here we're going to define a couple of functions that will end up writing test cases for the
first function which we're gonna create.
I'll define a concert for it.
It's going to be called Get a first name.
Now as the name suggests it's going to be a very simple function.
The function is going to take in a string a full name and it will return just the first name.
And I can use the split functionality to split the string by the space that returns an array and I'll
just grab the first item.
So right here.
Return.
I'll be using full name dot split.
So here I'm going to split on these space then this is going to be an array so I can grab the first
item by grabbing it by index using 0.
So there we go.
Just a very simple function that we can test to explore how testing works.
Now we're going to use export to make sure that other files can load this in and we are going to export.
The only thing we have.
Get first name perfect.
Now let's go ahead and actually write a test case for this function to make sure it works as expected
over inside of the user test js file.
I'm going to start by deleting all of the test cases.
These ones have dummy names and we're going to create a test case for the function we just define right
here.
We'll be calling the test function once again passing in a string name and a function and we can pick
a name and for the names I typically start off with should saying something like should log in user
or in this case should return first name when given full name.
Now it's really up to you to determine how long you want your test name to be.
Usually it's some sort of short sentence or small set of words.
Now inside of the test function itself it's our job to execute.
Get first name and ensure we get the expected results back.
So the first thing we have to do is inport it up above.
We are going to inport the things we're trying to test.
So right here I'm going to import one of the named exports Well actually the only one.
Get first name then we're going to grab that from the following file.
That's going to be dot dot to get out of the tests folder where this file lives from there in the root
of the project.
We're going to go into the source directory.
Then we're going to go into the Tools Folder and finally we have the little dummy file we created.
We have user dot J as perfect.
So we've created a simple function and export at it.
We've then imported that simple function into our test suite.
Now we can use it inside of the test case right here.
I'm going to go ahead and call it saving the result so I can make sure the result is correct right here.
Konst first name equals or at least should equal whatever comes back from calling get first name.
And I'll just pass in my full name Andrew Mead.
So here we are calling the code we're trying to test.
Then we're getting a value back and the next thing we're going to do is make sure the value we got back
is what we expected.
In this case I would expect first name to be the string.
Andrew assuming that things went well.
The question is how do we tell just whether or not a given test case should pass.
It all has to do with this function right here.
The one we pass as the second argument to test if this function throws an error the test fails if it
doesn't throw an error the test succeeds.
Right now this test and the code it calls is never throwing in errors so things are going well.
We have our test case passing if I were to save the file and let the test suite rerun.
Let's go ahead and throw an error and see what happens.
So right here throw new error and I am just going to provide some sort of error message.
This should trigger a failure as an example.
Now if I go ahead and save things when jest runs this function the function is indeed going to throw
an error Jeste is gonna see that and it's going to say OK that test case should be considered a failure.
If I go ahead and save the test suite down below things rerun and we can see we now have a single test
case and it is indeed failing.
If I scroll up in the output we can see that the test case no longer has a checkmark next to it.
And we even have some information about why the test failed.
In this case this should trigger a failure is the message right here.
That message is coming from our only test case should return first name when given full name.
So if we don't throw an error things should succeed if we throw an error.
Things should be considered a failure in this case.
We can use a little bit of conditional logic to determine whether or not I should throw an error when
would I want to throw an error.
I would want to throw an error if right here the value for first name is not equal to the string.
Andrew if the value is anything but that we know there's a problem with get first name it's not working
as expected.
So right here I would throw an error throw new error and I would say something like expected the string
Andrew.
Perfect.
Now if we actually save the file We're going to see our test case succeed because the function is indeed
working as expected.
And we got the result we actually wanted.
Now this test case is going to make sure that if that function changes in the future it's still working
as expected.
So let's say later on someone comes through and they're not really sure what the function does and they
mess it up.
Now that's a bit hard to believe sense at the moment it's a very simple function.
But as our code gets more complex testing becomes more and more important.
So right here all I'm going to do is split on an empty string and that's going to split on every single
character.
So if I go ahead and save the code the test suite is going to rerun testing our new version of get first
name and down below we do indeed have an error.
We can see that our test case failed.
It did not get back the result that was expected.
So by throwing errors from test cases we can go ahead and say that one thing succeeded or one thing
failed.
Now in this case we do want to bring our get first name function back to a nice working state.
So I will split on a space and what I want to talk about now before we add any more test cases is how
we can make these assertions a bit easier just actually provides us with a series of tools for doing
all sorts of interesting things we can for example ensure that one value equals another.
Or I can ensure that an array as a given item inside of it.
Let's head back over to the geste documentation and in that sidebar we're going to scroll to the bottom
once again and the page we're looking for is expect this contains a whole bunch of information about
the expect function that Jeste provides.
So similar to how Jeste provides test.
Jess also provides expect and it comes with all sorts of different methods that we can use to make very
interesting assertions I can expect one value to be another.
I can expect that a given function has been called I can expect some value to have been returned or
I could expect a number to be greater than some other number.
There are a lot of interesting assertions here and for each we can click it to learn exactly how it
works in this one.
We're going to start with.
To be to be is an equality assertion.
So it is going to check that one value equals another and down below.
They use it to assert that the ounces property on the can object defined up here equals 12.
Now it does.
So this test case would pass if it didn't.
The test case would fail.
We can use the exact same code in our test case to replace our existing assertion.
So in our test cases we're not going to be adding if conditionals and we're not going to be manually
throwing errors all of that obviously works but it's not ideal.
Instead we're going to be using expect now with expect we are going to call it as a function and we
are going to pass to it the value we're making an assertion about in this case we're making an assertion
about first name so right here I will pass in first name.
Next up we use one of the methods available on expect and those were all listed in the documentation.
We saw things like to be for example and that's the one that will end up using now to be also takes
in an argument which the documentation defines it takes in a value to compare.
So in this case we are going to pass in the value we're expecting that is the string Andrew.
So this code does the exact same thing as this code but with less work and less maintenance.
If I go ahead and save the user test suite once again things are indeed going to pass.
Let's go ahead and break the function one more time by removing the space and saving the file and I
would expect things to be failing and they are now the reason I wanted to trigger that failure once
again.
Aside from proving that things do indeed fail is to show you that just provides us with much better
error messages than we would be able to easily write on our own up above under the test case name we
have a whole bunch of information about why exactly things failed in this case.
We can see the expected value was during Andrew but the actual received value was the string a.
And that's obviously not identical to the test case failed the code inside of expect through an error
for us allowing us to avoid having to do all of that work manually.
So when we use geste And when we use expect it's going to be really easy to write our test cases.
I'm going to add that space back in save the file.
We can then remove our commented out code and there we go.
We have our very first test case.
We run the function we're trying to test we then assert something about how that function operated.
Now we might write multiple test cases for functions in our application.
We'll certainly be doing that for the graph.
Kulap Let's go ahead and write one more test case together.
Then there's a challenge for you to write a couple of new test cases for a different function we'll
be defining.
Let's go ahead and add that second test case by calling test once again passing in our string name and
the function to actually run this test case is going to ensure that when I pass in just the first name
to get first name I get the first name back.
So in our database some users might provide the full name.
Others might just provide their first name.
Either way we need that code to work.
So I want to write multiple test cases passing in different values right here.
Should returner first name when given a first name.
Excellent.
Now inside of the function we can start by calling get first name.
So Konst first name equals whatever comes back from calling and get first name and we'll pass in just
a first name.
I'm going to go ahead and use jet.
Now in this case I can write an assertion and making sure that first name is what I would expect right
here expect first name I'm going to use to be.
Once again it is the main assertion we'll be using throughout this section.
I am going to assert that the value I got back was the string gen.
If it's not that's a problem if it is.
That's great right here.
We can save the user test suite.
And down below we now have two passing test cases.
We were able to verify that indeed get first name function works as expected regardless of whether or
not a full name or just a first name is provided.
Now it's going to be up to you to write a test case for another function that we're going to end up
defining over inside of user dot J as will define the function together and you'll write the test cases
on your own right here.
We're going to create a function called is valid password.
This is going to take in a password and return true if it's valid and false otherwise then we'll write
some test cases that assert it's working as expected.
Right here we're going to take in just a single argument password and we're going to return a boolean.
So let's go ahead and set up the function itself.
Let's start by checking the length of the password.
So I'm going to make sure that the length is greater than or equal to 8 characters.
So all return TRUE saying the password is valid when the password dot length is greater than or equal
to 8.
So if your password is seven characters or less you're going to get false back from the function.
Your passwords are not valid if it's greater than or equal to eight characters.
You'll get true back saying the password is valid.
Which is great.
Let's also add another check.
I'm going to use the logical and operator to also confirm that your password doesn't contain the word
password which is very insecure though quite common right here.
We'll go ahead and do that using the string includes method.
So first up password then dot includes we're going to see if it includes the string password.
If it does that's a problem.
Now currently we have the opposite behavior.
This is going to say the passwords valid when it does include password.
We can flip that by using the logical not operator flipping true to false or false to true.
Now this is also case sensitive.
So if you had upper case P password and your password includes would not catch that.
We can fix that by converting password to lowercase before we use includes right here.
That would be password dot to lower case then dot includes.
So by chaining these together we now have a more secure version of is valid password and that's it for
this function down below we can export it by exporting it along side of get first name.
And once we have that in place we can save this file head over to our user test suite and we're going
to talk about the test cases that you're going to be creating.
Let's go one test case at a time to keep things simple.
The first one.
Create a test case called a should reject a password.
Shorter than eight characters.
And as the name suggests you're going to be importing and using our is valid password function.
You're going to pass in a password that's too short and you're going to use the to be assertion to expect
that the value you get back is false.
So take some time to knock that one out then test your work.
Save the file and you should see three passing test cases down below.
Then come back and click play
how that girl Ahman and kick things off by calling the test function.
We have our test name picked out.
Should reject password shorter than eight characters.
We're gonna set up our test function and we are indeed going to be calling the method that's exported
over here.
So we'll have to import it over here.
Opt-Out is valid password.
Now we can use it down below.
I am going to create a variable is valid.
That will be a boolean and I'm going to get its value from whatever comes back from calling is valid
password.
Now in this case we're going to pass in a password that is too short like ABC 1 2 3 which is only six
characters.
I'm going to expect that I get false back right here expecting that the is valid variable has a value
equal to using the to be method false.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and test things out.
I'm going to save my work and Down below I do indeed have a passing test case.
Now if we were to pass in a password that's too long or if this code was messed up let's say it was
2 instead of 8 we would see an error down below as expected.
Let's bring things back to their working state and talk about the next test case.
I'd like you to create for the is valid password function right here.
That's going to be a test case called should reject a password that contains the word password.
So you're going to pass in a password that contains the full word password.
And once again that should indeed be considered a failure that's not a valid password.
And we want to assert that that's the value we get back.
So take some time to knock this one out.
Test your work by saving the file and when you're done come back and click Play
All right.
How that go.
I'm going to kick things off by calling the test function and passing in that name.
Should reject a password that contains word password.
Excellent we can then set up our function and we can move on to actually calling is valid password right
here.
Konst is valid getting the value from calling is valid password this time we're not going to check the
length so we're going to use 8 characters or more we're checking that the password based validation
works right here.
ABC then the word password with an uppercase P then 0 9 8 that should be considered a failure and once
again I'm going to expect that is valid is indeed false to be false.
Perfect's if I go ahead and run things I would expect a forth passing test case and that is exactly
what we have.
Now comes the final test case where we actually ensure that things work when you meet all of the criteria
of a valid password right here.
A new test case should correctly validate a valid password.
So we want eight characters or more without the word password inside of it takes some time to write
that test case look out for that fifth passing test case down below.
Then come back and click play.
All right.
How'd that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off.
We're going to call test passing in our name.
Should correctly validate a valid password.
We'll pass in our function.
And we're going to get on to calling is valid password once again so Konst is valid.
That is the result.
We'll then call is valid password.
Passing in a valid password.
I'm going to use.
Let's use.
Test 1 2 3 0 9 8 exclamation mark.
Then we're going to assert that the value we get back is true.
So I would expect is valid to indeed be using to be true.
Perfect.
And there we go.
Our final test case in place we have all of the edge cases tested for this function.
And if I save the file we have a fifth passing test case which is fantastic.
Now that we have the test suite up and running all the tests are written we can verify our code works
as expected in just a fraction of a second.
So later on if any changes were made to these functions or they were expanded on we would be able to
validate that they do indeed at least work as expected.
So in this video we explored how we can create test cases that test real javascript code in the next
one we're going to start to learn what we need to learn in order to test our graph.
Q Well application I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.