In this video you're going to learn how to use a library called Appollo client to send off graphic operations
to a graphical API.
The only way we've ever communicated with our application so far is using graphical playground.
Now this is a fantastic tool to use while you're building out your API.
It's also a great tool to use to explore an existing one that you're supposed to consume.
But when it comes to actually making requests from code we don't know how to do that.
And this would be really useful.
We're going to do this for example from our test cases where they test that tries to do something like
sign up a user then will assert the user was actually added to the database.
We also need to be able to do this if we're going to end up building a client for our application.
So we want to be able to fire off an operation like a query from javascript in the browser to fetch
some data and render it to the screen.
That's exactly what we're going to end up doing in this video.
By the end you'll be using Appollo client in the browser to fetch and render data from the graph API.
Now the first thing we're going to do temporarily is shut down our test suite using control-C.
I actually want to run the development server so I can communicate with our graph API and I'm going
to do that by running NPM run dev running our development environment.
And once that's up and running we're going to go ahead and collapse all directories and close all files
and we're going to create a new directory that will be playing around with.
In this video right here we can call this something like Appollo hyphen client perfect.
Now what goes inside of here is in essence going to be a really small Web site.
We're going to have an H TNL file that'll be pretty bare bones and we're also going to have some javascript
that runs and it's that javascript code that's actually going to fetch data from the API and render
it.
Let's go ahead and create this barebones Web site.
I'm going to make a source directory in the Apollo client folder.
Then inside of the source folder I'm going to add a single file index dot each TNL and this file is
going to be a bare bones DML document.
And with Visual Studio code I can actually type out each DML Colan five then click that little option
right there and that's going to generate a bare bones document.
We can use your more than welcome to just type this out if you're using a different editor or use any
barebones boilerplate HVM L5 doc.
Now all we're going to do for the moment is add a script tag and a single div.
So right here I'm going to create a div element and this is where we will end up rendering the published
posts.
So right here Id I'll set an id attribute equal to posts allowing us to target this from javascript.
Then down below I'm going to link in a javascript file that's where the Apollo client code will actually
run and that's where we will work on rendering something to the screen right here.
We're going to set up our script tag and use the source attribute to link in an external javascript
file.
And I'll also be setting up the type attribute setting its value equal to application forward slash
javascript and the source attribute can set equal to something like Dot forwards slash and right here.
We'll just use index dot J as perfect.
So now we have our index dot J.S. file linked in.
Let's go ahead and create it.
I'm going to add it to the source directory index.
Dot J s.
And from here we can just add a little Konsole dot Lague to make sure things are running.
This should show up.
Perfect.
Now we can go ahead and save both files.
And what we're going to do is actually start up this little development server and to do that we're
going to use a really great little tool called parsel parcel is a great little tool and you can learn
more about it by heading over to the browser and going to parcel J s dot org.
Now parsel is similar to web pack.
It is an application bundler.
So it's going to enable things like the import export syntax in the browser and that also runs babbel
by default so we can take advantage of modern javascript regardless of what browser we end up running
in.
It's an awesome little tool and it's going to allow us to get started with zero hassle.
So let's go ahead and crack open a new terminal.
We want to leave our server running in the background and we're going to CD in to the Apollo client
directory and from here we are going to set up parsel.
First up let's install it.
I'm going to run NPM in it from the Apollo client directory to generate a package.
Jason File.
I'll enter through every single question using the default option for each.
I'll hit.
Yes and now the file is created from here we can now install parsel using NPM.
Install the library name itself is called parsel hyphen bundler.
And we're going to grab the latest version one point nine point seven.
And I will use the same dev flag to save that as a development dependency.
No parsel doesn't require a configuration file.
In essence we're just going to be creating a single script in package Dom Jason and that's going to
start everything up.
It'll give us access to import export from index dot J S and that's a good thing because we're going
to be installing Appollo client shortly and in porting it so we can actually fire off a graft operation
from the browser.
Now over inside of package Dom Jason we can set up our script and it's super easy to use parsel right
here.
I'm actually going to delete the test script as we're not going to be creating a test suite for this
little client example.
I'm going to swap that out with the start script and only have to do is run the parsel command and provide
a path to our DML file.
In this case it is source forwards slash index dot TNL.
And there we go.
We're done.
I can now save that package.
Jason down below we can run NPM run it start to execute that start script.
And this is going to start up a web server here it's running on local host 6 4 to 1 4.
I'm going to navigate over to that you're going to have to navigate over to your specific port.
I can actually just use alt and click it to automatically open it up in the browser.
Now if I crack open the developer tools in the console I should be seeing my little console message
showing up and I am.
This should show up is printing.
So now we have a little barebones website.
We have an H DML file and a J S file in the index dot J S file.
We're going to remove our console dot Lague call and we're going to focus on importing Appollo client
and actually firing off a graphical operation to fetch some data from the server.
We're going to knock that out in the next video.
So let's go ahead and jump right into that.