It now that we have our little bare bones web applications set up it's time to figure out how we can
actually communicate with our graphical application from the browser and we're going to have to answer
three questions to get that done one.
How do we define an operation in javascript to.
How do we send that off to the server to fetch a response.
And 3 How do we actually get that response and do something meaningful with it.
For example if I fetch all of the published posts in the browser I probably want to render them to the
screen so the user can actually see them.
As mentioned before we can use Appollo clients to get all of this done and that's exactly what we're
going to do.
We can learn more by heading over to Appollo graph Cuil dot com.
There are two sides to the Apollo ecosystem there is the server.
We already have a server in place and ours graphed Well yoga actually uses the Apollo server behind
the scenes.
On the other side we have the client and that's what we're interested in.
Now there are libraries for things like native iOS and Android.
And we also have all of the web frameworks you would expect we'll be using one of the many Apollo libraries
called Apollo boost to actually fire off requests from javascript code.
And if you were to click over to one of these guides you would see that Apollo boost is used there as
well.
We can find this library by googling Apollo boost.
And once we find it we're looking for this page Apollo boost migration.
Now it's not particularly important to this page isn't showing up in these search results any more but
if I scroll down we can see the basics of getting started with it.
In essence we install a library.
We then import the library.
We then create a new client providing the u r l for our graph.
Q Well back end and from there we can use methods on client client Dom query and client data mutate
to actually fire off things like queries and mutations.
So let's go ahead and knock all of this out from our application.
The first thing we're going to do is shut down the server and install what's necessary to use Appollo
boost.
And there are actually two things we need.
We need the Apollo Boost library and we also need the graphical library.
So right here NPM install First up Apollo high and a boost at the latest version zero point one point
fourteen.
And we're also going to install graphic QOL at the latest version fourteen point zero point to Apollo.
Boost is going to allow us to fire off those operations and graph you and just makes it possible for
us to define graph QOL operations in Javascript.
So I'm going to go ahead and run the installer installing both of those libraries and up above at the
top of index data J S We are going to import a couple of things from Appollo boost.
There are actually two things we're going to grab.
We are going to grab the Apollo boost constructor function which we can use to initialize a client and
we're also going to grab a little utility that makes it easy to define our operations in Javascript.
So right here let's set that up we are going to import those two things.
First up the default export Appollo boost.
Then a comma and in curly braces will be grabbing one unnamed export GQ out then from the library.
We just installed Appollo boost.
Perfect.
So now we have everything imported that we need to actually perform these three steps to define an operation
to send it off and to get the response back.
First up we have to initialize an instance of Appollo boost.
So right here I'm going to create a constant called client and we are going to get its value by using
the new operator with the Apollo boost constructor function.
Now this takes in a single option's object and on here we're going to define a single option.
It's you are I this is going to provide the path to our graph Q L back end.
Now for me that's localhost four thousand.
So right here HTP colon forward slash forward slash local host port four thousand and now down below.
We can actually use client dot query and client dot mutate to perform operations on the backend.
Now if we're going to perform a query which we're going to we would use client dot query.
This is a method and it takes a single options object on here we have to define one property query.
And this is where we list out what type of query we're trying to perform.
This is going to end up looking very similar to what we have over in the left hand side of.
Playground.
So it's a query we're fetching users and we want these fields.
We have to do the same thing when we're making our request from javascript code.
Now the catch is that the query property doesn't accept a string value it actually expects what's known
as an abstract syntax tree.
This is a very complex javascript object which represents a given graph QOL operation.
They're not designed to be created by humans in code.
Instead we get them generated by using utilities.
In this case we'll be using GQ well.
So the long and short of it is that we're going to end up writing strings those strings will get parsed
and we'll past that parsed string down to Appollo boost.
So right here.
Let's go ahead and define the operation we're trying to perform.
I'm going to create a constant I'll call it something like get the users to write.
Here we are going to define a template strain.
Now we're also going to use the tagging feature of template sharings and GQ owl is actually designed
for that.
So by adding this up front it's going to be able to parse our string and right here between those two
back ticks.
I'm going to add a new line and we're going to start defining our operation and it's going to look very
similar to what we have over here.
I'm going to start off with the type.
In this case a query I'm going to say that I want to fetch users so I'll define that.
And then for each user Let's say I wanted their ID and their name.
So we have our operation performed and it is indeed getting parsed.
The next thing to do is to pass it down to client dot query and that's what we're going to do right
here.
I'm going to set the query property equal to get users perfect.
So at this point we would actually be firing off the operation we defined up above.
We just haven't done anything to get the data back to actually do something with the users that get
returned.
As you might have expected the query method returns a promise and that promise resolves when our data
is available right here.
Let's go ahead and toss on a then method call to this promise.
If I was in an async function I could use a wait instead.
Right here we are going to set up the function to run when the promise resolves and we're going to get
access to the response from the server.
Now there are plenty of properties on response that we don't care about.
There is one though that's very important.
It is response dot data right here.
I'm just going to dump it to the console.
So console dot log response dot data.
This contains the actual data we requested back.
I'm going to save index dot J S and down below in the terminal.
We're going to start up our server once again by running NPM run start from the Apollo client directory.
Once it's up and running I will Allt click that you R-AL to actually pull it up in the browser.
And once again I'm going to crack open the developer tools so we can view the console output right here
what do we have.
We have an object.
And if I crack that open we have our users property the one queery we performed on users we have an
array of objects so we have 6 different objects each with an ID and name property.
Exactly what we've fetched over here.
So the first user for example is this object right.
Here we have the ID which we asked for the name which we asked for and also this underscore underscore
type name property this does shows us the type.
In this case it is indeed a user and down below we have our other five users as well.
Now at this point we have the data in the browser and we could go ahead and do anything with it.
We could render it to the user we could save it in local storage.
We could do whatever it is we need to do for the moment.
Let's go ahead and actually render a list of all users to the screen.
Now over in indexical HTL I created a little place to do this a div with the idea of posts and actually
going to switch that over to an idea of users.
Now that we have this in place we're going to target this with javascript and we're going to render
all of the users inside of it.
So let's go ahead and actually get that done by making a few changes to our callback down below.
Right here I'll get started by creating a new constant a concert called TNL and I'll start that off
as an empty string and we'll add to it over time.
Now the last thing we're going to do inside of this function is actually use H DML to render something
to the screen right here.
We'll be using Document dot get element by ID to fetch our element.
I have the ID of users we just changed that over in the index dot age DML file and from here we'll be
setting the inner HVM male property providing our string h DML.
Now at this point nothing's actually going to render because we have an empty string.
The goal right here is to iterate over each user and add something to the DML string so it can actually
get rendered to the screen right here.
I'm going to look at response that data then we're going to look at that user's property and from there
on that array we'll be using the for each method to do something for each user.
I'm going to pass in that callback.
We're going to have access to the individual user so I'll call the argument user.
And the only thing we're going to do inside of here is set DML equal to itself and concatenate something
new on to the end.
I'm going to use the plus equals shorthand for that and provide a little template string right here.
Now we can set up the markup that should render for each individual user.
I'm just going to dump something like their name to the screen right here.
I'll be creating a root did and we can put all other elements inside of there and for now we'll just
have one other element.
I'll use something like an H-3 Hatter tag.
I open and close that element and we'll use interpellation the dollar sign.
Curly brace syntax in the template string to inject a value and the value is user dot name.
Now I just noticed that I created this variable as a constant but if I am going to be reassigning its
value I want to switch that over to let instead.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can go ahead and save index dot J ass.
This is going to fetch that data and render it to the screen and what do we see.
I see a list of all of the users from our graph Cuil database.
So there we go.
We've successfully made our request to our Grath.
Q Well back end FIRMAT browser based script.
Now that we've done this once you're going to go ahead and do it again as your challenge for this video.
You're going to end up using the Post's query to fetch all published posts and render them to the screen.
Before we dive into the challenge comments let's give you a place to actually render the posts list
over here under users.
I'll make another div with an ID.
Let's use something like posts.
This is where you're going to end up rendering that data.
Now we can save this file and an index Dhananjay.
I'm going to paste in the challenge comments and talk about what I'd like you to do.
The big picture goal is to render all published posts to the browsers you're going to be using our posts
queery right here Step one you have to define this operation using Jeep's UL like we did above for the
users query then you're going to send this off using client and you're going to wait for the response
data.
When you get the data back you are going to render the list of post titles along with author names so
those are the two fields you have to make sure to get the post title and the name of the person who
wrote the post.
Now once you have Step Three done you can save the file and test your work over here.
You should see a rendered list of post titles with author names.
Now when it comes to the actual h DML structure it's not particularly important what you do.
You can just stick with a div with a H-3 inside of there and you can include the post title first and
the author named second or something along those lines.
You can choose to render it however you want the big picture goal is to actually get that data and render
it in some way.
All right take as much time as you need to knock this out.
As always feel free to use what we just did above as a guide to how to get this done.
Then come back and click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with Step number one.
We have to define the operation we're trying to perform.
I'm going to create a concert along the lines of get posts right here we will be using GTK UL along
with a template string to define the operation.
And in here we'll start with queries.
Since we're performing a query next up we are going to list the specific query we're trying to use.
This is going to be the Post's query to fetch published posts and then we have to define our selection
set for each post I want it's title and I also want the author name so Author.
We provide that selection set for author grabbing the name perfect.
Now that we have the operation defined we can move on to step two which is to actually send it off.
And for this you needed to use client dot query passing in the Options object setting up the query property.
In this case the value is going to be get posts where previously we had used get users.
Now that we've fired this off we can toss on a then method call with our callback function to do something
when we actually get that data back.
Right here we're going to have access to the response and what we want to do is generate an H DML string
and render it to the browser.
So I'm going to start once again with a variable let h TNL equal an empty string then from there we
can go ahead and actually use the selector like we did here to render things even though it's currently
an empty string document doesn't get element by ID.
The ID that we set up over here was posts so that's it I'm going to use inside of the string.
Then we'll be setting up the inner h DML property the value coming from our l variable.
Now all we have to do is actually iterate over all of the posts adding some stuff onto this string each
time.
So once again response dot data dot right here posts.
This is an array and on that array will be using the for each method.
Once again will set up that callback function will have access to the individual post object and we're
going to do is add on to TNL to h TNL plus equals a new string.
And right here we can define the markup we want to render for each individual post.
I'm going to use a div
inside that div I'll use another H-3 and inside of the H-3 we're going to include the title so right
here I will interpret the title I'm going to use post dot title which is where that data lives.
Now we could have included the author name alongside or maybe you added something else down below.
I could add as an example an H for element.
Putting the author name inside of there that's available on Post dot author dot name.
Excellent.
Now that we have this in place we are all done steps 1 2 and 3 and we can move on to actually testing
our work.
So right here I'm going to save index Dhananjay as in the browser.
What do we have.
We have our list of authors.
Then we have our list of posts starting with updated post by Andrew with his name down below.
Then we have a few posts by Jess with her name down the list all the way to the bottom.
Post by Andrew 5 written by Andrew.
So now we have figured out how to query data from javascript code.
And this is good because we need to be able to do this if we're going to write test cases that actually
interact with the API.
And we're going to need to be able to do this if we're ever going to build out a client for our application
and that's now something you know how to do.
All right let's go ahead and continue on with this section in the next video.