In the last video you learn how to use the Apollo Boost library to fire off graphic operations from
javascript in the browser.
This was fantastic because it allowed us to fetch data like users and posts and actually render those
to the screen for users to see.
This is a great step in the right direction and we're actually going to end up using the same technique
in our test cases though instead of fetching data and then rendering that data we would fetch data and
then make assertions about it expecting for example a certain amount of posts to come back or expecting
a user to have a specific name all using our expect assertions.
So let's take a moment to close down at the Apollo client directory and also all of the files we have
open and we're going to bring our attention back to the graphics.
Prisma project and are just test suite for our test suite to be able to communicate with the graphics
UL application the application needs to be up and running when the test suite starts.
Now there are a couple of approaches we could use to get this done.
And you might be saying that what's the problem the server is already up and running.
But remember we started the server using the dev script.
This is using the dev environment.
We don't want to use the dev environment here.
We want to use the test environment so we have two options.
One we could create another script very similar to this dev one just swapping out the files here or
we can use Jeste configuration options to tell just to startup the server before the test suite runs.
And to tell just to shut down the server when the test suite finishes and that's the approach that we're
going to take it will allow us to continue to run just a single command and PM test to do everything
and that's what we want.
It should be as easy as possible to test because that's the only way we're ever going to do it if testing's
hard.
We're going to stop writing tests we're not going to run the suite and we might as well not even waste
our time.
We want to make it easy so let's go ahead and go back to the Jeste Web site and explore the tools we
have available to us.
Once again you can find that at just J s dot I O.
Here we are going to head back over to the only page we've used so far.
The API documentation page and we're looking for the geste configuration details.
If we scroll down to the bottom of the page in the left hand sidebar we have a configuring jetzt.
This is going to walk us through the process of actually setting up one of many different configuration
options available to us.
There are dozens and dozens of them.
Now there are a few different ways we can actually define our configuration up at the top of the page.
Once again we can define it right in packaged.
Jason.
That's the approach we're going to take.
We could also define a separate javascript file where we define the configuration object and lastly
we could indeed define adjacent file as well.
We're only going to be setting up two properties though.
I'm just going to configure things right in package.
Jason all we have to do is set up a root just property.
I can put that wherever I want.
I'm going to put it right after scripts and before author.
So that's just setting it up as an object and then inside of here we can add on any of those configuration
options we need.
There are two options we're going to configure for just right here in the sidebar we have a list of
everything available to us.
We'll be setting up a global set up as well as global tear down.
Global setup is going to allow us to start the server and global tear down will allow us to shut down
the server.
Now both of these take a string value and the value for each needs to be the path to a custom file.
So right year global setup this option allows you to use a custom global setup module which exports
and async function that is triggered once before all test suites.
Down below we have the exact same thing but the global tear down function is triggered once after all
test suites.
So in the end of the day we're going to end up setting up two very short files one about seven lines
and the other about three.
So let's go ahead and kick things off by defining those two files in the tests directory.
I'm going to create a new folder I'm going to call this just.
You could call it something like config or set up whatever you want and in the geste directory we're
going to make two files one called Global set up so global set up Dhananjay s and the other global tear
down.
So global tear down and Dot J as in global setup will start up the server in global tear down will shut
it down.
Now the path to those files needs to be provided.
As the value in the just configuration.
So let's go ahead and get that done and we'll start with global set up.
So right here we have global set up exactly as defined in the geste documentation and the value for
global setup is going to be that forward slash.
We have to go into the tests folder then forward slash into the geste directory then forward slash the
file.
We called ours.
Global set up Dhananjay s a comma at the end of the line and will do the same thing again down below.
For global tear down.
So right here that's global.
Tear it down and the path will be the path to the teardown file.
So don't forward slash tests forward slash just forward slash global tear down dot J S.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place the jest is actually going to try to use those files when the test suite
starts this one and when the test suite finishes this one all we have to do is add some code inside
of there.
The goal inside of here is to start up our server.
The problem though is that the server is currently not easy to import into this file and then start
up.
The problem is because the server is defined and started all in the same file in source.
That's index dot J ass.
So this file is doing quite a bit of work.
First up it is indeed defining the server and it's also starting it up.
Meaning that if I wanted to create a server somewhere else like for our test files I'd have to rewrite
all of this code.
Obviously that's not ideal what we're going to do is create a separate file in the source folder called
server.
Jay ass.
This is going to define the server and export it then we'll be able to import it and use the start method
anywhere where we want to start it up.
We'll do it once and index JS to make sure our app still works and we'll do it again in global setup
Dhananjay ass.
So let's start by grabbing some code and bringing it over to that other file.
In essence we're going to grab all of these imports right here as well as all of the setup code down
below.
So there are a few things that will stay behind.
I'm going to cut out all of this code and bring it over to server.
Jay ass.
So here we define our server and we also load in everything required for that to actually work down
below.
We can now go ahead and export it so I can use something like export right here.
I'll export server as the default export as an example and this file's done we can actually save it
and use it over an index dot J s we can now go ahead and import that in porting server from right here
not forward slash server.
So now our application not the test app but the regular app it's still going to work as expected.
The only thing we've done is we've refactored our code a little bit making it possible to start the
server up from our test suite now down below.
I'm going to shut down the parcel's script and close down all terminals I'll boot those back up again
and we're going to run the dev script just to make sure we haven't broken anything so seedy into graft.
Well hyphen Prisma and from there.
NPM Ronit death if that still works then we know our factor was indeed just every factor and we didn't
actually break anything.
Right here the server is up it's printing.
So we are good to go.
Now we can close down index dot J S.
We're going to inport the server over here and actually get it up and running.
Now it's important to note that these files a global set up and global tear down.
They are not processed through babbel like our test suites are.
I'm not sure exactly why they chose to go this way but that is the reality we live in which means that
in here we only have access to the standard node syntax for requiring an export.
Both of these files should export a single function.
So involve see that module datt exports equal to a function and both of the functions will be async
functions.
So right here I'll define an async function in global setup.
I can take the exact same one and bring it over to global tear down the code inside of these functions.
That's what's going to run when the setup starts and when the process is complete.
So how do we actually use our server file while there is a catch.
The problem is that we are loading in a file server dot J S which uses features that node typically
doesn't support because all of our code has been running through Babble's so far.
There's a small babbel tool that's going to make this really easy to work around down below we'll be
shutting down in the terminal and we'll be installing it and pm right here install the tool itself is
called Babel hyphen or register and we'll grab the latest version.
That is six point twenty six point zero.
Now once this is installed it will be able to use it.
All we're going to do is use require to load it in.
So we're going to use the standard node require function to load in babbel hyphen register on the next
line we can load in babbel poly fell with a second to require call at Babel forward slash Pylea Phil
forward slash no conflict.
Excellent.
Now that we have this loaded in we can focus on loading in the server.
Now once again because we load in babbel register we're actually going to be able to require this file
without running into any issues.
If we did not use babbel register it would not know what to do with syntax like inport which node currently
does not support.
So over here we are going to create a cost server.
We're going to get the value from what comes back from require we will be requiring that file.
So we have to go dot dot to get out of the geste folder though and slashdot took it out of that tests
directory.
Then from there it's a forward slash source forwards slash server and on there we are grabbing the default
property.
So we have to grab default due to a difference between the two.
Here we are using require and Moggi Wilcott exports.
Here we're using import export and this is a compatibility concern but only used default.
We're still going to be able to access the server like we need to.
Now down below we can go ahead and use a wait with server dot start exactly like we do in index dot
J s we can even pass in an options object and pick the port for our test server to run on.
I'm going to define port as 4000 which is the default but I'll just define it to be explicit about the
port we're using now with this in place we can actually get the server up and running when the test
suite starts before we actually run it though.
We also want to tear down the server over here when the test suite is done.
Now the question is how do we access what we need.
We need access to what comes back from this start method.
So right here as an example Konst instance equals what comes back on that variable.
So in this case instance there's a close method.
That's what we have to call.
But we have to call it in this file.
So to work around this all we're going to do is assign this value to right here global dot and we're
going to pick a name I'll use HTP server.
Now we're going to have access to global dot HTP server and our other file as well.
And over here inside of global terror down we can await global dot HTP server dot close perfect.
Now we have a system for starting up the server and tearing down the server allowing us to run our entire
test suite with a single command.
Now before we do over in package dot Jason we also need to update.
Test test right now is not loading in the test environment which we do want it to since we're loading
in things like the server which is kind of try to start things up and connect to Prisma.
All we have to do is load in the test EMV file similar to how we load in the dev ESV file up above.
So right here we will use EMV ACMD once again that forward slash config a forward slash right here.
Test dot envy.
And this is going to allow us to provide those environment variables to geste.
And now we are all ready to go.
If we go out and save package dot Jason down below we can run our test suite NPM run test.
This is going to start up the test suite.
It's going to run all of our test cases from a few videos ago.
And once again we should see that everything is indeed passing.
Right here we have five passing tests.
Now if we didn't have things set up correctly we might get an error.
For example let's go ahead and comment out this line that loads in Babel register.
Now if we just save the file sure things still appear to work.
But remember we have to shut down just and restart it for our configuration files to be reloaded.
So if I were to shut it down and restart it this time I would expect it to fail.
And it does.
Right here we have an unexpected token as referring to things in server Dom J.S. like this first import
statement which is not familiar with it doesn't know how to parse that when we use Babel register though
everything works as expected.
So I know this video was one of those watch me do something videos and you don't have to remember all
of this.
This is something that you're really only going to set up once or twice ever.
Typically as will create later you'll have some sort of boiler plate project that already has all of
this configured to the next time you're trying to build a graphical application.
You don't have to get into the guts and configure all of this.
Again that's where we're going to stop for this one are just test suite is indeed going to start up
our server and shut it down which means that we are ready to load in Apollo boost in our test files
and actually fire off some graphical operations from our test cases.
We're going to focus on doing just that in the next video so stay tuned and I'll see you then.