You know know how to use Appollo boost to execute operations on the graphical application.
You also have the server up and running when just executes.
And in this video we're going to write our first test case that actually tests our graph UL application.
The test case that we're going to be writing is going to be for the create user mutation so we'll be
testing the Sign-Up functionality in our app.
Now all of the test cases we have in the user test file so far those were for exploring how testing
works.
They're not going to make it into the final version of our app though.
So we can go ahead and start with an empty test file down below.
I'm going to use Control C to shut down our test suite and we're going to install the modules we need.
We need Appollo boost as an example so we can actually fire off that nutation from our test case.
That'll be NPM install.
First up Appollo hyphen boost at the version we used before that is zero point one point fourteen.
We're also going to grab graft UL which we need at version fourteen point zero point do that as a dependency
of Appollo boost we have to have as well.
And we're also going to grab one more thing because we're trying to use Appollo boost in node j s this
is cross hyphen fetch.
This is a Thach API Pylea Phil will be grabbing the latest version that is to point to point 2.
Now we can go ahead and install all of this and well that's running.
I just want to take a quick moment to talk about fach if we head over to Google and Google something
like MTNL fach.
This will bring up the Mozilla developer network API docs for the fetch API.
This is a standardized API across browsers but it has yet to make its way to node j Jay as Apollo boost
as well as many other tools rely on it.
So that's why we're going to end up using the library cross fecche to get support.
If I scroll down to the bottom of the documentation you can see all the different places that it supported
it has pretty decent support overall.
Now that we have the poly Phil installed we're going to be able to use Appollo boost from right here
inside of our just test suite.
Let's go ahead and inport what we need.
First up I'm going to import cross heighth and fetch a forward slash poly fill that's going to make
sure we have access to the fecche API.
And that's a good thing because the next thing we're going to import needs it.
We're going to grab Appollo boost as well as GQ well from the Apollo boost library.
These are the exact same two imports we grab when working with Apollo boost in the browser.
Now from here we can go ahead and create a client before we actually write our first test case.
So cons to client equals we're going to use new.
With Appollo boost we're going to pass in that options object and all we have to define is the you are
property HTP Colinet forward slash a forward slash local host on port four thousand.
This is the port I chose two stirred up the server at.
And I did that over in the global setup file here.
I defined the port.
I wanted to use them using the same port over here.
Now that we have the client in place we can go ahead and write our first test case.
So I'm going to call test.
We're going to pass in our two arguments the test name and our test function the name for this one could
be something along the lines of it should create a new user.
So in this case we're going to use the create user mutation with valid data and we're going to expect
that a new user actually gets created.
Now as for the function I'm going to mark this as an async function so I can take advantage of async
await inside of here.
The first thing we're going to do inside of here is define our operation right here.
That's going to be create user we are going to use GQ Well what the template string.
And this is indeed a mutation.
So let's go ahead and start there defining it like we would have to find a mutation in graph Q L playground.
From there we'll be using the create user mutation.
This is the functionality we're trying to test.
And we are going to pass in those arguments.
And we're also going to define our selection set.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with the arguments that create user needs it just needs one.
Data and data is an object if you remember where we provide the name the email and the password we want
to sign up with right here for the name field.
I can just use my name Andrew and I'll do the same thing for an email.
I'll use something like Andrew an example dot com.
And then finally we have our password I will use something along the lines of my pass.
One two three.
Perfect.
So we have all of the arguments set up correctly and we can focus on our selection set what information
do we want back now in this case we could grab anything.
We will be able to grab engraft UL playground for example I could grab the authentication token.
I could also go ahead and grab something like the user's ID.
Perfect.
And now we can actually fire that mutation off.
So down below after our create user definition is finalized we're going to use client dot mutate.
So we've already used client and query to fire off our query operations here.
We're using client Dom mutate to fire off our mutations and we are going to call it as a function and
pass in an options object on here.
There is a single property we have to define for our queries.
It was the query property for our mutations.
It is the mutation property we set this equal to the mutation we want to use and I have that defined
right here.
Create user perfect with this in place.
I am indeed going to get their response back as well.
Now if you remember over in Appollo client in that index database file we just used Dopp then to wait
for the promise to complete in this code.
We have access to async and await.
So I am going to get the response by awaiting the promise that mutate returns so mutate and queery both
return a promise and both of those promises will end up resolving what the response when the operation
is complete.
Let's go ahead and actually test things out.
I'm going to save the user test file and before I run the test suite I'm going to pull up the data in
the database.
So for PGE admin I have my default default and default test.
I'll be using the test stage down below we have our tables and I'm just going to view all of the data
in the user table.
So view all rows right now we should have zero because we haven't executed our test cases actually interacting
with the test database.
Right now though we are indeed going to do just that by running NPM.
Run it test from the terminal.
This is going to start up our test suite.
The test suite is indeed going to create a user.
And we should indeed see that user over in the database down below.
We have a single passing test and if I refresh PGE admin What do we get.
We get a single user showing up with the exact information I provided.
Obviously though the password is Oppy skated since it has been hashed using B crypt but the email and
the name match up exactly with what was used over here.
Now you'll notice that our test case is passing and that's because none of the code inside of year has
thrown an error.
And we know that's how geste determines if a test should pass or should fail.
In this case no errors throw and so the test is considered a success.
Now a what would we expect to happen if we were to rerun the test suite again.
Well I would expect my test cases to operate as they did before so I should still have just one passing
test.
The problem though is that that's not what's going to happen because this test case is going to try
to add that user again.
But this email will already be registered.
So down below in the terminal if I hit a rerun all of the test cases we can see that the test actually
fails and the error message a unique constraint would be violated lets us know that the test is failing
because the email is already registered.
Now obviously this is a problem.
And in the next video we're going to look at how we can address that automatically for the moment though
to continue on.
I'm just going to manually delete the user from the test database.
And now we can focus on adding a single assertion then we'll be done.
But we're going to do is load in Prisma and use the exists functionality from Prisma to check if there
is a user with the ID.
We got back.
Now you might not think you know how to do that but I promise you you do know how to do that.
So down below this is actually going to be a challenge right here.
The goal is to use Prisma to check if the user was created.
So step 1 you'll be importing the source Prisma file we created.
Like we've inport it many times before.
That's this file over in the source directory that's going to give us access to our Prisma binding instance
which is good because in step 2 you're going to use the exists functionality from that Prisma binding
library which we've used plenty of times before to find a user by ID.
Now what Id Well the ID in the response and you already learned where that data in the response lives
we covered that in the Apollo client project created earlier in the section.
Now step three exists is going to return either true or false.
You're going to expect it to return true since the users should indeed have been created by the test
case.
And finally you're going to test your work by saving the file and watching the test case pass.
Now if you have to rerun it multiple times maybe you have a typo or something along those lines.
Just make sure to clear the user from the database.
If it got created.
Otherwise your test case will never pass but it won't be passing for the wrong reason.
It won't be a problem with the user not being created.
It will be a problem with the user's email already being taken.
So take some time to knock this out.
Using what you already know you've done all of this before and when you're done come back and click
play
how that go.
I'm going to kick things off with step one.
We're just going to inport Prisma up above.
So right here in Port like we've done in the past I'll be grabbing Prisma from have after use dot dot
to get out of the tests folder then forward slash source forwards slash Prisma.
Excellent.
Now down below we can go ahead and actually put it to use right here.
We have to use the exists functionalities.
I'm going to create a Konst called exists like we've done before and I will be using a weight with Prisma
dot exists dot right here user.
Excellent.
Now we can go ahead and limit our search by a field in this case by id and I'm looking for a user by
their ID where their ID equals the ID got back in the response.
That would be response dot data dot.
Create user dot user dot ID.
So remember we have data on response on there we have everything we requested so create user user ID
is going to get us to this value right here.
Create user user ID.
Excellent.
Now we can move on to Step 3 and use our assertion.
I am going to expect.
Whoops a little autocomplete there that exists equals using to be the following value.
True it should indeed exist.
Excellent.
Now we can test our work.
I'm going to remove the challenge comments we have our two lines in place.
I'm going to save the test suite and I would expect the test case to be passing and it is and there
we go.
We now have our very first test case that makes assertions about how our graphs UL application works.
If the create user mutation were to ever break in the future our automatic test suite would be able
to catch that and prevent bugs from getting into production and messing up with real users and in the
case of a production app messing up with your business messing up with your revenue your customer relationships
and more.
And now that we have this in place we're going to address that problem that happens when our test suite
runs a second time in the next video we're going to learn how to use geste lifecycle methods to clean
out our database before our test cases run.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.