In this video as promised we're going to learn how we can manipulate our test database before our test
cases run it.
We already saw that's causing a problem for us when we rerun our test suite trying to sign up a user
with an email that's already taken.
If I save the program the test suite restarts and our test case crashes because that e-mail is registered
now just gives us tools to make this possible.
There are various lifecycle functions we can tap into to do something throughout our testing lifecycle.
We can learn more about those by heading over to the just documentation in the left hand side bar away
near the bottom.
We're going to go to the Global's page and on here we can view all of the Global's we have access to
and we have one we've already used test.
There are four more I want to talk about.
And it's actually the first four we have after all after each before all and before each.
Now as the names suggest after all is going to run a single time after all tests are done after each
will run after each test case and same thing with before before all will run before all test cases a
single time and before each will run before each test case and our case we'll be using before each to
do something before each test.
What are we going to do.
Well for the moment we're just going to clear all records.
So all tests start with the same test database.
Let's go ahead and actually knock that out over in our code.
We're going to end up calling before each just like we would call test.
Right here I'm going to call before each end.
This just takes a single argument a function to run before each test case.
Now inside of here we will be doing something a synchronous so we can mark this as an async function.
And this is the same call signature of all of those lifecycle methods before all after all and after
each all just take a single function.
Now in this case what do we want to do inside of the function.
I want to wipe the database so all tests start with an empty database.
We already have Prisma imported and we're going to use a mutation.
We haven't explored before to get this done.
If we head over to localhost for 4 6 6 where are Prisma API lives we can crack open the schema and go
to mutations.
We've used plenty of these before.
But way near the bottom there is delete many for each.
So we have delete many users delete many posts and delete many comments.
Now this hasn't really served a practical application so far.
Which is why we haven't talked about them.
But now is a great time to use them.
We can use delete many users to wipe all users.
We could limit it to a specific set of users.
For example users whose name contains Andrew in our case though we're not even going to provide any
arguments.
We want to delete everybody.
So let's go ahead and actually get that done from Arbre for each callback function right here we'll
be using a Prisma dot mutation dot the one we just explored.
Delete many users and in this case we're not providing any arguments.
Now this does indeed return a promise and we are going to use a wait.
That's going to ensure that before each doesn't start the test case until the users are actually deleted.
We want to make sure we wait for that process to complete.
Now that we have this in place this function will run before every single test case.
In our case we only have one test but it will indeed pass every single time it runs.
I'm going to save the file the test suite is going to rerun with before each executing and down below
was a failing test suite is now a passing one.
I could use it to rerun the test cases again and they are indeed going to work because we're going to
wipe the users before our tests and this is fantastic.
We now have a way to manage the test database from inside of the test suite ensuring we get consistent
results.
Now wiping data isn't the only thing we're going to do inside of here.
Let's think about one of the other operations we're eventually going to write a test case for our loggin
a mutation.
In that case we're actually expecting data to be in the database.
We need it to be in the database.
Otherwise we're not going to be able to log in.
So what we're going to end up doing is creating a set of dummy data.
We are going to seed the database with this dummy data then test cases can choose to use it when they're
performing their operations.
So in the case of creating a user We're not going to need any dummy data but for logging in we're going
to need some dummy data for testing our posts.
Queery we're going to need some dummy data or any posts in the database.
So in the end of the day yes we will be clearing data from this function but we're also going to be
adding seed data into the database that our test cases can actually interact with and that's what we're
going to do right now as the second half of this video I'm going to await Prisma dot mutation does create
user that's going to allow us to create a user for this one we do have to provide arguments a single
one data with name email and password and remember.
In this case password is going to need to be hashed already.
Node is what hashes are password.
In this case we are bypassing node.
So we want to hash it in our code right here.
I'll just import the script from the script J.S. library that we've already installed and already used
before.
Down below we can set up a name for our first dummy user.
Let's go ahead and call her.
Jen will have an email as well.
Jen at example dot com gets the job done and finally a password.
Right here we can use B crypt dot hash sync to synchronously hash the password and that means we're
going to get the value back directly as opposed to getting a promise back.
We can pass in any value we like for the password.
I could use something for example like red 0 9 8 with a couple of special characters in there and there
we go.
Now we have code that's going to correctly create a new user that our test cases can rely on.
I'm going to go ahead and save user dot test dot J ass.
Once again I would expect our one test case to pass but this time if we head over to the database and
give things a refresh you can see we have two records.
We have Jen our little test user.
And then we have Andrew a user that was actually created by one of our test cases.
So now we have a little more robust setup.
We are wiping all of the data starting from a clean slate.
Then we're adding one user for all of our test cases to rely on.
Now it's Challenge time it's going to be your job to expand on Arbre for each function you're going
to also add at some posts to our test database for this user down below.
I have some comments outlining what I'd like you to do.
So the big picture goal is to create two dummy posts in the test database.
Step one you're going to have to use the correct Prisma mutation to create those two posts and you want
to set the author for the posts equal to the test user.
We just created.
So you're going to want to create a variable to get the user data back because you're going to need
the user's ID in order to correctly connect the posts with that user.
So the next step.
Make sure that one of those posts is published and the other is a draft that's going to give us a little
bit of variety with our data.
So if I'm testing the Post's query which should only return published posts I actually have some draft
posts and I can make sure those aren't coming back in the test cases.
Now once you have the two posts being created you also need to delete all of those posts.
You're going to do that just before you delete all users.
So that's going to go right up here and the post creation will go right down below.
And step three just test your work.
Save the file let the test suite rerun and then check out the posts table in the database.
You should see your two dummy posts showing up.
All right.
Take some time to knock this one out.
Test your work when you're done come back and click play.
All right.
How that go.
I'm going to kick things off by first deleting all of those posts.
I'm going to go slightly out of order.
I will await Prisma dot mutation dot delete many posts calling it not passing in any arguments like
we did with delete many users we want to wipe everything now down below after we create that user.
We can focus on creating our posts and we're going to need the user's ID so I'll create a user variable
so I can actually get that data back.
I can get back information about the created user down here we are going to go ahead and use a wait
with Prisma dot mutation dot create post and we are going to provide the options argument.
We have to list out a few different things in order to create that post successfully.
The first thing we have to list out is a title a body and a published value.
Now I didn't give you any specifics for title and body.
Just for the published value so I'm going to go ahead and set data equal to an object an asset title
equal to something like my published post so this will be the published one.
I can leave the body as empty.
And then I'll set the published value to true.
Perfect.
From here we can go ahead and set up the author property and remember we can either create a new author
or connect to an existing one.
We're going to connect it to the one we created up above.
So I'll use connect setting equal to their ID user dot ID.
Perfect.
We have one post down.
Let's go ahead and create a second one.
I'm going to take the code we just wrote copy it to the clipboard paste it down below and just change
up the data for the second post.
We're going to say my draft post that should be singular.
I'll make it singular up above as well though it's not a big deal.
And for this post we're going to set published equal to false.
So it's a draft and we'll leave the author and the body values the same.
Excellent.
Now we can actually test our work.
So I'm going to delete those challenge comments.
I'm going to save the file.
That's going to cause our test suite to rerun executing the before each callback function.
Down below the test case passed and we should see our data over in the database over in the post table.
I'm going to view all rows and right here we have two posts showing up.
I have my published post as well as my draft post.
One is published.
The other is not.
And that is exactly what we wanted.
And that's where we're going to stop for this one.
We now have some dummy data in the database and this is going to allow us to test the other queries
subscriptions and mutations that make up our application.
We'll continue writing test cases in the next video so let's go ahead and jump right in.