In this video we're going to start and finish two new test cases now that we have our Geske configuration
set up adding individual test cases really isn't going to be that bad for the moment.
We're going to continue to ignore authentication so we're going to test a couple of our queries that
don't require authentication together.
We'll be testing our users query making sure it exposes the public off their profiles.
And as your challenge you'll be testing the posts.
Queery making sure you only get published posts back.
So let's go ahead and knock this out down below.
For the moment we're going to keep everything in a single file though don't worry.
As we add more test cases we will create multiple test suites.
For now though let's go ahead and add the second test case.
I'm going to call this one should expose public author profiles.
This is going to test that we do indeed get those public author profiles back including things like
their name but excluding things like their email right here.
I will use an async function and we're going to use an async function for pretty much every single test
case as we'll always be doing something asynchronous.
The first thing I'm going to do is set up the operation.
I'll call this constant something like get users or get user profile or get authors.
Then we'll set it equal to here we'll use GTK UL with a template string to provide our operation.
It is indeed a query we will be using the user's query.
That's going to give us an array back and for each user We're going to grab their ID will grab their
name and we'll grab their email.
Perfect.
Now down below we can actually send that operation off and get the response.
Storing that in a response variable right here Konst response equals.
I am going to await the following client.
Dat query.
I'm going to call that as a function passing in the one property we have to define for the query method
which is query and right.
Here we have get users which defines that operation perfect.
So at this point we've created the operation and we've sent it off.
Now we're going to make two assertions about what comes back.
One I'm going to assert that that array users has just a single item.
So we're gonna make sure its length is one and the other assertion is going to be that the individual
user object has an e-mail property equal to null that e-mail should not be exposed.
We could even assert that the name is exposed.
That would work perfectly fine too down below.
Let's go ahead and play around with these.
Expect First up will look at the length of the array.
So that's response data.
There we have the users array with the length property on all the arrays will be using to be to confirm
that's the number one.
Next up we can expect something about that individual user right here.
Response date data.
Users grabbing the first one using bracket notation and we're going to assert some things about its
properties right here.
Let's start with email.
I am going to expect that to be null.
It should indeed be null.
I'm not logged in so I should not be able to access author emails.
Next up we should see the name showing up.
Now this is where testing it's a bit subjective.
There is no right or wrong way to test some code.
Some person might say this test case is fine.
You've done a good job you're done.
Others might say whoa you have to test way more looking at individual fields.
Once again it's really up to us to strike a bounce and test the things that are important to test.
In this case we could indeed add an assertion checking that the name matches up though it's definitely
not necessary.
But as we are experimenting Let's go ahead and knock it out.
Expect response.
Dot dot dot dot.
Users will look at that first user checking the name property.
Now in this case I would expect that to be using need to be method whenever we originally created it
with an up above.
If you remember the user's name was Jan.
So down below right here I would expect that name to be Jeon as well.
Now that we have this in place we can save our user test file down below.
I would expect to have to passing test cases instead of just one.
And that is exactly what we end up getting right here.
We can see we were able to create a new user and I was able to fetch the public author profiles.
Now that we have our one test in place for a query you're going to be adding a second one down below
for the Post's query confirming that you're just getting published posts back.
The process here is going to be very similar to what you did just now with the test case above.
Big picture goal.
Write a test for the Post's query.
You're going to create the test case.
You're going to fire off a post's query getting all of those scalar fields for each post.
Then you're going to assert that you've got a single post back and you're going to assert that that
individual post has a published value of true which you should be getting since the Post's query should
only be exposing published posts if you get two back.
That means the draft post is being exposed as well and that's obviously a problem.
So we want to make sure we just get one.
Then once you have that in place once you've fired off the operation and added your assertions you can
save the file to run your test suite and you should see a third passing test case.
So take some time to knock that out.
Using the techniques covered up above then come back and click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by defining our test function excuse me by calling the test function
that's already defined.
Right here we are going to pass in a name.
I'll call this something like should expose published posts.
We will set up our async function.
This is the actual test case that's going to run perfect and now we can define our operation.
So Konst get posts I am going to use Giac UL with a template string.
This is indeed a query and we are indeed using the Post's query.
I'm going to grab ID.
Title body and I'll also grab published.
Excellent.
So now we have our operation defined and we can go ahead and fire that operation off.
So right here I'm going to get the response back storing that in a response variable like we've done
in all of our test cases before.
We will await the promise that comes back from client Dom query passing in the only property on the
options object we need the query property.
Here we are going to use get posts defined above.
Now we can make some assertions about the response we got back.
First up we're going to assert that we got back just a single post.
So I'll be using expect and we are going to expect something about response dot right here.
Data dot posts dot length.
So remember posts is going to be an array.
We've got an array back right here inside of graft UL playground.
The same thing is true in our code.
We're using the length property and will expect that to be the number one next step.
We're going to look at that individual post and make sure it's published.
So I'm going to expect that response dot data dot posts right here.
We will grab the first item from the array by index using bracket notation and now look at it's published
property right here.
I'm expecting that to be true.
It should indeed be a published post.
Now that we have this in place we're all done as you can see we were able to knock out these test cases
pretty quickly once we had the basic infrastructure and know how in place I'm going to save the test
file and we should see a third passing test down below.
If we do we're all done with this video down here.
What do we got.
We've got three passing tests now at this point there is still plenty more to learn how to do for example
how do we expect that a given operation fails.
If I log in with bad credentials I want it to fail if I sign up with the password that's too short.
I want that to fail as well.
We're going to cover all of this and more in the very next video.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.