So far all of the operations we've fired off from our test cases we're supposed to exceed.
I was supposed to get posts I was supposed to get users.
I was supposed to be able to create the user but what about test cases that are supposed to fail.
For example if I log in with bad credentials.
I want that to fail if I sign up and my password is too short.
I want that operation to fail as well.
In this video we're going to learn exactly how we can do that using expect.
And then you're going to do it on your own.
Creating a second test case sir right here.
Let's go ahead and start by creating a test case together.
I'll be calling the test function.
This one is going to check that when you log in with bad credentials it does indeed fail.
Right here should not log in with bad credentials.
Excellent.
We can then set up our async function and we can focus on firing off our operations.
So just like we did previously we're still going to fire off the operation.
It's the assertion though that's going to change.
Now before we actually fire off the operation let's take a look at the functionality from expect.
We're going to use to get this done.
So if we head over to the geste documentation we can learn more about this by going down to the expect
page a page we have been to before and on this page we're looking for a method called to throw it down
at near the bottom right here.
We have our two throw method.
This is going to make sure that some set of code throws an error which is perfect.
So if it throws an error the test will be considered a success if it doesn't.
The test will be considered a failure.
Double-O they have an example where they call some sort of function that function where assuming it
throws an error.
And in this case the test case would pass.
Let's see that on our own over in our code.
So right here what we're going to do is pass a function to expect.
So I'm going to call expect I'm going to pass an aero function in and we are going to call to throw
on what comes back similar to how we would call to be up above for these assertions.
Now in this case this test is going to be considered a failure this function needs to be throwing an
error.
Right here we can clearly see that it's not.
So if I were to save the user test file we would have a new test case but it would indeed be failing
and down below that is exactly what we get right here.
We have the error expected the function to throw an error but it didn't throw anything.
Now we could go ahead and make this test case pass by actually throwing an error.
So right here throw new error.
For example and I could say something like this is my error.
Now this time around I would indeed expect the tests to pass where asserting that it throws an error.
It does indeed do that.
And down below we have four passing test cases.
So using the to throw functionality from expect we can make sure that some code throws an error in our
case we're going to assert that the Apollo boost code throws an error that promised that comes back
it's going to resolve if things go well and it's going to reject if things go poorly.
In this case we're betting that it rejects.
Let's actually define this operation right.
Here we are going to define law again.
Konst log in equals.
I'll be using GQ L with the template string.
And we're going to set up that operation right here.
It is indeed a mutation in a mutation is called a log in.
And we have arguments in and we have our selection set as far as the arguments go.
We're going to have just one data on there we provide the email and the password.
Remember we're trying to log in with bad credentials so we have to use anything but gen's credentials
from our database up above right here.
As an example e-mail could be Jeff at example dot com.
And then for the password we could just use a random series of characters.
Anything will get the job done.
Excellent when it comes to our selection set.
We're not actually going to get any data back but let's go ahead and say we want to grab the authentication
token.
Now it's time to fire this off.
And we know how to do that.
We use client mutate.
We then call that passing in an options object.
We set up the mutation property.
And in this case we have the longan mutation up above.
The question now is how do we make sure this code throws an error.
Well the first thing we have to do is use expect.
So down below I'm going to add a fresh call to expect and we pass to expect our promise.
So down below when we had regular synchronous code we passed in a standard function when we're working
with promises we actually take that promise and we pass that in.
Now from here we have to go ahead and use a new property that we haven't explored so far.
But we can learn about over in the expect documentation in the left hand excuse me right hand side bar.
We have two properties resolves and rejects that allow us to work with promises and expect which is
exactly what we're doing.
We can go ahead and check out resolves first right here.
Bev a little assertion that this promise that immediately resolves the string Lemon.
They then use the resolves property to extract the value off that promise and they make an assertion
about what it is.
In this case checking that it's the string.
LEMON The same thing is true but in the opposite direction with rejects here we can use the rejects
property on and expect call where a promise has been passed in and we can make sure that it throws an
error by chaining on a call to to throw.
Now in this case they're making an assertion about the explicit error by passing that in.
That's not necessary though we can leave that off and just ensure that an error is thrown.
Let's go ahead and actually knock that out in our code.
So right here instead of using to throw right away like we might have in the past we're going to go
ahead and start with rejects.
Since we're working with a promise we are indeed passing a promise in we have to use Regex.
Then we can use to throw.
Now it's important to remember that this is all an asynchronous operation.
The testing suite has to communicate with our graphs well at which has to communicate with the database
that takes time and is not synchronous.
Now to make sure that we actually wait for the operation to complete we toss a wait up front.
Now we can remove our little dummy example down below and actually test things out.
If you have a hard time reading a line like this you can always take the promise and break that out
onto its own line.
So right after the parentheses for expect.
And right before the closing parentheses.
I'll add new lines and we end up with something that looks like the following.
A bit easier to read.
Let's go ahead and save the file to fire this off.
We can see what happens now right here the test suite is running in what do we get.
We have 4 passing test cases which means that this code did indeed throw an error.
Now what if the credentials were good.
What if we actually used gen's credentials from up above.
In that case things would work.
I can memorize or email but I am going to copy her password since that's a bit long and we're actually
going to try to log in with these down below.
We have our loggin test.
I'm going to swap Jeff at example dot com out for Jen at example dot com.
Then I'm going to use gen's password in this case.
The mutation should not throw an error but we are expecting it to throw an error.
So the test case should fail right here the test suite is going to rerun again.
I would expect to have 3 passing tests and one failing one.
That is exactly what we get up above.
We expected to code to throw an error but it did not.
And down below it showing the payload with our token coming back.
Now if we were to mess up just a single character like changing uppercase r to lower case our we would
be back to our working test case and that is exactly what we want in the end of the day.
So let's take a quick moment to recap we can assert that a promise throws an error by passing that promise
to expect.
We then use dot rejects to throw tossing away up front waiting for the operation to actually complete.
You're going to use the exact same technique to write a new test case as your challenge for this video.
Right here there are four steps for getting that done.
Big picture goal test that you can't sign up with a short password.
So in this case we'll be using the create user mutation again.
But with bad data step 1 create that barebones test case step 2.
Set up the operation with the bad data.
Making sure the password is shorter than the requirements so make it something like 6 characters long.
Next up you're going to fire off the mutation and expect the promise to throw an error using similar
code to what we did here.
And finally you're going to test your work ensuring that you now have a fifth passing test case.
All right take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play
How'd that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by calling test.
I'm going to do that.
Up above though down below would work fine as well.
Right here we'll be setting up a new test case.
We'll be using an asynchronous function and we can pick a name for this test something like should not
Sign-Up user with invalid password.
Perfect.
Now we can actually define the operation we're trying to perform which is indeed a create user a mutation.
I'll create a constant create user and let's set up that operation right here setting up our basic operation
this is indeed a mutation.
We'll be using the create user mutation which we've already used from a test case.
And in this case we are going to provide data.
Once again this time with some bad data focusing on that short password so name it we can use anything
we like.
I'll stick with my own personal information e-mail.
Once again I'll just use Andrew an example dot com.
And then finally password in this case I'm going to use something like Pass which is indeed too short
to be a valid password when it comes to the selection set.
It doesn't really matter what I grab I'll just grab the token that should come back.
If create user or to actually work.
Now we're going to use code similar to this to fire off the mutation and ensure it actually throws an
error.
So right here I am indeed going to await a call to expect we're going to pass our promise in right here
and I'm going to split this out onto multiple lines.
Client dot mutate passing in our options object and setting up that mutation property.
We have our mutation stored in the create user variable.
Next up down below we'll use dot rejects sends we're working with a promise we have to extract that
value then we'll use to throw to ensure it actually throws an error.
Excellent.
With this in place we have completed steps 1 2 and 3.
And step four is to just test our work.
So I'm going to remove the challenge comments.
I'm going to go ahead and save the user test file.
And down below.
We're going to see a fifth passing test case.
Well hopefully we do it right here we have just that should not Sign-Up user with invalid password is
indeed showing up at this point we have a pretty nice test suite.
We've made some really great progress in the next videos we're going to continue on focusing on testing
more complex code so far as an example we haven't tested subscriptions and we haven't tested any of
our operations that require authentication.
We're going to figure out all of that in more in the coming videos.
So let's continue on in the next one.