In this video we're going to do a bit of refactoring that's going to allow us to write tests for our
operations that require authentication.
So we're going to figure out how to set all of that up.
And we're also going to break out our test cases into multiple test suites so multiple test files.
That's going to allow us to stay organized as the amount of tests that we have.
GROSS Now if we're going to define multiple test suites which we're going to do we're going to need
to make sure that all of the setup code we have in this file is reusable.
For example right here we have all of the code that creates the seed data as well as wipes old data.
This is only going to work for the user test suite.
So if I was to create another test file the database wouldn't be seated correctly to make sure that
we can reuse this code a crossed test suites all we're going to do is define that in a separate file.
We're going to define our async function over there.
Then we'll inport the async function into test files like this one and pass that function into before
each like we're doing now to start.
Let's go ahead and create a new folder in the tests directory.
This is going to contain some utilities that are test suites we'll use things that should be reused
across the test suites like this.
We can call this folder something like tills and in there for the moment we will create a single file
for seeding the database.
I'll call this is database dot J S and we're going to do is create an export a single asynchronous function.
And the good news is that we already have that function code.
It's this function passed in two before each.
So I'm going to take the async function all the way from the async keyword to the closing curly brace
and cut that out.
It should just leave R before each call with no arguments being provided.
And then over in the database I will create a seed database function getting its value from what I grabbed
over in the other file from here.
We need to do two things.
We have to grab the necessary imports for this file to work and we also want to export the function
so it can be used in our test suites like user dot test dot J.
S. Let's start with the imports.
Right here we need Prisma as well as the B crypt library.
I'll start with B script.
So I'm going to import B script from the following B script J.
S. Then I will import Prisma from our own file right here.
That would be dot dot.
Take it out of the utils folder.
Forward slash dot dot to get out of the tests directory and from there forward slash source forward
slash Prisma.
So in the end of the day we're just loading in the same in inport we needed over here to get things
working.
Now over in the C database file we can go ahead and export the function we defined.
So down below at the bottom export in curly braces we are going to export seed database and we're going
to export that as the default.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can import this function from our test suite and use it.
Let's go ahead and do just that.
I'm going to save the seed database file over in user dot test that J s we can remove the B script inport
as it's no longer being used and we can add an import for the database.
So right here in Port seed database from the following file that forward slash utility forward slash
seed database.
Excellent.
Now we can take this function and pass it into before each seed database and we're done.
We have the exact same functionality we had before but now it's refactored to be reusable.
And if I were to save this test suite down below we can see that the test cases are rerunning and right
here we still have five passing tests.
This is going to make it easy to define a nother test file which is what we're going to do right now.
So in the tests directory itself we are going to create a new file alongside of user dot test dot J
S and we can call this something like post dot test dot J S and this is where we can put our test cases
specifically related to posts by having separate test files each focused on something specific.
It's going to be easier to figure out exactly where a given test case lives and now out of the five
test cases we currently have in the user test suite.
One of them is post specific.
That's the third one right here should expose published posts.
This does seem to fit the post test suite more than the user test suite so I'm going to cut out this
call to test and I'm going to bring it over to the post test file.
Now we are going to have to initialize this test suite in a similar way we initialize the one over here.
There are a few things we have to get done but for the test case is going to work as expected over inside
of post.com test dot J S.
Let's go ahead and knock that out up top by adding a few imports into the mix.
First up I'm going to import to the crosshatch Pylea Phil cross hyphen fetch a forward slash poly fill.
Next up I'm going to import Appollo boost sends We will indeed be creating a client in here in Port
Appollo boost as well as the named export.
GQ well from the Apollo boost library.
Excellent.
And the last thing we're going to grab for the moment is the seed database function we created so I
can inport right here seed database from the following file that we just define dot forward slash tills
forward slash seed database.
Now there are two things we have to do before this test case is going to work.
We have to initialize a new client in and set up before each so Konst client equals we're going to use
new with Appollo boost passing in our options object and setting up that you are evaluated TTP colon
lowered slash forward slash localhost on port four thousand.
Perfect.
Now that we have the client initialized the last thing left to do is to call before each end to pass
in the seed database function.
Excellent.
Now that we have this in place this test suite is set up similar to this one and both are now going
to work.
Now before we save our test suites there is one command line argument.
We're going to have to add on to the just command.
Currently we're using watch.
Let's head over to the documentation.
Scroll down and talk about the other one we're going to use.
We can find it under just Selye options down below.
We have a huge list of all of the options available to us.
The one that we're looking for in alphabetical order is run in-band running bende allows us to run tests
in multiple test suites without trying to run them at the exact same time for us that would be a pretty
big problem since they're Polt interacting with that database.
So all we have to do now that we have asynchronous tasks in multiple suites is to add on hyphen hyphen
around in band.
And remember when you change your command line arguments you have to restart jast in order for those
to be used.
So down below.
I'm going to use control C to shut down that test suite then I'm going to save both of my test suite
files and I will rerun NPM run test to start it up once again with the run in band option being used.
Now if we do this we should have two test suites one with four Tests and one with one test and all five
Tests should indeed be passing down below.
It is running through the test suite.
We can see one finished.
Then the second to finished and right here we have the results we were hoping for.
So at this point we have these systems set up to easily create multiple test suites.
All we have to do is in port a couple of things set up a client and and before each into the mix.
Now in the second half of this video we're going to figure out how to send an authentication token along
with our operations whether we're using clients query or client dot mutate.
Now here's the catch.
We actually don't provide the header the JWT authentication token in the query or mutate call.
And actually all needs to get configured when we originally set up the client.
So what we're going to do is stick with one client for unauthenticated requests and we'll be creating
a separate client for when we want to authenticate with a specific J W.T..
Now this is going to require a little extra code.
So before we do any of that we're going to take the creation of our new client here and here and we're
going to break that out into a new file as well.
Currently yes they're doing the same thing but it's not that much code you could easily make the case
to just leave these in place.
But since we will be adding more code on there to configure authentication I'm going to refactor it
right now we'll create a new file in the tills directory and I'm going to create a new file called Get
client.
This is going to get a brand new client.
So get client dot J S.
We're going to create a function called Get client.
And this will be a simple arrow function.
It doesn't need to be marked as a sync sends we're not going to be using any asynchronous code inside
of here in this function.
We're going to do is return a new instance of Appollo boost.
Essentially exactly what we do right here.
So I'm going to copy the highlighted code.
I'm going to bring it over to get client and I am going to return what I just copied so here you call
get client and you get a new instance of Appollo boost back.
Now we are going to have to import Appollo boost if we're using it.
So up above inport Apollo boost and we're going to grab that from the Apollo boost module and next up
we will indeed export this function as well.
Alex boarded as the default so get client as default.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can use this file with a new get client function in both of our test
suites allowing us to remove this code right here.
Let's go ahead and start with the user test file so I can in Port get a client from the file we just
created daat forward slash you tills forward slash get client.
Then I can use it down below.
So instead of manually creating the new instance of Appollo boost I will just call get client I'm going
to call it with no arguments since it takes none.
And I'll get the new client back.
That's also going to allow me to remove that inport up above.
We still want to import GQ L from Apollo boost though so the line as a whole will stay in place.
Now that we have this file refactored we can save things and down below the test suite should still
be passing.
We're going to do the exact same thing over in this file.
I'm going to start by modifying my import statement for moving Appollo boost.
Then I'll grab.
Get client so inport get client from that forward slash utils forward slash get client and last up what
are we going to do.
We're going to call that function getting the return value and storing it on the client variable.
So right here I can save the post test suite and that test suite should have its one test case passing
down below.
It looks like everything is going well so far to passing test suites by passing tests.
So all we've done is we've created a function that's responsible for generating the new instance of
Appollo boost.
Now what we're going to do is accept an optional authentication token.
So the authentication token is something that we're going to have to define and we need what we need
the ID of the user in order to generate it.
So the authentication token itself is actually going to get generated over inside of seed database data.
J.
S in here we get the user's ID back from our call to create user.
We have to use that to generate a new authentication token then we're going to export it from this file.
So it can actually be used in our test cases.
For example if I want to fetch my user profile in a test case I'm going to need JWT in order to get
that done in order to authenticate as our seed database user.
We're going to set all of that up in the next video so stay tuned and I will see you then.