In this video we're going to continue what we started in the last one.
The goal is to create a test case that can test a operation that requires authentication.
And here's how we're going to do it in this file.
We're going to create a JWT for our test user and export it in this file or any test suite that needs
authentication.
We're going to import that JWT.
And in the individual test case we'll pass it to get client getting a fresh client.
That means get client is going to need it to accept a token and we'll get to that as well.
Let's go ahead and start though in ceed database dot J.
S. We want to create an authentication token and get it exported out of this file.
Now to do that the first thing I'm going to do is define a variable.
Up above Konst user 1 this is going to be an object and on there we're going to put all of the stuff
associated with the User 1.
So we're going to put the input what we passed to Prisma the output what Prisma gives us and the JWT
which will generate in just a moment.
Let's go ahead and start with the input right here on user one.
I'm going to be setting up an input property I'm going to set that up as an object and it's going to
have name email and password.
So down below I'm going to grab these three values I'm going to take them.
Paste them up above inside of the input object.
Then down here data can get its value from user 1 input.
Perfect.
Now we're also going to have a property on user 1 that stores the data that Prisma gives us back.
So right here I could call that something like output or I could call it user or data.
I'm going to go ahead and stick with user.
And this is going to get its value later on.
So for the moment I can leave it as undefined.
It's not necessary to set this property up with an undefined value but it is a bit more explicit.
So someone who's scanning this code can see that there are these two properties.
Well one is undefined.
That must suggest that it's likely going to get a value later which is true down below.
Instead of creating a user variable we're going to get the value for user 1 dot user from whatever comes
back here.
So I'm going to remove Konst end user and I will just add a user one dot user.
So here we are setting user 1 dot user to the data that Prisma gives us back.
Now we were using that user variable we removed down below the user ID was used in both locations.
So I'm going to have to refactor it to reference this property instead.
So right here user 1 dot user dot ID.
And the same thing down below user 1 user ID.
Excellent.
So now we have a lot of good stuff stored on user 1.
And the last thing we're going to do is store a J.
W.T. property for the moment.
I'll leave this as undefined.
We can't create it yet because we don't know the user's ID.
We don't have that till this code finishes executing.
Right here though we do indeed have everything we need to create a Jason web token for our seed database
user.
And that's exactly what we're going to end up doing.
Step one is the inport so up above we can go ahead and import JWT from the library we've been using
for that sort of thing.
Jason a web tokin which is already installed and down below we can now take advantage of it like we've
done before.
I'm going to go ahead and break things up a little bit and I'll even leave some comments to keep things
organized.
So right here delete test data then right here.
Create user one and just blow the creation will set up that tokens are right here.
User one dot JWT is going to get a value and that value is going to come from calling.
JWT dot sign which is what we've used to sign tokens in the past right here.
We have to provide those two arguments if you remember the first is our object payload.
And the second is the secret.
Now for the payload we were setting user id equal to the user's ID.
So in this case user 1 adult user data ID and for the JWT secret we'll continue to use the environment
variable.
So that's process then dot then EMV and the name of the variable is JWT underscore secret.
Perfect.
So now we have that.
Jason Webb token created we can export user one from this file and take advantage of it including the
JWT in our individual test suites.
So let's go ahead and knock that out down below.
I'm going to add a nother export.
We already have seed database will be exporting user 1 and we're not going to export this as the default
since we already have a default.
So we'll just leave this as a generic named export now that it is indeed exported though we are all
done with this file.
We can save it and move into one of our test case files.
Let's go ahead and start with a test in user dot test dot J S.
I'm going to ensure that I can successfully fetch my user profile if and only if I'm logged in first
up I'm going to grab user one off of the C database file so right here user 1 then down below we can
use user 1 dot JWT to get that Jason Webb token.
I'm going to create a brand new test suite right here.
We'll call test like we've done plenty of times before.
Whoops I said test suite.
We are indeed just creating a test case and for this one we can call it something like should fetch
user profile.
So in this case we are going to have an authenticated client and we're going to make sure that when
we're authenticated we can indeed get our user profile back I'll be passing in the async function.
And then here we're going to do what we've done plenty of times before we'll be setting up our operation
and firing it off making assertions about the result.
But the first thing we actually have to do is generate a new client so Konst client equals we're going
to call get client and we're going to pass to it.
Our Jason Webb tokin now currently get client is it going to do anything with that argument and that's
OK.
We'll fix that in a moment.
For now though user 1 dot JWT.
So in some instances we're going to call get client with a Jason Webb tokin in that case we want a client
that's authenticated as a particular user.
In other cases like what we have above we're not going to pass in a JWT.
And in this case we want a client that's not authenticated as a particular user.
So the only thing we have to do to actually get this code to work is to add support for that optional
J W.T. argument over in the Get client function.
Now that the argument is set up we also have to use it and we're going to use it by setting up a new
property up on our options object.
Here's what that's going to look like.
There is a request property that we can set on this option's object and it's actually a function.
I'm just going to use the ESX method definition and to define a request.
Now this function gets called for every single outgoing request and it gets called with the operation
itself.
Now we can use the operation argument to manipulate the operation.
And in this case we're going to manipulate it and add on a single authorization header.
Now we only want to add on the head or if a token was actually provided.
If we're in the case of the call up above like this one we don't want to do anything if no authentication
token was provided down here when we do provide a token though we want to run some special code.
So inside of our request method we are going to set up a condition if there is a JWT then and only then
are we actually going to do anything.
What are we going to do.
Well there is a set context method on operation and that's how we set headers.
So right here operation dot set context this gets called with a single argument an object that contains
the pieces of context you're trying to set.
And there is a header's property we can configure an on this object we can define the headers we want
to set up now in our case we just need 1 authorization
any value for authorization is going to be a string.
I'll use a template string.
We start off with barer space then the tokens are right here I get inter-relate the JWT variable.
So what are we really doing.
If a token was provided we generate a new instance of Appollo boost.
And for every single request if there is a token we set up the authorization Hetter.
It's as simple as that.
Now we can actually use this code in our test suites to write test cases that use authentication.
Now this code is set up and in user dot test dot J S we're already using it by passing in an authentication
token down below what we're going to do is go ahead and actually fire off an operation.
We are going to fire off a query which typically requires authentication so we're only going to see
it work if things were actually set up correctly.
All right.
Here let's go ahead and create a new constant for a get profile operation.
We'll be using GQ well along with a template string and right inside of here what are we going to do.
We are going to define the query.
It is indeed a query.
We'll be using the query we set up earlier in the class.
And let's just grab their ID their name and their e-mail.
And down below we're going to go ahead and fire that officer right here.
I'm going to use a wait with the client doc query passing in our options object and setting up that
query property which is going to get its value from get profile above.
Excellent.
So at this point we are creating a new client that is indeed using authentication.
We're setting up the operation we're trying to perform and we're firing it off.
Now if things are actually set up correctly if the token is getting used I would expect this test case
to pass.
No error should get thrown out if things are set up incorrectly.
This should be throwing an error as you cannot access a user's profile without being authenticated.
I'm going to save the user test suite and down below.
We're going to see what happens.
Right now it's rerunning both of those test suites.
And what do we have.
We have six passing tests.
So we have our brand new tests showing up.
It is indeed working as expected.
Now we can just comment out this one line to see the test case fail in this case.
It's going to use the other client the global client variable defined up above.
This one does not use authentication.
So when I try to fetch the profile I would indeed expect a failure with this line commented out.
I'll save the test suite once again.
And now we should have one failing test case.
If we do we know everything is working as expected.
And there we go.
That is exactly what we're getting.
If we scroll up the error is going to say you error authentication required.
So now we have a system for actually firing off operations that require authentication.
I'm going to uncomment this line.
And we are indeed once again authenticated as our test database user.
Now from here we can test all of the other operations that require authentication and we can even add
some assertions to this particular test case actually looking at the profile object that came back.
Let's go ahead and start there.
So what I'm going to do is create a constant.
I'm going to get its value by destructuring data right off of response if I'm going to use data from
response.
I could just break it out into its own variable and then what we're going to do is add an assertion
about what's on and data.
So for example I could expect that data dot me dot ID equals using and to be the user 1 ID.
So that's user 1 dot user dot ID.
So if I'm authenticated as this user the profile I get back should indeed contain my ID as opposed to
containing the ID of another user.
I can do the same thing for other properties as well.
So I could expect that data Daten me dot Neme equals using to be user one dot user dot name.
And finally we'll add an expect call for email data.
Email should equal right here.
User 1 dot user dot.
Email.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and actually save the file and see what happens.
Now we already know that the operation is going to at least succeed.
So the new part we're testing is whether or not our assertions work as expected if they do.
We're going to move on to the challenge for this video and they are indeed working.
Let's talk about the challenge by heading over to the post test file down below.
I have a set of challenge comments.
The big picture goal is to write a test case for the my posts query.
I want to try to fetch my posts.
Me being the test database user and I should get both back.
The published one as well as the draft post since I'm authenticated.
So Step 1 create the new test case and set up a client that has authentication then you're going to
fire off the my posts queery getting all of the scalar fields for each post.
Then you're going to assert that two posts were fetched.
So the length of the array you get back should indeed be two.
And finally you're going to test your work by saving the file and letting your new test case run.
Take some time to knock that out and test your work and when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
I'm going to kick things off by creating a brand new test function we're going to call it.
We are going to pass in a name.
I'll say something like should fetch users posts then we'll set up our async function and we can focus
on the test case code itself.
Now the first thing we're going to end up doing is creating a new client that does indeed use authentication.
So I'm going to end up calling get client a second time passing in a user one's JWT.
Now I don't have that in Portage So we have to start there.
I'm going to grab user one the named export down below.
I'm going to generate that new client Konst client equals right here.
I'll be calling get client passing in user 1 dot JWT.
Now we can move on to Step 2 which is to actually set up that operation and fire it off.
So right here Konst my posts seems like an appropriate enough name we'll be using GQ well with our template
string.
This is indeed a query operation and the query itself is called My posts and for each post I'll just
grab the id the title of the body.
And finally the published value.
Perfect.
Next up we have to fire that operation off.
So down below what I'm going to do is get their response destructuring data.
So Konst data gets its value from a weight.
We are going to await client dot query passing in our operations object.
The query gets its value from my posts above.
So instead of getting the response I'm just destructuring data type of response since it's the only
property we're ever going to use from response.
Now that we have this in place we're done step 2 and we can assert that we got two posts back.
This user has two posts I want to get them both.
Let's make sure that happens.
I'm going to expect that data dot my posts which is an array that length equals using need to be functionality.
The number 2.
If it's greater than 2 or less than 2 then obviously things aren't working as expected and that's a
problem.
So now that we have the assertion in place we can test our work.
I'm going to go ahead and remove those test comments.
I will be saving the test suite allowing things to rerun down below.
And we should have I believe at this point 7 passing test cases and right here we do two passing test
suites with seven test cases across both of them.
Everything is working as expected and we were able to get all of this done in just 6 seconds.
Now that we have this in place we know how to write test cases that fire off operations that require
authentication.
We're going to continue on in the next video reading a few more test cases using this strategy.
So stay tuned and I'll see you then.