We've written a few tests for authentication and in this video we're going to get a bit more experience
by writing a few more who are going to write a test for update post create post and delete post.
We'll work on update post together and you'll be writing test cases for create post and delete posts
as your challenge for the video.
So Dambulla Let's go ahead and create a test case making sure we can indeed update a post right here.
Test should be able to update own post and then we're going to set up the function and a sync arrow
function.
And we're going to use the techniques explored so far.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by creating a brand new client.
In this case we are attempting to test that things work well when authenticated.
So I'll create a new client calling get client in passing in user ones JWT that is user 1 dot JWT.
From here I can go ahead and set up that operation which is going to be the update post mutation rate
here.
Konst update post.
I'm going to set it up using a GQ L and a template string and down below will define the actual mutation
perfect.
Now all we have to decide which of our posts were actually going to update and we have to in the C database
file we have post number one which is a published post and we have.
Post Number two which is unpublished for this update.
I'm going to take post number one and turn it from being published to being unpublished.
Now in order to get that done in order to actually set up this operation I need to know the ID of that
post and this is not a hard coded value that we can type in because remember this code runs before every
test case it generates a brand new post.
That means there's a unique ID.
So like we did with our user we need to store this information somewhere and export it so our test file
can access it.
Let's go ahead and get this done.
Up above just below user 1.
I'm going to create a new variable right here.
It Konst post 1 and we're going to set up those two properties.
I'm going to set up input.
This is going to contain the input we pass to Prisma And I'm also going to set up right here post.
This is going to eventually contain the post information sent back from Prisma which will include the
ID.
But for now we can just send it equal to undefine.
Now what exactly are we going to put inside of input.
Well you don't have to use input at all for this particular test case.
Doing so would be optional but it's a good idea to see the input verse the output on the object.
So down below.
But I'm going to do is first leave a little comment up here.
Create post 1 and then down below.
Create post 2 and 4 post 1.
I'm going to grab the title body and published and rip those out of this object I'm leaving author in
place.
Since we won't know the author ID in time to include that up above down here all we're going to do is
take post one data input and we're going to spread it out so I'll use dot dot dot.
Up front that's going to copy all of the properties from the input object over to this one.
And what are we going to put on the input object.
I'm going to put those three values that we just grabbed.
Now what are we going to do.
Well we are going to make sure that post one dot post gets set so down below right here post one dot
post is going to get its value from awaiting the result of our create post call.
Excellent.
Now down near the bottom of the file we can go ahead and export it export on our local post one object.
So this is going to allow our test cases to access the input should they need it and the output should
they need that.
And in our case the new test we're creating definitely needs the output we have to know that ID.
So let's go back to the test file and inport what we just export it up to alongside of user 1.
I'm going to grab.
Post one end down below.
We're going to use that while defining our operation right here.
Now we can set up the operation will be using update post providing the arguments it needs as well as
these selections set.
Let's go ahead and start with that selection set for the response will grab the ID title body.
And lastly I'll also grab published for the arguments we have to start by defining ID which it needs
ID is a string and we have to provide the idea of the post to update.
In this case I will use the template string interpellation to inject post one dot Post dot ID.
So here we are grabbing the id property off of post one post and that's what gets set down below.
So we have the response data from Prisma back in the test case.
We can now define it data right alongside of ID.
This is going to allow us to define exactly what we want to change.
That is a published post.
We are going to unpublished it.
So I'll be setting published equal to false.
Excellent.
Now we can go ahead and focus on actually firing this operation off and asserting something about what
happens when the operation is complete.
Right here.
I will be destructuring data off of the response.
Then I will use a weight with client dot mutate passing in the Options object and setting up the mutation
in this case.
We will be using update post defined up above.
Now at this point the operation should have succeeded and we can set up our assertion.
Now there's no need to assert that the operation didn't throw an error.
Otherwise the cast case would already fail with the code in place because clients mutate would throw
an error.
There is no need to assert that we actually do get back these four fields since the graft UL operation
would fail if we requested a field that the type didn't support.
Right here for our assertion we can expect something about the particular value of the published value
data dot update.
Post dot published.
So we asked for that back and we want to make sure it is now false.
So I will use to be right here.
False.
Perfect.
Now this would be a complete test case.
You could also add more to this test case.
If you wanted to and for example sake we will do that.
What we're going to do is also make sure that when we look in the database we are seeing the post as
UN published.
So sure we're getting false back in the response.
But what about the Prisma database itself.
Now if I scroll up we actually don't have Prisma loaded into this particular test file.
We do indeed have it over in our user test file and we've been using it.
Let's go ahead and grab that inport line and bring it over to our post test suite as well so he can
take advantage of Prisma in our test cases down below.
We're gonna use the exists functionality once again to check that that post exists and that its published
value is false.
You could alternatively query for the post and look at its data directly.
Either approach would be identical and would work just fine right here.
I will create a new Konst called exists and I will use a wait with Prisma.
Exists.
Done post to check if a particular post exists in this case we're looking for a post with two features.
One ID should be post one dot Post dot ID and the other is that its published value should be false.
If the published value is not false that post won't be seen as existing and will get false back instead
of true.
So in this case we want to make sure that exists is indeed true and will add an assertion for that down
below expecting that exists equals using to be true perfect.
So now we're looking at the response and we're also looking at the database itself.
I'm going to save the file that's going to run the test case and hopefully we have.
Now I think 8 passing tests down below I can see one of the test suites finished now the other one did
and everything went as expected.
All right.
Now that we have this test case in place and you've got a bit more experience it's going to be up to
you to write tests for creating a post and for deleting a post and we'll talk about exactly what I'd
like you to do down below in some challenge comments right here.
You're going to write two test cases goal or write a test case for create post and delete post.
So one is the Create post test case.
You're going to use authentication so in this case we're expecting it to work and you're going to assert
that the post you create actually ends up in the database with the correct fields.
You can use a similar technique to what we used here to set up the arguments and to assert that the
database looks right down below that.
It's the second test case.
You're going to make sure that delete post works.
So once again you are going to work with a client that has authentication set up and you're going to
remove the second post asserting that it is indeed deleted from the database after the operation completes.
Now it's important to note that the second post currently is not exposed from the seed database file.
So you're going to go ahead and have to do something similar to what we did for post one up above.
Take some time to knock all of that out and test your work.
Right now we have 8 passing test cases.
So when you're done that you should have 10 passing tests.
All right.
Pause the video when you're done come back and click play.
How that go.
I'm going to kick things off with the first test case and I'll add that right up above.
A new test.
Making sure that I can indeed create a post so right here should create a new post.
I'll be setting up that async arrow function and we're going to go through the process described.
So in this case we will be using authentication.
So I will set up a new client.
Konst client equals.
I'll be using GET client to fetch a new client and in this case we're going to go ahead and pass in
that JWT.
User 1 dot J.
W T.
Perfect.
From here we can go ahead and actually put that to use.
First step we have to define our operations so cost to create post can store that.
I'll be using GQ well with a template string and right here.
This will indeed be a mutation.
The mutation we're using is create post and we have to pass in some arguments as well as our selection
set.
Let's go ahead and start with the selection set.
So right here inside of the curly braces for this newly created post we can grab whatever we want.
I'll grab the ID title body and published I'll just stick with those scalar fields to keep things simple.
And in terms of create post we have to define just one argument that's data on data.
We have to define the information that makes up the post we're trying to create.
Right here I can set up a title.
Let's go ahead and use something like a test post.
Then we can set up the body.
And for this one I can leave the string empty.
And finally we can pick a published value for this newly created post.
Let's go ahead and just use.
True though.
Either would work just fine.
So now we have the operation defined and we can go ahead and fire it off down below.
I'm going to use a concept we're going to grab the response data and we are going to await for the following
our client mutate call will pass in our mutation on the mutation property.
The mutation rate here is creed post.
So at this point a new post should indeed be created and we can focus on the assertions that check that
the post was created correctly right here.
Let's go ahead and add some assertions into the mix.
So I am going to expect something about data to create post title.
I'm going to expect that that equals the title we had above which is the string a test post.
Next up we can expect something about the body that's data create Post dot body.
In this case I can use to be to assert that it is an empty string and finally we have published Sarette
here expecting data to create post data published
equals using to be the following the boolean true.
With this in place we can go ahead and save our file the test suite is going to rerun and we'll look
for that ninth passing test.
If all goes well there we'll move on to the second test case we're creating for deleting a post.
Everything's passing.
So let's add that second test case right here.
A test should delete post we're going to set this up as an async function.
And remember we do indeed want to authenticate.
So let's get that out of the way and set up this brand new client Konst client equals.
I will be calling get client passing in the JWT user wan dot JWT.
Now we're going to end up setting up that delete post mutation.
But remember we need the idea of the post to remove and I asked you to remove the second post on purpose.
Over in the database.
Currently that Id never get stored anywhere.
It's lost to the ether since we don't do anything with the response value here.
What we're gonna do is set up a post to variable like we have for post 1.
So I'll set up post to I'll set it up as an object will have our input object as well as our posts property.
So right here post will be undefined for the moment and then we can copy the input up above.
So down below I'll grab title body in published cutting it out and pasting it up above in input removing
that extra comma on the published property line and from here we can use post to input down below.
So right here spreading that out.
Dot dot dot post to dot input and we're also going to do something with the return value.
I'm going to store it on post to dot post.
Excellent.
Now we can actually go ahead and export that Surve right here exporting post to.
And now we can access post to in the other file and we're going to use that to get the ID of the post
to remove.
I'm going to save the C database file over inside of the post test suite up at the very top alongside
of user 1 and post 1.
We will go ahead and grab posts to.
Excellent.
Now let's use that.
So down below we're going to set up our delete post-operation right here in the test case.
Konst delete post will be setting that up using GQ.
Well along with a template string it is indeed a mutation.
So we'll set that up right here.
The mutation name is delete posts and we have to provide the ID of the post we're trying to remove.
So right here ID equals a string and we'll use interpellation to add the ID in that's going to be post
to dot Post dot ID.
Down below we can set up our selection set and this is the selection set for the deleted post where
you can just grab something like the ID that would be perfectly fine and maybe you grabbed more or something
different.
That's OK.
And down below.
We're going to fire this off.
So I'm going to go ahead and await the following client docked mutate passing in our mutation property
on the options object using the operation defined above delete post.
Now we can set up an assertion and all we're going to do is use exists to see if the post is still in
the database so Konst exists equals we'll use a weight with Prisma dot exists dot post passing in the
ID of that second post.
So Id is going to get its value from post to dot post ID and then down below.
We're going to expect that the exists value is true to be passing in true.
Perfect.
Now we have our second test case in place I can save the test suite once again and we should have 10
passing tests if we do.
We're going to move on to the next video where we'll see the database with some comments and set up
a couple of comment test cases right here.
We do indeed have an error.
I can see that the following is occurring.
We expected.
True.
We received false.
This was a typo on my part.
This should have been false as opposed to true.
Now I can go back at this hour and pretend to be a perfect developer but when testing iteration is an
important part you might not nail everything on the first try and that's OK.
But once you do get to a working test suite you know that you're secure and you're going to be able
to detect changes down the line since your tests will start to fail if anything breaks.
All right.
That's where we're going to stop for this one.
The Focused of the next video is on comments.
So let's go ahead and jump right into that.