In this video you're going to learn about you l variables which is going to give us a way to reuse and
better define our graft operations so to talk about this.
Let's head over to the user test file right here.
What do we define we define a create user mutation.
What's the problem.
All of the data that we're setting up it's hard coded right inside.
So if I wanted to create a user with different values I would have to define this over again.
And that's exactly what I do down below in a separate test case should not sign up on a user with an
invalid password.
Down here I define the mutation once again passing in the other data values.
So this is obviously a problem sends out its core.
Both are using the create user mutation.
It would be nice if there was a built in way to pass in the values we wanted to use and the answer is
there is now to start exploring this.
We can actually avoid our code altogether and head over to graft Well playground.
So what I'm going to do for the moment is shut down our test suite and start up our dev server.
So NPM run dev once the dev server is up we're going to head over to local host 4000 where we fired
off so many operations before.
Now the goal here is to work with an operation that does define some dynamic values.
So I'm going to use something like create user right here.
For example we create a user and we define that data right in line.
Instead we're going to use variables.
Now you might have noticed down below along side of HTP hatters which we have used.
We also have a variable's tab and this is where we can define the specific values we want to use like
a name value of G-S and a password value of read 1 2 3 4 5.
Now there are three steps to getting this done.
First up we have to define all variables that a given operation should support.
This includes their name and their type that's going to end up happening right here on line 1.
Then we're going to actually pass in values for those variables.
That's going to happen down here and we'll learn how to pass in variables from our code in a little
bit as well.
And then finally we're going to use it.
So we're going to use it right here where we currently have hard coded data.
So define it assign it and use it.
Let's go ahead and start by defining the variables that this given operation should support.
Now right here we can set those up using a set of parentheses.
We can then list out all of the variables we want to support.
Let's go ahead and start with just one.
We're going to have a variable that's going to store the name for the user.
We're going to create now all variables engraft QOL are prefixed with a dollar sign.
So if I wanted the variable name it would actually be a dollar sign name.
I could also have something like Dollar Sign age or dollar sign amount or dollar sign whatever.
In this case we're creating a variable for the name so dollar sign name it seems appropriate.
It could be called anything the name here is in no way associated with the name down below.
Now for all of these variables we also have to define the type we're expecting.
So we have access to all of our standard graphical types any type we can use in our application.
In this case it could be an integer or a Boolean or a float but in actuality we want a string here.
And I'm also going to mark that as non nullable meaning it needs to be provided.
Now we have the name of a variable but if I over over that you can see that variable name is never used.
That's creating an error.
We can fix that by getting rid of the string.
Jess down below.
So I'm going to remove the string as well as the quotes but I will leave the colon and the comma in
place and we're going to reference the variable by its name right here.
Dollar Sign name perfect.
So currently we have defined the variable we haven't assigned it a value yet and we have used it down
below.
Let's go ahead and actually assign a value to that name variable.
So right here we're going to set up an object key value pairs.
The key being the variable where assigning a value to and the value being the value for the variable.
Now it's important to note we leave the dollar sign off down below.
So name is going to end up working with this variable right here prefixing them with the dollar sign
that's something we only do in our graph Cuil code.
Now what value do we want to use for name we'll.
I'll go ahead and use something like Gunther.
So now we have a fresh name that is no longer in line we have extracted that into a variable.
And since the e-mail is already taken I'm going to go ahead and swap that out for something like Gunther
an example dotcom.
Let's go ahead and see if our variable works.
I'm going to knock that out by just clicking that play button and taking a look at the data that we
get back right here.
What do we get back for name.
We get back the value Gunther the exact value we passed in down below.
Now that we have this in place let's take things one step further.
We're going to pass in all of the data.
The name of the e-mail and the password using variables.
Now when it comes to the types that we use up above for our variable definitions and these are not limited
to just these scalar types we can actually reference any type that we ended up creating as well.
So over in our application let's crack open the source directory and open schema.
Dom Graff you Al.
Just to jog our memories down below.
We created a whole bunch of different types.
These can be used as the type for a given variable.
Now do you remember the create user mutation.
Well it's defined right here and we have the type of data set to create user input.
We can actually use create user input inside of graph Q L playground or inside of our test case as we'll
see in a little bit.
So we don't have to pass in three different variables.
We can just pass in the one.
So right over here we are going to get rid of name and we're going to create a variable like data and
then we're going to get its type from our definitions.
We're going to use create user input.
So right here that's going to be create user input.
We'll leave that as non-global making sure that it is indeed provided.
Now down below we no longer have a name variable and we actually don't want to provide this object at
all the value for data is going to come from dollar sign and data defined up above.
And the last thing we have to do is to actually assign it a value.
Right now we only assign a name a variable which is not actually supported.
I'm going to set up data instead.
That value is going to be an object and on that object we're gonna set up all of the things that that
type actually lists out.
So we can go ahead and find that down below right here.
Create user input.
We need a name string.
We need an email string and a password string.
So let's go ahead and set up all three name.
I'm going to go ahead and use something along the lines of Ben.
Then we can set up an e-mail for Ben I'm going to use Ben at example dot com.
And finally we'll set up a passwords are right here password a password Lissa's stick with red.
One two three four five.
So now we have all three values extracted out of the operation itself making what we have here highly
reusable.
We could pass in different user data to create.
Let's go ahead and fire this off and see what happens.
I fire it off and what do we get.
We get an issue about a unique constraint that means I must already have a ban.
Let's go ahead and try a different name.
I'll use something like Kevin for the name and Kevin at example dot com for the email perfect now we
can see that the user was clearly created as expected.
Now in using variables in a you playground it can be hard to see the real value we're getting.
We already were into reusing this so we're not really seeing a ton of benefit from switching to variables
but when we actually set up our operations on a client like a mobile or browser client or in a test
suite we can start to reuse operations that we originally had to define over and over again.
For example if we switch over to the user test suite we use create user multiple times in this file
with variables we can easily reuse that operation.
So we don't have to write it out over and over again.
And that's exactly what we're going to end up doing to start.
I'm going to define a variable right here outside of all of the test suites.
This is something that can be reuse that accessed and all of those test functions.
And I'm going to take our existing create user operation and use that as the starting point.
Now we are indeed going to define a variable right here.
We'll call this one data just like we did in graphical playground and the type for data will indeed
be of the type create user input non-global.
Excellent.
So now we have the exact same variable definition we had engraft UL playground.
And we can go ahead and switch up the operation itself right here.
I am going to remove all of those hard coded values and reference the variable instead then I'm going
to grab tokin the user's ID and also grab their name and their email.
Perfect.
With this in place we now have something that's truly reusable and we can take it into our operations
down below.
Perfect.
I'm going to start with.
Should create user our very first test case.
We're no longer going to define the entire operation inside of the individual test case.
All we're going to do is define the variable value.
So right here a new constant variables is going to equal an object in like we do down below.
We'll be setting up that data property will have name.
I'll stick with Andrew like I did in here.
We also have the email.
I'll use the same value Andrew at example dot com.
And finally we have the password.
I'll stick with my pass.
One two three.
Perfect.
Now we can remove this operation entirely from the test case and we can still reference the existing
one we have up above.
So create user is still a valid reference since it exists up here.
The only thing left to do is make sure that create user gets the correct variables.
We've defined all of those on this object and along side of the mutation property for the mutate method
that would be alongside of the query property for queries we can set up a variables property.
Right here we can define the variables we want to use by referencing that object.
And we're done now since we have a property and a variable with the same name.
We can use the ESX property shorthand and there we go.
We now have a shorter version of that test case where we don't have to redefine the operation every
single time we can truly focus on just making sure the operation works as expected given some set of
input data input defined on the variables variable up above.
Now that we have this in place let's go ahead and save the test file and make sure that the test suite
still passes.
So down below I'm going to shut down the dev server and run NPM run test.
This is going to run the show to create a new user test suite using the operation we defined up here.
And if everything works then we know that all we've done is we've refactored things.
We actually haven't to change the functionality.
It looks like we're all done 10 passing test cases with variables introduced into the mix.
Let's continue on down the test case list.
Right here we have get users get users actually doesn't have any dynamic values at all which means no
variables are required.
That means I can cut get users out bring that up above for the sole purpose of making it reusable.
Should another test case need to access it.
There is no need to define it inside of the Test Case function specifically.
We don't have to set up the variables property here since no variables are accepted down below that
we have log in.
In this case we have another operation that does have some dynamic data.
So in this case what we're going to start with log in as the starting point we are going to have to
tweak it to support a variable above.
Let's go ahead and get that done.
I'm going to copy the log in operation.
I'm going to bring it up.
Top and I'm going to change the indenting perfect and in this case we are going to set up a data variable
as expected.
Now the type for that exists over inside of our schema definition.
We have log in user input.
So that's what we want to use right here.
After a mutation will set up support for data that is log in user input as a non nullable variable.
Then down below instead of defining that right here we can go ahead and simply reference the variable
dollar sign data and we're done.
Now we can focus on taking things back down to the test case and using this log in operation and actually
passing in the data expected.
So down here in the test case itself I'm going to start by defining the variables Konst variables equals
an object.
We're going to set up data and we're going to configure the variables needed right here.
We are going to need email.
I'll use Jan at example dot com which is the seed database email then I'll mess up the password down
below.
We have a password value equal to read lowercase 0 9 8 exclamation mark at sign pound sign a dollar
sign and we're done.
Now we can remove the log and operation right here.
We can still reference log in since we have that variable up above.
And we're going to add the variables property on getting its value from the object right here.
Now that we have that in place we can move on to the next test case.
And in this case we will be reusing the create user mutation.
The test suite is running in the background but that shouldn't stop us from continuing on.
Let's go ahead and actually reuse create user.
That means we don't need to define this operation again will remove it in a second.
All we have to do is define our variables.
We're going to have data.
And in this case we have values for name email and password password being short.
Now I can actually just copy these directly out of the operation.
I'm going to cut them and paste them up above and we can remove the operation definition entirely.
Now in this case we're using double quotes and I like to stick with single quotes so I'll go ahead and
refactor that.
We have the string Andrew for name.
We have the string and you're at example dot com or email and we have pass as the value for password.
All we have to do is pass those in.
So right here passing in variables and now we are performing the exact same thing without needing to
redefine the operation we've already defined before the test case is rerunning and we're going to move
on it to the final test we have thatching the user's profile.
We still have 10 passing tests so all the work we've done so far has been for the good.
Let's go ahead and start by defining get profile outside of this test case.
Now this one doesn't require any variables at all.
Nothing is dynamic.
So there's no need to do a ton of refactoring.
I'm simply going to remove it I'm going to take that up top and I'm going to go ahead and paste it in.
Now you might say why even do that.
We weren't reusing this particular operation at all.
But there are other test cases we're going to end up adding.
For example I might want to make sure that I can't fetch a user's profile when I'm not logged in.
In that case I would expect it to throw an error by factoring out all of our operations.
We now have the option down the line to actually reuse them should we need to.
And we've currently already re-used a couple.
The last thing we're going to do in this video is actually take these operations and break them out
into a completely separate file.
We are already using them but there is no need to define them inside of the test suite.
So I'm going to bring them over to a new file in the tills directory.
Let's go ahead and make an operations file operations.
J S and in here we're going to take all four operations.
I'm going to start with the concert and create user and go all the way down to the closing back Tich
forget profile.
I'm going to cut those out and I'm going to bring them over to the operations file.
Now the only inport we need is.
GQ well up above to make sure things still work.
I'm going to grab.
Well from Appollo boost and once we have that all we have to do is export things so down below Let's
export everything.
We'll start off with create user then we have log in.
That is the third one we have.
Get users and we have get profile as well get users get profile and we can expand this file as we add
more operations into the mix.
Now we can import all of those over in the user test suite up above.
Let's go ahead and inport from the file that we just created right here in Port a bunch of stuff from
that's dot forward slash you tills forward slash operations.
What do we need.
Well first up we have create user then we have a get users we have log in and we have get profile all
for being imported from the other file.
Now we're going to save things for the last time in this video the test suite is going to every run
and we should have 10 passing test cases.
The advantage is that now we have all of our operations in a separate reusable file.
All right.
We can see that everything is working as expected.
So I'll see you in the next video where you're going to do something similar for the post test suite.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.