In this video it's going to be up to you to extract every operation in Post dot test dot J.
S. out into the operations file.
So we have the Post's query right here.
No variables but it still needs to be extracted down below.
We have my posts which needs to be extracted.
We then have our a mutation update post which takes in dynamic values that needs to be extracted down
below that we have create post and then down below that we have delete post.
So we have one two three four five different operations.
I'd like you to take some time to pull all of those out.
Anywhere where a dynamic value is used you want to set up the appropriate type.
Similar to what we did in operations.
J.S. for things like create user where we used create user input or for log again where we used log
in user input.
So take as much time as you need to knock this out using what we learned in the last video.
And if you get stuck along the way just refer to the operations file and the user test file to see how
we did things over there.
Because in the end of the day the process is identical.
We're just working with a different set of queries and mutations.
All right knock that out.
Pause the video when you're done at test your work then come back and click play.
How that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off just working.
Top to bottom through the files starting with get posts no variables required.
So we could remove this one completely and bring it over to our operations file.
I'm just going to add that down below at the bottom of the list and then we'll take a moment to export
it as well.
So right here get posts.
Excellent.
Now from here we have to make sure that we still load the operation in since we are referencing a get
posts variable.
So I set up an import statement up above.
I'm going to import get posts from that file right here.
That would be daat forward slash you tills forward slash operations.
Excellent.
Now we have get posts in place we can save the program and move on to the next one.
The next one is my posts.
This one also requires 0 variables so we can go ahead and cut that out.
Bringing it over to the operations file.
So right here I am going to adjust the indentation of get posts and then down below I will set up my
posts and for my posts all we have to do is export it.
So right here my posts perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can go ahead and import it into the other file.
So right here we are still referencing my posts.
Let's go ahead an important
my posts.
Perfect.
Next on our list is the update post mutation.
Here we are going to want to support a variable especially for data.
So if you forget exactly what something uses you can always go over to schema dot graph QOL up at the
very top.
We have our update post mutation that is sitting right here.
We have ID of the type ID and data of the type update post input.
So those are the two arguments that we would need to pass in both variables.
Let's go ahead and actually set that up to start.
I'm going to grab this operation in its entirety.
I am going to copy it to the clipboard and I'm going to bring it over to the operations file pasting
it in at the bottom of the list.
Then we're going to go ahead and make some changes to it.
We need it to variable.
So we need ID of the type ID exactly like we had over in our schema definition right here.
And we also need data of the type update post input.
So comma space dollar sign data update post input.
Perfect From here we can go ahead and use both of those down below.
The idea is going to get its value from the ID variable and the same thing is true with data.
We'll remove that data object getting the value from data instead.
Now everything is defined over in this file we're all done.
We can export update post.
And now we can focus on adjusting the test case to actually use this operation.
The first step in that process is going to be in porting it up above let's grab that third one right
here update post and down below we're actually going to use it.
So the first thing I'm going to do is define the variables we want to pass in.
So Konst variables equals an object.
We're going to have to I.D. and data.
So our set up ID.
It's going to get its value from post one dot Post dot ID and I'll set up the second one.
We're going to have data which is an object and I'm going to define once again just published setting
an equal to false.
Perfect.
Now we can remove the operation down below entirely and the last thing you needed to do is make sure
those variables were actually used by passing them in right here variables setting up that property
to get its value from the variable with the same name.
Now that we have that in place we can save the file and continue down the list.
Next up we have create post followed by finally delete.
Post create post is going to go through the same process.
The first thing I'm going to do is just grab this operation copy it to the clipboard and bring it over
to the operations file.
I'll adjust the indentation of update post paste in create post and adjust the indentation there as
well.
And we're going to focus on the variable.
We need to create or be defining it right here.
This one called data is going to be of the type and we can always refer to schema to figure out what
we had called it right here we have create post.
It was called create post input.
So over here create post input.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can use the data variable.
Down here.
Removing the object and referencing the variable instead and last up we export it right here exporting
create post.
Excellent.
Now once again over in post.
Test.
J S.
We can adjust the test case.
I'm going to create a variable's object and we only need one property on there we just need data.
Data is going to have title body and published and we can use the same values we have below.
So title a test post body.
We can leave that empty and published.
We can set that equal to true.
Excellent.
Now we can remove this operation entirely and we can actually import it from up above.
So up above we are going to grab the thing we just export and create.
Post.
There we go.
We now have 4 out of five tests converted before we save.
Let's just make sure variables gets passed through.
Now we can move on to that last test case.
So down below we have delete post.
This does indeed take a dynamic value and the type for that one is just that ID as seen over here.
It's nothing special as a built in scalar type.
So let's go ahead and start by grabbing that operation definition.
I'm going to copy it and bring it over to the operations File.
We're going to be setting up a single variable ID of the type ID and this variable is going to get used
down below right here where we define the idea of the post to remove.
Perfect.
Now we can export it and use it in the test case.
Exporting delete.
Post over inside of our posts.
Test suite.
We can import it up at the very top.
Delete.
Post.
And then finally we can use it.
So down below to wrap up this video we are going to set up the necessary variables Konst variables equals
an object.
We define one thing id the value for that comes from post to post dot ID.
Now we can remove the old delete post-operation.
We're going to be accessing the new one that's imported and we will indeed set up those variables.
And now we're done all of our operations from the post test suite.
Now live over in the operations file allowing the test cases to stay focused on what it is they care
about down below our test suite is indeed rerunning And what do we have.
We have 10 passing tests.
Now I know the testing section has been a little long there's a lot of new information to cover and
it's a very important step to the development process here.
We were able to verify that a good deal of our application works in just 10 seconds.
I can go ahead and a and then rerun the entire test suite before I'm even done finishing this sentence.
That's going to allow us to verify our application is working as we build it out we'll be able to catch
problems as soon as they come up.
All right that's it for this one.
There are just a few videos left in this section.
We're going to talk about comments and testing subscriptions.
I'm excited to get to all of that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.