In this video we're going to see the database with some comment test data and then we're going to write
a couple of test cases associated with our comments.
Now all of this is going to be a challenge since we've done all of this before.
We're wrapping up the section and I want to give you as much experience as possible testing because
I find when people don't know how to test they don't test.
So let's go ahead and move into the seed database file and talk about the first of two challenges and
the first challenge you're going to set up the necessary seed data in the second challenge you'll actually
write the test cases.
So here's what I'd like you to do for this first challenge.
The goal is to set up some test comment data.
You're going to create three new things.
First up you're going to create a second user alongside of user 1 and then you're going to create a
comment on our published post authored by the second user.
Then step three you're going to create a comment on the published post authored by that first user.
So we'll have the published post sitting right here with two comments by the end.
Step 4 you're going to export those three things user to comment one and comment two then you're going
to save the file and look at the database to check your work.
You should see a nother user showing up and you should see two comments showing up.
So take some time to knock this one out.
You're going to define the variables with the input.
Up above then in the C database function you'll actually add everything in.
Also make sure to delete comments right here.
Let's actually go ahead and add that in before we even get started.
Oh wait.
Prisma dot nutation dot right here.
Delete many comments.
Perfect.
All right the rest is up to you.
Take some time to knock this one out.
Then test your work.
When you're done come back and click play.
How'd you do.
This is something we've done before.
So let's go ahead and get to it.
Down below we're going to start by creating that second user.
It's going to look similar in terms of structure to User 1.
So I'm just going to copy this object pasted down below and swap out the name.
User 1 for the name user 2.
Now for this user we can pick any one we like.
I'll go ahead and use Geoff.
That would be Jeff at example dot com and I'll change the password over to something like pass for Jeff.
Perfect.
Now we have that user to defined in terms of the object.
And down below we're going to end up adding it to the database so down here below where we create user
1 we're going to create user 2.
Now once again since we're going to follow these same steps I'm just going to take these two statements
bring them down below change the comment to create user to then right here will change our references
so user to dot user We're going to use user to dot input to create the user then down below that.
Just two more instances will set user to JWT and right here we'll use the ID from user to user ID which
we set up above perfect.
So that is the first user all done.
Let's go ahead and create a couple of comments.
We have step one knocked out step to create a comment by that new user for the published post.
So down below let's go ahead and get this done.
I'm going to create a new object Konst comment one sending an equal to an object and we're gonna set
up an input property like we've done for all of our other objects so far.
Whether it's a user or a post and down below input I'll be setting up a comment property.
This is where we're going to end up storing the final data that Prisma sends us back.
Now for this comment all we need to provide at least right here is the text so I can say something like.
Great post thanks for sharing.
As an example now that we have comment ones object defined down below we're actually going to use that
to add a comment for post 1.
Let's go ahead and knock that out.
Down at the bottom of the function right here I'll leave a little comment create comment 1.
And now we're actually going to use Prisma to get that done.
That's going to be comment one dot comment.
And here we are going to get its value from a weight awaiting Prisma dot mutation dot create comment
passing in all of the arguments.
We just have data and on data.
What are we going to provide.
We're going to provide all of the input necessary.
This includes things like that text but it also includes things like the link to the author and the
post we want this comment to be associated with.
So right here I'm going to go ahead and start by spreading out comment one dot input to set up the text
property then I'll link it with the correct author.
Now we already have the ID for that author on user to dot user.
So right here I'm going to connect to an existing user where ID is going to equal user to that user
done ID.
Perfect.
Next up we have to link to the correct post.
So down below post here we will also use connect to connect to an existing post and I want to add the
comment for the published post that is.
Post number one.
Post Number 1 defined up above as a published value of truth.
So down here that would be linked by ID.
Post one done Post dot ID.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place the last thing left to do is to create a second comment so up above.
I'm going to duplicate comment one calling it something like comment to then I am going to set up the
text property and I'll respond saying something like.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
Next up we can go ahead and duplicate the code down below to actually create that comment modifying
it to fit our needs.
I'm going to grab the comment along with the code that creates the comment.
I'm just going to swap out some values so create comment to then write here.
That would be a comment to doc comment and then comment to input and last up we want to make sure this
one is written by the other author.
That would be user 1 instead of user 2 and we'll leave the post the same.
This comment from user 1 is also going to be on that published post.
Now that we have this in place we can go ahead and move on to Step Number Four.
We want to make sure that we correctly export this stuff from our project and that's going to allow
us to use it over in our test suites down at the bottom.
All we're going to do is add those on as named exports so I'll keep things in order by group.
I'll put the user to right here after user 1 then I'll put the comments on the end though the order
isn't necessarily going to affect the functionality at all it's just to stay organized.
Comment 1 followed by comment.
Too perfect.
Now on the second part of step 4 was to test our work.
So I'm going to save the seed database file and we're going to make sure that over inside of our database
we actually have these new records showing up now down below.
You'll also notice that one test case is now failing.
This is failing because we've added more data.
If I scroll up we can see that we were expecting one but we got two and this was for our test should
expose public author profiles over in user dot test dot J.
S..
It's perfectly normal to need it to adjust your test cases as you change the seed database.
Right here we're no longer expecting just one user to exist in this case.
We would be expecting two users to exist since we have added a second one into the mix making this change
should affect that specific assertion.
Bringing it back to a nice working state down below the test suite is wrapping up.
And right here we have 10 passing tests once again.
Now let's head into the database and see what our data looks like.
I'm going to switch over to P.G. admin and I'll start by loading up the users.
So right here.
View all rows it's loading in the data now.
And what do we got.
We have two users we have Jenna and Jeff.
Let's also load in the comments.
So previously we had no comments.
I would now expect to have a couple and there we go.
We do indeed have 2 comments in the mix now that we have this in place.
We are done seeding the database we have all of the data we need to test every single part of our application.
The second challenge is going to be for you to actually use the comments to write a couple of test cases
and that's going to happen over in a new test suite.
So we'll be creating a new file in the tests folder and I'll call this one something like comment dot
test dot J S.
So this one is going to sit alongside of our other two test files and in here we're going to add a couple
of different test cases.
Now down below we have our one failing test suite and that's because there are no test cases inside
of here.
Let's go ahead and fix that by looking at the challenge comments.
The big picture goal here is to write two test cases related to comments.
One they should delete own comment and two should not delete other users comment.
So when the first test case we're going to authenticate as one of our users and delete their comment
we can then assert that it was indeed removed in the second test case.
We're going to authenticate as one of the users but we're going to try to delete the other person's
comment.
And in this case I would expect it to throw an error.
So we can use the to throw functionality we explored when signing up with bad data to make sure that
the request fails.
Then you can test your work so you can actually save the file and fire those test cases off.
Remember you're also going to have to set up the necessary imports to get everything this file requires.
And when you define your operations for deleting a comment.
Go ahead and add that over in the operations doc J.S. file.
All right.
Take some time to knock that one out.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play.
All right let's get to it.
Up top I'm going to start by adding in some of the imports we've used in our other test suites.
I'll start by grabbing cross vetches polyphenols so inport cross Ifan fetch a forward slash Pylea fill.
After that we're going to go ahead and grab some things that I know we're going to need for this test
case as an example.
We're going to need a user one user to as well as our comments from the C database.
We're also going to need things like get client so right here I'm going to import ceed database as well
as a couple of other things from the following module data forward slash tills a forward slash seed
database.
So right here what am I going to grab.
I'll grab user 1 I'll grab a user too.
Actually I really only need one user.
I'll grab comment one and I'll also grab a comment too.
Perfect.
Next up after this we can go ahead and grab a client which we will be using.
So import get client from the following location Dant forward slash you tills forward slash get client
perfect and last up for the moment we are going to go ahead and grab Prisma importing Prisma from the
following location dot dot burrowers slash source forwards slash Prisma.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and set up the basic test cases down below.
I'm going to add two test calls so we'll have our first one that will be for the first test case should
delete own comment that will be set up with an async function.
And then we'll also add that second test case right here.
Should not delete other users comment.
We'll set that up as an async function as well.
And now we can focus on those test cases themselves.
Both are going to use the delete comment mutation.
So before we can actually try to delete the comments we're going to have to set up that operation over
in operations dot Jay as I'm going to adjust the indentation of delete to post and add one more down
below.
Konst delete comment.
We'll set this up with GQ L. and our template string right here.
This is indeed going to be a mutation and we are indeed going to need the ID of the comment to remove.
So we'll set that up as a variable.
The variable name ID of the type ID below the mutation itself is called Delete comment.
I'm going to provide that ID as an argument.
And then finally we can provide our selection set.
In this case I'm going to go ahead and just grab the ID of the comment that was supposed to be removed.
Perfect.
Now we can actually add delete comment onto the export list after delete post.
I'll add on delete comment.
Now we can save our operations file and actually take advantage of this operation.
Over inside of our test suite the first thing we have to do is inport it.
So let's add one more inport statement in porting right here the following delete comment and we're
going to grab that from that forward slash you tills forward slash operations.
Excellent.
Now we can use get client along with before each to see the database right here.
Konst client equals we'll call get client with no off token to create a generic client that can be used
by any test case where authentication isn't required and I'll be setting up before each calling that
passing in the seed database.
Function perfect.
Now let's move on to the individual test cases and we'll start with the first one.
In this case we're going to go ahead and generate a new client where we're authenticated as user 1.
So Konst client equals Abi calling get client passing in user 1 dot JWT.
And from there we can actually set up our variable.
So Konst variables equals all we have to do is define the ID of the comment we're trying to remove.
Now remember user one created comment too.
And in this case we're making sure we can delete our own comments.
So that's the comment I'm going to remove.
Comment to comment.
Dot ID.
Next up we can actually fire this off so I am going to await the following.
We are going to use client does mutate to pass in our options object and right here we're going to set
up the mutation to be delete comment as imported up above.
Next up we're going to link in those variables and on the next line we can focus on making our assertion.
Now there are a few ways we could have gotten this done.
Maybe you query for all comments and make sure there's just one left.
Maybe you use the exists functionality to try to find this specific comment and make sure it doesn't
exist.
That's the approach that I'm going to take.
So Konst exists is going to be a boolean which will get its value from using a way with Prisma dot exists
dot uppercase C comment.
Now we're looking for a comment by its ID.
So we're going to set up Id only and the ID is stored under comment to dot comment dot dot ID.
From here we can actually set up the expect assertions.
I'm going to expect that the exists variable equals using to be false.
We are expecting it to be gone it should not exist.
Now that we have this in place we can test our one test case.
Well talking about our second one in this case we're going to stay authenticated as User 1 but we're
going to try to delete comment 1.
And we should not be able to do that since we didn't create it.
Down below we can see the test suite is wrapping up and everything went really well so far.
Let's go ahead and start by setting up a client.
So Konst client equals I'll be calling get client passing in right here.
User 1 dot JWT.
Then we're going to set up our variables ID equals.
In this case the ID for comment 1.
That's comment one damn comment dot ID.
And after variable's we can actually fire this thing off.
So in this case I'm going to await a call to client dot mutate and we are going to pass in what we are
going to pass in nutation still using delete comment and we're also going to pass in our variables.
Never remember we are expecting this operation to fail.
So we have to use the functionality we explored earlier and expect that allows us to see if a given
premise fails.
Right now we're just firing it off on its own instead we are going to use expect we're going to pass
our promise in right here.
Then we'll use dot rejects dot to throw to ensure that it throws an error and we'll use a weight up
front.
So all we have to do is provide the promise right here.
I'm going to break that out onto its own line and copy the code from above.
Everything from the client all the way to the closing parentheses.
I'm going to paste that in.
Remove the extra await which is no longer necessary.
And right here we have the finalized test case.
We're going to try to delete a comment.
We shouldn't be able to remove.
And we're going to make sure that it does indeed throw an error.
Now we can go ahead and save the comment test suite for hopefully the last time in this video.
And I would expect to still have 12 passing test cases.
We already had 12 since we had saved the file when both of those test cases were empty and remember
an empty test case is always going to pass down below.
What do we have.
We have 12 passing test cases which is a fantastic step in the right direction.
That's where we're going to stop for this video.
I'm going to remove the challenge comments and in the next video we're going to start to wrap up this
section by exploring the last thing we haven't tested and that is a subscription.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.