We've tested mutations we've tested queries and in this video you're going to learn how to test subscriptions.
So the process is going to look very similar.
We'll be setting up test cases instead of using client dot mutate or client Dom queery we'll be using
client dot subscribe.
We're then going to subscribe to changes.
We're going to make a change in the database and we're going to ensure that the subscription got notified.
We have a few different subscriptions we can write test cases for if I crack open the schema tab engraft
Well playground we have three in this video.
We're going to write two test cases together.
We'll be writing a test case for our comment subscription making sure we get notified about changes
to comments that belong to a post and then down below we'll also write a test for the post subscription
though that's something you'll be doing on your own as a challenge.
Now in order to get this done we have to use Apollo to fire off a subscription.
Right now we're only using it for mutations and queries.
Now here's the catch and it's a big one Apollo boost.
It actually does not currently support subscriptions.
Now obviously this is not ideal since we're using Apollo boost as our client.
If we're going to set up mutations and queries we also want to be able to set up subscriptions whether
it's from test cases or from the browser.
Now Appollo boost is nothing more than a collection of other libraries under the Apollo ecosystem.
It's easier configuration way to get started with Apollo.
All you have to do is provide that object with the property and you're done.
The other tools though can be used to create a more complex client one that for example supports subscriptions.
Now the Apollo boosted developers do indeed plan on adding subscription support to the library.
There are good issue threads about this but there's no definitive timeline and I'm not banking on it
happening in the next couple of days.
So what I've done as a temporary work around as I've created for you.
A new version of the Get client file instead of relying on Appollo boost that version uses all of the
libraries that Appollo boost uses behind the scenes.
It's going to give us what we already get from Appollo boost but it's also going to set up subscription
support.
So that's going to give us something a little extra we can find this file that we're going to end up
using by heading over to the browser.
I've uploaded it at Lincs dot meet DOT.
I go forward slash get client that's get client in all lower case and if we head over there it's going
to redirect us over to a get home.
Just this is a single file that we're going to use as a replacement for now.
The first thing you'll notice is that we have plenty of new libraries from the Apollo ecosystem being
used.
Previously we had just one that was Apollo boost.
Now we're going to have seven different ones.
Things like Apollo client Apollo link HTP and Apollo utilities as well as others.
Many of these are already being used by Apollo boost behind the scenes but not all of them.
Apollo link.
WS This is what sets up web Sacket support.
And that's the protocol that allows us to have real time communication with our subscriptions.
This is something that we have to manually set up as once again Apollo boost does not support web sockets.
So down below we have a whole bunch of configuration everything that Apollo boost does plus a little
bit more to add support for web sockets.
This file still exports a get client function that accepts a JWT argument just like we have over here.
We're actually going to be able to swap out the files without needing to change any of our test case
code.
The two functions return a client and those clients are identical.
Besides the fact that the new one supports subscriptions down below that we have all of the code necessary
to actually set up the client manually.
And it is quite a bit of boring configuration.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by grabbing the NPM command up top on the second line.
I'm going to grab everything from NPM install all the way to the end of the file.
I'm going to grab that command.
I'm going to bring it over to our application.
I will shut down the test suite.
I'll paste it in.
Fire it off and that's going to install all of the modules necessary now.
In the meantime we can grab everything else in this file starting with our first import all the way
down to the end.
We can copy this to the clipboard.
And this is what we're going to bring over to the Get client file we have in our application.
Now you can always leave a version of the Apollo boost file in place incased subscription support gets
added down the line.
So what I'm going to do is right click on get a duplicate file or directory.
Here I can call this get client without subs without subscriptions.
Damn Jay S..
And now that we have that file in place as a backup of sorts I'm going to move back to the original
get client file delete everything and paste in the contents of what we copied over from the browser.
So now we have a much more advanced setup for Appollo client.
This is one that's going to enable support for what we need which is subscriptions.
Now before we do anything with subscriptions let's save.
Get client restart our test suite and make sure that all of our existing test cases are passing before
going any further.
We had 12 before we made this change and all 12 were passing.
I said that the GET client function shouldn't change the functionality.
So I would still be expecting all 12 to pats down below were wrapping up and everything looks good so
far.
We have 10 passing and in a couple of seconds the other two should finish.
There we go.
We have 12 passing test cases.
So now that we have the new version of Get client in place we're going to start to test our subscriptions
and to start we are going to make sure that we get notified of comments for a particular post and we're
going to do that over inside of the comment test suite.
You can also make the argument that that belongs over in the post test suite.
In the end of the day either way is fine as long as you're consistent with where you put stuff down
below.
Let's go ahead and explore how we can test a subscription to start.
Let's set up a place for this new test case.
I'm going to call test and we'll pass in a name something like should subscribe to comments for a post
then we'll set up our async aero function and we can move on to the actual meat of the test case.
Now in this case we're going to be firing off a subscription.
One of the three subscriptions we have available to us that is the comment subscription.
And remember this does take in an argument to the ID of the post.
You want to monitor.
So we're going to monitor our first test post which is indeed the published one.
So let's go ahead and start by actually defining the operation in operations.
J.S. down below at the bottom of our operations list we can set up a new one Konst subscribe to comments
right here.
I'm gonna set it equal to we're still going to use.
GQ well with template strings and we're going to set up our subscription like we've done plenty of times
before right here.
It is indeed a subscription.
We are going to provide a single variable post ID of the type ID and then down below we can talk about
the subscription.
We're going to use which is comment.
Now we have to provide a post ID as an argument and we're going to get its value from the post ID variable
perfect and then down below we can choose exactly what we want.
Remember the payload for our subscriptions has a mutation which lets us know what happened.
Did a comment get deleted updated or added and node which contains the individual comment fields.
So in this case I could say I want to know exactly what happened.
So I'll grab mutation and I also want to grab the comments ID and text.
So right here node ID text perfect.
Now we can go ahead and add subscribe to comments on to our export list subscribe to comments and we
are going to save the operations file and inport subscribe to comments over inside of the comment test
suite up top.
We're going to go ahead and grab two new things.
First up from the operations file We're going to grab what we just exported subscribe to comments then
we're going to grab something from the C database as well.
We're going to need a post ID to monitor all grab.
Post one.
Also once we have these two ports in place we can actually move down below and use them to set up the
test suite right here.
We're going to start by defining our variables.
So we do indeed need a variables object.
Since our operation our subscription requires the post ID a variable.
So right here let's set that up post ID and we'll get its value from post one.
Post dot Id like we've done plenty of times before.
Awesome.
Now that we have the variables object in place we can go ahead and use a new method on client to actually
set up the subscription that his client doesn't subscribe subscribe method takes in an options object
like queery and mutate did.
And we provide two properties.
First up query this is where we list out the subscription we want to use and we just imported that it's
subscribe to comments.
And next up we go ahead and list out the variables we want to use and we'll register those as well.
Now with queries and mutations the data comes back a single time.
So if we fire off a query it gets the data it sends it back and that query is complete.
We're never going to get new data back without sending off the query again with our subscription though
we're going to get new data back any time a comment for this post changes that means we actually can't
use a promise because promises can resolve or reject a single time with a single value.
In this case what we do is we actually set up a callback function that fires every time the subscription
gets new data.
To do that we call subscribe right here chaining on the method calls we pass in an options object and
to set this up with a single property.
Next Next is a function.
So I'm going to set it up as such and it gets called with the response and next will fire as many times
as it needs to every single time a comment changes.
Now that response is similar to what we'd get back for a query or a mutation.
We have access to response data to get information about the comment that was altered whether it was
created updated or deleted.
Now let's go ahead and talk about what we're going to do to trigger this function.
So here we're going to end up setting up some assertions making sure that things went well.
But in order for next to fire we actually have to change a comment.
So down below all we need to change a comment in order to trigger next.
And we need next to run.
So we can assert the subscription is working as expected.
Now that's not a hard process.
We can use any of our Prisma mutations to change one of the comments for that post.
I'm going to use the delete comment nutation to delete one of the two comments so down below.
We can await the following.
That's going to be Prisma dot mutation dot delete comment and we're going to delete the comment by providing
the where object will delete a comment where the ID equals let's say the first comments ID so comment
one dot comment dot ID.
Perfect.
Now at this point the next function should indeed be triggered a single time and we can go ahead and
focus on our assertions.
Now before we do anything real I want to set up a dummy assertion to prove a point.
What we're going to do is expect that one equals two.
So I'm going to expect one to be two.
Now clearly that's not the case.
And the reason I'm setting this up is to talk about exactly how tests like this need to be configured.
So down below we have the test suite running and then just a few seconds we should indeed see our test
case.
And I would expect it to be failing because one is not two but down below as we can see.
We now have 13 passing tests.
So what exactly is happening here.
Clearly this assertion isn't being taken into account when jast determines whether or not this test
should have succeeded or failed.
The problem is that just runs our function and as soon as the function finishes it goes ahead and says
the test is done and determines whether or not an error was thrown.
Now right after delete comment is done that's when the function finishes.
It's actually going to finish before the asynchronous process can notify our subscription that the new
event has been fired.
In which case next would run.
So this code does run but it runs a little bit after this function completes.
And by that time just has already determined whether or not the function threw an error.
Now we can fix this by setting up a new argument for our test function just supports a done argument
when we configure done like this.
That test case won't be considered finished until done is called.
So all we have to do is call.
Done right here.
I'm going to call.
Done.
And now if we were to save the test suite with our dummy assertion in place we would indeed see a failure
because we're not going to actually consider this test done until this function runs.
So once again we'll set up the subscription will fire off the delete comment of mutation.
We'll wait for next to complete and when next is complete geste We'll look at the test case and determine
whether or not it should be considered a success or a failure.
Right here we have a single failure.
And if I scroll up what do we get we expected to.
And we received one.
So at this point everything is working as expected.
We have actually proved that this function is at least running so we know when we delete a comment the
subscription is indeed getting notified.
Now let's talk about what we should actually assert this test case as it stands actually does a pretty
good job ensuring that things go well.
This ensures that the function does indeed get called meaning that our subscription did indeed get notified
if it didn't this function would never get called done would never fire.
And after a certain amount of time it just just considers the test a failure if done never runs.
So we know that at least next is executing.
Now we don't need to assert something like the fact that the comment has indeed been removed because
the subscription.
It's not what's removing the comment.
It's just getting notified.
If we were to assert that the content is indeed removed we're essentially testing the Prisma library
itself making sure it works and that doesn't make too much sense in this case.
I'm just going to assert that we're getting notified about a deletion.
So I could set up something like the following.
I could expect something about response data on here we're going to have all of our data the common
property is where we'll have the data for our comment subscription then we're going to access something
like mutation which we did indeed ask for and we can check that it equals using to be the following.
In upper case the string deleted.
So now we are confirming two things we're confirming that we're getting notified because something's
been deleted and we're confirming that we're actually getting notified just based off of the fact that
Dunn is set up.
Now this should indeed complete the test case down below.
I would expect to have 13 passing tests and if we do we're going to wrap up this video with a quick
subscription challenge down below.
We have just that everything is working really well.
And this video has gotten a little long.
I was thinking about breaking the challenge out into the next one but I'd like to bundle this up all
in one.
So bear with me as we move into challenge territory.
It's going to be your job to set up a test case for the post subscription.
So if I head over to our schema real quick we just added a test case for comment down below we also
have post.
So this is going to get notified if a published post gets created updated or deleted and that's good.
That's exactly what we want.
It takes no arguments so no variables need to get set up.
So big picture goal as a test case for the post subscription you want to set up the subscription operation
in the operations file then you're going to actually fire that operation off then you're going to fire
off the Prisma mutation that would trigger the subscription.
So if we're listening on published posts you're going to have to manipulate a published post.
You can go ahead and delete posts 1 to do that as an example from there you're going to make sure that
things actually worked by setting up an assertion and making sure the mutation property is correct either
created updated or deleted.
And remember to get that done you'll also need to use done to ensure that geste waits for next to fire
last.
Test your work so you can use the above test case as a template for what you need to get done.
All right.
Pause the video and when you're done come back and click play
how that go I'm going to kick things off by setting up the operation.
There's no point in setting up the test case until we have something to test over here.
I will call this something along the lines of Konst subscribe to posts and I'll use this with GQ UL
and a template string.
This subscription doesn't take in any arguments so there's no need to take in any variables.
All we're going to do is set up the subscription and the subscription name itself is post.
In this case once again no arguments necessary and all we're going to do is ask for mutation though
we could also grab things off of Node.
Now that we have this in place we can go ahead and export it over here at the end of the list.
Subscribe to posts.
Excellent.
So now that we have these subscription exported we can save operations dot J s over any comment test
file before we create the test case.
I'm just going to inport what we just export it so subscribe two posts then down below we can actually
put that to use.
Let's go ahead and create a brand new test case and new test case.
I'm going to set up a name for this one.
Something like should subscribe to changes for published posts.
This will also be an async function.
And we're also going to configure this to accept that done argument allowing us to confirm that the
subscription actually got notified of a change.
Now there's no need to set up variables inside of here so we can kick things off right away with a call
to client doesn't subscribe.
I'm going to pass to the two things it expects.
We have a query the one we're going to be using is to subscribe to the posts and we would have variables
but no variables required from there.
We're going to end up changing on a another call to subscribe like we did above.
This is where we set up next next Nectars the function that runs when the subscription gets notified
of an event right here.
We're going to do is get the response and we're going to do something with it.
Now it's important to remember that next a won't run unless we actually mutate something in this case.
I'm going to go ahead and delete that published post so I'll await Prisma dot mutation dot right here
delete post.
And we are indeed going to provide the criteria for deleting a post we'll use where to delete a post
by its ID the ID.
In this case being the ID of post number 1.
So post one dot post dot ID.
Excellent.
Whoops.
Not is ID.
Now that we have this in place next should indeed be running in here.
We can set up an assertion and we definitely need to called done otherwise.
Remember just won't consider the test case complete.
After a certain amount of time if done is in called it will be considered a failure by default.
Now we can use expect to look at that mutation type.
This is step number 4 expecting that response dot data dot.
In this case Post has a mutation property with the value using to be.
In this case once again deleted.
With this in place we are all done.
We can go ahead and remove our comments down below.
I can save the comment test suite and we're going to watch our test cases run for the last time in this
video.
So let's take a quick moment to recap.
Well that's happening in this video we had to swap out get client instead of using Apollo boost which
doesn't support subscriptions.
We have used a custom setup that I've provided maybe in the future we can switch back to Appollo boost
if subscriptions or ever support it.
We then used those in our test cases to set up calls to subscribe waiting for things to change.
Now in these test cases we actually had to trigger changes and there is a reason here that I'm working
with Prisma and not maybe firing off one of our own operations.
We want to isolate our tests so if we were using our own subscription and our own delete mutation it
would be hard to pinpoint exactly why a test is failing if it failed.
In this case Prisma does its own testing so we can assume that it's going to work as expected and we
are just testing the subscription related features.
Dambulla we have 14 passing tests and there we go.
You now know how to use subscriptions queries and mutations from clients whether that's the browser
or in this case a test suite.
And that's where we're going to stop for this one.
I'll see you next time.