You now know how to use Appollo client to fire off subscriptions queries and mutations and you also
know how to use geste to test your graph.
Well code now there are more test cases we could write based off of what we already know.
For example I can make sure that I can create a new comment when I'm authenticated and that I can't
create a new comment when I'm not authenticated.
Doing that would use techniques we're already familiar with and we've already gotten practice with instead
of creating 10 more videos to cover these test cases.
I'm going to create just this one and provide you with a list of additional tests you could write to
get more experience based off of what you already know.
You can find this list by heading over to the browser and going to links dummied dot I O forward slash
test ideas and all of the tests listed here are things you can already create using what you already
know.
There's no test here you can't write with the information covered in this section.
I have a little section for user post and comment related test cases.
Let's quickly go through the list and then we'll be done.
If for user we have some pretty basic ones should not sign up a user with an email that's already in
use.
So we want to sign up as a user using the same e-mail as a test database user.
It should fail.
We're going to expect it to throw an error then it should log in and provide authentication token.
In this case we will use the loggin mutation with valid credentials one of our test database users and
we'll ensure that it goes well.
It doesn't throw an error then we should reject me query without authentication and should hide emails
when fetching the list of users.
Remember that email field is hidden from the public eye.
Down below we have post should not be able to update another users post along with it should not be
able to delete another user's post.
From there we have it should require authentication to create a post and this could be a test case for
updating and deleting as well checking that those require authentication to Dambulla that should fetch
published post by ID.
So I should be able to fetch a published post even if I'm not authenticated.
Then it should fetch.
Own post by ID.
So if I am authenticated I should be able to fetch something like a draft post that I own and last up.
Another idea should not fetch draft post from another user.
Dambulla we have comment.
It should fetch.
Post comments should create a new comment.
Should not create a comment on a draft post.
Should update comment should not update another user's comment.
Should not delete another user's comment.
And finally you could add three test cases making sure that authentication is required when adding updating
and deleting a comment.
So you already know what you need in order to get all of this done.
It was all covered in the section and this is more optional than anything if you want a bit more experience
writing tests.
This is a great list to get started with.
All right that is it for this one.
Let's go ahead and jump into the next one.