Welcome to Section 7 in this section which is a relatively short section there are two key things we
want to focus on setting up.
We're going to set up the ability to sort our data and the ability to paginate our data.
So imagine we are creating a client for our.
Q An app whether it's a web client or a mobile client.
We're likely going to show a list of posts on the home page and we want them to be in a particular order
likely with the most recently published up top then getting older as you scroll down the list.
We can't do that unless we can sort our data.
So we're going to set that up.
Now we're also going to set up pagination.
So imagine we do show the posts in the correct order with the most recent up top but we have 15000 posts
in the database from a number of users over a dozen years.
We can't fetch and render all 15000 at the same time as we would likely cause major slowdowns on the
device.
So instead we would paginate I would fetch maybe the first 15 or the first 50 then if the user gets
to the bottom we could load in the next 15 or the next 50.
So we're going to set up both of those and we'll start with pagination.
Let's go ahead and jump right in.