There are a few topics scattered throughout this section to start.
We're going to focus on implementing pagination.
Pagination is going to give clients the ability to fetch just a subset of the data in the database.
So imagine I have 450 posts in the database and a client comes along saying they want to render some
to the home page.
Does that client want to actually fetch and render 450 posts.
And the answer is No.
First off it would be expensive to fetch 450 posts and it would also be expensive to render them the
likelihood that someone who loads the page actually sees all 450 is slim to none.
So what we're going to do instead is allow clients to fetch just a subset of the data.
Maybe the first 100 or the first 10 then the user can make requests for more when they're ready.
So if you scroll down through all 10 posts the client could automatically fetch the next set of 10 or
it could do something like show a load more button which could be clicked to load the next ten.
So either way we need pagination in order to get this done it's a very important feature of any app
that's expected to scale before we actually crack open any files and make changes to our graphical project.
We're going to pull up the Prisma graph you playground instance and explore how Prisma gives us the
ability to paginate our data.
So to start what we're going to do is swap out the user's query for a post's query since we have more
posts than users are right here.
I am going to use the Post's query and for each post I'll grab the ID.
I'll grab the title and I'll also grab the published status.
Now if I fire that off I get back 11 different posts and if there was just 11 posts in the database
it would be fine to fetch and show all of them but we can't guarantee that there could be 600 in which
case it would take a lot of time to fetch that data and render it.
So what are we going to do instead.
Well if we crack open the schema we can view the options we have for our posts query right here.
There are a bunch of different arguments we can use and we've already explored where later in the section
we're going to explore.
ORDER BY which is going to allow us to sort data.
What I want to focus on for the moment are these five.
We have Skipp we have.
After we have before we have first and we have last to start let's just focus on first first takes in
an integer value and this allows us to get the first X where X is the integer you passed in.
So currently we are seeing all of the posts and by default Prisma limits you to a thousand.
We can go ahead and start to customize this by providing operation arguments so right here we are indeed
going to use first.
And I am going to type in first two.
So this is going to give us just the first two posts from the database.
So updated post by Andrew and post by gests 1.
I would expect all others to go away and if I fire it off that's exactly what happens.
So using First we can limit how many records where C..
Now this alone isn't particularly useful.
Let's say that I fetch the first two and then someone says they want to load more.
How do I fetch the next two.
Well to do that we're going to introduce a nother argument.
This one being Skip Skip is an integer that tells Prisma how many records to skip.
So in this case we can set Skipp equal to another INT and I am going to use 2 again.
So now we're going to skip to then we're going to grab the first two.
So currently I'm seeing the updated post and post by gests one.
If I fire off the operation with these arguments I'm seeing the next set of two post by just two and
post by just three.
I could then go to the next page.
I could skip four.
I would see post by just for and post by gests 5.
So using a combination of first and skip we can really hone in on exactly what data we want to access.
In this case we have pages of two.
We could have pages of any size for example let's say I want to get the first five records and I want
to skip 0.
So here I have a page size of 5 and I get the first 5 posts.
I could then skip 5 to get the second page of 5 posts.
And here we have that.
Then I could go ahead and skip 5 more for a total of 10 to get that third page of 5 posts and right
here you can see since we have 11 posts just one is showing up.
So there we go using first and skip.
We can set up basic pagination and that's where we're going to start over inside of Visual Studio code.
We are going to crack open a schema and graph QOL as well as queery dot J.
S.
Now we have a few different queries which should all support pagination are first for users posts my
posts and comments.
Anything that ends up sending back an array.
There's no need for pagination for me or post since you just get back a single record.
Now to start we are going to implement pagination together for the user's query.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by adding support for those two arguments.
So we want to be able to use both first and skip inside of here.
So we're going to accept both of them right here.
After query we're going to add on first that will indeed be an optional integer and we are also going
to add on Skip.
So right here Skip.
Also an optional integer and in the end of the day we're just going to pass both of these through to
Prisma.
So no J ass really isn't going to do anything meaningful with them at all.
We can now save schema.
Well we can head into queery dot J S And We can actually make use of our brand new arguments down below.
In the OP args objects we are going to set up both first and skip.
So first is going to get its value from args dot first and skip is going to get its value from args
dot skip.
Excellent.
Now we have pagination set up we can now use pagination with our users query and that's exactly what
we're going to end up doing.
So let's head over to local host of 4000.
Our API and fire off a user's query.
Now if we do so what are we going to get.
We're going to get back all records.
As expected we have Jess Andrew Jen and Sarah from here we're now going to make use of those arguments.
Let's start by providing just first.
So right here I'm going to get the first two users.
Now currently this is an invalid operation.
But if we refresh the schema we can see it's now valid and if I fire it off what do I get.
I get Jess and Andrew back.
I could also grab the first three for example and I would get Jeff's Andrew and Jen.
Now let's make use of Skipp as well.
So right here I am going to skip some records.
Let's go ahead and start by skipping zero records or grabbing the first page.
Then we could skip three records to grab the second set of three.
If I do this what do I get back.
I get back just Sarah because we only have four users total So that second page isn't exactly full.
Now if I were to skip on further down the line for example skipping to the third page I would get no
users which is expected.
There are not 9 users in the database.
So there we go we have basic pagination all set up.
Now it's Challenge time if you're going to add pagination for one of our other operations we're going
to go ahead and work on the Post's query next.
So right here I am going to paste in the comments describing what I'd like you to do.
The goal is to add pagination for that post query and you're going to do this by first adding the necessary
arguments to the post query over in schema graft.
Well just like we did for the users query.
From there you're going to pass those arguments through to Prisma in the posts resolver down below.
After you have that in place it's time to test your work.
So you're going to fire off that posts query from localhost 4000 and you're going to make sure you can
use the arguments to paginate through the data.
Take some time to knock that one out.
Don't forget to test your work and when you're done come back and click play.
How that go let's go ahead and kick things off by first updating schema graphs.
Well we're going to go ahead and add to the Post's query.
Two arguments first which will be an integer in we're going to add Skipp also an integer.
Now we can save this file and that actually wraps up step 1 step 2.
We have to pass those arguments through.
So down below we have the resolver for that Post's query.
We now have those two new arguments.
They both need to get added on to here.
So we're going to have first.
First we can have args dot first which is where that value will live.
Then we're going to have Skip and Skip will get its value from args dot skip and then we'll add a comma.
Making sure that we still set up where limiting this to just posts that are published.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can move on to the final step.
Step three which is to test our work.
So I'm going to remove the challenge comments.
I'm going to save the file and we're going to head over to localhost 4000 and run our posts query now
by default I should still be getting a ton of records right here.
I have about 11 different posts.
Let's go ahead and use our arguments to paginate through them.
So I'm going to set up those arguments.
I'm going to configure first.
Let's grab the first five and I'll configure skip.
Let's go ahead and skip the 0.
So I want to see all of them.
Now if I refresh my schema those red lines will go away.
And then we can fire off our operation and hopefully we just see the first five posts.
And that is exactly what we're getting now from here we can go ahead and grab the second set of five
by skipping five posts.
If I fire that off I do indeed see the second set of five and I can also grab the third set of five
by setting skip to 10 if I fire this one off.
What do we get.
We get no posts showing up since we only have ten published posts.
The first page was populated and so was the second this third page though is empty.
Perfect.
So now that we have this in place we have basic pagination set up for the Post's query as well.
And that's where we're gonna stop for this one and the next video we're going to continue to talk about
pagination.
Though we're going to use a slightly different set of arguments to get there.
I'm excited to cover that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.