In this video as promised we're going to continue to talk pagination.
We currently have two arguments set up.
But if you remember Prisma gives us five separate arguments to add pagination into our projects.
Currently we're just using skip and first in this video.
I want to focus on after after takes as its value a string and this string is a ID for a record.
So if I'm paginate ing over posts it would end up being the ID for a post.
Now this allows us to start pagination at that point.
So we would only be paginate ing over records after that record which is a very useful technique.
Now we're not actually going to use before or last.
Both of those allow us to paginate in reverse order but that's not particularly useful for our purposes.
So we're going to stick with just skip after and first before we actually change any of our application
code.
Let's see what this can do for us over here in the Prisma instance of graft well play ground.
I'm going to grab the first five and I'm going to skip the zero sum grabbing the first five posts.
And here they are.
Now we're going to use after so alongside of first and skip.
I'm going to specify after setting its value to a string.
One of the post ideas and let's just use one of the ID's we have here.
I'm going to grab this ID.
The ID for the second post.
Now when I use that for after we're saying that we want to start paginate ing after that record.
So skipping 0 would result in this being the first post we should see and then we're going to grab the
next four for a total of five.
So if I fire that off I would expect to see a post by just two as the first one followed by four more
posts.
And if I do that's exactly what I get.
I have post by just two.
Then down below I have the next four posts in order.
So after allows us to start after a specific record which can be super useful when all you have is the
ID of the last thing rendered to the screen.
Now that we have this in place we are going to also implement After into our application we have a couple
of queries that already have basic pagination support and we have two that currently don't support pagination
at all.
We're going to address those as well.
To start we're going to add the after argument onto both users and posts.
So after we'll use the same name as Prisma does then the optional string the same type as Prisma does
and we'll do that down below as well after being an optional string.
Now we can save this file and move in to queery.
Ass in here we're going to update our resolvers we're currently passing through first and skip.
We're also going to pass through after getting its value from args after spelled correctly of course
and we're going to do the exact same thing down below for the Post's query right here alongside of our
other three.
We're going to be adding on after args after is where that value lives.
Excellent.
Now that we have this in place we can actually save queery dot J S and test our work.
I'm going to move over to local host 4000 and we're going to change both our users and posts queries.
Now for users Let's go ahead and grab the first three skipping zero.
And then I'm going to grab the ID of the first one and use that as the after value.
So I would expect to start with Andrew as the first record once this argument is in place right here
after I'm going to provide that ID as a string.
I'm going to refresh the schema of fire that off.
And what do I get.
I get.
Andrew Jen and Sarah as expected.
Let's do the same thing for posts right here I'm going to grab the first five and skip the zero.
Then I'm going to use this ID the third post as the value for after right here adding on the after argument
setting an equal to a string then we can go ahead and fire this off.
Let's go ahead and do just that.
And what do we get we get what we expected.
We start with that fourth post and then we have the next down the list and there we go.
We now have support for first for Skip and for after really letting us fine tune exactly which records
we want to get back.
Keeping everything efficient there's no need to transmit thousands of records across the wire.
That's expensive to actually fetch.
It's expensive to transfer and it's expensive to render.
It's best to render a reasonable amount maybe 10 20 or 30 at a time.
Now that we have this in place it's going to be your challenge to do the exact same thing for both the
my posts query and for the comments query.
So let's talk about what I'd like you to do.
Right here you're going do and pagination for those two queries just mentioned Step one is to add the
necessary arguments to the query definitions and schema Audograph UL then you're going to pass those
arguments through to Prisma in the resolvers down below.
And finally you're going to test your work and make sure that things work as expected.
So take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off over in schema engraft.
Well we're going to be setting up those arguments.
Let's start with my posts right here.
We can configure first to be an integer.
We can configure script to be an integer and we can configure after to be a string.
And we're going to do the same thing for comments.
Now comments currently has zero arguments.
So we have to add those parentheses in them we can set up all three pagination arguments first and then
we have Skip Int.
And finally we have after as a string.
Excellent.
Now we can save this file and move into queery J as and on to Step Two down below.
We have to pass all of those arguments through and we'll start with my posts.
So with my posts We already set up where on op args we have to set up those other three.
So I can start with first getting its value from args dot first then we're going to have Skip coming
from args dot Skipp.
And finally after coming from args dot after.
And we're going to end up doing the same thing for other query as well.
Double-O we have comments now comments currently doesn't even pass in an options object.
So you get to go ahead and create one and pass it in.
Maybe you passed it in inline by creating it right here.
Or maybe you went ahead and defined a variable and then referenced that.
That's the approach I'm going to take.
So I'm going to create an op args object like I did for my other queries and I will create it right
here on args.
Setting it up as an object and passing it in to Prisma.
Now on here we can just set up those three arguments like we've done elsewhere.
First comes from args dot first then skip comes from args dot Skipp.
And finally after comes from args dot after excellent from here.
We're actually done with step 2.
We can go ahead and save the file and move on to step three which is to test our work.
So over inside of local host 4000 I have the comments query right here and if I were to fire it off
without passing in any arguments I would expect to see a whole bunch of records like I was seeing before.
And that's exactly what I end up getting from here.
We're now going to go ahead and provide those pagination arguments.
I'm going to go ahead and configure them.
Let's go ahead and set up Skip.
So we are going to skip zero records.
We're going to grab.
Let's say we want to grab the first two records and we're going to start after the following.
I'll start after this comment.
So I would expect to see the next two records based off of what I have here which would be Andrew comment
to Andrew comment 3.
I'm going to add after into the mix I can go ahead and grab that latest schema fire this off and what
do I see I see exactly what I expected and if I wanted to grab the next set of two I could change Skipton
to then I could change Skepta for so on and so forth.
Now that comment is working let's go ahead and use my posts my posts is just going to return the posts
for a given user.
In this case I am seeing all of the posts for G-S.
We're going to set up our arguments here as well.
Let's go ahead and configure them I am going to set first equal to lets use for this time.
Then I will skip 0 so I'm getting the first four and I am going to provide an after value of this ID
the first one.
So right here after pasting in the ID so I would expect to see the first four posts after that one which
would be 2 3 4 and 5.
If I actually fire this off that's exactly what I get to 3 4 and 5.
The other post by Jess is nowhere to be found.
All right that is it for this video and that is it for pagination it's now all set up and when clients
are interacting with our app they don't have to be burdened by a ton of unnecessary data.
They can use those arguments to grab just the data they need.
That's where we're going to stop for this one.
I'll see you in the next video.