Remember when we first created data with Prisma we looked at that data NPG admen and we noticed a couple
of interesting things.
One we noticed that an I.D. was automatically generated for us and we also noticed that there were two
columns that we took no part in creating updated and created that we never specified these fields on
our type definitions and we never provided those values.
Well the truth is that ID updated and created at our all managed internally by Prisma.
We are currently making use of the ID field but we've never touched updated at or created at all that's
going to change in this video.
The goal of this video is to expose those values via our node Agellius app so the client can do something
with them.
Maybe for example they want to show when the post was published on a post page before anything meaningful
can be done with these time stamps we have to expose them via our No.
JS app and we're going to do that by changing both schema graphical and also data model data graph.
And I'd actually like to start there with the data model diagram.
Q L file in the Prisma directory.
This is where we define our three types.
User post and comment.
And if we want to work with updated at and created at we have to define them on these types as well.
Even though Prisma already has that data saved it's going to save that data regardless of whether or
not we use them right here though we are.
So we are going to set up two fields on our type.
I am going to configure updated at and I am going to configure created at.
Now both of these in the end of the day are going to be represented as strings but Prisma gives us a
type we have to use here in data model and graphs.
Well that is Date Time.
Capital D capital T.
And these have to be non nullable.
So I'm going to set up the exact same type definition for created that down below using the date time
type provided by Prisma and then using an exclamation mark to mark that as a non nullable field.
Now this is only half the puzzle once we save this we also need to redeploy our application.
So I am going to expand the terminal I'm going to shut down our server I'll use a CD to navigate into
the Prisma directory and from here I'm going to go ahead and run Prisma deploy a can and we haven't
used in a long time.
This is going to take the changes we just made to this file and it is going to deploy them to our instance
right here we can see that our fields were indeed changed.
We have our two fields on the user type.
Now from here what are we going to do well I am going to use C D dot dot to go back to the project root
and I am going to run NPM run get schema to fetch a new schema file.
So remember in generated we have the schema file that Prisma binding uses.
Anytime we change Prisma we should fetch a new schema.
Now that we have that in place we can just start up our app again using NPM start once the app is up
and running we can collapse the terminal and focus on the second half to the puzzle which is to make
some changes to schema engraft.
Well we've changed the user in our Prisma type definition.
Now we have to change the user over here.
Down below I have my user type.
There is no mention of updated at or create it at.
And we're going to fix that.
So right here updated at and created at and we're going to be setting the types for both of these to
non nullable strings.
So right here strings for each.
Excellent.
Now that we have this in place we're actually going to have access to those time stamps for all users.
Let's go ahead and see that in action.
I'm going to switch over to local host 4000 to my node.
J.S. grad school playground instance I'm going to switch over to my users query and refresh the schema.
And from here we're going to do is ask for both updated at and created at for each user.
Now we actually fire this off.
We should still see our users showing up and here they are.
The only difference is that now we have two time stamps for each.
We have one that lets us know when the user was last updated and a number that lets us know when the
user was originally created.
And now that we have this in place we are all done in terms of exposing those timestamps to the client.
It's important to note that this time stamp is not designed to be human readable.
This is for machines.
So this is not something you would just dump to your web app or to your mobile application.
This actually follows a standardized format.
And if I open a new tab you can find that format by googling ISO that's ISO 8 6 0 0 1.
This is the standard for describing time in a way that machines understand.
And in our case these are time zone independent time stamps.
If I crack open something like the Wikipedia page we can see some example values that look pretty similar
to what we have over here.
So the goal here is to not give the client the date in a way that's easy for a human to read.
The goal is for the server to give the client a date that's easy for machines to read the client which
is a machine can then go ahead and format that using some sort of time library and display or whatever
it is they want to display.
A good example of a library for javascript would be something like a moment Jay J.S. which can consume
this string and then it gives you an easy API for representing the date exactly as you want to.
You might be able to say something like three hours ago or maybe you want month day year.
Or maybe you just want the hour into the day at which the event occurred.
Regardless the server just needs to provide the client.
This single value to get all of that done.
We can also sort by both updated and created at.
Which is something we'll explore in the very next video.
Let's go ahead and wrap this one up with a challenge where you're going to expose the time stamps for
both posts and for comments I have some challenge comments right here.
There are three excuse me four stabs for getting this done.
The big picture goal is to configure both updated and created at four posts and comments step 1 you
have to update the Prisma models with those fields.
That's going to happen over here.
Then you're going to redeploy your Prisma application and fetch a new schema then you're going to update
your schema to include those fields as well.
And finally you're going to test your work you should be able to fetch posts and get their updated at
and create it out values and you should also be able to fetch comments getting those time stamps as
well.
So take some time to knock this out.
Don't forget to test your work when you're done come back and click play
how that go let's go ahead and kick things off by making some changes to data model don't graft well
down below we have post and comment both need to be changed.
We have to add updated at with the type of date time as a non nullable field and created at with the
exact same type date time.
Non nullable perfect.
Now we can take those two fields and copy them down below for comment as well.
And that's actually it for this file.
That brings us to step 2 we have to redeploy our app and fetch a new schema.
Otherwise things won't work or change when actually take effect.
I'm going to shut down the server.
I'm going to change directories into Prisma and run Prisma deploy.
Once that's done I'm going to shut that down and go back to the root of the project and fetch that new
schema.
So right here Prisma deployed C-D dot dot to go back to the root.
Then NPM run get schema to fetch that new schema.
Once that's done we can just start up our app and wrap up this challenge NPM start once the app is up
and running.
I'm going to shut down.
Well excuse me just collapse the terminal.
I'm still going to leave things running in the background and we're going to move on to Step 3.
We have to update our node J.S. app schema otherwise those values will never see the light of day.
So right here for a post I need to set.
Updated at and created at.
For both.
I'm going to set it as a non nullable string for updated add and also for created at perfect.
And once I have those in place I can just take those type definitions for those two fields bring them
down to comment save the file and we're all done.
Aren't Prisma app has been updated are no genius app has been updated.
And now we can test our work.
So I'm going to remove these comments.
I'm going to save the file.
And we're going to fetch some posts and some comments.
So right here I have my posts queery.
I am going to remove the part of the selection set that grabs the comments and I'm going to ask for.
Updated at.
And I'm also going to ask for.
Created at.
If I fire this off what do I get.
I get time stamps for each.
For all of my posts which is perfect I'm going to go ahead and do the same check for my comments.
Aside from grabbing the ID and the text also grab updated at as well as created at.
If I fire that off what do I get I get back those time stamps for each and every comment.
Notice that for some records the values are the same.
Like this one here.
That's because this comment was never updated so updated at and created at are identical for other records
like this one which actually was updated.
We have a different and more recent time stamp for updated at than we do 4 created at.
In this case it looks like this comment was updated about 3 or 4 minutes after it was originally created.
Now that we have these dates exposed the client can do whatever it wants with them and we're going to
go ahead and explore in the next video how we can soar by other fields and also by these date fields.
I'm excited to get to sorting.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.