In this video you're going to focus on sorting your data.
So whenever you get an array back you're going to be able to specify in which order it should come back.
So for comments as an example you might want to get the most recently created comments first or maybe
you want to get comments by their text sorting them alphabetically regardless of what order you want
to get things back in.
Prisma gives us a way to get this done.
So in reality all we have to do is pass through an argument just like we did with Skip first and after
now we head over to the graft playground instance for Prisma and we can figure out exactly how to do
that by cracking open the schema.
Let's go to the schema for our posts queery which is right here.
And to get this done we use the ORDER BY argument an ORDER BY in the end of the day has its type post
order by input of ENM and down below we have a list of all of the different ways we can sort for each
property on our model.
There are two options sorting by that property in ascending or descending order.
It doesn't make a whole lot of sense to sort by id sense that's a randomly generated value.
So let's start with our strings we have title and body.
When we sort of string in ascending order we go from A to Z in descending order we go from Z to a.
So we can use that for all of our string based fields for booleans if we sort in ascending order.
We start with false and go to true.
If we are in a descending order we start with true and go to false.
If we sort our dates in ascending order we go from the oldest to the most recent.
If we sort in a descending order we go from the most recent to the oldest.
Let's go ahead and actually mess around with this.
So we are going to use the order by property right over here on our posts.
Query and for the moment I am going to remove all other arguments.
So we're actually seeing all data.
I'm going to set up the order by argument and we're going to pick what we want to sort by let's start
with the title.
We can sort in either ascending or descending order.
I'm going to go with ascending first.
So that would go from A to Z.
Now if I actually fire this off what do we see.
We can see that our posts by Andrew show up before our posts by Jess post by is the same.
The first difference is an A and A J A comes first.
So those are up top and jays are down below at the very bottom.
We have updated post by Andrew because that's a U which does indeed come after P.
Now if we wanted to sort in the other direction all we would need to do is use descending instead of
a sending.
And if I fire that off.
Now we have the order going from Z to a at the bottom.
With this in place we can sort by one of our other properties we have available to us.
For example I could put our unpublished posts first by sorting by the published Beeld.
If we go published in an ascending fashion it's going to go from false to true.
So we'll have our one unpublished post up top and all of our published ones down below.
If I reverse that by going in a descending order now I have all of my published posts up top with my
one unpublished post down below.
We can also sort by when a given record was updated or created.
Let's go ahead and sort by the created value.
Now just to make it a bit clearer what's happening.
I'm also going to fetch that value so we can actually see the data showing up.
And if I fire off the operation without making any changes I can see that the date is indeed showing
up which is great.
Now let's actually sort based on it right here.
I'm going to order by the created at field and we're going to start in an a sending fashion now by fire
that off this is actually the order that things are stored by default in the database since new records
are added at the bottom.
So the first post we have here is the oldest one.
This was the first one created and the most recently created one is down below.
So we go from dates further in the past to dates in the more recent past.
Now if we actually look at the time stamps I can see this one was created at two.
This one was created at three.
Then we start to get into posts being created every second.
This one at 22 23 26.
As an example we can always reverse that order by sorting in a descending fashion.
This is going to take us from the most recently created posts to posts created further in the past.
So down below we have this one created at 2:00 p.m. then up above we have one created at 3pm and we
have our most recent post sitting way up at the top.
And this is likely the order you would want to use for some sort of home page where you got most recent
posts at the very top.
Now that we've seen how this argument works all we really need to do is integrate it into our queries
in schema graph.
Q Well we have four queries that we're going to set up with this argument and that's going to allow
the client to order whether it's users posts my posts or comments.
Now this is where things get interesting.
We're going to start with our users query and we're going to set up an argument called Order By.
But what type are we going to use the type that presumably uses isn't enough.
It is post order by input and it lists out all of the various ways a post can be ordered.
So we have a couple of options when it comes to our users.
Users also have order by.
And we also have something similar instead of post order by in but it's a user order by input with a
long list of potential enough values.
So we have two ways we can implement this into our app.
One I can just copy and paste this code creating a new name over here.
The downside of that is that as our models change I'm going to have to manually update that ina.
There's actually a better approach.
We can use an import like statement to pull stuff out of our generated Prisma engraft file including
those Inam definitions.
So we don't have to define them over and over again.
They can automatically be pulled from the generated graphic schema.
Now there is a library that makes all of this possible.
So let's take a quick moment to pull it up.
If you google Prisma followed by the library name graphical hyphen inport that's going to bring you
over to the correct place where looking for the repository page here we can learn a bit about how this
tool works as well as learn how to set it up.
Now the good news is that it comes built in with our yoga server so we do not need to do any manual
configuration.
All we have to do is use it.
And down below there's an example of that.
We start off with what looks like a standard import statement just like the ones we've used in the course
but you notice we have the hash sign or the pound symbol whatever you want to call it up front.
And this is actually what starts a comment in our graph.
Q Well files so this commented outline is going to get parsed by the library and it's going to pull
in what's necessary since graft you l doesn't officially support any sort of inport statement and needs
to be hidden behind the comment.
So the file can be parsed correctly.
Let's go ahead and actually use this.
So in this case they are pulling in post from some other graphic file.
In our case we're going to pull in user order by input from the other files so right here we start off
with our hash sign then we inport then we list out the thing we want in this case it is user order by
input and we're going to grab that from inside of quotes where we have to provide the path that is dot
forward slash generated forward slash the file name Prisma dot graph.
Q Well now if you want to figure out what you can grab from that file you can always open the file up.
If we search for user order by input we can look for the definition.
Right here we have that definition along with two uses of it.
So yes we could type all of this out in our file but that's completely unnecessary.
Instead we can just import it.
So now we actually have access to user order by input in this file and we're going to set it up right
here.
We're going to add a new argument to the user's query.
I am going to call it order by and its type will be user order by input and we will leave that as completely
optional.
Much like our other arguments and there we go.
Now we have our schema dot graph Q L file all set up.
If we save this file we can move over into our query database file and all we have to do is pass it
through.
So right here we are going to pass through order by getting the value from args.
Ordered by and we're done.
We now have the ability to sort our users using our node J.S. application.
Let's go ahead and test things out.
I'm going to head over to graph school playground.
I'm going to switch over to the user's query the only one that currently supports.
Order by.
And I'm going to remove all other arguments.
So the only argument we're going to set up is order by.
And we're going to automatically see a list of all of those values.
All the potential ways we can sort a user showing up.
Now I'm going to go ahead and sort my users.
Let's sort them by name.
So right here I'll go name in an ascending fashion.
So going from a at the top to Z at the bottom.
Now if I go ahead and fire that off what do we see.
We see that we have Andrew then Jen then Jess and at the bottom we have Sarah.
And if I switch that over to a descending order we have Sarah then Jess then Jen then Andrew which is
fantastic.
So now one of our four queries does indeed have sorting built in.
Now if we wanted to grab something else using this port statement the syntax is actually slightly different
than what we've learned about so far.
If we wanted to grab a second thing we would just provide a comma separated list.
So right here comma space something else and then we could grab some third item as an example.
So here we just have a comma separated list of all of the things you want to grab from that file.
In this case though we just have one.
Now the reason I'm telling you that you can grab multiple things using this syntax is because you're
going to have to do just that for your challenge.
In this video.
So let's talk about exactly what I'd like you to do and I have some challenge comments.
I'm going to paste in right here right here the goal is to add sorting for posts my posts and comments.
So step 1 you're going to set up the order by argument for each with the correct imported ENM.
So if you want to figure out what that ENM is called You can always refer to the schema for the graph.
Well Prisma instance they're all listed here.
For example you just have to go to the other three.
And that's just step one.
Changing our schema digraph file.
Step 2 you have to update all of those resolvers down below to pass through that argument as well.
Currently they're all passing through first.
But after you just have to set up support for order by last up.
Test your work try to sort each of those by something and make sure the sorting is actually functional.
All right.
Take some time to knock that out.
Test your work then come back and click play
how that go.
We're going to kick things off step one over inside of schema dot graphics.
Well now I'm going to start with posts.
So right here we're going to set up.
Order By.
I am going to provide the correct ENM name which is going to be Post order by input and that's something
that we're going to import from over here.
So right here we're going to have post order by input in our input statement.
Remember it is a comma separated list.
Next up we can go ahead and grab the inport for my posts.
Now there's actually nothing special about my posts since it just posts so right here there's nothing
to grap.
Order by
once again post order by input which is in the same type for each.
Because both are based off of the same model.
In the end of the day we just have one that shows published posts and another that shows Drats down
below that we're gonna set up our final one which is comments right here.
Order by for this one we are going to have to import something new Kamen to order a by input.
I'm going to use it down below.
Copy the name and import it up above a comma after our last one and then a space and I'll paste it in.
Now we have all of the necessary arguments set up and that actually wraps up step 1.
We can move onto Step 2 which is just to pass the arguments through.
So down below for my posts I am going to pass through order by args dot.
Order by.
And I am going to do the exact same thing for my other two.
I can just take this line and copy it to the clipboard and bring it down below.
We're going to add it right here for posts and then down below for comments as well.
Perfect.
I just gotta clean up those commas for comments and we are all done.
Now that we have this in place step two is done.
We can go ahead and test our work.
I'm going to remove the challenge comments.
Save the file and head over to local host 4000 to see if all of this actually works.
I'm going to move over to my posts query.
I'll refresh the schema and if I crack open the schema viewer for posts I should see order by and I'd
do it showing up down below and up above.
I also have it for my posts and comments which is great.
Let's go ahead and actually use them.
So right here I'm going to remove all other arguments and I am going to sort by the descending created
out values in order by created at we're going to go in a descending fashion and if I fire that off that's
exactly what we end up getting.
We have the newest created posts up top and we have the oldest posts in the database down below which
is perfect.
Now let's go ahead and sort our comments.
I'm going to use the exact same thing so I can just head over to the comments query.
I'm going to go ahead and remove all of the existing arguments and use order by sorting by created at
and actually let's go in an ascending fashion this time.
And if I fire that off I have all of my comments showing up.
So in this case I have the oldest ones up top and the newest ones down below right here.
This comment was created at 3 p.m. 20 minutes.
This was 3 p.m. 38 minutes.
So we have the oldest followed by the newest As we move down the list.
We could always reverse that by using descending.
And now we have the opposite order.
Last up is my posts.
I'm going to move over to my posts all the way at the end.
We're going to remove all of those pagination related arguments and we're just going to set up order
by right here.
Let's go ahead and order by the titles.
I will sort by title and I'm going to go ahead and go in an a sending fashion.
Perfect.
If I fire that off what do we get.
We get our posts.
We have posts by Jess.
Then down below we go in order.
So we go from 1 to 5.
Now the reason that we're seeing just posts by Jack is because this is a query that requires authentication.
But if we switch that over to a descending order we can see things in reverse going from 5 down to 1.
So there we go.
We now have sorting in place for all of our queries which is a step in the right direction.
I'm excited to continue on with this section so stay tuned and I'll see you in the next video.