Welcome to the class.
Thanks so much for joining in Andrew and together.
We're going to explore what graft well is why it's useful and how we can use it to build better applications.
Now we'll get into all of that shortly.
I just want to take a moment in this one to talk about a couple of important things.
We're going to talk about how we'll be spending our time together so I'll break down what we're going
to cover in each part of the course.
And I'm also going to offer up a few tips and suggestions for getting the most out of a class
the course itself is broken up into two major parts.
In part one we're going to focus on learning the fundamentals of graft well and figuring out how we
can integrate it into Noad.
Jay ass so here we'll be focusing on the core building blocks those built in features learning how we
can build our own Grath applications from scratch.
Now that's part one and we'll be starting that in just a couple of videos in part two later in the class.
We'll transition into integrating what we learn about graft Well in part one with all of those real
features we'd expect from applications things like authentication database storage production deployments
automatic test suites and more.
By the end Yula the real application.
So part one.
Those building blocks part to integrating the building blocks to create a real world app.
All right let's go ahead and talk about a couple of tips and tricks for getting the most out of the
class.
This course was designed to be completely interactive.
So as you move through the videos I'm going to be typing code on the screen.
It's important that you have your text editor open and that you're typing that code out as well.
As we progressed through the videos we're going to end up building on our existing application and you
want to make sure you have all of the same features that I have.
Now this is sort of a monkey see monkey do situation.
That's great for when you're first exposed to a topic but it's not so great for retaining it or for
figuring out how to use it to solve problems on your own.
That's why throughout the class I have about 85 separate challenges.
These are little points in the video we're going to ask you to pause the video.
Solve a problem based off of what you learned then you can come back and watch me work through the solution.
It is essential that you follow through with both of these.
So if I write code you should be writing code and when there's time for a challenge break you should
actually take some time could try to solve the problem on your own.
That's going to make sure that when you're done the class you can actually use what you've learned here
to solve problems and build applications which is my goal for you.
All right let's take a quick moment to talk about getting help if you need it.
The last thing I want to talk about is how to get help if you get stuck.
So as you're moving through the course maybe your project fails.
In the video you can see my project working but when you run the project on your machine you get a cryptic
error message.
Or maybe you just need clarification on why we're using one technique and not something else.
Regardless of what your question is you can always ask a brand new question in the course of Q&amp;A to
get help.
When you do be sure to include as many details as possible as those go a long way towards us being able
to help you faster.
Things like screen shot code samples and error messages are going to allow us to track down and fix
the issue quickly.
Now there are two other ways you can get help even faster.
One is to browse the Q&amp;A for similar questions.
So we get dozens of questions every single day and they all have answers.
There might be a question similar to yours so you can get help in a matter of seconds as opposed to
having to wait a little bit for one of us to respond.
Last up if you're running into a problem and you suspect it's code related I do include the lecture
code as the zip download for each and every lecture here on you to me so you can always download the
code I wrote in the video.
You can then compare my code to yours and likely find the problem if not.
As always feel free to ask a question in the course.
Want.
All right.
That is it for this little welcome video.
Let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.