This course it contains a lot of new information.
So to make that information easier to digest and remember I've included a PTF companion with the class
this PTF guide can be downloaded as part of the lecture resources for this lesson and they recommend
taking just a quick moment to download it.
Crack it open and see what it's all about the guide itself contains lecture notes as well as documentation
links and code samples for everything we talk about in the class.
It's a much more scanning or friendly version of the Course that's not meant to be read front to back
like a book.
It's meant to be your companion as you move through the class.
So if you forget where I said something or exactly what we talked about the PTF guide can get you that
information quickly and easily.
All right that's it for this one.
Let's go ahead and talk about why we should ever use graphs.
Well.