Before we wrap up this section and died anti-graft Well there are two things we're going to have to
have installed on our computers.
The first is node SJS which you can find out.
No.
J.S. not org since knowing node is a pre-req for this class Hopefully you already have it installed
on your computer.
If you don't have node installed or you're using a much older version just go ahead and grab a V8 of
node or higher you can grab the installer run through it by clicking next a bunch of times and then
you'll be all done the exact version of node you use with this class.
Does not matter.
All of the graphics.
Well functionality that we're going to be exploring comes from specific NPM modules which we'll be installing
later.
We just need a semi-modern version of node to get the environment up and running the 8 of node or greater
is going to work perfectly fine.
So v 8 9 10 or whatever else comes out in the future so run through that installer.
Make sure you have node installed and if you do we can move on to the second tool which is going to
be a text editor.
As always you are more than welcome to use whatever text editor you're comfortable with if you're interested
in following along and setting up your environment just like mine.
I'm going to be using Visual Studio code.
You can find that over at Code dot Visual Studio dot com if you haven't used it before I recommend giving
it a shot.
It's a fantastic editor that integrates really well with all sorts of environments including graphs.
Well Visual Studio code is free.
It's open source and it's available for all operating systems.
So if you do want to use it go ahead and grab the installer and get it installed.
We're going to wrap up this video by going over the plugins.
I'll be using for VSC in this class.
Now some of these plug ins will have replacements in other editors but I can't guarantee that.
So here's the plug in list I'm using for Visual Studio code.
I got about half a dozen or so that really come in handy.
The first one Babel six slash iOS 7 just gives us support for all of those modern features like Aero
functions and async await the next plugin beautify allows us to format our code on the fly.
After that we have Dharker which is going to come in handy later in the course when we worry about deploying
our applications.
After that I have duplicate action.
This is a simple one that allows me to write click files or folders to duplicate them inside of the
file tree.
After that I have graphed well for Visual Studio code.
I definitely recommend installing this one as it's going to give us syntax highlighting for the graphics
you l code that we're going to be writing very soon after that.
I have NPM NPM Intellisense which just give me better support when working with NPM modules something
we will be doing in this class.
Then I have Sublime Text key map I use that because I really fell in love with the Sublime Text keyboard
shortcuts.
I had a really hard time switching to some of the Visual Studio code defaults.
This one like all of these is completely optional but if you do like the Sublime Text keyboard shortcuts
it's a great tool.
Last up word count.
Just count the words in a markdown file.
Nothing fancy there.
So these are all the plug ins.
I'll be using throughout the class if you have node installed and a text editor installed you are ready
to dive into the next section where we're actually going to start learning about graft.
Well I am super excited to get to it.
So stay tuned and I will see you then.