Welcome to Section 6 in this section we're going to focus on authentication.
So right now our database exists but it's wide open anyone can come through and read any record they
want and they can manipulate them too.
They could just come through and delete everything.
Obviously that's not what we want.
So in this section we're going to start by setting up authentication then we're going to focus on putting
some of our data behind authentication.
So there'll be some stuff you could still access if you're not authenticated like published posts but
pretty much everything else is going to require authentication.
If you want to access your drafts or if you want to do something like manipulate a comment or a post
you're going to have to authenticate so we can confirm you actually have the ability to do that.
For example I shouldn't be able to edit a post that you create.
All right let's go ahead and dive into the section and figure out how we can set up authentication.