In this video you're going to start the process of putting no J.S. Right between our public users and
the private Prisma Graph API.
So we don't want users to be able to directly interact with the Prisma Graph API because then they could
read and write from the database doing whatever they want it could sabotage another user deleting all
of their posts for example instead we went no.
J.S. as the middleman.
This is going to allow us to set up things like authentication and data validation.
You'll really be able to customize this to fit your needs.
For example in the case of our blogging application there are certain things where it makes sense to
expose data even if someone's not authenticated like the published posts.
That's the whole point of visiting the blogging site.
After all you're trying to read those published posts.
And there's no reason to leave those restricted now other pieces of data very well should be restricted.
For example a user's draft posts should only be accessible by them which means we're going to have to
authenticate them to make sure that the actual owner.
Don't worry we'll get into all of that and more in this section.
For now though the goal is to put no Jay between the public users and the Prisma graphical API.
In this video let's go ahead and start with our queries.
So I'm going to open up the resolvers directory and crack open.
Queried Dhananjay.
And we're just going to work our way from top to bottom.
So let's start with the first one.
We have the users query right here.
Currently we are just reading a data from that array.
We have access to DB users right here and DB users down below.
This is reading from that static array defined in DB J S.
In the end of the day what we really want to do is use Prisma inside of this method.
We want to use Prisma.
Queery dot users to fetch the data from the database and that's what we're going to end up doing.
The next thing we have to do real quick before we make any changes to this file is to make a small change
to Prisma dot J ass down below.
We have all of these examples we created to explore how Prisma works in known G-S.
These are all great because it allowed us to explore all of these features and we will use what we've
learned we're just not going to use it in this file.
So for the moment what I'd like to do is just highlight everything in this file down below.
Comment that out and leave just these two things in place.
The one line where we import Prisma binding and the second line where we create a new instance using
the Prisma constructor function.
The only thing we're going to add to this file is an export.
We want other files to be able to access Prisma so we can use things like Prisma Dopp mutation Prisma
queery Prisma data exists and Prisma subscription export.
We are going to be exporting Prisma from up above the lower case version and I will export this as the
default export.
Excellent.
Now we can actually save this file.
And what we're going to do is set up Prisma to live on our application context.
So inside of index Dhananjay.
Just like we have D-B and pub sub.
We are going to add on Prisma So it's accessible for all of our resolver functions to do that.
All we have to do is one change this in port statement right here.
Previously we were importing this file without grabbing anything from it that made sure the file actually
ran.
So our little experiments down below ran when the start script executed.
But we're going to do though is go ahead and actually grab something from that file we're gonna grab
the default export we just set up Prisma from perfect.
Now that the inport statement is in place we're just going to add it on to the context.
So right here I will create a Prisma property getting its value from the variable with the same name.
So now we can say of index Dhananjay as we can close this file down and we can move into queery dot
J S and actually take advantage of Prisma which is now part of the application context.
So just like I could access D-B and pub sub if I needed to.
I can also write here Access Prisma giving me access to things we need like Prisma dot queery dot users.
Let's go ahead and start up our application.
So I am going to use C.D to switch into the graphed fuel Prisma project and once I'm inside of there
I will run NPM start to start up the application like we've done plenty of times before.
And then we can move over to the Grath QOL playground instance for our app.
So for me that is the very first tab localhost four thousand if I go ahead and give it a refresh we
can see all of our queries showing up here.
Now in this case we're working with that users query which is the very first tab.
And if actually fire it off what do we get back.
We get back all of that static data from the array.
So the goal is to actually change method to get the data back from the Prisma database instead let's
go ahead and kick that process off the first thing I'm going to do is actually comment out all of the
lines we have in that method so far.
The reason I'm leaving them in place is so we can remember what features we had set up to support for
example we do have support for that query argument.
We'll add support for that shortly.
For the moment though we're going to ignore it and just get a bare bones version in place which returns
all users.
If we want to fetch all of the users out of the database we'd better use Prisma queery and we are going
to use one of the queries that the Prisma graph Cual API provides in this case.
I'm going to be using the user's query which we've already explored before.
Now we are going to call it with those two arguments.
The first argument contains are operation arguments if any we can provide null for the moment will add
support for query a bit later.
And the second argument is our selection set.
So for each user what fields do we want to grab.
Now there are actually three distinct types of values we can provide for this second argument for the
second argument you can provide nothing at all.
You can provide a string which is what we've seen so far.
And you can also provide an object.
So before we go any further I want to talk about all three and why you would use one over another.
So first up we can actually provide nothing as that second argument.
I could just leave the second argument off altogether like this.
Or it could provide a falsie value like no or undefined.
In this case Prisma is going to fall back to a default and that default is going to grab all of these
scalar fields for the type.
So in this case we are fetching users which returns a user type which means that we will get all scalar
fields for the user.
If I open up Prisma and crack open that data model file we can see that means we would get back the
id the name and the email for every user.
These are our three scalar fields.
We would not get back anything about the posts or the comments.
Now in this case that is not what we want.
The problem with providing no second argument is that we can never ask for relational data.
So well a query like this might indeed work because we're only asking for scalar fields.
If I started to ask for something like posts it would not actually come back.
So we need to adjust what we're doing providing no argument is nice in some cases.
In this case it's not what we want.
Now next up we have the string and we've already explored the string in detail.
This is what we used over in prison.
J S for example.
When I called the Create post mutation I provide by selection set as a string.
I ask for some information about the author.
Then I ask for all of the author's posts getting some information about each of those.
Now this is something we can indeed do.
But the problem is that we have to explicitly as a string define what we need and we don't know what
we need because what we need is coming from the user.
In this case when I say user i could mean the client on the web or the client on I O S.
So we have this query coming from our client.
It's coming through node.
We don't want to type out a different query.
We actually want to use the same one.
So once again using a string can indeed be useful in this case though it is not what we want what we're
going to end up providing is an object.
No it's not an object we define it's actually an object that's created for us.
The object that we're going to be passing in as the second argument is the info object.
That's right here it's been here all along we just haven't used it so far.
So in the end of the day info contains all of the information about that original operation.
So this operation would exist somewhere like a web browser or an iOS app.
It will get sent off to the server and it's accessible via info.
But we're going to do is pass it through right to Prisma.
So Prisma can grab the same things that were requested.
If I asked for certain fields Prisma I would grab those fields if I asked for related data Prisma it
could grab that related data.
Now when the end of the day what this means is that what we're going to do is pass that info argument
right here as the second argument to our query method and this is something that we're going to do throughout
all of our resolvers while they're there for queries or mutations we want to replay the query provided
to node j as we don't want to explicitly type out something new using a string and we want to get more
than just the scalar values that providing nothing would give us.
Now in this case what do we have.
Well we have a promise and we need to do something with this promise.
Our resolver methods like users can actually take a promise as the return value.
It will wait for the promise to resolve and then it will send that data back which means that we can
just return exactly what we have right here and there we go.
That is all we have to do to get a bare bones version of this in place for the moment what I'm going
to do is head into one of our other files we're going to open up schema graphics.
Well and we're going to scroll up to the user.
The user currently supports age something we don't have in the Prisma API is going to go ahead and remove
that just leaving an ID name and email we can then go ahead and save schema dot graphics.
Well and we can also save query dot J as I'm going to save this file.
And now what we're going to do is run our query on localhost 4000.
So this query is going to get sent off to no.
Jay ass and the past return data from our static array.
This time around though we should be getting data from our database.
Now I am going to make a small adjustment if I refresh the schema.
You can see that age is no longer recognized and that's correct.
We just changed that file.
If I fire this off what do we get back.
Well after a few moments what we get back is all of the data that we saved in our postgresql database.
So now my putting no J.S. Right between our public API and Prisma we are able to fetch that data from
the database.
Currently yes there are no restrictions we're going to work on adding those in over time.
I for the moment we're not going to worry about adding support back in for that query argument.
We'll handle that very shortly.
What I'd like to do for now is move on to your challenge for this video where you're going to end up
doing is exactly what we just did for users.
But you're going to do it for posts.
So right here there are a few challenge comments to outline what I'd like you to do.
And once again the big picture goal is to modify the Post's query to return posts from the post gress
database.
So step 1 you're going to comment out all of that existing code down below.
Then inside of the Post's method right here you're going to use the correct Prisma method call.
Similar to what we did up here for users.
Once again you can ignore operation arguments for now and you're going to provide info as that second
argument passing through the original request.
Step three what you're going to do is go ahead and actually run the Post's query on the node.
J.S. graphed you Al API to verify a works.
So right here in localhost 4000 I would go over to the Post's tab and run that query.
Currently all of this data is coming from that array NDB data J as.
Once you're done the challenge though you should be seeing the posts in your post graphs database.
If you don't have any posts what you can do is just switch over to the playground tab for the actual
Prisma API.
You can add a couple of posts in.
Then you should be able to fetch them using the node.
J.S. graft UL API.
And once again just ask for scalar fields.
We'll talk about handling relational data shortly.
So take some time to knockdown out test your work when you're done come back and click play
that go let's go ahead and kick things off by commenting out all of the code down below.
We are going to add support for all of this stuff back in filtering by things like the title and the
body.
But for now we're going to ignore that and get back to the basics what we're going to do is use the
correct Prisma method to fetch all of the posts.
So we want to access Prisma.
We should probably grab it off of context and we want to perform a query.
So I'll be using Prisma and query the query that we're going to be using is the query that fetches all
posts.
That is the Post's query and we're going to provide the necessary arguments.
Once again I mentioned that you can ignore operation arguments for now so will provide null and for
the second argument we're not going to explicitly outline what we need because we don't know what we
need.
Clients are going to request different things from the API is all we're going to do is pass info through
giving Prisma exactly what it needs to fetch the data.
Now in the end of the day we do have to return something from the Post's method.
I'm going to return the promise that comes back from calling posts now that we have this in place we
can move on to step three which is to actually run the query and make sure we're getting the data back
from the postgresql database.
Since we're no longer using DBI either in the user's query or the Post's query I can remove that from
both arguments save the file and now we can rerun our posts query at local host 4000 right here.
I'm asking for all of those scalar fields.
No relational data.
If I go ahead and run it what do I get back.
I get back the one post I have in the database.
In this case it is an unpublished post with nobody.
And the title is Prisma post.
So there we go.
We've successfully started the process of putting no Jack ass right in between the public and our private
Prisma graph Cual API.
Now once again for the moment we aren't performing any restrictions what so ever.
So it's still like you have access to anything in the database for example right here I'm not authenticated
and I am getting an unpublished draft post later on that's something we won't allow.
But for now it's a great starting point.
Over here we can make a few small changes before we're done.
I'm going to remove the D-B argument from both of those queery method since it's no longer used up above.
I am going to delete the challenge comments and that's where we're going to stop for this one in the
next video we'll continue working on our queries.
We're actually going to set up all of those.
Operation arguments so for users will add support back in for a query and down below will do the same
thing for posts.
I'm excited to get to that.
So stay tuned and I'll see you in the next one.