In this video you're going to wrap up the conversion process for both the users query and for the Post's
query and to get this done all we have to do is learn how we can filter data using Prisma.
In the case of the users query we were previously allowing them to filter just by users that had a particular
name.
I want to restore support for that.
And then down below for posts we were allowing them to search for a specific piece of text either in
the title or the body and we returned just posts that actually contained that text.
So we're going to add all of those features back in now and the end of the day we're really going to
be doing is providing operation arguments to Prisma.
So we're really just going to be creating objects and passing them in for the operation arguments.
We're going to start this process together for users.
Then down below you'll go through the same process a bit later.
For posts to kick things off all we're going to do is create an empty object.
This will be our starting point.
So a new constant right here and I'll call it something like oph args which is short for Operation arguments.
And once again just an empty object to start.
This is the value that we're going to provide as the operation arguments for the users query as opposed
to currently providing nulls are right here.
Op ARX.
Now when we pass it an empty object it's just like passing in null which means that things are still
going to work as expected in this case.
We are still going to get all users back but we're going to do though is set up a series of conditional
statements to make changes to oph args over time.
For example if args don't queery exists you are going to modify oph args to actually use it.
So right here we can set up an if statement with our condition and our code block to run if that condition
passes.
And all we're going to do is check if args queery exists.
If it does this code is going to run and all we're going to do is change the structure of the object.
Now when it comes to learning which operation arguments you can actually provide you have to refer to
the schema us over engraft QOL playground.
All I'm going to do is crack open that schema tab and we're looking for the user's queries so up above
we have our users query right here we can see all of the arguments that users supports.
And it's a whole bunch we have wherefor filtering.
I have order by which allows us to sort alphabetically or by ID or by anything else like age.
And we have a few other arguments which are useful for pagination.
For the moment we are just focusing on where now where is of the type user where input as we can learn
more about what we provide for wear down below.
If I actually click this we're going to see that on this type there are about maybe 60 different fields
we can provide.
And you'll notice that all of these fields directly correlate with things that we set up specifically
for the user.
Right here I have about a dozen or so different ID related fields I can check if an ID matches exactly
or if an ID is not a match or if there is something in the ID or if the ID is less than less than or
equal to greater than or greater than equal to I can check if the ID contains particular text or starts
with something.
There are all sorts of fields we can provide that allow us to filter.
We have the same thing down below for name.
I can check if the name starts with a certain string or if the e-mail is not a different string.
So all of these are going to allow us to filter correctly.
Now for our purposes we're going to change the behavior slightly.
We are still going to take in that query argument and I am going to search both the name and the e-mail.
It either the name or the e-mail contains that string.
We're going to consider that user a match and they will be returned if the string you provide is not
anywhere in the name or the e-mail.
Then we will consider them to not be a match and you will not get them back.
So let's take this process of the first thing we're going to do is set up OP args where this itself
is equal to an object and we're going to start by looking at the name.
We're going to check if the name contains some other value and we already know how to do that in the
schema tab for a name we have name contains.
So right here what do we do.
I set up the value name underscore contain.
Now we can actually move on to the value for name contains which is just going to be our exact query.
So that is the string that was passed in we're going to check if the name contains that if it does great
if it doesn't that's OK too.
Now before we go on and add support for the e-mail let's just start here.
I'm going to save query J S and make sure things are working well so far.
Now we can switch over to graph Q and playground for node.
J.
S. and we could fire off the exact same operation we had before and we would get the exact same results.
So query is not required.
But now we can add it in and see how that influences the data that we get back right inside of here.
I am going to set up a query.
We know its value is a string when it's provided.
So right here we will provide a string and I'm going to start with something simple like the letter
r the letter R is indeed contained in names for all three users.
So if we fire this off I would expect to see all three users showing up right here.
They all do.
If I were to switch that over to something like Q Which is not in any of the users names I would expect
new users to come back and that is exactly what we get.
And if I were to try something like R E W which is indeed contained in Andrew I would expect just that
user to show up and right here that is exactly what we end up getting.
So as we've seen in the graph Cuil schema for Prisma there are all sorts of ways we can filter our data.
I could check if the name does not contain something or if the name ends with something.
All sorts of really useful techniques.
For now though we found the one that works for us with respect to name.
We want to do now though is also look at the email we're going to return a user if their name contains
a string or if their e-mail contains the string.
If we open up the schema Explorer and scroll to the top of the fields available on where we want to
explore the first two we have.
And and we have or these take an array of objects an array of the object we're seeing defined here user
where input and this is going to allow us to set up various conditional logic.
I could return a user if their name is something and their email is something else.
Or I could return a user if their name contains something or their email contains something and that's
what we're going to do.
So let's see how to use these in action down below inside of our editor.
We're going to start by wiping the aware object completely.
And we're going to set up the or property it is indeed an array of objects.
Let's go ahead and add our first object into the mix.
And for this object we provide exactly what we would have provided before I can set name underscore
contains equal to the value that was passed in args dot queery.
Awesome.
Now the other thing we want to look at is provided via a nother object.
So we need either this to be true or this to be true in this case we can check if their email contains
something and we're still on the check.
The same thing Argosy dot query.
So now we're going to get a user back if either of those actually end up passing.
Let's go ahead and save queery.
J.
S and test things out over at localhost 4000 we're going to play around with this.
Currently I have that little rou query string.
I'm going to remove it and fire off that operation just so I can view all of my data and I am going
to search for at example.
Now the name for none of these users contains an example but the email for all of them does.
So if I were to fire this off I would expect to see old data and that is exactly what we're getting.
Now if I were to try something else like an ad example dotcom that is only contained in this user right
here am at example matching up perfectly.
The other two users don't have that.
We have to add example and then down below we have to add example as well.
So if I find things off I would expect to just see that second user and that is exactly what I end up
getting.
So in this case as long as either of these are true the user gets returned.
Now if I were to flip that and use uppercase and D and we would see some different behavior in this
case we now need to find the string in both the name and the e-mail.
And that's not true for our current query.
While this user does have it in the email it is not in the name.
So if I were to fire things off we would get no data back.
So being able to play around with an ad or to perform filtering is super essential for getting our filters
in place.
But this one though we are going to switch it back to or since that's the behavior we actually want
when filtering users and now that we have this in place we can remove all of the old comments we had
down below since everything is wired up to work perfectly now it's up to you to do the same thing for
posts down below.
So up above I have a few comments describing what I'd like you to do.
And the big picture goal is to modify posts to support the query argument.
The Post's query already supports that argument.
You just need to actually use it down below in this function.
So step one set up an object for those operation arguments.
Step two if the queery argument is actually provided you want to modify that object setting it up.
So it only returns posts that have the string in either the hosts title or the hosts body.
So you can refer to the schema Explorer to figure out how to get that done.
For posts step three test your work so you can perform a few different queries and make sure you get
the correct values back.
You can provide no query and you should still get all of the posts.
Then you could provide a piece of text in either the title or body for a given post.
And you should see just those ones showing up all right.
Take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Pause the video and when you're done come back and click play
how that go I'm going to kick things off with step one.
Down below we are going to create that object for those operation arguments.
So that would be something like Konst OP args setting it up as an object and then passing that in as
the first argument value.
So right here.
Op ARX.
Now we want to go ahead and check if the query argument was actually provided.
Once again using an if statement if args don't query exists we want to go ahead and actually change
a property on arx we want to change the ware property so OP Ark's dot where is now going to equal something
new that is going to be an object and this is where we're going to provide all of the filtering necessary.
Now you might be able to guess exactly what we're going to end up using based off of field names but
you could have also used the explorer to figure out exactly what supported.
So right here I have my posts query.
We also have a where argument post where input which is described down below.
And here we can see we have some of the same stuff like and and or.
And we also have various filters for all of the fields we have ID.
We have title we have body and we have published in this case we want to use both title and body.
I'm going to be using Title contains and I'm also going to be using body contain.
So let's switch over into the editor and actually get this done.
First up I will start with or I want to check if either of a title or the body contains this thing as
long as one do that's fine.
Right here we are going to set it up as an array of objects.
I'm going to go ahead and set up those two objects one for title and one for body right here.
I will use title underscore contains setting that equal to args dot queery.
Excellent.
And then down below I am going to use body underscore contains.
And for this one the value also comes from args dot query.
Awesome.
Now we can go ahead and actually test things out.
First up let me go ahead and delete all of the comments down below for the old version of this method.
And up above.
Also remove the challenge comments since we've knocked out hopefully successfully.
All three steps.
Now we can save queery dot J S and test our work over in localhost four thousand I have the Post's query
sitting right here.
And if I run things as we currently had them we still get our 1 post back.
Now if I go ahead and actually provide that argument we can make sure it filters correctly.
We have query.
Its value is a string.
And if I were to search for something like post I would expect this post to still show up since it is
contained in either the title or the body.
If I fire this off we do still get that post.
If I were to switch this over to something like that which is not contained in either field I would
expect to get no posts back.
And that is exactly what I get.
Perfect.
So now that we have this filtering in place for posts we're going to be able to easily search for posts
and that's great because that means on the user interface in either your mobile application or on the
browser you can have a text field for searching.
You can then just take that text.
Use it as the query argument and you'll be able to get just the data that actually matches what the
user wants to view.
Nothing more and nothing less.
Now that we have this in place we are all done for this video we have posts and users looking really
good so far.
We're going to continue on in this process in the next video.
I am excited to get to it.
So stay tuned and I'll see you soon.