In this video we're going to turn our attention towards relational data.
Once again we have our users query and our posts query working.
But it's only working if we're just selecting scalar fields.
If I were to select some relational data things would actually be breaking and that's because we've
overridden that behavior using files like comment Dhananjay as post.com J as end user Dot.
Yes.
So to illustrate the issue I'm talking about let's make a small change to the user's query in localhost
4000.
Right here I am going to remove the operation argument so I can fetch all users and if I actually fetch
all of them I can see I have three.
Let's go ahead and ask for not just scalar fields but another field as well.
I'm going to grab the posts for each user.
Now for each post I can grab the ID and I can grab the title and then we can fire this one up.
Now when I fire it off we don't get an error.
The program isn't crashing but we're also not getting the expected data.
I do indeed have a single post in the database but it's not showing up anywhere for all three users.
We have an empty array even though that's not really accurate.
The reason we're not getting the correct data is because of the contents of user data J S which we had
set up previously.
If you remember this is the file where we told graph Q L how to find the user's posts and how to find
the users comments and we did this by looking through our array data.
So I looked through DB posts up here and in DB comments down below.
So currently the reason we're not seeing any data is because we're not even looking in the real Prisma
database.
Instead we're just looking in those arrays and we're not finding matches which is to be expected.
So there are two ways we can approach solving this.
The first way and maybe the more obvious way is to actually load in Prisma right here and then use something
like Prisma doc queery dot posts to get all of their posts.
Now that would indeed work.
But the nice thing is that Prisma has support for relational data built right in.
Which means that both of these methods are actually completely unnecessary.
We can actually delete everything inside of the user object though leaving that object in place we can
save the file and we're done.
We can now rerun the exact same query we ran before though this time around.
As you can see we are indeed getting our one post showing up for that post's author.
All of this is working by default because we've chosen to pass that info argument in and remember info
contains all of the information about the fields requested.
This includes not just those scalar fields but also related ones.
So by passing info into Prisma query users we can get this behavior by default.
There's no need to add more code so this is a nother great reason to use Prisma because it works directly
with graft Well it makes it really easy to set up your node J.S. application.
Now we're going to do is the exact same thing for posts.
If I go over to the Post's query and I go ahead and fetch all posts by removing the query argument we
can see that it does indeed work.
We get our one post back but if I were to ask for something about that post's author Let's go ahead
and grab the authors ID and the author's name.
Things are going to fail if I wrote it.
You can see we're getting an error.
It's trying to find the author for a post and it knows that author is a non nullable fields so it should
indeed exist when it doesn't find a author it throws an error saying that it cannot find the required
field.
So once again all of this is happening because of what's inside of post.com J ass right inside of here.
We are overriding what happens when we look for an author.
So we're actually making prisoners job harder by removing both of these and saving the file.
We will once again be able to perform that operation without any errors.
If I rerun it what do we get.
We get the information expected right here.
I can see that this post from the Prisma database was indeed written by this user who also exists in
that database.
So in the end of the day by wiping those two objects we are allowing Prisma to do the heavy lifting
for us.
Now for the moment I want to keep these files and these objects in place even though they're currently
empty as we started to work on features like authentication and authorization they're going to become
a little more important as they're going to allow us to lock down a behavior so instead of deleting
them now and adding them back and five or six videos I'd rather just keep them around for now.
Currently they're not changing the application behavior at all.
Now it's Challenge time what you're going to do is follow the same process for the comments query which
we actually haven't touched so far what I'm going to do is close down both the user Dhananjay as and
Dot js files and I'm in a place those challenge comments right here.
So the big picture goal is to convert the comments query over to Prisma.
There are three steps for getting that done.
Number one you have to modify the comments query to fetch that data out of Prisma instead of fetching
it from our arrays.
Then you want to modify the code to allow for relational requests when using the comments query.
This is similar to what we just did for both users and posts.
And finally step 3 you want to test your work and make sure that it's actually working inside of graft
Well playgrounds over here on local host 4000.
I should be able to fetch comments and grab related data like the author's name.
Let's also grab their ID and that should actually work.
Now currently it's getting all the data correctly from the arrays by the end of the challenge you should
be seeing all of the data from the database.
Now if your setup is anything like mine you probably don't have any comments inside of your actual database.
We can fix this by just adding some directly using the Prisma graphical API playground.
Right here I have one of the queries from before.
It's nice because it shows the ID for all users posts and comments.
I am going to add a new comment onto my one and only post and I'm going to make an error the person
who's leaving that comment so I'll grab his ID right here and bring that over to my Create comment nutation
tab.
Swapping it out with the old ID the old value for author connect ID and then I'm going to make sure
the post ID is correct as well.
Smackover in this tab I am going to grab the ID for the one post I actually have.
I'm going to bring that over here and I will leave a comment by replacing the ID out.
So if I actually run this it should indeed leave a new comment and there we go.
Now we actually have a comment that we can test when working with our query.
Now that we have some data in place it's your job to make sure that this query actually works.
So knock out all three steps making sure to test your work along the way.
When you're done come back and click play
How'd that go let's go ahead and kick things off with step one.
We're going to modify the comments queries to fetch data from Prisma that happens down below.
All right here we have our function currently it's just returning all of the comments from the array.
We're going to swap that out.
So we're going to swap out D-B for Prisma and then down below instead of returning D-B Dom comments.
We're going to return what comes back from calling Prisma dot queried dot comments and then we are going
to call it with the correct arguments.
The first argument is going to be.
No.
There are no operation arguments necessary for this one.
And the second argument is going to be info perfect now that we have this in place we should be able
to at least fetch those scalar fields.
And that brings us to step two step two.
We want to make sure that we can actually fetch relational data which means that we need to remove the
customer resolvers set up in comment Dhananjay as here we are overriding how a comments author and a
comments post fields are populated.
If we actually remove these We'll let Prisma do the heavy lifting for us.
I can say of comment and Jay as I can save queery.
J s.
And that brings us to step three actually testing our work.
Over here I am going to run the query as it currently stands sends we're asking for some scalar values
as well as some related fields.
If I fire this off what do we get.
We get data from the post gresse database right here.
I have my one comment showing up the comment we just created and I also have correctly the author information
for the person who created that comment here.
That was indeed created by Andrew excellent So there we go.
We now have our three main queries all working they're working with Prisma and they're working when
we ask for related fields as well and that's where I'd like to start.
For this one with our queries out of the way in the next video we're going to turn our attention towards
our mutations.
We'll be following a lot of the same steps though.
Obviously things will be slightly different since we're working with mutations and not queries but in
general we're going to be able to reuse what we've learned so far.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.