In this video we're going to start to turn our attention towards our mutations.
We have more mutations than we do queries and with the mutations we also want node j ass to serve us
that middleman that's going to make sure that when we do add in things like authentication we can use
node to make sure that someone has the correct permissions to edit some post or delete some comment.
So to kick things off what I'm going to do is close all of the open files and I'm going to open just
a single file to start.
Mutation Dhananjay as in here we're going to go one by one.
Updating all of our mutations to interact with the data from the database as opposed to interacting
with the data from our arrays which is what it's currently doing first on our list is the create user
mutation.
Eventually this mutation will be called Sign-Up.
That's coming a little bit later in this section but for now we'll leave the name the same and all we're
going to do is switch the functionality from working with the array data to working with the real database.
I'll start by commenting out everything we have so far and swapping out the D B argument for Prisma
so we can actually interact with that database.
Now the first thing we do inside of here is going to be something very similar to what we did before.
I'm going to try to find a user with the e-mail.
This person is trying to register with.
I want to make sure that it's not already taken.
So Konst email taken once again this time though we are going to take advantage of Prisma data exists.
We are going to call user and in this case we're just going to search by ID so I can pass in that object.
We're looking for users where their email is equal to the value provided in args dot data dot email.
That's the exact value we were using before.
Perfect.
Now it's important to note that what comes back from user is indeed a promise.
So we're going to take advantage of a sink and a weight inside of this method so let's market as an
async function when we're using the ESX method definition we put the async keyword upfront like we're
seeing here now down below.
I can actually await this promise and what we're getting back is a boolean value email taken is true.
If it did find a user with that e-mail e-mail taken is false.
If it did not find a user with that e-mail now on the end of the day we're going to throw the same error
we through before.
So I can actually just take this code copy it paste it up above and uncomment it.
Excellent.
Now we have the actual uniqueness verified and we can continue on down the list.
But we're going to end up doing is creating the user by using Prisma Dopp mutation not create user.
Now what is important to note that if we tried to create a user and the email was already taken yes
we would indeed get a failure.
The only reason we're using exists here is to allow us a little more fine grained control here we can
explicitly throw an error with the exact message we want.
So once again you can really go either way.
Maybe you just pass all the data to the nutation and see if that fails maybe you first check using exists.
Either way works.
They're both perfectly valid approaches and I've worked in projects that actually use both techniques
successfully.
So now we're going to continue on down that list and the next thing to do is to create the user.
So I will create a variable Konst I'm going to call this user and right here we are going to await the
promise that comes back from Prisma dot mutation dot.
Create user.
Perfect.
We're going to call that as such and pass in our necessary arguments.
The first argument is where we provide our operation arguments to the Prisma Graph API and we're just
going to pass the arguments through.
So arguments were provided to the node Graph API.
We're going to pass them right along.
I'm going to set up data getting its value from args ADOT data which is the arguments provided to the
node j s graft UL API.
Now I know this can be a little confusing to visualize at first.
So what happens is that the client makes a request to the node JSE API and it passes in the arguments
necessary.
We can always remember exactly what we set up by going into schema.
Graft well up above I have the mutation for create user.
This is the node j as a graphical API mutation.
It takes in create user input which we created down below.
This requires the name and the email just like the Prisma API does.
Now it still has age left behind as an artifact from when age was on the user.
We could actually remove that right here from create user input and I can also remove it from Update
user input.
Perfect.
So in the end of the day the object that we're talking about right here args dot data we know that is
going to have a name and it is going to have an email.
So it's perfectly fine to pass that right on through to Prisma which also requires a name and an e-mail.
So where are we going to go from here.
Well we have that user created an over going to do is pass in as the second argument info.
This is going to ensure that whatever selection set was asked for actually ends up coming back.
So if I create a new user and just ask for their ID that is the exact information we'll get back.
So we're passing info through.
Perfect.
Now with this in place we're actually all done.
I can remove all of the comments down below and all we have to do is return something.
I am going to return the user.
Excellent.
Now remember that we can indeed return promises from our resolver functions so the code we have here
is actually identical to just returning that promise directly.
There's no need to create a separate variable and await it.
If we're just going to return that value right away this code is just a little more concise though.
Once again both solutions are identical.
Perfect.
Now I can save this file and we're actually going to test things out.
We're going to make sure that it does interact with our real database over inside of local host 4000.
We're going to be firing off a create user mutation to our node J.S. graph.
Q Well API now to do this we will move over to the create user tab which we already have in place and
we have a mutation creating a name Jess and an e-mail Jess at example dot com Dambulla we have our selection
set and all we need to do is remove age since that's no longer something we can actually select.
Though I am going to grab the id the name and the email.
Awesome.
From here we can actually fire this off and see what we get.
Right here we have an ID.
We have a name and we have an e-mail as expected which is a great first step.
Let's go ahead and verify it's actually in the database by moving over to P.G. admin down below.
I have all of the tables for my default default schema.
I'm going to view the data in that user table.
So right click View added data.
I'm going to view all rows.
I should have my three old users as well as my one new user and right here that is exactly what I have.
I have the name Jess and I have the email.
Just an example dot com.
So the new user was indeed successfully created.
Excellent.
So at this point we do indeed use no JS as a middleman between the Prisma API and our API.
Now currently Yes you might say that I could just go over to this you Arel and do whatever I want to
the database shortly though we are going to lock that down.
So you'll need a secret password to actually directly interact with Prisma.
But the moment though we have one of our mutations converted which is a fantastic first step.
Now out of all of the original nutation methods I would have said the original create user mutation
was one of the least complex mutations.
There was not that much there.
The code is a bit simpler now but it was already pretty simple to begin with.
Some of our other mutation methods though are going to be able to get reduced drastically for example
delete user in this one.
We had to do some stuff directly related to the user but we also had to do a lot of stuff just to delete
user's posts and comments remember all of that is now automatically handled via Prisma.
So we're going to be able to reduce the complexity of this method by a great deal and that's a good
thing.
Now actually refactoring delete is going to be your challenge for the video I have some comments right
here.
So let's go ahead and talk about what I'd like you to do.
The big picture goal for this one is to wire up delete user to work with the Prisma database.
So once again when I fire off the delete user mutation right here from local host 4000 I would expect
it to actually be deleting users from inside of the post Gras database.
You're going to end up firing this off to verify that things work.
Step 1 refactor the delete user mutation resolver to use Prisma instead of working with that array data.
Now you're going to have to check if the user exists by their ID if they don't.
You can throw an error.
And if they do exist you can delete them and return the user itself.
Once again don't worry about deleting the posts or the comments like We are currently doing.
All of that's already been configured.
When we used the at relation directive and we set up the cascade deletion preferences.
Now step 2 I already talked about you're just going to test your work.
You're going to remove a user and verify that they were actually deleted from the database.
So take some time to knock this one out.
All you're going to have to do is change what's inside of this method.
Then fire off some operations from graft UL playground.
Take a moment to pause the video.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play.
How'd you do.
Let's go ahead and kick things off down below by commenting out everything we have so far.
As always I'm choosing to leave it in place temporarily as a reference so we can make sure we get back
to feature parity that the refactored version does the same things the old version did.
Step 1 we want to go ahead and check if there is already a user's right here a variable something like
user exists would have got the job done the exact name isn't particularly important and we are going
to go ahead and use a wait.
We're going to await something so we should probably mark this as an async function.
Perfect.
Now we are going to be using Prisma exists so I should probably get access to that too.
I'm no longer going to need DBI so I can use Prisma instead.
Then right here we are going to await the promise that comes back from Prisma data exists dot user and
this time around we are searching for a user by their ID so I'll look for a user whose ID equals args
dot ID.
The argument that got passed in next up if there was no user were going to throw an error.
So if right here there is no user exists.
If that's false what are we going to do I will throw a new error and we're going to pick a good message.
I'll use the same one we had before.
User not found.
Excellent.
Now if there was a user found that means the code down below will actually run.
And in this case we just need to use the Prisma delete user mutation.
So right here I am going to return Prisma that mutation dot delete user.
And remember we have to pass in those arguments.
The first one is our operation arguments.
The second one is info.
Now for that first argument we need to search using whatever arguments are actually set up.
If you forget Remember you can always pull up the schema at localhost 4 4 6 6.
Down below we have all of our mutations we have delete user we can delete users by providing the where
argument.
Here we can delete them by ID or by email.
We're going to go ahead and delete them by ID so I provide where
I set that up as an object and I provide ID getting the ID from args dot ID.
Excellent.
And there we go.
This is actually all we have to do.
We are already returning the promise which means that the data that comes back will get sent back which
is good.
The node JSE graph Q L API will be able to send back the necessary data to the client whether its a
web site or a mobile application and the posts and comments are automatically going to get cleaned up
because we have the relation directive already configured to do that.
So we took what was much longer and more complex and made it much simpler or abstracting away a lot
of that complex logic to Prisma itself.
Now we can actually remove all of the commented out code down below and test our work.
I'm going to save mutation Dhananjay ass and try to delete one of our users.
I can get a user's idea a couple of different ways.
I'm just going to head into PGE admin and I'm going to pick one of my victims.
I'm going to delete victim number one right here I have his ID.
I'm going to copy that to the clipboard then I'm going to take that idea over to localhost 4000 and
I'm going to try to delete a user.
I'm going to swap out the ID of one with the value.
I just copied.
And for this deleted user.
I'll get back there.
Id their name their email but not their age since that no longer actually exists.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and fire this off and see what happens right here.
The Delete user operation did indeed work as expected.
Once again we can always verify that by going into the database and refreshing things we click that
lightning bolt.
And what do we get.
We can see that we now only have one victim which is perfect.
We are now able to create users and delete users with no J.S. acting as that intermediary.
We're going to end up doing this for all of our other mutations as well but for now this is a great
place to stop.
I'm going to delete all of the challenge comments up above.
Save the file and I'll see you in the next video where we continue working with our mutations.