In this video we're going to continue to refactor our mutations.
We've refactored a create mutation and delete mutation in this one.
We're going to turn our attention towards some of our update mutations which in the end of the day were
actually the most complex.
We had a lot of conditional logic to only update certain things if they were provided.
All of that is going to become completely unnecessary.
So we're going to be able to reduce the amount of code in these methods and we're gonna be able to reduce
the code complexity.
So let's go ahead and kick things off like we've kicked off all of our reef factors so far by commenting
out everything we have already.
We're going to leave this in place to make sure we don't forget to add any features back in like with
our other mutation methods.
I am going to tag this one as an async method and I'll also be accessing Prisma instead of accessing
the divi object where all of our arrays live to prove a point.
I'm actually going to structure this one slightly differently.
Instead of first verifying that the thing we're trying to change exists like we do right here when deleting
a user We're just going to get right down to business and pass everything along to Prisma allowing that
to do the checking for us.
So let's go ahead and see what that would look like right here.
We are actually going to start with a call to Prisma mutation and Dot update user.
And we're going to pass all of the necessary data in.
Now if you forget what that mutation takes you can always head over to localhost 4 4 6 6.
Right here we have our update user mutation.
We pass in data which is the data update and where.
Which is how we want to figure out which user to update for where we're going to provide the ID for
data.
We're going to provide the name and e-mail optional.
Just like they are for the actual Prisma mutation.
Now we can go ahead and actually knock this out.
Passing in the necessary arguments so we have our object.
We're going to set up a where as an object we want to search by id and we get the value from args dot
ID.
So we have that ID argument which we just explored in schema.
Dr. Kraft Well next up we have data.
Data can actually just come directly from args dot data.
Remember args dot data is an object with either name or email.
Right here we just explored that.
They're both completely optional.
We have the exact same requirement over here for data for the Prisma API so we can actually just pass
that data right through.
There's no need to look at it for any properties there's no need to make any changes to it.
The data that node j s expects is the same data that Prisma expects.
So the data can get passed through last up we are going to pass in the info argument to get all of the
data provided in the selection set.
So if I ask for the idea of the updated user I want to make sure the idea actually comes back.
The last thing to do is to return this promise.
We want to make sure that the color of the node.
J.S. API gets the data back.
They were expecting in this case they get back the data about the updated user with this in place were
actually done and we can save nutation.
Jay asked and test things out.
So I'm going to head over to local host 4000 and we are going to use the update user nutation.
Now I am going to kick things off by finding one of my existing users over here I have my users query
which I can fire off one more time.
I have Andrew I have Vickerman I have yes.
I'm going to go ahead and try to change Andrew's name from Andrew to just Andrew so right here I'll
grab his ID.
Now I can move over to the update user mutation.
I'm going to swap out the old ID with the new one.
And in this case we're not going to change anything about the age which no longer exists.
We're just going to change the name so data name and I am going to provide Andrew perfect down below
we have our selection set.
I don't want to grab anything related to the age since that no longer exists.
I'm just going to grab the id the name and the e-mail if I actually fire this off what happens.
We get our update operation successfully working.
And if I actually verify the database I can see that the data has indeed changed.
I'm going to click that lightning bolt and right here we can see the two was removed from the end of
Andrew which is awesome.
So in the end of the day we really can defer almost all responsibilities off to Prisma.
Now obviously if we change the ID to something like ABC at the end this is not going to match up with
a user.
And things are still going to fail they just fail in a way that's a bit less clear.
So here the message is no node found for the model user with value.
Then here's the ID when we actually used exist.
First we were able to customize that error message to something a little simpler like user not found
or e-mail.
Take a so in the end of the day it's really up to you to determine if you want to do a little verification
first or if you want to pass everything off to Prisma that means we can actually choose to remove our
exists check as well as the if statement from both delete user and from create user.
Now when I first show people a refactor like this their first thought is why are we writing a note app
again.
Why aren't we just using Prisma.
And remember the goal is to set up a node as that intermediary.
So when we do configure things like data validation sanitization an authentication node is going to
sit right there making sure that the clients for our applications can't just do anything to the database.
We want to restrict what someone can do based off of role's authentication and more.
With that said let's go ahead and delete all of the commented out code from Update user it is no longer
necessary.
And now we're going to go ahead and do the same thing for posts.
We have create post.
We have update posts and we have delete.
Post all of these are pretty substantial.
There's a lot of work going on in there.
And the good news is that with Prisma we're going to have almost nothing in any of these methods.
Now this is the point in the course where students often feel frustrated because we spent a whole bunch
of time working with graphs and arrays we wrote all of this code and now all of the code is ending up
getting removed.
It's important to remember that all of this code served a very valuable purpose early on in the class.
Its job was to get out of our way and allow us to focus on the basics of graphics well by working with
simple arrays and objects which we already knew about.
We were able to focus all of our actual learning on well itself.
Now that we understand how to structure a standard graphs you all application it makes sense to introduce
more complex tools like Prisma trying to use Prisma from the beginning would have made things almost
impossible to understand.
Remember the goal isn't to write the most cutting edge app right from the beginning.
The goal is to get to the most cutting edge by the end of the course and actually understand how and
why we picked the tools we picked.
Now it's your challenge.
We're going to go ahead and refactor create post update post and delete posts.
Let's head up to the top of the file and talk about what I would like you to do for this challenge in
particular it's going to be your goal to just worry about refactoring the Create post mutation to use
Prisma.
We're not going to worry about the other post related mutations yet.
We'll focus on those in future challenges one at a time.
So step one refactor create post mutation resolver to use Prisma instead of working with that array
data.
And when you're doing this don't worry about pub sub or anything related to subscriptions.
We are going to explore subscriptions shortly and how Prisma works with them.
And the good news is that Prisma handles almost all of that stuff internally which means that we don't
need to use pub sub dot publish anywhere inside of this file.
So while you're refactoring don't worry about replacing this code with anything you can actually just
remove it entirely.
So up above that brings us to step 2.
You're going to go ahead and test things out.
Create a new post at localhost 4000 from one of your users then verify it actually exists by looking
in the database.
So take some time to knock this one out.
I will move on to the other methods in future challenges.
Paused the video test your work and when you're done click play
how that go let's go ahead and kick things off down below by commenting out all of the code inside of
create post.
And remember this time around I'm not going to do any manual checking to see if the user exists first.
And we also don't need to do any manual publishing So it's going to be much simpler.
Exactly like we had up above.
Right now let's go ahead and start by destructuring not D-B and pub sub but Prisma the one thing that
we need from the context now we can go ahead and actually return a call to Prisma dot mutation dot create
post passing in the necessary data to actually create a post.
And if you forgot what's necessary you can always refer to the schema at 4 4 6 6.
That's localhost 4 4 6 6 for me right here I am going to pass in an operations argument object.
I'm also going to pass in info as that second argument and right here we're going to add a few things
into the mix.
If I head over to localhost 4 4 6 6 we can pull up the documentation for create post.
We know we need data.
We need Title body and published and we also need to know the author associated with that post.
We have all of that information already.
If we go over to schema Dom graft well and look at Create post we can see exactly what data we get with
Create post input.
Right here we have title body published and author.
So we're going to have to do a little bit of restructuring but nothing too bad right here to kick things
off.
Let's go ahead and set up a data we need to provide those three values right here we need.
Title title can come from args dot data dot title we also need a body which can come from args dot data
dot body.
And finally we also need published which can come from args dot data dot published.
Now we do still have args dot data dot author but that does not go right on this object.
Instead we define that author object we choose to connect it to an existing author and we are connecting
by IDs.
So this is where the idea ends up going right here.
Args dot data dot author.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can actually go through the process of testing things out.
We are all done.
There is no need to add any more functionality in ignoring the checking letting Prisma do that for us.
We are ignoring the publishing because that's no longer necessary.
Which means that we have all of the features set up.
Now I can go ahead and actually remove all of the commented out code and test things out.
I'm going to save mutation.
J S then over inside of localhost 4000.
I'm going to try to create a new post.
I am going to need a user ID for that.
If I go over to the user's tab I have a few different user IDs right here.
I'm going to create a post for Jess.
You could have used any one of your users and up here I do have that create post nutation so it takes
in the data title body published and author title.
My new post.
I'll change that to stories by Jess I'll leave the body as just dot dot dot.
I'll leave this one as published and the author ID is the author ID.
I just copied.
Excellent.
Now down below we have our selection set asking for all of those scalar values.
I can also choose to grab other things like the authors ID and the author's name.
That would be perfectly fine as well.
Now we can go ahead and create the post by firing that off.
And what do we get.
We get back exactly what we might have expected.
We have all of the information about the post that was created and we also have some information about
that post's author which is perfect.
If I had over two PGE admin I can actually move on to Step Two and verify that the data actually exists
in the database so I have my data sitting right here.
But it looks like I lost my place on the sidebar.
Let me go ahead and find my database once again it's sitting right here.
We are looking for a particular post that should have been created so I'm going to view the data in
the host's table.
I'm going to view all roads and I should have my new post showing up right here.
I do indeed have that I have the title of stories by Jess.
I have dot dot dot for body and the published value of true which is fantastic.
So there we go.
That is all you needed to do for the Create post mutation challenge.
Now that we're done with this we can go ahead and remove the challenge comments.
Up above for that one and save the file.
That's where we're going to stop for this video we obviously still need to refactor update post and
delete posts.
We're going to get to that in the next video.
Let's go ahead and jump right into that.