In this video there are two big picture goals one refactor and delete posts and to refactor update post
you're going to end up doing both of them as challenges but we'll split that up into two challenges
to keep things a bit more organized.
So right here.
Challenge number 1.
Refactor the delete post mutation to use Prisma.
So you're going to re factor the resolver method to use Prisma instead of the array data.
And once again there is no need to do anything related to pub sub or subscriptions.
And when you're done just go ahead and test that mutation.
You should be able to delete posts directly from a local host 4000.
So to solve this one all you got to do is change the code in this method right here take some time to
knock that one out.
I'll scroll us back up so you can view the steps to get this one done.
Pause the video.
Test your work when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
Should have been pretty straight forward.
Let's go ahead and take this process off down below by refactoring delete post.
I'm going to kick things off by commenting out all of the code we have in here so far and swapping out
D.B and pub sub for Prisma.
Excellent.
Next up we can go ahead and return what comes back from calling Prisma dot nutation dot delete post
right here.
We are going to go ahead and delete a post by its ID.
Now we call it with those two arguments we have are operation args and we have info as the second argument
and we know that to delete a post using Prisma we provide the adware argument.
This is an object and in the case of our posts the only thing that makes a post unique is its ID.
So we are going to delete by id getting the value from args ID which is the argument we were previously
using and there we go.
That is all we need to do to get this to work.
Down below I can remove all of the commented out code we can save the file and we can actually test
things out.
So I'm going to grab the ID of one of my posts and delete it over inside of PGE admin.
I have to post IDs sitting right here.
I'm going to delete the one we created in the last video.
These stories by Jess.
I'll groud that ID and this is what I am going to bring over to localhost 4000.
From here we can scroll over to the delete post mutation and we can fire this one off right here.
I am going to delete not the post with the ID of 12 but the post with the ID of the value I just copied
from PGE admin.
Now for this one I am going to fire that off and see what we get back.
What do we get back.
We get back all of the correct information and we can always verify that things actually worked as expected
by refreshing the data in admin right here.
I'm going to click that lightning bolt and we can indeed see that that second post was removed which
is fantastic.
Now that we have delete posts working as expected we're going to move on to our last post based mutation
update post.
So let's talk about exactly what I'd like you to do for that.
Once again we can scroll up and I am going to swap out these challenge comments for a different set
of comments.
Here they are.
It's the same process as last time just for a different method.
I wanted to break it up into two challenges so we could test our work as we refactored.
As opposed to making a bunch of changes to our code then testing things out.
So once again the goal refactor the update post mutation to use Prisma.
You're going to refactor the actual method.
Ignoring anything related to pub sub or subscriptions.
Then you're going to test things out at localhost 4000.
So exactly like what you did last time.
Now if we scroll down the update post mutation I believe is one of the longest mutations that we actually
created when we worked with arrays.
That's because there are all sorts of different ways that the data could be published.
Sometimes when we're updating a post to the outside world it seems like it's deleted.
If we were to unpublished it sometimes it seems like it's created if we were to change its published
status from false to true.
We don't have to worry about any of that.
All we have to worry about is calling our mutation method and passing in the correct information.
So take some time to knock that out and test your work when you're done come back and click play.
How that go.
Hopefully you didn't run into any trouble with that factor.
Down below we have our update post nutation.
I'm going to comment out every single line of code.
It is by far one of the longer mutation methods we had and we're going to swap out D-B and pub sub for
Prisma and on Prisma we are going to access the one nutation we need that is Prisma dot mutation dot
right here.
Update post perfect.
But remember there are two operation arguments we have to provide.
We provide where to determine which post we actually want to update and we provide data which contains
the data we actually want to change.
So for where we are searching by id I'm going to look by id and we have an argument for that.
We have args dot ID exactly what we were destructuring previously.
Now the other argument we need to provide is data and data already exists on args dot data so we can
pass that through directly.
Awesome.
Now that we have this in place we can go ahead and provide info as the second argument and we will set
up a return statement up front to make sure that all the data that's actually returned gets sent back
to the client inside of graft UL playground.
Perfect.
Now if we scroll down we've handled everything.
The checking whether or not a post exists is done automatically is no longer necessary to look at each
field because we can just pass them all through to Prisma and it's not necessary to use pub subduct
publish since Prisma handles all of that for us.
Let's go ahead and delete all of the comments down below and actually test things out.
I'm going to save nutation dot J S and I'm going to update one of my posts.
Now I only have a single post in the database.
I have this Prisma post.
I am going to grab that ID and this is the one that we're going to end up changing.
Never remember when it comes to what are new.
J.S. Grafix UL API accepts we can always refer to schema.
Graft well down below.
We should have update post input and we do.
We can provide any one of these.
We could provide none one or all three.
Let's go ahead and actually get that done over in localhost four thousand.
We have our update post mutation.
I am going to paste that ID in and if I remember correctly this post was unpublished.
I'm going to go ahead and publish it.
So right here I am not going to change the title.
I'm just going to change the published status setting the value to true.
Excellent.
Now if I go ahead and actually fire this off what do we get back.
We get back everything that we had previously except published which has indeed changed and if I were
to refresh PGE admin I would hope to see the change there as well.
And that is exactly what we end up getting.
Perfect.
So in this example with the update post mutation we went from maybe 40 lines of code to sitting just
around 7.
So this is a huge upgrade.
Not just in the amount of lines but also in the complexity of those lines.
Everything here is very simple very straightforward and we defer all the complexity to Prisma itself.
Now that we have this in place we can remove the challenge comments up above and that really just leaves
our comment mutations.
Now if you remember a while back we actually made a change to the data model inside of Prisma.
If you remember I had forgotten to add comments on to both user and post.
Now when we did that it wasn't a big deal but when we actually integrate with Prisma bindings we need
to make sure that the Prisma app is not just deployed but that our generated file is also refreshed
when ever Prisma is deployed.
So to fix this a little quirk all we have to do is refresh the generated file.
We can do that by running our script.
I'm going to use control C to shut down the terminal and if you remember in package Jason we set up
and get schema.
We're going to go ahead and run that one more time.
So right here NPM run to run a script.
The script itself is get schema and if we actually fire this off we should see a success message printing
in just a second right here.
Project Prisma schema file was updated and then it provides the path to it.
Now we can restart our application and we can actually use the Prisma bindings related to the comments.
So Dambulla we're just going to move through this process together.
We've already done plenty of challenges for refactoring our mutations.
If you feel that you would like a bit more practice feel free to pause the video now and refactor all
three.
Comment based mutations.
Otherwise we're going to move through this process together.
Step one is to swap out D-B and pub sub for Prisma and step two is to remove have everything we have
so far since we are just creating a comment now when we create a comment we do have to associate it
with a particular user and a particular post.
So let's get that done.
I'm going to return whatever comes back from calling Prisma dot mutation dot create comment.
And for this one we have to provide all of the necessary data to provide the text.
I have to link it to the correct post.
And I have linked it to the correct author right here.
Before I do any of that I will just pass in info as the second argument.
Now we can set up the args for the mutation itself.
If you forget what those are you can always refer to the schema documentation.
Over here we have the mutation down below for creating a comment.
We have to provide our data argument.
We provide text and we link author and post.
So let's get that done.
Now when it comes to what data we have access to we can always refer to our schema to figure that out.
We have our create comment input right.
Here we get access to text author and post.
Let's put all of that into practice right here.
We set up data on there we provide text text gets its value from args dot data dot text.
That is exactly what we just explored.
Next up we are going to set up either author or post.
Either way works.
I'm going to go ahead and start with author we are going to connect it to an existing author.
So I will provide connect.
And in this case we are going to connect by ID so I'll provide their ID args Daten data.
Arthur is exactly what we just saw over in schema graphics.
Well the last property we are going to provide on this data object is post we have to link it to an
existing post connect by id and we have that idea as well.
Args dot data dot post.
Awesome.
Now we're all done and we can actually go ahead and test things out.
I'm going to save the file to save my changes to create comment and I'm going to create a comment for
a specific author in a specific post over inside of local host 4000.
Let's start by getting an author and post ID.
I can use the user's query to do that.
And that's already asking for all users and all of their posts.
And if I run the operation we get updated data.
I'm going to go ahead and leave a comment on the only post I have and I will say that this user is the
one who is going to leave the comments so I'll start by copying the author ID to the clipboard and I'll
bring that over to create comment right here.
I'm going to paste that in.
Then I'll go back over to the user's tab just to grab that post ID.
I'm going to copy that and bring that over to create comment as well.
We can pick whatever comment text we like.
I'm going to use something like this should be in Prisma.
Perfect.
Now we can go ahead and actually fire this off and see what happens if I send this off.
What do we get.
We get our created comment back which is perfect.
And once again we can always verify that by checking the database.
That brings us to our other two mutation methods.
I'm going to go ahead and refactor update comment first so I can update the comment that I just created.
Now we have a whole bunch of code inside of here which we can go ahead and remove and we can just grab
Prisma and from there we're going to use the update comment mutations.
I will return right here.
Prisma adopt mutation dot update comment and we are going to pass in everything necessary.
We have our operation arguments and we have the info argument getting passed in as the second argument
and right here we're going to set up what's necessary.
We have to provide where and data.
So where is the comment.
We are trying to update what we are going to find it by ID and I have that via our exact ID.
Once again we can always refer to schema graphic.
Well to refresh our memories we have up above the mutation for updating a comment.
We get the ID and we get our data.
We have already used our exact ID down below.
We're going to set data equal to args dot data.
Perfect.
Now we can test this one out as well.
Let's update the text for the comment that we just created.
I'm going to go ahead and grab that comments ID which is showing up in the output over here.
Now I'm going to scroll over to the update comment tab pasting that ID in and I can leave the same text.
Actually let's go ahead and switch it up.
I will use new text for comment.
Excellent.
I'm going to fire this one often what do we get back.
We get back the same idea we had before and we get back our new text value.
That leaves just one final mutation then we are done.
All of this refactoring that is delete comment.
So once again all we need is Prisma.
Down below we can remove everything we have so far and we are going to go ahead and return Prisma does
mutation dot delete comment passing in our operation arguments as the first argument and info as the
second.
Now we have to delete a comment by its ID.
So we provide where for that we then provide the ID and we have args dot ID exactly what we had before.
And remember we can refer to the documentation for either Prisma to figure out what goes here or we
can refer to schema graphics ul to figure out what level on args.
Now that we have this in place let's test things out.
I'm going to save the file and over inside of our application I'm going to start by fetching all comments.
So right here I fire that off and I have my two comments showing up.
I'm going to delete this comment the one that we just created and then update it I'll scroll over to
the mutation tab for delete comment after copying that ID to the clipboard and right here I am going
to paste that in.
I'm going to fire that off.
It appears to have gotten removed.
I can always verify that by rerunning that comments query once again and there we go.
It is indeed gone.
Now we have all of our mutations refactored to use Prisma which is a fantastic step in the right direction
with no J.S. serving as the middleware of sorts between the two.
We're now ready to look at more advanced stuff in the next video we are going to talk about subscriptions.
Then we're going to start jumping in to authentication.
I am beyond excited to continue on.
Thanks for bearing with me through this video.
There is just a lot of stuff to refactor and I didn't want to make it all challenges and spread it out
too long.
So a sort of a Choose Your Own Adventure.
Maybe you actually used those comments related methods for challenges or maybe you just followed along.
Either way is fine.
All right.
Enough of that.
Assia in the next one.