In this video you're going to turn your attention towards working with subscriptions.
Now the good news here is that Prisma has built in support for subscriptions and the set up process
is way easier than what we had before where we had a bunch of pub sub dot publish calls throughout our
code with Prisma.
All of that happens behind the scenes.
So out of all of the files in the resolvers directory the only one we haven't touched in this section
is subscription dot J S and this is where we're going to be making our changes for this video before
we make any changes to this file.
I do want to head over to localhost 4 4 6 6 and mess around with what Prisma actually gives us.
So over here we have our schema and if we scroll down to the bottom what do we get.
We get three subscriptions.
We have one for each type defined over inside of Prisma forward slash data model digraphs ul.
So once again this file is what is auto generating the entire API including our three subscriptions.
Now we're going to start by making some changes to the comment subscription and we'll focus on post
afterwards if I want to subscribe to comments.
I am going to use the comment subscription that Prisma gives us.
So once again no genius is just serving as the middleman between the clients whether they're browsers
or iPhone apps and the database.
So in this case what are we going to do.
We're going to use that for a property on Prisma.
We have not used yet.
Now if I actually click the comment subscription we can see that we can indeed pass in a ware argument
that would allow us to for example subscribe to comments by a particular author or comments on a particular
post.
We also get some data back.
We get quite a few fields back.
Notably we get the nutation type is something being created updated or deleted.
And we also get the new data via the node field.
In this case we are getting the comment data back Dambulla we have updated fields so we can see what
exactly changed.
And we have previous values.
So lets go ahead and actually mess around with this by making some changes to subscription dot.
J.S. Right here what I'm going to do as you might have expected I'm going to comment out everything
we have so far I'm going to remove D-B and pub sub.
All we need is Prisma.
Right here we are then going to return something we are going to return what comes back from calling
Prisma data subscription.
The fourth property we haven't used yet Don.
And then right here we list out which one we want we can list out either user post or comment.
In this case datt comment.
Excellent.
Now like all of our query methods and all of our mutation methods we pass in those two arguments I can
choose to pass in nothing for my operation arguments since we can clearly see from the schema that where
is totally optional and I am going to pass in info as the second argument something we are always going
to do.
And there we go.
We now have a comment based subscription.
All set up at no point in our code do we need to use anything like pub subduct publish Prisma already
knows when the database is changing because its code is in charge of changing it.
So it's very easy for Prisma to actually manage this subscription allowing us to reduce the complexity
of our code which as you might have noticed is a theme for this section.
Now obviously Prisma comes with its own complexity it's something we have to learn and integrate but
it is well worth the cost.
Especially in the long term as our apps get more complex now it's not time to run our subscription just
yet.
Currently it's actually pretty useless and to talk about why it's useless.
I just want to write a quick comment and you can actually just sit back and watch this part.
There is no need to write this comment out.
I'll be deleting it shortly.
So when data flows in our application it flows from Prisma to node then from node to the client.
And we've seen this work really well with our queries and our mutations Serat here the data starts at
Prisma will use an arrow to represent the fact that it gets sent to node then node sends it off to the
client which is currently just an instance of graft UL playground.
So this is something we've already seen so far.
Now the same process is going to happen with our subscriptions.
The problem though is that the data that Prisma is sending node currently does not align with the data
that node is sending the client.
And that means we're actually going to lose data as data flows through the application.
Let's illustrate this by looking at our application schemas over in the browser we have localhost 4
4 6 6 and we have our comment subscription definition.
There are four fields that come back.
We get mutation we get node we get updated fields and we get previous values.
If we go over to localhost 4000 we see what the node API actually sends the client.
If I crack this one open going down to the comments subscription we can see there's only two fields
we have nutation and data.
So if Prisma sends all of these fields to node but node only sends these fields to the client then all
of the data is getting to the client.
First off there actually is no data field even coming back from Prisma.
So things would fail.
We're saying that data is required.
We've made that non-global.
But Prisma actually doesn't send back a data field.
So currently no J.S. really can't serve as the middleman.
It's actually not a good middleman.
What we need to do is align the type definition here a bit closer with the type definition over here.
Currently the only data that would successfully make it all the way to the client is the mutation field
because it is sent between node and the client and it is sent between Prisma and node.
So to fix this all we're going to do is make a single one line change in schema graft Well all the way
at the bottom of our file we have our comment subscription payload type.
Here we have the mutation field and we have the data field.
All we're going to do is change the name of data to align it with what Prisma is already sending node
and it's calling it node.
Now I know that's a bit confusing.
Prisma is sending the data to node j.
S. the field it's sending is called node and this is what represents the data.
So in the case of a comment subscription This is where we would get the comment that was created or
the comment that was updated or the comment that was deleted.
Now you'll notice that with the Prisma definition we have node as a nullable type comment.
We're going to do the same thing over here to align those up correctly.
And there we go.
Now our subscription is actually going to be useful.
We're not going to be able to get a hold of updated fields or previous values but that's okay.
We are going to be able to access what we need to access.
Mutation and node.
Let's go ahead and actually test things out.
I'm going to save schema dot graph.
Well over in subscription.
Jay ass I'm going to remove the comments that I used to illustrate why we had to make that change.
And I'm going to save this file as well.
Let's go ahead and test things out for this one I am going to be interacting with our public facing
no JSA API that is local host 4000 and we have our subscriptions all the way over on the right.
We're going to do is subscribe to comment the one we've actually configured.
Now yes comment does take a post ID.
And currently we're doing nothing with that.
We'll adjust that in just a few seconds.
For now though all we have to do is update the operation down below.
There is no longer a data field that is now called node.
There we go.
We can actually start the process of listening and we should get notified when data either gets created
updated or deleted.
So let's go ahead and actually interact with some data.
We are going to start by creating a new comment.
So we have create comment over here and I already have a valid author ID and a valid post ID from the
last video.
I got these from my user's query.
So there's no need to add them in again.
I'm going to change the text to make things unique.
This is a Prisma based subscription.
Perfect.
Now we go ahead and fire this off.
We can see the comment was created and if I go all the way back over to that subscription tab I can
indeed see my comment right here.
We have our mutation value of created and we have all of the data that we asked for about the newly
created comment.
We would also see an event fire if we were to update or delete a comment.
So I am going to do just that.
I'm going to head back over to create comment to get the ID for the comment that we just created and
I'm going to update it.
So I'll head over to update comment.
I'll put the idea in there and I will change the text to updated sub comment.
Now if I go ahead and actually run this I can see that things have changed.
And if I go back over to the subscription tag I can see that we have an updated status report.
So the comment was created then it was updated.
Finally we can also track when a comment is deleted.
I'm going to delete a comment I already have the ID in the clipboard so I'll just paste it right in.
I fire that operation off head back over to the subscription tab and right here we can see information
about the deleted comment.
Now you can see that we are getting null for node and this is why it was important that node was non
nullable when you are deleting a comment.
There's nothing to return so null is what ends up getting sent back.
Now all of this was possible without us adding any code to our mutations.
All we did was we added this one line right here to wire things up.
Now I want to take the post I'd be into account making sure that we can subscribe to just comments for
a particular post before we do.
Let's go ahead and remove all of the commented out code we have so far and we are going to provide operation
arguments.
So we're going to pass some operation arguments to Prisma right here.
But set that object up and as we explored in the beginning of the video there is only a single argument
we can provide.
It is where it's an object.
On here we determine what criteria we want to use to determine what comments we want to subscribe to.
As always we can refer to the schema tab at localhost 4 4 6 6 to see what our options are.
Right here we have the where argument and there are quite a few options.
Now a lot of these aren't related to anything specific about the comment itself.
For example mutation in allows us to subscribe to just created mutations or just delete it so we can
be specific.
We can also subscribe to changes where a certain field changed.
Now in our case we want to use node.
I want to subscribe to comments where we specify something about that comment.
Now right here we have all of these standard items I could use something like.
Id contains.
I could use text.
I could use text contains things we've seen plenty of times before.
We actually don't care about what the comment data is at all.
What we care about is the post for the comment.
Does that post ID align with the ID that got passed in.
So down below we actually have a field for that.
We can do something with the Post sitting right here and then we have all of the same fields over again.
So in this case we're going to use post ID to look at that posts ID.
So right here in this object we are looking at the node on the node we want to look at the post and
for the post I want to make sure the ID is equal to the post ID value that got passed in.
So in the end of the day this is the exact object that is going to allow us to subscribe to comments
for a specific post.
Let's go ahead and test things out.
I'm going to take us back over to localhost 4000 and we're gonna run the same subscription.
We're trying to subscribe to comments for a post where you post.
ID is 10 that no longer exists in our application since we're using real random generated IDs so I would
expect to never ever see an event.
Right here we are listening.
I'm going to create a comment much like I did before this time around though I shouldn't see any event
actually occur.
I'm going to create a comment I'm going to go back over to that subscription tab and right here we have
nothing which is great.
Now let's go ahead and run the subscription again but use a valid post ID.
So over in the create comment tab.
I have the post ID.
I'm going to copy that to the clipboard.
Bring that over to the subscription tab and test things out.
I'm going to paste it in.
I'm going to start up that subscription now once again we're just going to create a comment some and
go back over to the Create comment tab.
I'm going to click down play button and hopefully this time around.
We do get a notification right here in the comments tab that is exactly what we have.
So we didn't get notified about comments for other posts.
We did get notified about comments for the post where subscribing to and this is fantastic.
Now that we have this in place for the comment subscription it is your job to do the exact same thing
for the post subscription.
There are a few steps for getting this done so let's go ahead and talk about exactly what I'd like you
to do.
Right here the big picture goal is to set up the post subscription to work with Prisma.
So step 1 we have to update schema graphics.
Well we want to make sure to use knode as a nullable field instead of data for posts.
So we're going to make the same change to the post subscription payload that we ended up making to the
comment subscription payload to make sure they align.
Now that brings us to step 2 you're actually going to update the subscribe method down below to use
the correct Prisma method.
And when you're doing that you're also going to use the where arguments.
I want you to limit the subscription to just posts that are actually published.
So here are limiting the comments to comments where the Post has a particular ID down below.
You want to limit the posts to posts that have a specific value for that published field and once again
you need to go over to localhost for 4 6 6.
Dig into that schema tab and figure out what you need to actually set up to get that done.
That brings you to step 3.
Test your work.
Start that subscription.
Create one post that's published you should see a notification.
Create a nother post that's unpublished and you shouldn't be notified.
All right take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Don't forget to test your work when you're done come back and click play.
Now you do.
That was a tricky one but let's go ahead and work through it together.
First up step one over in schema graphic.
Well we want to align what node sounds the client with what Prisma sends node.
I'm going to swap out the data field for node and I am going to make this nullable by removing that
exclamation mark we can save the file and there we go.
Step one done step to update the subscribe method down below to use the correct Prisma method that is
going to be us returning Prisma which currently is not in scope.
I have to grab that in on Prisma.
We're going to be using dot subscription like we did above.
Dot right here post passing in an options object so we do want to pass in those arguments.
Now down below before we worry about setting up the where argument I will just pass info in as that
second argument.
Now it's going to be our job to set up where correctly.
The goal is to limit us to just subscribing to posts that are indeed published so we can always dig
into the documentation to figure out how to get that done over in local host for 4 6 6.
We have our subscription to posts.
We have our where argument and what we want is Noad.
So with Noad we can assert things about the post itself related to the ID related to the title the body
or in our case related to published so we can check if it is or is not a specific value.
In this case we're going to make sure it is true.
So right here I will be setting up node then I'll be setting up published setting that equal to true.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place that's it for step 2 let's remove those comments up above.
Save the file and actually test our work so I'm going to bring things over to local host 4000 and make
sure the subscription works as expected over here I am going to start up the post subscription.
Over here we do have to make that one change.
We have to swap out data for node.
It is going to be invalid.
But once we refresh the schema it will become valid once again.
Now we can start this process and it is going to listen for changes.
All we have to do now is actually interact with posts in some way to make sure things work as expected.
I'm going to be creating a post one that's published one that's unpublished.
I'll create the post for that first user.
This is Andrew.
I'm going to grab his ID and I'm going to go over to the Create post mutation right here I'll swap out
the IDs.
And in this case we have stories by Jess.
I'm going to change that to stories by Andrew.
I can leave body as Dot dot dot and for this one I will have this be the published post.
So this is the one I would expected to get notified about if I go ahead and fire this off.
We can see the post was created.
And if I go all the way back over to that subscription tag I do indeed have a notification stories by
Andrew is showing up which is great.
Next up we're going to create another post.
I'm going to go ahead and call this one.
Secret stories by Andrew.
And I'm going to leave the published value as false if I fire this off that should indeed be creating
the data.
But any subscriber shouldn't have been notified.
If I go back over here you can see there is nothing related to secret stories by Andrew.
The last notification we have is for that first post were created.
So there we go.
Challenge.
All done.
We now have our two subscriptions set up and in both cases we are able to customize exactly what data
comes back up above.
We are returning just comments from a particular post and down below.
We are returning just posts that are published.
That's where we're going to start for this one.
I'm excited to continue on with this section.
So stay tuned and I'll see you in the next one.