So far we spent this section putting no yes right between our client and the Prisma graphical API.
So we have our server sitting in the middle and this is going to be useful because once again it's going
to allow us to authenticate and validate requests before actually reading and writing from the database
so we can use the node server to check if someone has permission to read or write some data before the
operation is actually performed.
Now the problem with our current set up is that this is not enforceable because the client can just
directly communicate with Prisma.
We can for example go to localhost 4 4 6 6 and mess with the database.
All we want there is no need to go through our node J.S. graphical API.
So what we need to do is cut off this channel for the client and force the client to use this channel
so we want to force the client to pass all requests through node and that's what we're going to end
up doing to do this.
We set up what's known as a Prisma secret and then the end of the day it's nothing more than a password.
You need that password in order to communicate with Prisma.
So we're going to set that password up on our node back end and the Prisma back end.
So in Prisma says What's the secret node will be able to respond correctly.
We're not going to give anyone else that information so any client out there won't know the secret and
it won't be able to communicate directly with Prisma it will have to go through node j.
S. So in the end of the day yes.
Any client in the world would be able to interact with our node.
JS API.
But that's OK because we are going to authenticate and validate those requests before we ever touch
the database.
So this is the strategy that we're going to use to lock down our data.
Let's go ahead and actually implement it back inside the Visual Studio code we can do this by first
closing all of our open editors and cracking open just two files on the Prisma side of things.
We're going to open up Prisma Dajuan now on the No.
J S side of things we're going to open up Prisma dot J S.
So we're going to configure a secret over here and to make sure that our connection from node is still
works.
We're going to add the same secret onto this options object we pass into our constructor per Prisma
binding.
So let's go ahead and get that done over here and Prisma ADOT why M-L we're going to set up a new property
secret.
And the name here is important.
And then we pick a value we can pick whatever value we like.
I'm going to go ahead and use something like this is my super secret text.
Perfect.
You can use any string value you like.
You can also use a password generator to generate something stronger and later on in the class you will
learn how to pull this value out of the code and use it in an environment variable instead.
But for now we do have our secret configured.
We can go ahead and save this file and redeploy Prisma.
So I'm going to shut down gnomon from graphics.
Well Prisma.
I'm going to change directories into the Prisma folder and once again we are going to use Prisma deploy
now once we run this.
We will actually have completely locked down Prisma and anyone who wants to communicate with it is going
to need to provide a password and we can prove this by trying to communicate with it without providing
that password.
So I'm going to use C.D dot dot to go back to our project route and NPM start to start up that application
once again.
Now if we head over to graft UL playground we could try to make a request for example I can go all the
way over to the left and make a user's query to the node.
J.S. graphical API when I do that what happens we can see we get an error your token is invalid.
It might have expired or you might be using a token from a different project.
So here it's letting us know that we could not connect and we're going to see the exact same thing if
we try to connect directly to Prisma.
So over here I'm connecting directly to Prisma using localhost 4 4 6 6.
If I tried to perform any operation we're going to get the exact same thing.
Now obviously we do still want to be able to communicate with Prisma but on our terms just the No.
Yes.
So let's go ahead and actually get that done by providing this same secret in Prisma J S on the object
we pass to the Prisma constructor function.
We need to provide a property called secret whose string value matches up with the secret we picked
over here.
I have this is my super secret text.
I'm going to add the exact same thing over here.
This is my super secret text.
Now we are going to be able to communicate with Prisma via No J ass.
I'm going to save the file and we're going to test things out once again.
First I will try localhost 4 4 6 6.
This should still fail and it does great and I'm going to try.
No James.
This should now work.
I fire things off and it does indeed work.
So there we have it.
We now have a way to force all communication to go through node j.
S and this is useful because once again we're going to be setting up things like authentication and
validation.
We want to force all requests to pass through node.
Now given our current setup it's impossible to use local host for 4 6 6 and there are still plenty of
reasons we might want to do that for development.
Maybe we add a new model or some new fields and we want to explore them over in the Prisma API before
we try to integrate them into node.
So it might still be useful to be able to interact with Prisma using localhost for 4 6 6 and we can
do so securely by providing an authorization token and this is done by setting up an H TTP Hetter.
So down below we have an HTP Hatter's area and this is nothing more than a little bit of Jason.
So we provide an object that we have key value pairs.
We have the header name and then we have the header value.
We can set up an authorization barer token it to get all of this to work securely.
So right here is the key for the header is authorization it the value is barer space followed by a token.
Now the token that we have to provide is not our secret.
It's actually a token that Prisma can generate for us and we generate it by running a single command.
So once again I am going to shut down our server.
I'm going to C.D into Prisma and all I'm going to do is run it Prisma space tokin Prisma token is going
to generate an authorization token that we can use for standard HTP requests.
It's something that can be put inside of a header allowing us to authenticate that we do have access
to the API.
If I run this command it is going to spit out a token.
We're going to copy that value to the clipboard.
So right here I have my really long token value.
Make sure to grab all of it as it might spread out to two or more lines and then I'm going to do is
take it over to graft and playground and paste it right here.
After a space.
So there needs to be a space between the word bearer and your token value.
Now if we fire off the request we're going to see that this time around it succeeds.
So given our configuration we can now securely access Prisma from node j asked by providing the secret
here and we can still use graphical playground by setting up an authorization token.
So at this point Prisma is secure no one who doesn't have access to the secret is going to be able to
access our project.
And that's a good thing.
We're forcing all requests to go through node with this in place.
It is time to continue on with this section and get into the meat of the section which is authentication
in the next video we're going to start working on this process which I am super excited to get to.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.