In the last video you set up a Prisma secret that closed down this back channel between the client and
Prisma forcing the client to go through no.
J.S. in order to read and write from the database which is a good thing.
In this video we're going to focus on how exactly we can authenticate a client's requests after we go
through this quick visualization.
We'll be focusing on our Sign-Up request.
Currently there is a way to create a user Yes but we're not doing anything special related to a password.
There's actually no password field.
So we're going to incorporate that and we're going to get everything up and running.
So let's run through a quick example and for example we're just going to stick with plain English.
So right here the client might want to perform an operation like editing a post.
I'd like to edit the post with the idea of a 9 and end.
Now this request is going to get sent off to node j s and no J S is going to respond correctly.
Now if we're not authenticated we're going to be locking down almost all operations.
The only thing you'll be able to do if you're not authenticated is read published posts.
You won't be able to read your drafts because we don't know who you are and you won't be able to create
update or delete anything.
Now in the end of the day the node server is going to say you have to log in to do that.
So we'll move on to the log in stage.
The client will actually go ahead and log in passing in an e-mail and a password.
Let's say for example that the account already exists.
So the client is providing those credentials.
It's going to send them off to no.
J ass and no jackass is going to verify that they actually exist in the database so we're going to make
sure there is a user with that e-mail end with that password.
Now in this case if it does find a user it's going to say I found your account.
Here is an authentication token.
So Noad is going to create an auth token and send that back to the client.
The client can then use this token to make requests that require authentication.
For example editing a post.
So now that our client actually has the token it can send that with future requests so we can actually
replay the request from before that originally fell.
I like to edit the post with the idea of a 9 am n.
Here is my auth token proving it's my post.
Now Knode can get that off tokin it can verify that it actually belongs to the user who is the creator
of the post that's being edited.
And if it is a match it can go ahead and perform that operation.
So we can say something like perfect.
I verified you in the post and I've updated the post.
And that's exactly what we were hoping to happen.
So this is a quick look at the authentication mechanism that we're going to be using the client is going
to get a token from the server the client then uses that token when it makes other requests other requests
that require authentication.
All right.
That is it for this quick visualization.
I just wanted to give us an overview of exactly what we're going to be setting up.
Let's go ahead and move into the editor and actually get this process started.
The first thing we're going to end up doing is adding a new field for the user.
We're going to store a user's password alongside their name and email.
Now we're not going to be storing it in plain text so if your password is password 1 2 3 we're not going
to be storing password 1 2 3.
We'll be using a hashing algorithm which we'll be talking about shortly.
So after email or before or wherever we're going to set up password in data model Dom graft Well I'm
going to set it up as a non nullable string.
Awesome.
Now in this case we're also going to do the exact same thing in schema graph.
Well so let's save this file head over to schema graph QOL and add a password for the user type there
as well down below.
We have our types I have name I have e-mail.
I'm going to add password into the mix.
Setting this up to be a non nullable string too.
So now we have the password field inside of schema UL and data model engraft.
Well what I want to take a moment to do is actually wipe our database then redeploy to add this new
field to post grass.
Now why are we deleting the data.
Well once again we've just added this new non nullable field and short from adding a password for each
of our existing users.
There's no way to deploy this new data model without deleting our existing data.
Now there's a shortcut way to get this done.
Down below we can run a command from the Prisma directory.
So make sure you are in the Prisma directory.
We can run Prisma delete.
That's going to delete the default service.
So it is going to wipe all of our data.
We can't type yes we do indeed want to delete it.
It's going to remove it.
Then we can redeploy it by using Prisma deploy like we've done plenty of times before.
So there we go once this is done we will have our database with a password field for each and every
user.
Now there's one more thing we have to do before we really dive into any more code.
We've made a change to data model accom graft UL which means we need to grab a new generated file then
do that.
We can use CD dot dot to go to the graph.
Well Prisma directory and we're going to run that one script we had set up over here that was get schema.
Now the problem here is that by setting up the Prisma secret we've actually locked out this command
from being able to do its job correctly.
If we were to run it it would actually fail.
So down below we can go ahead and do just that.
NPM run get schema.
This is going to try to fetch a new schema.
It's going to then replace the current generated Prisma graphed file.
While it would do that if it worked correctly but as we can see we get an error and if we scroll up
to the top of the output your token is invalid.
Now there are a couple different ways we can overcome this problem.
We could add a whole bunch of arguments onto this command but that gets nasty and ugly providing a token
here.
Well we're going to do instead is make a small tweak to dot graph Cuil config.
Currently the command is failing because the only way I can actually access that schema is by end point
and we've locked down that end point for that one script specifically though we're going to provide
an alternative where we're going to be able to run and get schema without providing a secret.
Now the only reason this is going to work is because we have the Prisma directory right in the same
project.
So we're just going to point get schema right towards these files so it can get the new schema without
needing to go to localhost 4 4 6 6 which is locked down.
So over here what are we going to do all we're going to do is add a single property onto the extensions
object.
This one is going to be called Prisma and all we're going to do is directed towards our Prisma.
That's why M-L file the one in our Prisma directory.
So for us what would that be.
It would be Prisma the Prisma folder.
Forward slash Prisma dot wya now.
Perfect.
Now we still have that locked down End Point.
Making sure that the client can't directly interact with our Prisma graphed API.
But we've provided an alternative for our local development tools allowing us to keep the script exactly
the same.
So by adding that single property and saving the file I should be able to rerun our get schema script
and this time it should work as expected down below.
We can see that our schema file was updated which is fantastic.
Now the next thing we're going to tackle is to actually make some changes to node j s.
So I'm going to close all of our open files and the file that we're concerned with is mutation dot J
as we are going to be updating create user.
Now in this case we're going to perform some validation and we also want to hash that password we don't
want to store plain text passwords.
So there is going to be a little bit of work to add inside of here and I'm actually gonna save that
for the next video.
I don't want these videos to get too long.
So what have we done in this one.
We've just set up support for that password field both on Prisma and in node j s.
We've added that to the user type in the next one we're actually going to make use of it by changing
our application code.
I'm excited to get to that.
So stay tuned and I'll see you in the next one.