In this video as promised we're going to be modifying the create user mutation.
We're going to set this up to actually take a password in and we're going to be doing a few things with
that password.
So let's create a rough outline of what we're going to try to accomplish.
We are going to take in password then we are going to validate the password so we can validate that
it is of a certain length then we're going to hash the passwords since we don't want to store plain
text passwords.
And finally we will generate an off token.
So when all is said and done we're going to generate and send back an art token that can be used to
perform tasks that usually require authentication.
We're going to generate and send back an auth token with the sign up operation and with the log in operation
which we'll get to later in this section.
For now though let's go ahead and start with what we need to do.
These four steps First up we've got to take in that password.
If I had overed to schema that graphic Well we have our create user mutation right here the data comes
from create user input that's defined down below.
And if we scroll down Currently it is not accepting a password.
We are going to add that field on password making it non nullable.
Excellent.
Now whatever someone tries to run or create user mutation they're going to have to provide that password.
So step one is done.
Step 2 we want to validate that password.
Now in this case we're just going to validate its length.
I'm going to make sure it is at least eight characters long and to do that we're going to use an IF
statement.
We have our stateman with our condition and our code to run.
Now we're going to have this code run.
If the password is invalid and in here we're going to throw an error.
So let's set up the condition we want to look at the passwords length.
We have data on args dot data.
There we have the password field which we literally just set up support for.
We know this is a string since we set up that type in our type definition and all we're going to end
up doing is checking its length using the string length property.
If the length is less than 8 we're going to throw an error if it's 8 or greater or not I'm going to
throw an error.
So right here throw new error printing a message password must be 8 characters or longer.
Excellent.
So now we have steps 1 in steps to complete.
That brings us on to hashing the password.
Remember that it's a terrible idea to store plain text passwords in the database.
So we are going to be passing all of the plain text passwords through a hashing algorithm.
There are a lot of hashing algorithms out there as well.
Some are pretty insecure and shouldn't be used.
Others are sick here and are great for production use.
We're going to be using the very popular very secure big crypt algorithm.
Now in the end of the day we're really just going to be installing an NPM module and taking advantage
of a couple of methods.
It provides us.
So let's go ahead and get things set up over inside of the browser.
I'm going to pull up the documentation for this module.
We're about to install and use it is called script.
Jay asks if we google that.
The first result should be the NPM package page we can head over there.
This is the exact module we're going to be installing and it is a very popular one.
We've got about a quarter million weekly downloads now on this page you can learn exactly how this algorithm
works though we're going to cover that in the video.
All I want to do for the moment is actually get this install.
So over here inside of the terminal we're going to do two things.
First up I am going to uninstall you you I.D. which we're no longer using then I am going to install
be crip.
So right here NPM uninstall you you ID we can remove that module since it's no longer being used.
And we can also remove the import statement from up above.
Then once that uninstall command is finished which it now is we will install crypt J as.
So NPM install B crypt J S at the latest version which is two point four point three.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and get this installed then we'll set up an import statement and we'll take advantage
of one of its methods down below in create user.
Right here we can set up that inport statement.
We're going to be grabbing one of the default exports.
So inport I'm going to call this big crypt.
You could call it B crypt J S as well.
Either way works.
And we're going to grab that film the module that we just installed.
Crypt J.
Excellent.
Now down below in order to actually hash this password we're going to be using a single method from
the crypt that is B crypt dat hash.
This is going to take in our plain text password and it is going to give us back the hashed version.
Now in the end of the day the hashing algorithm is going to take our plain text password in let's say
it is password 1 2 3 a terrible password and it is going to spit out a long random series of characters.
Let's say for this example it has the following characters.
It's not let's just say it is the hashed value.
What we have here this is the value that we're actually going to store in the database.
We're never going to store the plain text version.
We are going to store the hashed version.
So we're going to store what comes back from calling B script dot hash.
Now hashing algorithms are one way which means that we can take a plain text password and hash it but
we cannot take the hashed version and get the plain text version back.
And that's a good thing.
Now if you're wondering how we're ever going to verify a password We'll talk about all of that and more
when we actually implement a log in mutation operation allowing people to log in with their existing
email and password.
For now we're just concerned about generating that hash.
So let's go ahead and get to it.
We're going to call this method with the two arguments that it expects.
The first argument is the plain text password that is available at Ark's dot data dot password.
And the second argument we're going to provide is a salt.
We provide a number the length of the salt.
We want to use.
I'm going to go ahead and use the number ten.
Perfect.
Now if you're wondering what a salt is a salt is nothing more than a random series of characters that
are hashed along with the string you're hashing.
So right now if I were to hash password one two three twice without a salt I would get the same value
both times and this is not ideal.
This is less secure since we now know that anytime we see this value the password is password 1 2 3.
That's a problem.
In order to create truly random hashes even if we have the same input we use a salt.
A lot of hashing algorithms the less secure ones don't have Salt's built in be crypt Dud's you actually
can't use B crypt without a cell.
And that's a good thing and makes it way more secure.
Now what do we do here.
Well hash returns a promise.
That promise resolves with the hashed Valley which is nothing more than a string.
So we're going to go wait that and store the hashed value in a variable Konst password would get the
job done.
I'm going to set that equal to.
And we are going to await whatever comes back from the hash method.
So now we have our hashed password and we can actually go ahead and make sure it gets stored in the
database which means that we're going to need to make a change to our create user mutation called down
below.
Currently we are just passing in our exact data which is where the plain text password lives.
That's a problem.
And we're going to address it to start.
Let's go ahead and add some new lines for this object since we're going to be making the object a bit
more complex.
So I'm going to structure things like I have now and we're going to set data not equal to args dot data
but equal to right here.
A new object.
Now on this object what we're going to do is two things first.
We're going to use our spread operator to spread out all of the properties on our X-Com data.
So we still want to use things like the name and the email which are passed in as arguments then and
we're going to set up the password to be the hashed password from above.
And when you're setting up an object property whose value comes from a variable of the same name we
can always use our shorthand.
Now args dot data is still setting the plain text password on this object but we're overriding it down
below making sure only the hashed version is stored.
So let's go ahead and make sure this actually works.
I'm going to save mutation.
J.
S. And what we're going to do is start up our application and try to create a new user.
So down below that would be NPM start once the application is up and running.
We can move over to local host 4000 to interact with our node API.
Right here I have the create user request and if we give things a refresh we're going to notice that
our current nutation is invalid.
It's invalid because we are not providing a password and password is now required to down below.
We can go ahead and add that on password setting an equal to a string.
Now the nice thing about graph you Al is that it can automatically perform some base level validation
for you.
We can use our exclamation mark to Mark Fields as required and our type definitions make sure we're
getting the correct type.
So if password was set to true this method wouldn't even run.
Now that doesn't mean we don't want to do a little validation even when it's set to a string.
Things can still go wrong.
For example if the password is less than 8 characters I'm going to start with a password of read which
is indeed less than 8 characters.
And if I fire that off what do we get.
We get an error.
Password must be 8 characters or longer.
Let's go ahead and fix that.
I'm going to add incrementing numbers 1 2 3 4 5 bringing the password length to 8.
Now if I go ahead and fire things off what do we get.
We get our operation completing successfully and we can now go ahead and move into the database and
see what value was actually stored for the password field over NPG admin.
I'm going to refreshed that database by clicking that lightning bolt.
And what do we get back.
We get back our user.
Her name is Jess.
Her e-mail is just an example dot com.
And the password is not what we typed in.
It is a long long long series of random characters.
This is the hashed output.
This is what we do want to store in the database.
So now that we have this in place we have successfully completed steps 1 2 and 3.
The only thing left to do is to generate and send back and auth token remember we're going to be creating
an off token when a new user signs up and any time an existing user logs in that's going to be the topic
of the next video.
So on this one we set up create user to take in that password to validate the password and to hash the
password.
That's a great start and the next video will talk about how we're going to generate and manage our authentication
tokens.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one where we will finish off our create user mutation.