In this video as promised we're going to focus on this last step in the process we need to generate
and send back and authentication token this token is going to be something that the client stores and
passes along with future requests whenever it wants to do something that requires authentication like
creating a post or deleting a comment just as two examples.
Well there are plenty of different ways we could create authentication tokens in this course.
We're going to be using the very popular approach of the Jasen web token that is JWT for short.
This is an open standard that gives us a way to securely transmit information between parties and it's
also tamper proof so we can grant certain privileges to the holder of that token.
So the server generates the token the client then gets that token and the client can then use that token
for future requests that require authentication and each token is going to be associated with a specific
user they're going to expire after a certain amount of time.
So we'll be able to implement all of the features you would like to be able to use when working with
authentication and actually can do this to actually use adjacent web tokens.
We're going to be installing a library that gives us everything we needed to implement that into our
application.
That's exactly what I want to explore right now.
We can go over to the browser and in a new tab we are going to search for NPM.
Jason Webb tokin and the first result is the one we want.
It is the Jason a web tokin package.
We can go ahead and move over there and all we're going to do is install this and use it.
This is a super popular tool about a million weekly downloads.
So let's go ahead and actually get this into our program so we can learn more about these tokens down
below.
NPM install Jason Webb tokin at the latest version is eight point three point zero.
I'm going to fire off that command and then we're going to inport the library up above right here.
I'm going to import JWT for short that as a default export.
And we're going to grab that from the library we just install.
Jason Webb tokin awesome.
Now before we actually implement Jason Webb tokens into create user I just want to mess around with
them right here.
We'll use a few different methods from that library to explore how these tokens work and we'll use council
dialog to dump some output from the terminal once we understand how Jason Webb tokens work will actually
implement them and to create user itself.
The first method that we're going to use from Jason Webb token allows us to create a new token and in
the end of the day a token is nothing more than a really long string.
So let's go ahead and actually use it right here.
I'm going to use JWT dot sign.
This is how we create a brand new tokin and we passed to it to required arguments.
The first argument we provide to it is an object.
This is known as our payload.
And this is where we can provide information for our specific purposes.
So in this case we're using WTS for authentication.
So what are we going to put inside of here.
We're going to put inside of here the user's ID.
So if I'm trying to create an authentication token for a user with the idea of 46 I would set id to
46 something like this would get the job done.
Now it's important to note that it is not required to use ID.
There's nothing special about this.
In the end of the day we can put what ever we want into this object we can get as many properties as
we need in this case though we really just need to associate this token with a particular user by their
ID.
Now there is a second argument we have to pass to sign to.
This is known as a secret and this is used to verify the integrity of a token making sure that someone
doesn't get a token and try to change the ID to a different user for example.
So the secret is something that's only going to live on the node j s server as it can pick whatever
we want.
For the moment let's just use something like my secret.
Later on in the class We'll break this out into an environment variable.
Now what comes back from the sign method is indeed our token.
So we can actually save it in a variable and do something with it.
Konst token equals then down below I'm just going to use console dot Lague to dump the token to the
console.
Now let's save the file run our program and see what output we get down below I am going to use clear
to clear the terminal output.
I'm going to run the program with NPM start and once again we're looking for a really long string in
the output and where it is we have our Jason Webb token showing up.
This is the token that the server is going to send to the client when the client signs up or logs in
and at the same token that the client will then store and send along with future requests when it wants
to be authenticated.
Now what I want to take a moment to talk about is the fact that the payload what we've provided right
here it's not meant to be encrypted.
It's actually publicly readable.
Anybody who has access to this token can look at this data and that's perfectly fine.
That is all part of the JWT standard.
We can actually prove this by writing two more statements right here.
We're going to create a variable called Decoded and we're going to decode our token using JWT dot de-code
What do we pass to decode.
We pass our string tokens.
I'm going to pass in token the exact same super long string that we dumped to the console and then all
I'm going to do is dump the decoded object to the terminal so cancel that log decoded and we're going
to be able to see exactly what comes back.
Now notice we've gotten the token but we do not have the secret.
So without knowing this secret.
Yes you are able to read the payload.
It's not meant to be encrypted.
Now if I were to say mutation that Jay asked the program is going to rerun we get a newly generated
token sitting right here then down below we get our decoded object.
And you'll notice that there's two properties we have ID which is the one property that we provided.
So right here we can see this token is associated with something or someone who has an idea of 46.
Then we have a tree which stands for issued.
And and this is a time stamp of when the token was initially created.
So there are a few nice to have features like the initialization time stamp that are built right into
Jasen web tokens.
So far we've created a token which we saw required a secret.
We have then decoded that tokens payload which does not require a secret.
What we want to be able to do lastly is verify that a token was actually created by this server.
What's to stop someone from just creating a token on the client spoofing the ID using some other users
ID and then sending that token to the server.
Well what's stopping that from happening is the secret.
There is another method we're going to be using JWT data verify much like de-code it decodes the token
but it also verifies that the token was indeed created with a specific secret.
And this is how we're going to ensure that the tokens that we're reading are tokens created by US created
by this server.
So right here JWT dot verify takes into arguments it takes in the token we want to actually verify we
have that in the token variable.
And this one also requires the secret and if the token wasn't created with the same secret verify is
going to fail.
Only if it is a match is verify going to succeed.
So right here let's have it succeed by using the same secret.
My secret.
Exactly what the token was created with up above.
Now what comes back is once again decoded data.
I can create a cost decoded to and then dump that to the console console dot Lague printing decoded
too.
And now all we're going to do is run the program and watch things work.
Now in this case I would expect the verification to succeed since the token was created with the exact
same secret.
And that's what we see down below.
We have our token we have our decoded data that we have our decoded and verified data.
This data is less important.
We're never really going to trust what comes back from that the server is only going to trust the data
that comes back from varify because we verified that it was indeed created with the same secret.
And that means that came from our server.
Now let's see what happens when these secrets don't match up.
So let's say that a malicious client tries to create a token to spoof the user 46 when they're really
the user 22 they don't know what our secret is so they just type something it.
My best guess in this case when the token right here gets to the server and the server verifies it.
It is not going to see it as a match.
If I save things the program is going to rerun and you can see that we got an error that crashed the
program right here.
Jason Webb token error.
Invalid signature.
So this is letting us know that the token we tried to verify could not be verified which means that
it should not be trusted.
And this is how we're going to make sure that the client cannot tamper with the token.
It all comes down to the secret the client's not going to know the secret so it won't be able to ever
generate the exact same token that we would generate on the server where we do know that secret.
To wrap up our discussion on Jason Webb tokens the last thing that I want to do is give us a little
insight to what exactly is stored in this strain because it's not a completely random set of characters.
Well we're going to do is copy this string to the clipboard and we're going to bring it over to a Web
site that allows us to inspect this token.
We're going to head over to J.
W T Dot I.
Oh.
Now this Web site might have changed or it might have moved the debugging tool.
If you can't find it it's perfectly fine to just watch this portion of the video down below.
They have a debugger for Jason Webb tokens on the left hand side.
They have a dummy token on the right hand side they have the contents of that token.
Now all we're going to do is paste our token in.
So I'm going to paste things in and now you can see that the data on the right hand side has actually
changed.
Now we have a color coded sections of our token there are actually three distinct pieces.
We have our Hetter.
We have our payload and we have our signature.
And they're separated in our token by the period character.
So we have one right here and we have another right here.
This first piece.
This is the header data.
This second piece is our payload.
And the last piece is the signature.
Now you can see that the periods were not added by this Web site.
We had the exact same thing over here.
We have our first period separating the header and the payload and we have our second period character
separating the payload and the signature.
So what do we have on the right hand side while the header just contains some information about the
token.
In general this is not something that we the end user are ever going to modify or read from.
This is for internal purposes only.
It allows it to provide some information about the token type.
In this case it is a Jason Webb token and it also allows it to provide some information about the algorithm
used to generate the signature.
Now down below Hatter we have our payload as expected.
This is the data that we saw in the terminal.
We have the property that we added ID as well as the issued at data property showing when exactly the
token was created.
And finally we have the signature for the token.
This is what keeps everything tamper proof and secure the signature is nothing more than a hash.
So we hash the header and the payload together with our secret.
And that results in the signature we're seeing right here.
Now someone could indeed try to create a new header a new payload and generate a signature but that
signature is never going to be valid because they won't know the secret that we're going to end up using
on the server.
So both the sign and verify methods actually generate a signature when we sign a token it generates
that signature.
And as we can see here it adds it onto the end of the token when we verify a token.
We once again do the exact same thing.
I take the header and body data and I hash it with the secret provided here.
If I get the same signature that shown in the token I know the token is valid since things match up.
If I get a different signature then I know that the token was created with a different secret.
And that's why we're getting different results when we hash the data together.
So this is what keeps things secure and tamper proof.
Now it's important to note that while this data might encrypted it's not it is just base 64 encoded.
So to prove this the last thing I want to do is take the purple taxed our payload data between the two
periods and we're going to bring it over to a generic base 64 decoder.
So I'm just going to Google base 64 decode online.
We'll pick whatever first site comes up.
Any of these sites will get the job done.
We're going to dump that text in.
We're going to decode it.
And what do we get.
We get some Jason data.
So this is where the Jason and Jason web token comes from our header and our payload are just base 64
encoded Jason.
So now that we've seen the inner workings of the Jason Webb token we're ready to actually use it inside
of our create user mutation if you have any questions whatsoever about anything discussed here or you
want to know more about how exactly this works.
Just crack open a question in the Q&amp;A we could talk all day about header's payloads and signatures and
hashing algorithms but I don't want to dive too deep into the inner workings of JWT.
I just wanted to give you a brief overview so you can understand exactly what's happening.
All right I'm going to shut this tab down and we're actually going to use this in create user down below.
Our goal is to create a new token and return it along with the newly created user.
The first thing I'm going to do is actually change up our return statement.
We're no longer going to return directly what comes back from create user.
Instead I'm going to get that user.
So Konst user equals then I will await that promise.
And down below that's where we're actually going to set up our return statement because remember we
want to return an object that has 2 things on it.
The user information and the token which we're about to create.
Let's go ahead and get that done right here.
We are going to add a return statement into the mix.
We are going to set it up as an object and we're going to add on those two properties.
I am going to set up user to come from the User variable created above and I am going to set up token
and we will use JWT data sign right here.
Now we're going to pass in those two arguments.
We know we have to provide the first is our payload and the second is our secret for the secret.
Let's just use this is a secret and for the payload we're going to do is set user id equal to the user
ID that we just got back from creating a user's are right here user dot ID.
Perfect.
Now we actually have everything in place in terms of what needs to go inside of this method.
We do still have to change the return value of create user though inside of schema Dom graft well over
in schema Dom graphed Well currently create user should be returning in just a user that is no longer
the case.
So were going to make a slight modification.
Instead we're going to be returning a type that has token end user on it.
So down below we can actually create a brand new type I can call this something like off a payload and
we're going to set it up with two fields we're going to have token as a nun at nullable string and we're
going to have user as a non nullable user then we can set that up as the return value from create user.
So we remove user and we swap it out with off payload.
Now the value we're expecting to come back matches up with the value we're actually returning and we
are ready to test things out and make sure that our token comes back.
Now down below we are still getting our error and that's coming from the mis matched secrets we were
using up above.
We can actually just remove all of this stuff that was added for example purposes only.
And it no longer serves much of a purpose and now we're going to save this file and move over to local
host 4000 to create a new user.
Now jazzes already in the database.
So let's switch up the name and the e-mail.
I'm going to use my name and my example email and it's important to note that this request is actually
going to fail.
Let's go out and talk about why.
Well first up we know that right now this is going to fail because it's invalid.
We just changed what comes back.
We no longer have ID name and e-mail but we have access to our user and tokin for user I can choose
to grab ID name and email if that's what I want and I'm also going to grab the auth token.
So I can actually do something with it.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place it's important to note that the request is still going to fail if we
actually send it off.
We're going to get the following message.
Field create user of type user must have a sub selection.
So what's happening here is that we're taking this selection set and we're passing it in to create user
via the info argument.
The problem with this is that we can't select a token or a user on what comes back.
We can only select the fields from the user.
So in this case where we're returning something a bit custom like this object using info is actually
not what we want.
Instead what we're going to do is leave off that second argument altogether.
And as we discussed previously in the course this will return all scalar fields.
So for the user it would return any of these scalar fields we have listed over and R-Type definition
that would include ID name email and password.
Now for the moment yes even password will actually make that private.
A bit later in the class for now let's save this file and test things out.
So I'm going to save mutations jast the server restarted over here we're going to take the exact same
mutation which previously failed and we're going to fire that off when we do.
What do we get.
We get our successful data showing up we have our newly created user information.
And we also have an authentication token that the client can store and use later to perform privileged
operations like creating a post or updating a comment both of which will require authentication.
Now if we actually go over to PGE admin and refresh our users table we can see that right here we have
Andrew showing up alongside of gests exactly as we would expect.
So the only thing we've done is we've moved all of those user fields onto a user property and we've
added the addition of a token property.
Now if any of this didn't make too much sense it's probably because we only have half of the picture
completed.
We know how to generate tokens but we don't know how to actually verify a token and use that to determine
whether or not someone can do something.
Can this user delete this post.
I don't know.
We're going to dive into all of that in more in the next several videos.
I'm excited to get to it.
For now we just have the token creation process locked down.
Let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.