In this video it's going to be up to you to create the loggin mutation.
We're going to go through a series of challenges where you're going to build up that mutation from scratch.
Now before we dive into any of those challenges I want to talk about one thing we need to learn about
before we can actually create the loggin mutation.
Now we know how to have a password and store that in the database but when someone logs in they're not
going to give us the hashed password when someone logs in they're going to give us their plain text
password.
They're going to give us their e-mail and their password.
We have to figure out how to compare that to the e-mail and hashed password in the database.
So let's knock that out first then we'll talk about the challenges right here to explore this.
I'm going to create a little dummy function an async aero function.
We're not going to set up any arguments.
I'm just going to call it giving us a little place to play around with this code and when we originally
call this mutation remember we're going to pass in the e-mail and the password so Konst e-mail equals
something like Andrew at example dot com and then Konst password is going to be the plain text password.
So if I signed up with read a one two three four or five when I log in I'm once again going to pass
in red.
One two three four five.
The problem though is that this value is nowhere in the database even for users where that was the password
used because we are storing the hashed password values.
So over in the database I actually have just hashed values.
I don't see red.
One two three four or five anywhere but actually both users were created with just that password.
So don't mess around with this.
Let's go ahead and grab this hash value.
Copy it to the clipboard and bring it over into the javascript file right here.
Konst hashed password is going to be a string and I'm going to paste the hashed contents in.
So what do we have.
We have the data that's going to come in with the log in request and we have the hashed password which
we're eventually going to get from the database.
So with the log in mutation we're going to fetch a user just by their email.
Once we get that user back we'll have access to the hashed password from the database and we'll be able
to compare that to.
Now how do we compare the two.
Well we use the crypt dot compare and this takes into arguments.
It takes in the plain text password and it takes in the hashed password and it is going to return a
promise that we can await the promise resolves to true if it is a match and false otherwise so Konst
is match equals whatever comes back from the compair promise.
Now we can actually go ahead and use console dialog to dump is match to the terminal.
Now in this case I would indeed expect a match since this hash is a fuelers password and the user was
created with red.
One two three four five.
If I save nutation J.
S. What do I get in the terminal I get.
True.
Now let's say I try to log in with invalid credentials.
So I'm going to change up that password from.
Read it with a lowercase are to read with an upper case are this time around the password should be
invalid.
And I would expect false to print and that is exactly what I end up getting.
So this is how we are going to end up comparing passwords were going to fetch the user by e-mail.
We'll get the hashed value from the database and we'll compare it with the plain text password using
our compair method.
Perfect.
Now it's important to note that once again this Beecroft algorithm is a one way hashing algorithm.
So we are not decrypting this getting the plain text version back and comparing this with RAD.
One two three four or five.
Instead we're actually hashing this and comparing the hashes.
There is no way to get the original plain text value back from our hash.
So now that we know how to compare passwords using the Compare method it is time to move on to our challenges.
And I'm saying challenges plural because in the end of the day the goal is to create this log in mutation.
But I'm going to break it up into three distinct steps so we can make sure we're all headed in the right
direction.
Let's go ahead and talk about the first challenge.
I'd like you to work through right here once again the big picture goal is to create the log in mutation
which we will do via three challenges and part one is to create the mutation structure itself.
So what are you going to do.
Well number one you will define the mutation in Scheme ideographs.
Well we have all of our other mutations defined over here.
We get a new one for logging in as well and you could call that something like loggin.
Next up this mutation should accept two arguments we need email and we need a password.
So in the end of the day in order to log someone in that is all we need we need their email and we need
their plain text password in terms of the response value it should be of the type or payload just like
we already have for create user.
So with the new logon nutation you can use the exact same or payload defined down below there's no need
to really define that.
Now once you have schema you UL all set up.
Step two is to define the mutation resolver in this file along with its four arguments.
So in the end of the day you're not going to have something complete.
You can actually test out Yoda's be part of the way there.
Take some time to knock this out and set up the basic structure for the mutation when you're done.
You can come back and click play
how that one go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off.
Over inside of schema graft well in here we want to set up a brand new mutation.
The order it comes in does not matter.
I'm going to put it right here after create user and we need those two arguments which we'll talk about
in a second.
And the response value is of the type off payload just like we already have for create user.
Now there are a couple of different ways you could structure the arguments maybe you created separate
email and password arguments.
Maybe you went ahead and created a single argument like data creating a new input where you have the
email and password.
Honestly either approach is fine.
I'm going to create a single argument data and have that be of the type log in user input as a non nullable
value.
Perfect.
Now down below we can actually define that so down here input log in user input that's going to have
two fields.
We're going to take in the email as a non nullable string and we're going to take in the password.
Also a non nullable string.
Excellent.
Now in the end of the day you could have used either approach to arguments or one.
Both are perfectly valid.
It's all a matter of personal preference and style.
Now that we have these schema graphed you all file all done we can move on to step two which is to define
our mutation resolver in this spiles so down below right below create user.
I'm going to create a new async method called log in which matches up with my mutation name.
We're going to set that up putting a comma at the end of the function.
And right here we're going to define all of those arguments we have parent.
We have args for the context.
I will deal structure Prisma.
And finally we have info.
Awesome.
Now that was it for part 1.
We have our basic structure in place.
Now let's go ahead and talk about what I would like you to do for part two.
Part 2 is all about verifying the email and password.
So step one you're going to query for the user by their email in your mutation resolver down below.
And we just need the scalar fields for the user which means you can leave off that second argument.
Now when you actually get the result back you want to see if you found a user if you did not find a
user then you're going to throw an error something generic like unable to authenticate or unable to
log in.
Now if you did find a user by that e-mail we only verified half of the stuff we need to verify we've
only verified the email.
We also need to verify the password.
So you're going to pull the hashed password out of the user you found from the database and you're going
to compare that password against the plain text password provided as the argument.
So you're going to use the compare method exactly like we did down below.
Now once again you end up seeing that the passwords do not match.
You want to throw an error saying something like unable to log in.
So take some time to knock that out.
All you're going to have to do is add a few statements as well as some if statements into the log in
method down below.
Pause the video.
Knock that out when you're done come back and click play
how that one go let's go ahead and kick things off down below.
We have our in method of right here.
And the first thing that we're going to end up doing is finding the user by their e-mail so I can create
a new constant.
I'll call this user and we are going to await one of our queries we have Prisma dot queery dot and we
are going to use the user query.
Now we know when we're searching for an individual user we can search by ID or email the two things
that make the user unique.
In this case we will be searching by the email which is one of the arguments right here where e-mail
equals args dot data dot email.
Perfect.
Now if there was no user we want to throw an error.
Let's go ahead and check if no user we will throw a new error and we can say something along the lines
of unable to log in.
Awesome.
The next thing for part two was to verify the password.
Now at this point we know we have a user sends this code obviously didn't run or we wouldn't get to
this point which means we have a user account password which is where the hashed password is stored.
But we're going to do is actually run a check using the crypt compare.
So Konst is match equals we are going to await a B crypt.
Compare we are going to pass in first the plain text password args dot data dot password.
Then the second is the hashed password user password.
Perfect.
Now if there was no match we want to throw an error.
So if there was no match
we are going to throw a new error and once again we will say something like.
Unable to log in when it comes to sending back errors about why authentication failed it's best to be
as generic as possible.
It's not a good idea to say something like authentication failed because the password you provided doesn't
match up with the email for that account.
It gives away more information than is really necessary.
And a hacker or a social engineer could use that to gain access so you're really just giving them more
contacts than they deserve.
In general I just stick with something generic like unable to lock it.
Now what are we going to do.
Well we are actually all done for part two.
We have verified the e-mail and we have verified the password.
So that brings us to part three but we're actually going to put all of this together and test our work
right here for part 3.
Your goal is to send back the correct information and then test your work.
So you want to send back an object that matches up with off payload much like we did for create user.
That means you need to provide a user field as well as a token field.
And when you create that token you want to make sure to use the same as secret we used with create user.
So the tokens created with create user and with log in should be using the exact same secret.
In this case this is a secret is what I used here and it's exactly what I'm going to use down below
as well.
So step 1 is really just setting up the correct return statement.
Step two.
Test your work.
You want to log in with an existing user and make sure you can create a selection set that grabs back
some user details as well as the authentication token if you can't remember the email and password for
any of your users.
You can go ahead and just delete the database or just create a new user and use that user when testing.
All right.
Take some time to knock this out.
Test your work when you're done come back and click play
How'd that go.
We're going to go ahead and start with step one.
We need to return the correct stuff.
So right here in our log in method I want to return an object.
This object needs to have both user and token so it matches up with our auth payload that we have set
up as the response value.
Now to get that done we are going to start with user first.
That one's easy.
The user property will get its value from the user variable up above and the second one is going to
be token where we're going to create a brand new authentication token JWT dot sign.
We have to provide user ID for this one.
We can get the value from user ID.
And we also have to use the exact same secret.
This is a secret.
Excellent.
Now that we have this in place we are done with step 1 and the last thing left to do is to test our
work and make sure it works as expected.
So let's go ahead and actually get that done by saving the file and moving over into local host 4000
engraft UL playground.
I'm going to try to log in as this user.
We have the email of Andrew at example dot com and we have the password of read 1 2 3 4 5.
I'm going to create a brand new town for this mutation.
It is indeed a mutation.
We named the mutation log in.
We are going to set up all the correct arguments.
First though let's go ahead and refresh the schema.
So it actually shows up over in the list we now see it which is great.
We can set up our arguments list.
We just have one data and on that we provide both the email and the password.
So we have e-mail.
We're going to have the value Andrew an example dot com and we're going to have the password which was
indeed the read one two three four five.
The last thing to do is provide our selections set ometer grab some information about that user.
I'll go ahead and grab the user's ID and the user's name.
And I'm also going to grab the auth token that was created after all that is the whole point of logging
in.
Now that we have our operations set up we can actually go ahead and fire this one off.
And what do we get.
We got a success operation back.
We have data log in.
We have the user field we requested and we have our brand new token all showing up.
Now if I were to change the e-mail let's try Andrew to add example dot com.
I would expect it to fail and it does indeed fail.
If I revert the e-mail back to the valid e-mail but messed the password up I would also expect things
to fail and right here.
It does indeed fail only when both the e-mail and the password align.
Do we actually get a valid authentication token being created.
So there we go we have our loggin mutation in place which means that we now have a consistent way to
generate authentication tokens when someone logs in or when someone initially creates their account.
But we're going to focus on in the next video is how to lock down some of our routes making sure that
you can only do things like create a post when you do indeed provide a valid auth token.
To wrap this video up let's go ahead and remove all of this stuff from up above.
I'm going to remove the dummy function and then above our imports I'm going to remove all of the comments
for those challenges.
And there we go.
That is it for this video.
Let's save the file and I will see you in the next one.