In the last couple of videos we've set up a sign up and a lag in a mutation both of which send back
and authentication tokin.
In this video we're going to figure out how to actually use that to authenticate users.
So we're going to figure out one how this token can get passed from the client to the no Jay s server
and to how the no js server can actually use this token to perform some sort of authentication.
Now the first mutation that we're going to modify in order to actually accept tokens is that we create
post mutation which is sitting inside of mutation.
Ass right now like all of our other mutations queries and subscriptions It doesn't require any authentication
it's all sitting out in the open.
We're going to fix that.
We're also going to remove the author argument since you shouldn't be able to create a post for any
author.
You should only be able to create a post for the author you're actually logged in ads.
Now not all of this out.
The first thing we have to do is get the token from the client to the server to start.
What I'm going to do is copy the token to the clipboard.
I have a token from the last video when I logged in.
If you don't have one just log in or sign up a user and grab one and we're going to move over to our
create post nutation And here we're going to provide the auth token via an H TTP Hetter.
Now HTP headers allow us to pass those values from client to server and server to client.
And regardless of what platform you're using you can set headers for your requests.
So if you're working with an iOS client or an android client or a web client you can set headers for
all of those.
And the structure we're going to use is actually the same structure that Prisma uses.
Over here where we have our authorization header and then we have our barer token.
Now this set up is by no means specific to Prisma and is a very common structure for authentication
headers and that is exactly what we're going to end up using as well.
So over inside of localhost 4000 we're going to set up our object.
We're going to set up our key value pair.
The key authorization the value is barer space and then the token that we copied to the clipboard and
there we go.
This is actually all we need to do to get the token from the client to the server.
Now we need to figure out how we can get access to our J W from inside of Node.
J.
S. I want to be able to access it inside of my individual mutation resolvers since some mutations require
authentication like create Post and others won't like loggin to do this we're actually going to make
a change to the context for our server.
So if you remember we haven't touched it in a while we have this context object right here.
We provide various things those things get passed in as the value for this third argument.
What we're going to do is switch this up a little bit the context property can actually also be set
to a function.
This function then returns the object much like the object we have set up here.
So I can actually cut this object out copying it to the clipboard and I'm going to set context equal
to a function then I'm going to return the exact object we had before.
So at this point we actually haven't changed the functionality at all but we have set ourselves up to
be able to make an important change which is to be able to access our request headers which is where
our authorization token actually lives.
Let's go ahead and pull up the documentation to clarify exactly why this is important.
So I'm going to head over to the documentation for a graphic.
Well yoga I have the hub page sitting right here in my history and we're gonna scroll down a little
bit to look at the various options we can provide.
So after the initial examples we have our API and we have our context documentation right here.
We can use an object or a function.
Now this contains custom data being passed through to your resolver chain so all of our resolver methods
get this data.
It can be provided as an object which we've already seen or as a function with the following signature.
Here this function actually gets called by graft UL yoga with an argument the request object.
This is where we can access our head hurts.
So what we're going to do is grab this request and we're going to pass it through.
I'm going to add that on as a another context property.
Now before we mess around with this mutation J S let's just see exactly what lives on there.
I'm going to use Konsole dot Lague.
I am going to dump a request to the council then we're going to start the server up and we're just going
to run one of our operations.
I can run any of the operations I like.
I'm just going to run this one it's going fail.
Since the author IDs don't match up with anything in the database but that's OK.
I'm going to let it fail over in the terminal on going to scroll up just before the error and we can
see what outputs from this console dialog statement and as you'll see it is a ton quite literally a
ton of information.
It has everything that makes up that request including as I found right here are raw headers and are
parsed headers and this is the information that we need to access.
Now we don't want to dig through this entire object to find what we need.
It's really actually pretty simple to find what we need.
It is request datt request dot headers.
This contains all of the headers which is where our token lives.
So if we go ahead and save things once again we can scroll to the bottom of the terminal and then going
to rerun this operation which will once again fail and then I'm going to look at the output that gets
printed and now it's much more manageable.
It is just an object.
It starts here and it ends right here.
Now there are plenty of headers we didn't set.
Most of these are actually set by graphical playground itself but we do indeed have our authorization
hetter with our Jason Webb token.
So this is where we can grab that token parse it and verify it.
Now we're not going to do that in this function we're actually going to remove that console that log.
We are done with this file we can save it and close it.
All of that is going to happen in the individual methods.
Now we're going to have a whole bunch of different methods that require authentication.
So for each of those methods we're going to have to get better value.
We're going to have to parse out the token then we're going to have to verify the token.
You get the idea.
It goes on and on and on.
There are a few steps we have to do.
I don't want to write out this code for every single nutation query and subscription that we want to
actually set up to require authentication.
So I'm going to create a simple utility function that handles all of that's for us.
We can write the code once in that function and we can reuse it anywhere we want to set up authentication.
Now to do this what I'm going to do is create a Noojee rectory in the source folder.
So a new directory alongside have generated and alongside of resolvers I'm going to call this utils
in here we're going to have a few files eventually that will contain some utility methods.
For now we're just going to have one and I'm going to call this get user id dot J as in here we're going
to define a single function get user ID and that's where we're going to abstract all of this logic.
So let's create the function and right here will actually define it.
Konst get user ID.
Well talk about its arguments and what exactly it's going to do and return in a little bit.
For now let's go ahead and export it an import it from the other file so export right here get a user
ID as default.
I'm going to save this file go over to mutation dot J S and inport it up above the top of the file in
Port get user ID which we just set up from in the following file.
Now this file is in the resolvers directory.
So I'm going to use dot dot to go up to the source folder.
From there I'm going to use forward slash utils to go into the utility directory then forward slash
get user ID to actually load in that file.
So now we have access to get user ID and we can take advantage of that down below inside of create post
right here.
We're actually going to end up calling it Konst user ID as the method name suggests excuse me the function
name get user ID is going to return a user ID.
I'm going to call it get user ID and we're going to pass to it.
The new piece of context that we just set up.
So I am going to do structure request and I am going to pass that in.
Perfect.
Now what's going to happen is that function can be in charge of actually doing all of these steps.
And that's what we're going to get to in just a second.
Now that we're passing an argument to get user id Let's go ahead and actually name that over here request
and the first thing we're going to do is pull off the raw header value.
So I'm going to create a constant this constant can be called something like Hatter and we're going
to get the header value.
So we already saw where the headers live it's on request dot request dot headers and on there we have
authorization that's the one we want.
Perfect.
Now if you're wondering why we have request twice that is because in the whole request there is a request
and a response.
There's actually two pieces to each quote unquote request and that's where the redundancy comes from.
It can be a little confusing at first but honestly this is the only place where ever even going to use
it.
So if we understand it here you're good to go.
Now what's next.
Well we have that letter.
Let's go ahead and see if anything was actually there.
So I'm going to set up an if statement if there was no header.
What are we going to do.
Well as you can probably guess we're going to go ahead and throw an error so right here if no header
we are going to throw a new error authentication required.
So we're going to say that to perform this action.
You have to be authenticated.
Now obviously this error is only going to get thrown if we call and get user ID which we're only going
to call from mutation queery and subscription resolvers where we actually care about authentication.
I'm never going to call get user ID from something like my log in mutation where authentication isn't
important.
Now we're not quite done inside of here.
We still have to parse this string to get rid of the bearer and the space that we want to verify this
token using j.
W.T. verify.
So let's go ahead and knock that out right here.
I'm going to create a concert and we're going to call this one token.
The goal is to extract the token value.
So leaving off barer and the space and there are a ton of different ways you could get this done.
My personal favorite is to just use the string method on a header replace.
I'm going to replace barer space with an empty string which successfully just removes it.
There are so many other approaches you could have taken as well header dot split for example I could
split that string on the space.
So now I have an array of two items.
The first is the string bearer and the second is my string token.
Then I could grab that second item by index that would work as a replacement for this too.
I'm going to stick with the replace approach though.
Personal preference.
Now that we have the token we want to verify it which means that we need to use JWT verify and if we're
going to use it we've got to import it.
So over the top of the file inport the JWT from Jason Webb tokin then down below we're actually going
to call it.
So we are going to get back our decoded data.
We are going to call J.
W.T. dot verify.
And we're going to pass to two arguments.
The first being our token and the second being our secret we need to use the same secret our tokens
were created with that was.
This is a secret for both sign up and log in.
So I'm going to copy that string to the clipboard bring it over to get user ID and paste it right inside
of here.
So now if the token was a failure for whatever reason this would have throw in an error causing the
get user ID function to stop if we are continuing on then that means things went well and we can actually
just return the user IDs.
I'm going to return on our decoded object which we've printed before one property from the payload user
ID.
Perfect.
So let's go over this big picture.
We grab the header if there was no header we stop.
That's a problem.
If there was a hammer we remove the beginning piece that contains barer and then we try to verify the
token if token verification fails we stop.
Lastly if everything worked we returned the user ID so we can save get user ID and over in mutation.
J.
S. We can now take advantage of the fact that we have the user id of the authenticated user and we're
going to use that right here.
No longer are we going to accept an author ID getting passed in.
Instead we're going to use the user id of the authenticated user.
Now we can save mutation J.
As and over inside of schema dot graph.
Q Well I am going to change the Create post mutation.
We have our create post input and that's defined down below.
This no longer needs the author ID so we can actually remove it completely when we are creating a post.
We just need the title the body and the published fields.
So let's go ahead and save all of our files and we're actually ready to test things out and make sure
authentication is all set up over inside of a local host 4000 ongoing going to refresh that schema and
my request should become invalid.
It should complain that we're providing author but author doesn't exist and that's exactly what we're
seeing.
I'm going to remove the author field which is no longer necessary.
Now my request is valid and we're going to go ahead and fire that off with the Tokin in place.
Now I'm going to change the title to keep it original.
This is with JWT in place.
I'm going to fire this off and what do we get.
We got a successful post creation.
The post was created successfully because we provided a valid authentication token.
And you'll notice that it associated it with the correct user.
So based off of the information embedded in that token it was able to figure out which user is actually
being authenticated.
And it did indeed create the post for Andrew.
Now if I were to leave off this header or I were to change it.
Let me go ahead and just add a queue up front.
For example things are now going to fail by adding that one character we've messed up the signature
for the JWT.
And if I run it you can see we're getting invalid token back which is great.
So it's only if we provide a token and it's valid that we're actually going to see things work.
So to test the last case let's go ahead and highlight everything down below.
I'm going to cut it out removing all headers.
I'm going to fire that off though we can see that this time around.
It also fails.
We're getting our authentication required message showing up.
So now that we have authentication set up it's actually not going to be that difficult to add it for
other mutation resolvers.
In the end of the day all we really need to do is grab a request from the context call our get user
id method and then do something with the ID.
There will be a challenge in the next video where you have to do just that.
So that's where we're going to stop for this one.
We have the basic infrastructure for authentication in place.
What do we do.
Well we provided a header when we made our initial request inside of our code.
We changed index dot J asked to make sure the headers got passed through to the context from there.
Are individual mutation resolvers were able to pass the request object down to get user ID that parses
and verifies the token and everything works really well.
All right.
I'll see you in the next video where it's going to be up to you to add authentication to some of our
other mutations.