It now that are create post mutation is all locked down.
We've already done all of the heavy lifting necessary to set up our authentication scheme actually integrating
this same scheme into other mutations or queries or subscriptions is going to be a super easy process.
We already have everything in place.
We really just need to add a few lines of code for each.
Now we're going to start together and then there will be challenges.
Will you have to do this on your own and to start.
We're going to make some changes to update user.
Now if I go to schema and graph Google and scroll up to our update user mutation we can see that it
takes in two arguments it takes in the ID of the user to update and it also takes in the data the actual
updates.
We want to make when we integrate authentication you're not going to be able to upgrade any old user.
You're only going to be able to upgrade yourself.
Now we know your idea because we have the token which has your ID embedded.
So it's no longer necessary to pass the ID argument in to update a user.
All we need is your authentication token and the data you actually want to change because once again
you can only update yourself.
At least that's how we're setting it up.
So I'm going to save this schema graphics well with that ID argument are removed and over inside of
mutation.
J.
S. we're going to be switching things up a little bit from the context.
We are also going to grab a request like we did down below or right here and once we have a request
we are going to actually use it.
We are going to call get user ID once again.
So right here Konst user ID equals get user ID.
We're going to call this anywhere we actually want to force authentication and we know that we will
either have an error thrown if the user isn't authenticated or we'll get an I.D. back if they are.
So right here we would expect that if we are still running code in this function that we do indeed have
a user ID.
So where are we going to make use of this.
Well we're going to replace what originally was args dot I.D. remember you can't customize which user
you're updating any more.
You can only update yourself.
So right here the I.D. We're going to use is the I.D. found in the authentication token.
And there we go.
Now one update user is indeed locked down you have to be authenticated to use it and to customize the
behavior making sure you can only update your own profile.
With this in place let's go ahead and save update user and actually test things out over inside of graft
playground.
I'm going to grab the authentication token I already have in the headers area down below and copy that
to the clipboard and then going to move over to my tab for updating a user and paste the header in.
Perfect.
Next up we have to update our structure.
If I actually grab the latest schema we're going to see our call is invalid because the ID argument
is no longer accepted.
So we're going to remove it.
And right here we can specify the changes we'd like to make.
I'm just going to change the name for this user the name is already Andrew.
So I'll just change it to my last name.
Mead now Double-O I have my selections set.
I'm grabbing the id the name and the e-mail.
Let's go ahead and fire this off and see what happens right here.
What do we get.
We get our updated user showing up.
Now if I were to leave off the authentication token and fire off this same request we can see that we
are indeed getting our error.
So everything is working really well so far.
Now that we have this set up we can go ahead and move on to one of our other mutations.
As you can see now that we have the structure in place we have all of the architecture and infrastructure
set up actually locking down an individual mutation or queery or subscription really isn't going to
be that bad.
Let's go ahead and do one more together then I'll set you off on your own to do a few as a challenge
so up above we are going to knock out delete user now and the end of the day delete user 1 should require
you to be authenticated.
And when you actually delete a user you should only be able to delete your cell.
You shouldn't be able to delete any one just by providing their ID.
So to address this change the first thing we're going to do is remove the ID argument for the delete
user nutation no longer are we going to allow you to pass in the ID of the user.
You want to remove.
So we're going to remove the arguments list altogether.
We actually don't need any arguments to delete the user.
Now what are we going to do.
Well we're going to save schema engraft Well then over inside of mutation database we're actually going
to load in request.
So right here.
Request and then down below we are going to call get user id so Konst user ID equals calling yet user
id passing in the request object.
Now if we are actually deleting something if this code actually runs we know a user ID was found and
were going to use it right here where we were previously using the ID passed in via the argument.
So User ID.
Perfect.
Now delete user requires you to be authenticated and if you do actually get the chance to remove something
you can only remove yourself with this in place we can now say that nutation dot J S and test things
out.
Let's go ahead in time to delete the user from graft playground over here.
I'm going to start by grabbing this authentication token from the HTP hatters of update user and we
are going to scroll over to our delete user mutation.
I'm going to add the headers in and we are going to change the arguments lest we actually need none.
So we're going to remove the arguments list and when we refresh the schema we're going to see that's
valid.
Now we have no arguments.
We just remove the parentheses altogether.
So here we are deleting a user the user who has indeed authenticated and were grabbing their ID name
and email back.
I'm going to go ahead and fire this one off.
And what do we get.
Right here we get our request successfully returning the response.
We have the information about the deleted user and if I were to try to fire this off again it would
fail.
We would try to pull that idea out of the Tokin and we would see that there is no longer a user with
that Id sense they were just deleted.
Once again I fire off and we can see we are indeed getting an error saying there is no user with that
ID.
So there we go.
Now all of our user based mutations do indeed require you to be authenticated.
And we also restrict what you can do to just mutating yourself so you can delete yourself or you can
update yourself.
You can't delete or update others as I'm sitting here writing down what I'd like you to do for the challenge.
I realized there's one piece to the puzzle we haven't put together for some of our other nutation So
here's what we're going to do.
We're going to do just one more together I promise.
This is the final one more then in the next video you're going to update 1 2 three four on your own.
So the last one that we're going to change is going to be delete post.
Now you'll have to update update post create comment delete comment and update comment in the next video.
Let's take a quick moment to talk about why we're going through Duleep posts together when we delete
a post.
We want to take the user's ID into account.
So once again we want to grab request.
We want to get the user's ID by calling get user ID and what we want to do is only delete a post if
the ID matches up with the post Id passed and as the argument.
And if the post's author is indeed this user.
Now here's the problem.
Delete post does not accept any other arguments on where for example there is no way to delete a post
where the author has an ID that equals user ID.
This syntax doesn't work and we can just prove that by looking at the schema for delete posts at local
host for 4 6 6 over here we have our mutations we have our delete post mutation.
If I go to where what do we get we just get the ID so we can actually confirm that the post where deleting
belongs to this user without adding a bit more code.
Well we're going to do is actually use exists what we explored earlier to make sure that the post does
exist and that the author is indeed the person with this idea.
So let's go ahead and knock that out.
And that'll give us everything we need to know to do this again.
For update post and all of our comment mutations.
So right here we are going to first mark this as a sink since I am going to use a weight Konst right
here post exists or something similar.
And we're going to get its value by awaiting the promise that comes back from Prisma dot exists dot
and right here we are checking if a post exists now right here we can provide our criteria.
And this is where we can actually make sure a post exists that has the correct post ID and the correct
author ID.
So right here I am going to check if the post ID is indeed what was passed and as the argument and I
am going to check that the author's I.D. is indeed of the same value as the tokens ID.
So this is going to return true if it is a match and the post should be deleted.
It is going to return false if something's off.
If the post ID doesn't match up or if the post was created by a different user right here.
All we have to do is add a little condition if there was no post existing then we don't want to delete
the post.
Instead we are going to throw a new error and say something like unable to delete post or unable to
find posts or operation failed or whatever argument text makes sense.
Now let's go ahead and actually see this in action.
I'm going to save this file and well we're going to do is create two users so we already have one we're
going to create a second one since we just deleted our second user earlier and we're going to add a
post for each of those users.
Then as one of the users we're going to try to delete both posts.
When I try to delete the post I own it should get removed when I try to delete the post owned by someone
else.
The operation should fail and we should get our error message so let's go ahead and knock this out.
The first thing I'm going to do is sign up a second user.
Right now I only have just so I'll use create user to create.
Andrew once again.
And I'm going to grab his authentication token and create a post for him so I have create posts over
here.
I'm going to swap out the old authentication token for the deleted user and paste in the new one that
I just got from that sign up request and I'm going to create a post with a title like post by Andrew.
I'll leave this as a published post with nobody when I fire this off.
What do I get.
I can see that my post was indeed created.
Now I'm going to log in as my one existing user and create a post for her as well.
So over here the logon page.
I'm going to log in as Jess an example dot com which had that same password.
I'll log in I'll grab her token and I'll bring that over to the Create post mutation.
So over here we have great post and I am going to create a post with her token and I will change it
to post by Jess.
Excellent.
Now if I actually run a query like our users query I should see that we have our two users and each
has a post.
Now as Jess I'm going to try to delete both posts.
We'll see one fail and hopefully we'll see the other succeed over in the delete posts tab.
I'm going to use Jess's ID so in the headers area authorization
we have a barer space the token.
Now up above we're going to grab the correct IDs.
Let's start by deleting Jessy's posts so the one that should actually work right here I have her post
ID.
I'm going to bring that over to the delete post tab.
I'm going to paste it in.
Fire off that request.
And what happens while it looks like things worked well.
I have the data about the deleted post and I can run that same query once again to confirm right here
Jess's post is gone down below as Jess.
I'm going to try to delete injuries post so I'll grab that post ID.
I'll bring that over to delete.
Post pasted in and this time things should fail.
I fire that off and what do we get.
We get unable to delete post.
Why.
Because when we found the post by ID we saw that the author ID did not match up with the person who's
currently authenticated.
Jess was not the creator of this post so our IF statement ran and our error got thrown.
So now that we know how to use exists inside of our mutations when we're trying to confirm that a user
does own something you're ready to continue on to the next video which is going to be a challenge video
will you'll be updating the rest of our mutations.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.