In this video as promised you're going to be updating the rest of our mutations.
So there are four left in this file.
We're going to get all four locked down and behind authentication then in the next videos we'll be able
to move on to locking down our queries and our subscriptions.
For now though let's go ahead and work with update post that is the first of the four.
We're going to change in this video and right here I have the challenge comments for what I'd like you
to do.
Once again big picture goal lockdown update post.
There are three steps for getting that done.
Step one we have to validate the authentication token that's going to give us the id the user id for
the user who has authenticated making sure there actually is a token and that its valid step to check
if that post exists with the post ID and the correct author ID.
So the post ID gets passed in as an argument and the author ID comes from the token.
We want to use exists similar to what we did up above to make sure the post actually exists before we
update it.
And if you dont find the post you can just throw an error like we did up above as well so.
Else throw an error.
Now if you do find the post are going to do the exact same thing were already doing.
And step three is to just test your work to actually run some operations from graft Well playground
to make sure all of this works as expected.
All right take some time to knock this one out.
Test your work when you're done come back and collect play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off.
Step one.
We are going to grab a request off of the context and step two.
We are going to validate the authentication tokens so cards user ID equals get user id passing in the
request object.
And now that we have validated the token we can go ahead and actually check if a post exists that matches
the IDs we have.
Now I am going to mark this as an async function so I can use a wait right here Konst.
We are going to check for a post exists.
We will await Prisma dot exists dot.
Post passing in our criteria now in this case I want to make sure the post ID matches up with the ID
passed and as the argument and then I want to make sure that the author ID matches up with the authenticated
users ID.
So right here I am setting author to an object and setting the id property equal to the ID we pulled
off of that token.
Now that we have this in place we can go ahead and set up our IF statement.
If there is no post bound we're gonna throw an error if no post exists throw new error with a message
along the lines of unable to update.
Post perfect.
Now there's no need to change anything down below.
Right here we do indeed have everything set up correctly and we can move on to Step 3 and actually test
our work.
I'm going to save this file and we're going to move into graphical playground over here.
I'm going to start by creating some posts using my Create post mutation.
So we need some data to actually work with.
Since we deleted all of the posts in the last video I had a post by Jess and I'm just going to add a
bunch for her.
I'm going to add one to three four Let's go ahead and add five total So just one more five.
Perfect.
So now Jess has 5 posts.
We can work with.
I'm going to quickly log in as Andrew and do the same thing.
So over here I'll log in as Andrew I'll grab his authentication token bring that back over to create
post and we're going to create some posts for him.
I'll swap out the token down below.
Pasting in the new one I just got from the lounge in mutation and right here I will start with post
by Andrew one that I'll do to three four and five perfect is a little bit of dummy data to work with.
So now we have a whole bunch of posts.
Let's go ahead and stay logged in as Andrew and try to perform some updates.
So if I run my users query I can see that each of my users has 5 posts.
I'm going to try to update one of the posts from Andrew which should work since that's who I'm logged
in as.
And I'll also try to update a post from gests which should indeed fail.
So over here I have my update post mutation.
I'm going to set up the headers we need our authorization header
the value of barer space token then we can actually pick a post ID.
So once again I will start by updating a post from Andrew.
I'm going to grab this first one right here.
Then I'm going to bring that over to update post pasted in and we're going to do is change the title.
So title equals a string and I will just say updated post by Andrew as an example.
Now if I fire this off what happens I can see that things did go correctly.
And if I were to actually run our users query again I should see that data changed.
And right here it is indeed changed.
Now as Andrew let's try to update a post by Jess I'm going to grab one of those IDs bring that over
to update post paste of the ID in.
Fire off the operation and right here we get unable to update post which is fantastic.
So there we go.
We have update posts all locked down.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next mutation which is create comment so we need to put this behind
authentication and we want to make sure that the created comment belongs to the logged in user.
Right here I have the challenge comment for this one.
You're going to lockdown create comment.
We have one validate the authentication token to update the mutation to no longer accept the other ID.
It is non-negotiable.
If you're creating a comment we are going to create the comment with you the authenticated user as the
author.
Step Three create comment with the authenticated user as the author.
So we are going to have to make a small change to our create comment method call then step four.
Test your work try to create a comment and make sure it does show up successfully when and only when
you're actually logged in.
All right paused the video.
Knock this out.
Test your work.
When you're done come back and click play.
All right.
How that one girl.
Let's go ahead and kick things off in the usual way I'm going to grab a request.
I'm going to then get the user id by calling get user ID and passing in the request object from here.
What we're going to do is modify the mutation.
We no longer want to take in that author ID over in schema data graphic.
Well we have our create comment mutations sitting right here and we have all of the data coming from
create comment input defined down below.
Right here we get the text we get the author and we get the post ID.
We are going to remove author we still want the text and the post ID.
We no longer want the author to be passed in.
Now that knocks out step two step three create the comment with the authenticated user as the author.
So down below there is no more args dot data dot author we just removed it.
Instead we have user ID which comes from that authentication token.
That brings us to step 4.
Testing our work.
I'm going to remove the challenge comments.
Save the file and actually try to create a comment.
So let's go ahead and grab the headers down below.
These are the headers for Andrew.
So this is his authentication token.
I'm going to go over to create comment which is sitting right over here to the left.
I'm going to paste those headers in and I am going to remove the author argument since that's not something
that's accepted any longer.
Now let's go ahead and grab a valid post ID.
If I were to fire it off as is it would fail saying that no post can be found without ID.
That is totally expected.
As Andrew I'm going to leave a comment on this post by Jess so I'll grab that Id bring that over to
create comment and paste it right in here.
Now if I update my schema this should be completely valid and it is and if I fire it off we can see
once again we were able to create a comment if I didn't have the authentication token in place this
operation would fail saying authentication is required.
Perfect.
So one more down create comment is looking really good.
And we're going to move on to the final two.
We have delete comment and we have update comment.
Now we've already changed several mutations to be locked down.
So for this one I've left the challenge comments intentionally vague.
Your goal is to lock down delete comment and update comment.
How are you going to get that done.
Well you're going to lockdown delete comment and then you're going to lockdown update comment.
So use what we've done already to figure out how to get this done.
I'm not giving you any more steps since it's something we've gone through before.
All right.
Take some time to do everything.
Make sure to also test your work when you're done come back and click play.
Welcome back.
Let's kick things off with the lead comment.
I'm going to start by grabbing our request object and then down below verifying the tokens so Konst
user ID equals who we're going to call get user ID.
Passing the request in and the next thing we have to do is make sure that comment we're about to remove
does indeed belong to this user.
The authenticated user.
Now I am going to use exists to get that done.
I'm going to mark this as an async method so I can take advantage of a wait right here.
Let's go ahead and do just that.
Konst comment exists equals I am going to await the promise that comes back from Prisma dot exists dot
comment and we are going to pass in our object and set up our search criteria.
We are looking for a comment where the ID equals the ID of the argument passed in and where the authors
ID matches up with the ID of the logged in users are right here user ID.
Next up we just add an if statement.
So if there was no comment existing that match that criteria were going to throw a new error saying
we can not delete it since we cant find it right here.
Unable to delete comment.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place for delete comment were going to be doing something very similar for
update comment.
For this one once again I am going to market as an async function and I'm also going to grab the request
object off of the context.
Now the first two steps are actually going to be the same.
So I can choose to write that code out again or I can paste it down below right here once again we are
looking for the comment with the matching ID and the matching author Id only if we find one.
Do we actually want to update the comment.
And I am going to add an if statement right here if no comment exists.
You are going to have our error message for this particular mutation.
Throw new error saying something like unable to update comment excellent.
Now that we have both of those completely converted and locked down it's time to go ahead and test our
work.
So I'm going to save mutation J.S. and we're going to head over to graft Well playground to start with.
I'm going to go ahead and create some more comments.
So right here as this user on this post I'm just going to add a few different comments.
We can play around with.
Now I'm currently logged in as Andrew.
So I'll just say something like Andrew comment.
I'm going to create that one and then I'll add a couple more into the mix and you comment to Andrew
comment 3 and Andrew comment for perfect.
Now that we have our comments created for Andrew I'm also going to create some for Jess so we can make
sure that things work correctly across users.
I'm going to go ahead and log in as Jess over here.
I'm going to grab her authentication token and bring that back over to the Create comment mutations
over here.
I'm going to use her token instead of this token then I'm going to create some comments for her.
So just comment one on fire that off comment to comment three and comment four.
Excellent.
Now we have some interesting data that we can actually use when it comes to testing delete comment and
update comment.
If I run in my posts queery I can change this to also fetch comments.
I'll go ahead and grab from each comment the ID and the text and if I fire that off I can see the post
that has all of the comments sitting right here.
Let's go ahead and stay logged in as Jess and try to delete a comment that she created.
So I'm going to move over to the delete comment mutation.
We do need to add that header in down below
setting up the bearer value with our token.
And now I am going to update the comment Id So I'm going to grab one of those comments that she created
over here.
We have just comment 1.
I'll grab that I.D. and I'll bring that over to the delete comment mutation.
I'm going to paste it in.
Fire it off.
And what happens.
The comment was indeed removed which is perfect.
Now let's have just try to delete a comment by a different user.
I'm going to have her try to delete Andrew comment one by grabbing that I.D. bringing that I.D. over
to delete comment and pasting that in right here.
Unable to delete comment which is awesome.
So the last thing to test is our update comment mutation.
Let's go ahead and do just that.
I'm going to stay logged in as Jess and I'm going to try to update one of her comments down below.
I have Jess comment for example.
Let's go ahead and change the text for that.
I'm going to go over to the update comment mutation and change things up right here.
I'm going to use that comment Id.
I will change the text too.
This is updated with authentication and I am going to grab her actual credentials from the delete comment
mutation that we just set up right here.
I already have the headers in place so I can grab them and bring them over to update comment and just
paste them right in.
Now if I fire this off it should work and right ear we can indeed see that things are working as expected.
So there we go.
We actually have every single mutation sitting behind authentication so we're locking down exactly what
someone can do.
If you're not logged in you can sign up or log in.
If you are lying in it you can perform lots of other interesting operations but with restrictions for
example you can't delete a user other than yourself.
Now mutations are only one piece to the puzzle in the next video.
We're going to start to look at how we can use the exact same logic with very little effort to lock
down our queries as well.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.