All of our mutations are now sitting behind authentication which means that people cannot create update
or delete data without being properly authenticated the entire database though is still publicly readable.
So in this video we're going to turn our attention towards locking down our queries.
We want to make sure that some data is still accessible to the public like all of the published posts
but things like my private drafts should not be exposed to the outside world.
That should only be viewable by me when I'm authenticated.
So we're going to start the process of getting all of that set up.
Now there is a reason that I've chosen to lock down our queries after already locking down our mutations
and that's because it's a bit harder to lock down our queries.
There's some gray area there with our mutations.
It was really black and white a given mutation either did or did not require authentication.
That is not true with our queries.
Let's look at the post query for example.
This can be useful in both a public and an authenticated setting.
When it comes to public use I want to use post to fetch the given information about a post so I can
show it to the user when they're on a poster page and they're trying to read it from an authenticated
standpoint I might want to use this to fetch a draft post.
So if you're authenticated you should be able to fetch a draft if it's your draft.
If you're not authenticated you should only be able to get back public posts.
So in this case there are ways to use the post query with and without authentication.
And that just requires a little extra effort which is why we're tackling it after already seeing the
basic set up in our mutation database file.
So we're actually going to start with this query.
Now the first thing we need to do is get an I.D. passed in the whole point of the post query is to be
able to get a individual post by ID.
So over in schema autographs.
Well I'm going to update the post query right here.
Some of our queries do have arguments set up.
Others don't.
We're going to go ahead and add an arguments list on for post and we're just going to take in a single
argument which I'll call ID of the type ID and I am going to make that required if you're going to fetch
an individual post.
I need to know the posts ID.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can actually make use of that inside of our resolver function over
here and to start I'm going to name out our four arguments we have parent we have args which is where
that idea is going to live.
We have our context and I'm just going to grab it Prisma from that.
And then lastly we have info.
Now the first thing we want to do inside of our method is figure out if the request is coming from an
authenticated user or not.
And currently the only way we can get that done is with get user ID.
So Konst user ID equals get user id like we've done plenty of times before and we are going to do the
structure request and we are going to pass that in as the first and only argument.
Now the problem with this solution is that the code down below this code it's only going to run if the
user is authenticated if the user is not authenticated.
This function actually throws an error stopping our post method in its tracks meaning that we can't
really do one thing if they're authenticated and another if they're not.
Now we could go ahead and added try catch around this to catch that error and run some other code.
But the approach that I'm going to take is going to be a little cleaner and a little easier to reuse
what we're going to do is make a small tweak to get user ID.
We're going to add on a second argument right after request.
The second argument is going to be called require off and this is going to allow us to use get user
id in two different ways now by default.
We are going to set this boolean value to true so you can pass in either true or false as the value
for.
Require uthe.
If you pass in a value of true we're going to throw an error if you are not authenticated if you pass
in a require off value of false we're not going to throw an error will return undefined as opposed to
returning a user ID.
So in the end of the day this argument is just going to give us a bit more flexibility.
Now the reason I'm setting a default value is so that we don't have to change everything over here.
We don't have to pass in a second argument because by default require auth is true.
And that's what all of our mutations expect.
They want to throw an error if there is no authentication I don't want to run the code below.
The nice thing though is that with this argument in place I could change my call over here passing and
false for that second argument.
This would not result in an error being thrown if someone was authenticated it would just result in
user id being undefined.
So let's go ahead and actually change a user ID to support this argument.
Now the first thing we're going to do is actually not going to change the functionality of our function
whatsoever.
We're just going to do a little restructuring to start with down below.
We're going to flip our IF statement on its head.
So instead of doing something when there is no better we're going to do something when there is a hatter
and what are we going to do.
Well we're going to do the same things we were doing down below.
So I'm actually going to copy these three lines.
I'm going to move those into the if statement then I'm going to take our air and move that out.
So at this point we haven't changed the functionality of get user ID at all.
We've just changed its structure.
Now the reason we're doing this is so that we can conditionally throw this error based off of the value
of require off.
So right here we're going to add an if statement if we are going to check if required off is true.
If it is true and authentication is required We're going to throw an error if authentication is not
required.
The rest of the function will run.
There is no more of the function.
So it will implicitly return undefined.
So once again we still care about the matter if the headers provided we're going to get you authenticated
and we're going to return your user ID.
The only thing we've changed is what happens when there is no header.
In this case sometimes we throw an error.
Other times we don't.
In the case of our mutations the error will get thrown in the case of our queery the error won't get
thrown allowing us to actually do what we want to do at this point in the code a user ID is either a
string if the user is authenticated or it's undefined if the user is not authenticated allowing us to
do what it is we need to do.
Now what are we going to do well we're going to grab that post out of the database.
No longer are we going to return that dummy data down below.
Now there are two main queries we can use to grab a post that Prisma provides us over in localhost 4
4 6 6.
We can explore this.
We have posts plural and we have post Cingular.
Now when it comes to querying data the Cingular version gives us way fewer options.
We can only limit buy things that actually make that post unique which in this case is just the ID when
it comes to posts plural.
We get way more options in where here I can actually filter posts by all sorts of interesting things.
And even though we only want a single post for the post query we are actually going to take advantage
of posts from Prisma just to use some of our where arguments let's go ahead and start the process of
setting this up over inside of our resolver.
Right here I am going to create a constant called posts so pleural post.
Then we are going to await Prisma dot queery dot posts plural passing in those two arguments we have
our operation arguments and we have info.
Now if I'm going to be using a wait I do have to mark this as an async function.
So let's knock that out.
And then we can turn our attention to what's honestly going to be the bulk of the code in this method
are aware argument what do we want to do to grab the correct post.
Well first we do indeed want to limit by ID so the post needs to have an ID value that matches up with
the ID argument.
This is already going to restrict it to a single post sense Id is unique.
So we either have no posts in the posts array or we have just one.
There's no chance we're ever going to get more than one.
Now the next thing we're going to do is determine whether or not this particular person should be able
to access this post.
So we are going to consider it a match.
If the post is either published or this user is the author We're going to get that done using our or
queery.
So over here inside of our schema definition for where we have or and or like and allows us to consider
something a match if one of many things is true.
So in this case if the post is published or the person is the author.
Now over here we can actually knock that out or get set equal to an array of objects where the object
is just the exact same thing we have here.
So we can limit by anything.
And in this case we are going to limit by published.
So right here published.
True.
Now we want to pass another object to or so we can limit by something else as well.
So the post is either published or this person is the author and we're going to check that by looking
at author setting that equal to an object and looking at the author's ID the value we're going to use
is whatever is stored in user id up above.
So if there is a user authenticated we'll have a real user id getting passed in if there there's no
user authenticated we're actually going to be setting this value equal to undefined which is the same
as having not provided it.
And that's a problem because that means this or query right here isn't going to be searching for anything.
Which means that it's always going to consider something a match if it's not actually limiting by anything.
And that's a problem so to fix that quick tweak to get user ID.
All we're going to do is return NULL.
Perfect.
So instead of returning undefined if you are not authenticated and require auth is false we are going
to return NULL instead.
Now with this in place we are all done.
We have successfully set up our query and the last thing we have to do is one throw an error if no post
was found and 2.
If a post was found actually send its data back down below we can knock both of those things out.
If we're going to look at posts length if the length is equal to zero then we can throw a new error
saying something like post not found otherwise what are we going to do.
Well we do indeed have our post and I am going to return it so I'm going to return from the Post's array.
The first and only element.
Awesome.
So once again we are taking advantage of the Post's query plural so we can set up our conditional logic
inside of where now that we have this in place we're actually all done with the post query and we can
go ahead and test things out before we start up our application.
Up above.
We do need to import the get user ID function in Port get a user ID from the file where it's defined
dot dot to get out of the resolver directory.
Forward slash utils to go into that folder then forward slash get user ID which is the file that we
actually want to load.
Now we can save queery dot J as startup.
The server with NPM start and switch over to graft UL playground to mess around with things so over
in local host 4000.
We actually don't even have a tab for the post query so let's go ahead and create one all the way on
the right hand side and right here we're going to set it up so it is indeed a query.
The query name is Post.
We're going to set up our arguments which is just one.
The ID will grab the ID in just a moment and then will provide our selection set and I'm just going
to grab my scalar fields so we have ID title body and finally published.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by leaving ourselves unauthenticated and trying to read a published
post.
That should work if I go over to the user's query.
I'm currently asking for posts.
I'm also going to grab their published statuses so I know what they are.
And right here we have this first post for Jess.
It is indeed published.
So let's go ahead and try to get it.
I'm going to copy the ID to the clipboard.
I'm going to head back over to my post queery.
I'm going to paste it in.
Fire off the operation.
And what do I get.
I do indeed get the post data showing up.
Now let's go ahead and unpublished this post.
I could do that via the update post mutation or I can just change the data directly in the database
for the post with the title post by just one.
Over here I have all of my post titles.
Here is post by gests one.
I'm going to double click.
True I can either check or uncheck the box.
If you leave it at question mark that sets the value to normal.
We want unchecked which is false.
Checked is true.
I click away.
I clicked Save up above and now the post we're working with is not published.
I should not be able to fetch it since I'm not authenticated.
If I fire off the operation what do I get.
I get post not found.
Now I should also get posts not found if I am authenticated but I'm not authenticated as Jess who's
the owner of the post so I'm going to use the Ilog in request to log in as Andrew.
I'm going to grab that token and I'm going to authenticate as him over here down below.
We have our HTP headers.
I'm going to set up authorization.
I'm going to set up a barer pasting in that token.
And now we can fire off our request again and this time what do we get.
We get post not found we are authenticated but we're not the post owner.
Now we can go to log in and log in as Jess right here I'm going to log in as her.
This is her authentication token.
She should be able to read the post because she is indeed the author.
I'm going to delete the old token.
I'm going to paste in the new one and we're going to fire off that operation right here.
I'm asking for the same post as before and this time.
I am indeed getting the data back so we can see this post is not published.
But since I am authenticated as the author I am able to get this data back and that's a good thing.
Maybe I want to show this in the back and dashboard and give the user a couple of text fields where
they can actually change the existing post content.
So now that we have this in place we have one of our queries completely locked down.
Remember it doesn't require authentication we just limit what you can do based off of whether or not
your authenticated.
Let's go ahead and wrap up this video with a quick challenge for you.
Up above we have our Me query.
You're going to go ahead and lock this one down.
Now for me we require authentication there's no way to get you without knowing who you are and we're
going to know who you are by grabbing your ID out of that authentication token.
So what are you going to do for this one.
Step one you are going to require authentication like we've done with our mutations unlike what we did
down below.
Step 2 you're going to use the correct Prisma query to get and return a user by their ID.
Then three you're going to test your work.
So if I'm logged in as Jess I should be able to use the query and get my profile if I'm logged in as
Andrew I should be able to use the query and get that profile.
Instead take some time to knock this out.
Test your work and when you're done go ahead and click play.
How'd that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by setting up all of our arguments.
So what do we have.
We have parent we have our eggs we have our context.
I'm going to grab a both.
Prisma and a request off of there.
And then finally we have info perfect down below.
We are going to start by requiring authentication.
So Konst user id we're going to get that value from calling it get user id passing in just request.
Now I could also choose to pass in true for the require off argument but remember we made it true by
default so we can actually leave that off.
In this particular case.
And down below we can now use the correct Prisma query to get and return our users.
So right here I am going to return here we're going to call Prisma data queery dot user and I am going
to search for the user by their IDs so where ID equals user ID from our argument up above.
And that's actually all we need to do inside of here.
Not too bad.
Now maybe you also used Prisma data exists that user to check if the user exists first.
So you could throw a custom error that would be perfectly fine as well.
You could also fall back on Prisma allowing it to throw its own error.
Now we can remove those challenge comments.
I'm going to go ahead and save query japes and test things out.
I'm going to create a new tab.
I'm going to set up the query for me grabbing ID name and email.
Now when I do that and I'm not authenticated I would expect an error.
So down below I'm going to remove this token which got copied by default from the last tab I was on.
If I actually run things what do I get.
I get authentication required which is good.
If I grab the logon information so I'm gonna grab the token for Jess for example.
We should now be able to see her profile when we actually log in.
So down below we'll set up our header's
And once we have the headers in place we're going to fire off the exact same query.
And what do we get.
We get Jess's profile information.
So there we go.
We now have Army query sitting completely behind authentication.
So this is actually a great set of queries right here.
We have comments comments is never going to sit behind authentication we're actually not going to make
any changes to that.
There are no such things as private comments.
If there is a comment on a post we know that comment is publicly readable.
So this is completely public me on the other hand is completely private.
We can't do anything unless you're authenticated and post sits right in between.
You don't have to be authenticated but if you are you get access to a different set of operations.
Now that we have some of our queries set up let's go ahead and jump in to the very next video and talk
about how he can handle some of the other ones that we have.
All right.
I'll see you in the next one.