In this video we're going to continue to lock down our application data and we're going to turn our
attention towards how we're fetching posts.
Right now we have a single way to fetch posts with the posts queries and this returns every single post
in the database for godless of whether or not it's published.
So we're going to go ahead and fix that.
We're going to make the posts query a public query so we're not going to require any sort of authentication.
But if we're going to do that we're only going to send back published posts now to get that done.
We're going to set up our OP args object to be a little different than it is right now.
Instead of setting it up as an empty object we're actually going to start it off with a WHERE condition.
Right here we are only going to get posts where published is true.
Perfect.
Now we are setting up an initial where a value on args and this is a good thing.
The problem though is that down below we could potentially be overwriting the object that we just created
with something completely different.
We still want to set up our or condition where it is going to change how we do that instead of assigning
a new value to where I'm just going to set up args dot where Dot or equal to the array we had down below.
So I can copy this paste it right here and now we have the same functionality up above that we have
right here only using a slightly different structure allowing us to avoid overriding what we set up
up above.
So at this point the Post's query is completely public.
You're only going to get back published posts and if you choose to provide a query we will limit it
by that as well.
If I were to save a query Dr. J asked we could actually test this out in the background.
I have my post to query a local host 4000 and we can see over here that we're getting a combination
of published posts like updated post by Andrew and unpublished posts like post by Jess one.
Now if we go ahead and write it with our changes in place post by Jess one should go away.
I'm going to go ahead and do just that.
And what do I get.
Post by.
Yes one is gone.
I'm still seeing a bunch of posts but you'll notice that for all of these the published value is true.
So now our posts queery is all locked down making sure we're not exposing anything that we don't want
to expose.
Now it's Challenge time and in this challenge you're going to create a brand new query from scratch
that allows a logged in user to get all of their published and unpublished posts.
So up above I'm going to paste in the challenge comments for that's a right ear big picture goal.
Create a new query for accessing your posts when you're lying down and you can call it something like
my posts.
Now I'll be honest this is actually the second time I'm filming this video the first time around.
I had you and this logic in two posts down below allowing you to use posts if you were logged in and
if you are not logged in that ended up making this query way more complex than it needed to be.
The code got quite long and quite complex.
So instead of trying to cram everything in one query posts we're going to end up creating a second one
and this should go a whole lot smoother.
So step 1 define the query and schema Dom graph.
Well it's going to have the exact same set of arguments and the same return value as the Post's query
below.
We still want that query string and we're still sending back an array of posts.
This time though we do want to require authentication so make sure to set that up.
Step 3.
Set up the operation arguments to just fetch posts where the authenticated user is the author.
Step 4 you're going to set up support for the query argument exactly like we end up doing down here
and then step 5 you're going to use not user use correct Prisma query to get and to return the data.
Last up you're going to test your work.
So if you're not authenticated you should never be able to get data back from my posts.
If you are authenticated you should be able to get your posts back.
Take as much time as you need to knock this one out.
Don't forget to test your work when you're done come back and click play.
How'd you do.
Let's go ahead and move through that together so step 1 we have to define this query inside of a schema
dot graphics.
Well over here it's going to be almost exactly the same as posts so similar in fact I could just duplicate
this line and change the name from posts to my posts.
We still want to set up that query argument and I still want to send back an array of posts.
The reason I'm creating two separate ones even though they're so similar is to keep each query focused
on a specific task.
Now over inside of query.
Jay asked.
We can move on to Step 2 in order to require authentication we're going to need our method in place.
So right here my posts setting it up with all of those arguments we have parent we have args we have
our context.
I'm going to deal structure both Prisma and request.
Since I know I'm setting up authentication and last up we have info perfect.
I'm going to set up the method body toss a comma on the end and now we can require authentication by
calling get user id so Konst user ID equals.
We're going to call get user ID and I am going to pass to just a single argument request.
I'm not passing in false because I don't want this to be optional.
I want to force authentication so I can either pass in true or leave it off altogether.
Now down below we can move on to setting up our initial operation arguments.
So right here we're going to have a Konst OP args where we set up where like we do down below.
This time though we're not concerned about the published value.
We're concerned about finding posts where you're the author.
So we're going to look at author and we're going to make sure the author ID is indeed equal to the user
id from up above.
And that wraps up step three and we can move on to Step 4.
Setting up support for that queery argument.
So right here what are we going to do.
Well we're going to knock that out if args dot queery exists.
We're going to set up oph args dot where Dot or end right here we're going to define our array of objects
and we're going to have to in the first one we're going to check that title contains matches up with
args dot query.
And then in the second one we're going to check if body contains matches up with args dot wearie that's
exactly what we have down below.
And that wraps up Step 5 excuse me step 4.
Now we're on to Step 5 which is very simple.
It is just our return statement more we actually use what we've built.
So I am going to return Prisma dot queery dot right here posts passing in our op args and also passing
in info that brings us to step number 6 which is just to test our work.
So I'm going to remove all of the challenge comments and save a query dot J.
S. and I am going to head over into graphics.
Well playground at local host 4000 and create a new tab for our brand new queries over here query we
are querying for my posts.
We don't need any operation arguments let's leave them off for the moment and for each post we're going
to go ahead and grab the posts Id the title.
The published value and the body.
Now currently we can see that this is invalid.
That's because the schema can't be fetched if I just refreshed the page.
This should become a valid operation and it is and not why I should be able to fire it off and see it
fail because we have not authenticated so right here.
What do I get.
Authentication is required.
Now I know that Jess has both published and unpublished posts so I'm going to log in as her over in
the ME tab where I am landan as her.
I can just grab the headers down below and I can bring them over to this tab.
Pasting them right in.
Now if I fire this off what do I get.
I get all of the posts just by geste just by the user who is authenticated.
I have her unpublished post right here and I have all of her published posts down below.
So now we have a few different options depending on what sort of information you want to get.
And this gives us a lot of flexibility when it comes to authentication.
We have posts for public posts and we have my posts.
When you're working in your back and dashboard and want to manage whether that's deleting or updating
the posts you've written so far that's where we're going to stop for this video.
The only query left is our users query but to actually get this one working as we want.
We're going to have to learn a few new things.
So in the next video we're going to go on a small side tangent as we cover a new feature of graphics.
Well then we're actually going to integrate it to properly lockdown down our users.
Let's go ahead and jump into the next video and learn all about that.