In this video we're going to continue to lock down our data and the focus here is going to be on some
less than obvious ways someone can get access to data that they shouldn't be able to access.
We spent a considerable amount of time locking down our individual queries.
For example my posts requires authentication while others like posts do not.
Now there's actually a way for someone to get the draft posts for any user without being authenticated.
And that's by just providing a selection set over here for example.
I'm grabbing all of the users using a user's query and for each user I'm asking for their I.D. their
name and their email.
Then all I do is ask for their posts as well.
Here I'm asking for the title The ID and the published status for each.
Now if I actually fire that off without being authenticated in any way what do I get.
I get everything back right here.
I can see that one post by Jess which is not published.
Post by Jess one with a published value of false and that's a problem.
So we're going to focus on locking down data when we have all of these crazy selections sets we want
to make sure there are no loopholes in our authentication system.
Now we're also going to learn how we can lock down specific fields for example.
It's a terrible idea to expose all users email addresses to the outside world so we're going to address
that as well.
Now to actually get this done to lock down the email and to hide draft posts.
We're not going to be making any significant change to the user's query.
This actually isn't a problem with the user's query.
It's a problem with how users are resolved we would run into the exact same issues if we were getting
a user via posts for example or comments.
So right here I have comments.
I then get access to the user via author and from here I could just grab their posts I could grab the
ID I could grab title and I could grab a published and once again I'm going to be able to see information
that I shouldn't be able to see down below where we have yes we have a post that is not published showing
up a little further down the list.
There it is.
Right here we have that data visible.
So once again not a problem with the users it's a problem with our selection sets.
Anytime we can select information about a user We can also dive in and grab things like posts leaving
us open to vulnerabilities.
How are we going to address this.
We're going to address this by making some changes to user data J S and customizing how some of our
fields like posts and email are actually resolved.
Now if we just wanted to hide the email altogether that would be pretty easy all we would need to do
is go over to schema doc graphics UL find our user type and just delete the email field.
Someone would still be able to create a user passing an email in but whenever it came to selecting a
user you would never be able to pull that e-mail value back.
If I were to save the program I could go ahead and rerun my query and it would actually fail because
we're grabbing I e-mail and e-mail doesn't exist.
If I were to remove e-mail and fire it off again.
Now things work.
The problem is that this is not the approach we want to take because that would also affect things like
our Me query which could be useful for generating a profile page.
So in reality I don't always want to hide the email I just want to hide the email.
If you're viewing a user other than yourself the authenticated user.
So how are we going to do that.
Well the first thing I'm going to do is make e-mail nullable.
So when you're selecting an e-mail sometimes you'll get a string if you're lived in as that user.
Other times you'll get no.
If you're trying to pull the e-mail for every user out there.
So that's the first step.
Just removing that exclamation mark opening the door for us to not provide the e-mail.
Under certain situations.
Now over inside of user J ass we can actually customize what happens when the user's email field is
resolved.
Right here like we've done in the past previously in the course I'm going to be naming one of the fields
in this case email and we're going to set it up as a resolver function.
We're going to have our same arguments parent.
We're going to have args.
We're going to have our contacts and we're going to have info and in here we can write some code to
determine whether or not we should send the e-mail back.
Now at its core we're going to return from this resolver either a string an email or NULL.
So if we actually just a return call I can save the program and we can see what happens when we run
our users query and ask for the email.
What do I get back I get back null for both users.
If I were to go ahead and return a string like testing one two three and see if the program we would
see the e-mail value as testing one two three for just right here and down below for anger as well.
So we don't want to return a static string we want to return the user's actual email and to get access
to all of this information.
Remember we have parent so in this case parent is that user object.
And what we're going to do is one check out this user is authenticated and then to see if the authenticated
users I.D. matches up with parent dot I.D. if it does then we know a user is trying to select their
own e-mail and that's fine.
If it doesn't match up we know they're trying to select a different user's e-mail.
And that's a problem.
So right here what are we going to do.
Well we are going to use get user ID first up what's important inport get a user ID from I got to go
up a folder I've got to go into utilities and the file is get a user ID then right here I'm going to
go ahead and grab off of context request and we are going to set it up our call like we have every single
time before Konst user ID equals we will call get user ID and I will pass to it two arguments.
The first is request and the second is false.
We are not going to require off here if you're not authenticated you're just going to get Knol back.
You're not going to be able to see the e-mail for this user.
So now that we have this in place we can actually set up our conditional logic down below.
And the first thing we're going to do is check if your that user or not the data we're going to need
to make this assertion lives on.
Parent if you forget what that looks like we can just console log parent.
I'm going to save user dot J.S. fire off an operation that would actually triggered this like my users
query.
And over in the terminal we now have a bunch of stuff printing.
Right here we have the start of the second time this resolver gets called that is for user Andrew.
Then up above we have the start of that first time it gets called.
Here we have the parent object for G-S.
So Parent ID parent die name parent.
Email parent dot posts all of the fields we selected over here.
Now how do we use this information to help us.
Well we set up some if statements right here.
We are going to set up an if statement and we are going to determine if the user is authenticated and
if the authenticated users I.D. matches up with the ID of the person where resolving so right here is
there a user ID then with the logical and operator does that user id equal parent id.
Now if that is the case what are we going to do.
Well we're going to send back the e-mail and the e-mail as we can see lives on parent dot e-mail.
So right here I'm going to return parent dot e-mail by returning parent e-mail this resolver is doing
nothing it's just passing the value through.
Now we can add on or else clause if there is no user ID or they don't match what are we going to do.
Well we're just going to return NULL hiding whatever value was on parent id.
So if I'm logged in as gests I am going to see her e-mail if I'm logged in as Jess and I fetch in Jeru.
The IDs aren't going to match up and we won't see his e-mail.
Now we can actually save user data J.S. and test things out.
I'm going to fire off our operation over here and we have Knol for the email field of both Jess and
Andrew.
If I go all the way over to one of my other queries though like the me query I should still be able
to see her e-mail when I fire this off.
And right here I can see the e-mail is still showing up which is awesome.
Now I could even take my authentication headers and bring them over to one of my other requests like
the users request if I use those down below I should be able to see Jess's e-mail which I can and Andrew's
e-mail should be hidden which it is and that is fantastic.
We now have a way to individually hide those fields based off of whether or not you're authenticated
as some user.
Now this is a great approach but there's actually a serious flaw with our current code and it might
not be obvious unless you run into the edge case to illustrate this and to dive into the meat of what
I want to talk about.
We're going to simplify our query so no longer am I going to ask for posts.
I'm just going to ask for ID name and e-mail and if I fire off the request we get exactly what we would
expect for just the person I'm authenticated as I get.
Id name and email for Andrew.
Someone I'm not authenticated as I get.
Id name and no.
Now what actually happens when this query fires off.
Well the first thing that happens is that it heads over to the query.
J.S. file and the user's method runs the one that's associated with this query.
Now what does this really return.
Well it returns for every user.
Whatever information was selected in this case we've decided to select ID name and email.
If I were to leave off name and just ask for ID and e-mail it would no longer be getting name back.
Now what happens after this method runs.
Well it runs our individual field resolvers if any are set up.
So over here it would run e-mail.
It would pass in as the value for a parent.
One of the individual items that came back over here that means the information on parent depends on
the selection set of the client.
And that's a problem because we are using things like parent and Dot I.D. which are not guaranteed to
exist.
So in the current situation just asking for the ID and the email.
Once again things go very well.
If I were to just ask for every user's e-mail though what happens.
We no longer get Jess's e-mail because we did not ask for the ID.
So this actually fails.
So we're not getting the e-mail.
And that's a problem.
I'm logged in as Jess.
I should be able to see her e-mail data for one field.
Should it change because a nother field is being selected or unselected that's a problem.
We're going to address this issue in the next video when we learn about graft fragments and don't worry
there will be challenges where you're going to need to customize field resolvers as well like we did
with the user e-mail field.
All of that is coming up.
So let's go ahead and jump right into the next one and learn all about fragments.