In this video you're going to learn how to solve the issue we discussed at the end of the last one where
if we don't ask for the ID inside of our query our code can actually run as expected because we're using
Parent ID right here.
So to fix that what we're going to end up doing is talking about fragments.
First we're going to talk about them engraft you play ground to see exactly what they can do for us
then we're going to integrate them into our Prisma application to actually solve the problem we're having
here.
So to kick things off let's go ahead and just add a little bit of code into any one of our queries or
mutations.
I'm going to stick with this one right here.
Our users queery a common complaint by new graphic developers is that we have to be so explicit with
the fields we want back there is no way for example to get all of these scalar fields for a user if
I want a field I have to explicitly list it out.
That means I do this in my queries I do this in mutations and subscriptions.
I'm constantly listing out the same stuff with fragments.
We no longer have to do that.
A fragment allows us to create a reusable selection set so we can define what we want once and we can
use it anywhere where we want those things.
So this is easiest to see in practice.
Let's go ahead and create a brand new fragment that fetches all of these scalar fields for a user.
That would be id name and email.
So right here we start with the fragment keyword.
After that we provide a name for this fragment.
You can think of this just like a variable name.
I'm going to pick something descriptive like user fields then we use the on keyword followed by the
type we are selecting from.
So with each fragment it has to be associated with a specific type.
In this case is it a user.
Is it a post.
Is it a comment.
It is going to be a user.
Then down below we list out all of the fields we want.
So I want ID name and email.
Now you can see that what we have here is a valid fragment because the user type does indeed have ID
name and email.
If I were to ask for something that the user type doesn't have like title we can see that causes an
error because we've been explicit about the type.
We are selecting from the can actually validate this operation before even performing it.
So let's go ahead and just grab ID name and email.
Now how do we actually use this.
Well anywhere we provide a selection set we can use the following syntax dot dot dot followed by the
fragment name.
So in this case that is user fields.
So in essence what we're doing is creating a variable here that we can use wherever we want to grab
these fields off of a user.
And if I actually fire this off what do I get I get.
Id name and email.
Showing up for both.
If I were to change this asking for just ID and name and I would fire that off you can see that the
results have updated correctly.
Now up above along side of our fragment we could go ahead and ask for other things like e-mail explicitly
so we can use a combination of the two in our fragments.
We could also ask for related data so I could grab all post IDs for example now.
For each user what am I getting I'm getting their ID their name their email and all of the post ID's.
If I actually fire that off we can see that is exactly what we end up getting.
So using fragments is going to allow us to avoid having to retype out the same old selection set over
and over again.
No inside of graft you playground this little demo client there's no way to share these between your
various queries and mutations.
But that's OK.
We're still going to be able to use fragments inside of our Prisma application to solve the problem.
We're running up against over in user data.
We can now integrate fragments into our application.
So when we provide our resolvers for fields like email we can also choose to provide a fragment.
And that's going to make sure that Prisma fetches certain data about.
In this case the user when a specific resolver runs.
So for this one we need the ID and with a fragment we can force Prisma to get the ID from the database.
Even if the client didn't request it to get this done we're going to make a few small structural changes.
First up e-mail is going to be an object not a function.
Now we're going to end up reusing this function exactly like we have it currently.
So I'm going to grab everything from the opening parentheses for our arguments list all the way to the
closing curly brace.
I'm going to remove it and we're going to set e-mail equal to an object instead on here.
We're going to provide two fields.
We're going to provide fragment which is going to be a string and we're going to provide resolve which
is going to be the exact same function we had before.
So we can just paste that in inside of the string.
We can now set up a fragment that Prisma is going to use and we can ask for the fields that we need
like in this case just the ID.
So right here we're going to create a fragment exactly like we did over here.
So fragment then we provide a name we can call this anything.
I'm going to call it user id on what type the user type.
And then inside of curly braces we provide the fields we want and in this case we just need the ID.
If I was using other fields like parent dot title or parent dot comment taxed I could ask for those
depending on the type.
In this case though the only one we need is indeed parent dot I.D..
Now you might be wondering why not also grab the email since we're using that here.
Well this resolver is only going to run if the client asked for the email.
So there's no need for us to ask for it.
Now with this in place we actually need to do a little refactoring.
Well Prisma does support fragments in this way.
It requires a little bit of configuration.
So we're not actually going to need to change anything inside of user dot J.
S. But we are going to have to make some configuration changes to how we're setting up the server to
add support for fragments.
This is definitely something we want to do as it is an essential feature when it comes to really locking
down your data to kick things off.
Let's go ahead and close all open editors and we are going to focus on just a couple of files.
Index dot J.
S. end Prisma dot J S.
Now and the end of the day the goal is to grab a single function from Prisma binding.
It's called extract fragment replacements.
It's a function and it gets called with our resolvers.
What it gives us back is something that we're going to pass into our Prisma constructor function here
and our graft Juelz server a constructor function.
Over here that's what's going to enable the syntax that we just used over inside of user J S.
Now in order to actually get this done we're going to have to do a small amount of refactoring because
our current application architecture doesn't actually make this possible.
The function that we're going to get needs to get called with resolvers those live over here but it
also needs to get passed into this constructor function in the other file.
Now maybe you say well we create things over here we export them and we import them over here.
But then we have a circular dependency where Prisma is importing index and index is importing Prisma.
And that's a problem with a small amount of refactoring though we can solve this problem.
But we're going to do is just create a separate file where our resolvers get defined.
We can then load that in where necessary and to start we're going to create a brand new file in the
resolvers directory called index Daten J ass.
This file is going to be in charge of getting that resolvers object built the exact same object we have
right here.
And we're going to be able to repurpose almost all of the code necessary for getting that done.
So the first thing we're going to do is grab all of our resolver in ports right here.
There are six query nutation subscription user post comment exactly like the six we have down below.
I'm going to cut these out and we're going to bring them over to this brand new file in here.
We're going to load in all of those resolvers.
Now it's important to note that this file we're importing from it's already in the resolvers directory.
So we have to do is remove resolvers from the path for all six.
Instead it'll just be daat forward slash and then the file name because the files are live in the same
directory as this file.
Now the next thing we're going to do is create a concept called resolvers and we're going to construct
that object the object that we have right here.
All we need to do is cut this out.
Then over inside of our other file We're going to paste it right in and from here we're just going to
export it.
So right here we can set up an export exporting resolvers.
Perfect.
So now our resolvers object is constructed in this file and we can inport it right over here.
Let's go ahead and actually get that done.
I am going to import resolvers from the file we just created that's dot forward slash resolvers then
forward slash index.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can actually just remove the colon down below.
And the resolvers property is going to get its value from the resolvers variable up above.
And we know the resolvers variable is just the exact same object we were previously passing in.
So at this point we have not changed the functionality of our application at all.
It's still not going to work because we haven't set up support for fragments.
But we now have an application architecture that will actually let us set up support for fragments.
So let's get to that.
Over inside of index dot J S we're going to be grabbing that thing from Prisma binding that I mentioned.
So right here in inport statement we need to import extract fragment replacements.
This is the function I was talking about that we're going to end up calling passing in our resolvers
right here.
That comes from Prisma binding
awesome.
Now where are we going from here.
Well the next thing to do is to call this function and pass in the resolvers.
And since the resolvers are defined in this file it's going to be very easy down below.
All we're going to do is create a new variable.
I'm going to call this one fragment replacements.
And this is where we are going to call extract fragment replacements and we are going to pass in our
resolvers object.
Excellent.
Now we can actually export fragment replacements from this file and we can import it into both Prisma
J.S. and source forward slash index dot J S and we can pass them into the necessary constructor functions.
So all of the refactoring we did was to make this possible to make it possible to create our fragment
replacements in a separate file that can be imported and used inside of both of those.
Now the question has to be asked what exactly is fragment replacements.
This is nothing more than a list of all of the graph Cuil fragment definitions.
And in our case we have just that one in user dot J S.
So extract fragment replacements takes in all of our resolvers.
It goes through all of our resolvers including the user resolver and it extracts all of those fragments.
The one we set up and it returns them right here and fragment replacements.
This allows us to specify the fields that are required for the resolver function to run correctly.
In this case the email resolver function requires the ID from the user.
Now we can actually import this from those two files and we'll be all done.
Our future will work.
So over in Prisma and J.S. we are going to inport the fragment replacements
we're going to grab that from the following file.
Forward slash resolvers forward slash in their index.
Awesome.
Next up we have to make a change down below so we have new Prisma we have our constructor function.
We have to pass fragment replacements in.
Now the property that we're going to be setting up is also called fragment replacements so we can take
advantage of our Yes six properties shorthand right here we can just list it out.
Awesome.
That's actually it for this file.
The next thing we're going to do is exactly the same just an index dot J S.
So we're going to grab resolvers but we're also going to grab fragment replacements
down below we are going to set up that property as well alongside of type deaths resolvers and context.
So right here fragment replacements awesome.
Now our server and Prisma are both configured to actually use the fragment we set up in user Dhananjay
as.
And we should be able to test things out and see that they're working.
So over here what I'm going to do is remove the little fragment example we messed around with and we're
going to go back to our standard example.
We were asking for an ID and an e-mail.
In this case things worked.
If I rerun it I can see that yes I am still getting the e-mail for yes.
The problem before was that when I didn't ask for the ID resolver wasn't able to run correctly and we
got Knol for both emails if I fire things off with our new code in place we can see that we are able
to poll just Jess's e-mail out which is awesome by using fragments we can really create custom resolvers
that do something meaningful.
Now it's Challenge time and in this challenge it's going to be up to you to set up a Netherfield resolver
for user alongside of a user e-mail.
Now this one is going to be four posts and it's going to limit exactly what posts you can fetch from
a given user.
We don't want you to be able to fetch draft posts only public ones.
So right now if I were to change this query for example and also ask for the posts for each user I would
be able to grab whatever I wanted.
Id title and published and I'd be able to see both published and draft posts right here for example.
I am seeing post by just one which is not published.
I should not be able to view this when accessing a user's posts.
So that's what we're going to fix.
We're going to leave the only way to fetch draft posts to our my posts query which already does a great
job at that.
So let's talk about what I'd like you to do.
Right over here I have three steps for getting this one done.
The big picture goal once again limit the users posts to just showing the published ones.
Step one we have to set up a new field resolver down below.
So we're going to add the Post's property onto the user object and the Post's property itself is going
to be an object with fragment and resolve inside of it.
Step two is setting up the fragment So we need to set up a fragment that ensures we always have access
to the user's ID which we're going to need in step 3 so any to fragment.
Much like we have down below.
Step three is to actually fill out that resolver method.
You're going to be using the correct Prisma method to grab all posts.
So you're going to be using Prisma query posts and you want to limit the posts you're fetching to those
that are published and belong to that user.
So you want to make sure that the authors ID for the post matches up with the user id on parent Id never
remember.
The goal is to return an array of posts because that is exactly what the Post's field was set up to
be.
In schema Dom graft.
Well if I scroll down to my user type definition what do we have under posts.
We have an array of posts.
That's why we are using Prisma.
Queery dot posts.
Take as much time as you need to fill this out and then actually test your work.
So if you rerun the query over here you should no longer see published posts showing up.
All right.
Pause the video test your work.
Then when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
Let's get to it.
I'm going to kick things off by creating the field resolver down below.
Now I could go ahead and set it up right here before email or after email the order isn't important.
I'm just going to go ahead and put it first.
So we need a new object and on this object we are going to have fragment that's going to be a string
and we're also going to have resolve which is going to be a function.
And let's go ahead and start with the fragment that brings us to step 2.
So I need to make sure that I always have access to the user's ID.
Otherwise I won't be able to figure out if a given post belongs to this user.
So right here we are going to set up a fragment fragment.
User ID on user grabbing just their IDs since that's the only field we actually need.
Next up down below what we're gonna go ahead and do is set up all of our arguments so we're going to
have parent.
We are going to have args.
We're going to have context.
I will just d structure Prisma off of there and finally we're going to have info now from here.
What are we going to do.
Well we're gonna move on to Step Three and fetch those posts so I'm going to return Prisma dot queery
dot posts and what are we going to fetch.
We are going to fetch all posts that belong to this users are right here for our operation arguments.
We are going to set up where I'm going to start by limiting it to the published posts so I'm looking
for just posts where published is equal to true.
Then from there we are going to go ahead and limit it by the author as well making sure the author ID
matches up with the value in Parent ID.
Awesome.
And with this in place we are all done.
I can actually remove the challenge comments and test things out.
I'm going to save user genius and let the application restart.
I'll head over to graft you playground and fire off the exact same operation and when I do so what happens.
That data goes away.
No longer are we seeing that draft posts it's published posts all the way down for all of my users and
that is fantastic.
That's where we're going to stop for this one our authentication system is almost complete.
There are only a few videos left.
So let's go ahead and continue on in the next one.