In this video we're going to be taking care of a few small and necessary changes that haven't fit into
a video so far.
Now the first of those changes is actually going to live over inside of query dot J.
S. in here we have our users query which is indeed restricted in the sense that you can't access a user's
e-mail or a user's unpublished posts.
The problem though is that we still let someone search by e-mail.
Now they're not going to be able to view the e-mail but if they knew someone's e-mail they could try
to search for it and associate it with a given account.
So we don't want them to be able to do that.
When you are querying for a user the only thing you can search by is this stuff you can see.
And in this case it is the name perfect.
So there is.
Thing one.
Now the other two things that we're going to take care of live in mutation dot J s and they're related
to create comment.
First of all an update post.
Second of all right here we're creating comments but now we've locked down our posts so we should really
only be able to create comments for published posts.
So that's the first thing we're going to take care of knocking this out is actually going to be a challenge
for you to complete.
And I have the challenge of comments sitting right here.
So go allow comments to be created unpublished posts only.
So what are you going to do inside of here.
Well we're not actually going to make any changes to this.
You're just going to be adding a few new things in the mix.
First up you want to check if the post is published.
Now you can use exists to get that done.
So you want to see if there's a post that exists with this ID that also has a published value of true.
Once you know whether or not in the published post exists you can determine whether or not you want
to throw an error if you didn't find a post throw in error then you're going to test your work.
So in the end of the day you should be able to create a comment for a published post and you should
not be able to create a comment for a draft post.
All right.
Take as much time as you need to knock that one out.
Adding just a few lines of code to this method.
Then test your work.
When you're done come back and click play
how that one go.
I'm going to kick things off by using Prisma dot exists dot post.
So right here we are going to create a contest.
I'm going to call this something like post exists equals and then we're going to await Prisma dot exists
dot post and if I am going to use a wait I have to mark this function as a sync which I will do.
And then we can define our search criteria.
So in this case we are looking for a post whose ID matches up with our DOT data dot post.
That's where the idea lives.
It's the ID we're using down below to connect to the comment to a given post and we also want to make
sure the Post has a published value of true.
Perfect.
Now if there is no post so if there is no post existing with that criteria what are we going to do.
We're going to go ahead and throw a new error and we can print a generic message something along the
lines of.
Unable to find posts or are able to create comment.
I'm actually going to stick with unable to find post.
Excellent.
The exact error message you used wasn't important.
The goal was to just throw some sort of error if the post can't be found.
Now we can actually remove the challenge comments and test our work.
I'm going to save mutation.
Jay asked.
And we're going to try to create a comment for a published and an unpublished post.
Now I'm going to go over to the ME queery I have actually I'll go over to my posts.
This is where we can get all of the posts for Jess.
I'm going to first try to create a comment for post by geste too.
Which is indeed published so this should work over in the create comment nutation tab we can go ahead
and get that done.
I'm just going to call it some comment.
I'll paste the idea of that published post right here and hopefully that authentication token still
works.
I fire it off and it does.
Right here we are getting our success data coming back.
Now let's grab the idea of an unpublished post right here we have just one.
It's sitting right here for this one we are going to once again create a new comment.
This time it should fail.
I'm going to swap out the IDs.
I'm going to fire off the operation and this time we are getting our error.
Unable to find post which is fantastic.
Now that we have this in place create comment is all locked down.
And the last thing I want to touch on in this video has to do with updating a post.
The goal here is to delete all post comments.
If a post is about to be unpublished So if the post was published and it's about to be unpublished because
of this operation we want to remove all existing comments.
Now we don't need to do that when deleting posts because we use that at Cascade directive.
But that's not going to help us in this case.
It's still going to require a very small amount of manual work.
So right here I am going to paste in the challenge comments.
Big picture goal.
Delete all comments when an publishing a post.
Step one we need to determine if this post is published or not.
Because remember I only want to delete the comments if it's published and it's about to be unpublished.
So step one use exist to determine if this post is published or not.
We can add another exists call sitting right here below our current one.
That brings us to step 2.
An if statement if the post is published but based off of our X-Com data it's about to be unpublished.
We want to delete all of the comments.
Now how do you delete many comments while you can check out delete many comments.
It's a mutation.
You can view it in the schema tab for Prisma.
Once you have that in place once you have your exists call here and your if statement set up down below
you want to test your work and so try to unpublished a published post and make sure all of the comments
do indeed get deleted.
All right that's it for the set up.
Take some time to knock this out when you're done.
Come back and click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with step 1.
I want to figure out if this is a published post now to do this.
What are we going to do while I am going to create a variable.
Is it published and I am going to await a call to Prisma exists.
Post to determine if this particular post is indeed published.
So I want to find the post where the ID equals args ID and where the published status is true.
Now down below we can write that if statement for step 2.
So right here if we want to see if the Post currently is published so is is published true and we want
to make sure it's about to be unpublished so is args dot data dot published
equal to false only under these circumstances do we want to delete all of the posts comments now right
here we can use delete many comments.
And once again I mentioned that you can explore that over in our Prisma schema tab.
We have our mutations down below.
We have individual deletions and we also have bulk deletions down below I have Duleep many users posts
and comments.
We are going to delete many comments and if we use where you should have figured out that you want to
delete comments where something about the post is indeed the criteria and in this case we are looking
for the post by ID.
So right here what are we going to do while I am going to await.
We are going to use Prisma dot mutation dot delete spelled correctly of course many comments and we
are going to pass in our search criteria are where I object.
In this case we are looking for comments.
Where are the post right here.
Has an id property equal to args dot ID.
Awesome.
Now you could have broken this out onto multiple lines you could keep it as one line.
The choice really is yours.
The end of the day though we have all of the functionality set up and we can actually test our work
out.
I'm going to remove that challenge comment and we are going to head over into localhost 4000 and actually
see this in action.
So do I have any published posts with comments.
The answer is yes.
Over here I'm querying for all posts and all of their comments.
I'm going to fire this off down below.
I have a post post by gests too.
It is published.
It does have a comment.
So here's what we're gonna do.
I'm going to unpublished it and I'm going to make sure this comment goes away when I publish it.
This post should have zero comments.
Let's actually knock this out.
So I'm going to grab this post ID.
This is the one we're going to change.
I'm going to take it over to update post and I'm going to paste it in.
Then down below.
We're not going to update the title.
I'm just going to change.
Published equal to false.
Perfect.
The next thing we have to do is make sure we are authenticated as the author which is gests.
If I go over to the logon page I have Jessy's authentication tokin sitting right here and I am going
to just swap that out with the token currently used for update post down below.
I'll remove the old token paste the new one in and now we can actually fire this off.
I'm going to fire it off and what happens it seems that the post was indeed unpublished and then I am
going to publish it once again.
Perfect.
Now at this point that post should have zero comments and if I head over to the original query and fire
it off I'm expecting to see this comment go away.
And right there it does.
Which is awesome.
So there we go.
We've cleaned up a few little loopholes and edge cases around our application and everything is now
pretty secure.
All of our data is locked down.
There is just one last video for this section.
You're going to learn how to lock down subscriptions now in our application.
We're not actually going to lock down any subscriptions but I am going to show you how you can do that.
In case you needed to do it for your own projects in the future.
All right let's jump in to that.