In this video which is the last video for this section we're going to turn our attention towards subscriptions.
So we've already locked down our queries and our mutations and we can use the exact same system to lock
down our subscriptions and that's exactly what we're going to do.
Now we have two subscriptions we have the comment subscription for subscribing to comments on a particular
post where we provide the posts ID.
We can also use the post subscription to subscribe to all published posts but we're going to do is create
a third subscription which requires authentication.
And this is going to be called my post and this is going to allow a logged in user to subscribe to just
their posts.
This would include both published posts as well as drafts.
Now to get this done what are we going to do.
Well we're going to start like we would for any other subscription.
I'm going to create my post sending an equal to an object that I am going to set up the SUBSCRIBE method
providing all of those arguments we're going to have parent.
We're going to have ours.
We're going to deep structure Prisma off of the context and we're going to have info from there we set
up our curly braces and what do we do.
Well we use get user id so we're going to inport that and use it just like we did from our mutations
and our queries.
So Step 1 let's inport it up above inport get user ID from we have to go out of the resolvers folder
into the utils directory and in there we have get user id perfect.
Now we can actually take advantage of this down below and it's going to look exactly like what we did
for the queries and the mutations.
I am going to the structure request off of context that I'm going to pass it in to get user ID.
So right here Konst user ID equals I'm going to call get user ID and I am going to pass in request.
Now if we wanted to make authentication optional I could pass in false.
But we are going to require authentication.
So I'll either pass in true or just leave it off and allow it to fall back to its default value.
Now there is a problem with what we've done so far and it has to do with what happens inside of get
user id in here to fetch the higher value we use request data request that dot authorization.
The problem though is that when we are working with subscriptions it's actually a bit different.
So with queries and mutations we're using standard HTP requests with subscriptions.
We are using web sockets and in that case the data lives somewhere else on request.
The data we're looking for for subscriptions actually lives on request dot connection dot context dot
then right there we have authorization.
Perfect.
Now why it's lowercase on headers and uppercase on context I do not know maybe that's going to get cleared
up down the line in which case it'll break this code.
But for now that is the case there is no rhyme or reason to it.
I'm not sure why that's how the library is setting it up but this is indeed correct.
So in some cases we want to use this in other cases we want to use this.
And what's the determining factor.
Well it's whether or not request data request exists.
That's only going to exist for our queries and our mutations.
It's not going to exist for our subscriptions.
So what are we going to do.
Well I'm just going to cut out what we have so far and pay it down below.
So now we have our two approaches we have our one for TTP.
We have the other for web sockets our subscriptions and right here we are going to dynamically set this
value based off of whether or not request daat request exists and to do that.
I'm going to use our ternary conditional operator if this is indeed truthy then the value for hetter
will come from what's right here in which case we want to grab the header exactly like we were grabbing
it before.
I'm going to paste that in.
Now we can provide our colon if this is falsie than the header value is going to come from whatever
is after the colon which in this case will be what we have right here.
So I'm going to cut that out and paste that in right after the colon.
And there we go.
That's actually all we need to change.
Forget user ID.
We just have to change exactly where we are pulling that authentication token everything else down below
is going to stay exactly the same.
Now we can save user id go over to subscription dot J.
S. and actually wrap up the rest of the my post subscription.
Now actually finishing this off is going to be your challenge for the video.
So right here I have some challenge comments.
The big picture goal is to finish the my post subscription Step one you need to define the subscription
in schema Dom graph.
Well all of our other subscriptions are defined over there and the same needs to be true for this one.
Once you have it defined you want to come back to this file and use the correct Prisma method to subscribe
to posts and you want to customize exactly which posts were subscribing to.
Now we customize what posts were subscribing to up above.
In this case though the criteria is a bit different.
We don't care about the post itself.
We care about the posts author.
We want to make sure the posts author ID matches up with the User ID right here for the authenticated
user.
Then step 3.
Test your work.
If you try to subscribe and you're not authenticated it should fail.
If you try to subscribe and you are authenticated you should see that listening message and you should
be notified.
Anytime one of your posts change to really test things go ahead and actually change one of the posts
and make sure the notification shows up all right.
Take some time to knock that one out.
Test your work when you're done come back and click play
How'd that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by making our small change to schema.
Well over here at the very top we have our subscriptions and we have our comments subscription payload
and our post subscription payload for comment and post respectively.
Down below we are going to set up my post and we are going to set it up with no arguments and the value
that comes back will indeed be post subscription payload.
Just like it was for a post up above.
So we had the same response type for both.
Now we can actually save this file.
I'm going to close this file as well as get user ID and we're going to move on to Step 2 which is to
make a change to this method.
We have to go ad and actually subscribe to data using Prisma data subscriptions are right here.
I am going to use return to send back the subscription that is Prisma datt subscription dot.
And in this case it is post and we pass in our options object and the only operation argument we're
going to define is where we want to limit it by posts that belong to this author.
How do we do that.
Well we start by providing Noad remember when we are working with subscriptions.
If we want to actually specify some criteria about the individual thing we use knode.
That's what we did above to filter by just posts that have a published value of true.
And that's what we did up here too to filter by comments that belong to a particular post down below.
What we're gonna do is look at the posts author and make sure that author has an ID value equal to the
authenticated user's ID.
Perfect last up we do have to provide info as the second argument to post.
So down below right here comma space info.
Now we can remove the challenge comments.
I can actually save this file and we can test things out to test things out.
I'm going to bring us over to well playground and we're going to go all the way over to our subscription
tabs.
I have one for post.
I'm going to repurpose this for my post so right here I'll change post over to my post.
Now if I fire it off in it's current state we should get our authentication error because we are not
authenticated and if I do sell that's exactly what I see right here.
Authentication required.
Let's go ahead and actually authenticate as one of our users.
I have the correct headers set up in one of my other queries like the meek query.
This is the header for Jess So let's go ahead and subscribe to Jess's posts by providing the authorization
header.
Now if I fire things off we shouldn't see the error.
We should get our listening message and that is exactly what's happening.
So now it's just waiting for one of our posts to change.
Let's go ahead and actually change one of them over in the update post tab.
What I'm going to do is alter this post that I altered a video go for Jess right here.
I'm going to take it from being unpublished to being published.
Now I'm actually going to fire that off.
We can see the post did indeed change and there should be a notification about that change over here
in our tab and right here.
What do we have.
We have our notification that that post was indeed updated.
So there we go.
This is how we can create a subscription that sits behind authentication only really needed to do was
make a small tweak to get user ID.
Everything else is very similar to what we've done in the past.
That's where we're going to stop for this video and that's where we're going to stop for this section
our entire application now sits behind authentication.
And we're going to be able to expand on this knowing that our mutations queries and subscriptions are
all locked down and someone can't just fire off some operations and completely obliterate all of our
data.
All right.
That is it for this section the section introduction for the next one is coming up now.
So let's go ahead and jump right into that.