Hey this is Indri with a quick update on my section to authentication I realized that while going through
the editing of this section I never showed you how to expire a Jason Webb token when we created Jason
Webb token we can set it up to be valid for a certain period of time whether it's one hour two days
or a month.
Now in this video we're going to quickly go through that process and the good news is that the Jasen
web token library has built in support for tokin expiration.
The only thing we need to do is make a small change to our calling.
JWT dot sign.
Right now we're calling it with two arguments we're calling it with our payload and we are calling it
with our secret.
There's actually a third optional argument we can provide this as an options object.
And this is where we can specify how long this token should be considered valid.
Now let's go ahead and pull up the documentation real quick so we can see where we can learn more about
this.
If I head over to Google and Google NPM and Jason Webb token it should pull up the package page right
here.
We have it and if I scroll down on the read me documentation we are looking for the docs for JWT sign.
We have our Palen we have our secret.
We have our optional options object and down below we can see all of the options we can configure.
Now I've used this library on a ton of different client projects.
I've used it on personal projects as well and the only option I've ever specified is this one right
here expires in this lets us set up a specific amount of time in which the token should expire and we
express it in a human readable way.
So right here a valid string value would be two days.
We have 10 H for 10 hours 7 D for 7 days.
And the actual syntax for what you can use is right here.
There's another library that allows you to express time as sentences as we're seeing there.
And if you pull that up you can see all of the ways it can be used.
So right here we have two days 2.5 hours minus three days one y for one year.
All of these are perfectly valid and what we're going to do is express our expires in value using the
syntax.
So let's go ahead and actually set that up.
We're going to configure expires in we're right here in our options object so expires in we're going
to provide a string value and we're going to determine how long this token should be valid.
Maybe it is one hour maybe it is two years.
In our case let's go ahead and start with one second.
So this token is only going to be valid for a single second and that's going to allow us to see what
happens when we try to use an expired token.
Now it's important to remember that this is not the only call to JWT sign we have we have another one
down below in our loggin request so we can add this one as well.
Right here we can create an options object I can set up expires in configuring it to 1 second.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place let's go ahead and test things out on actually going to save mutation
J S and over inside of local host 4000.
We're going to loggin after a second.
The token will expire and we're going to try to use it.
So right here I have my loggin mutation.
I'm going to fire off a new request and get a brand new token this token should already be expired since
it's been more than a second since I've clicked that button and we're going to try to use it in one
of our operations that requires authentication.
I'm going to use the query where I get a user's profile down below.
I'm going to remove the old token which didn't have an expiration date and I'm going to paste in the
new one which is already expired.
If I actually fire this operation off what do I get.
Right here I get an error.
I get an error with the message.
W.T. expired.
So Jason Webb token the library has built in support for this expires in property.
So all we have to do is configure it when creating the token we don't need to make any changes to how
we're verifying it over in get user ID.
The JWT Daten verify method is going to verify everything it was verifying before like the payload with
the secret for example.
But it's also going to verify that the token is not expired if it is this will throw an error.
So we have to make no changes to this file to get things to work.
The only change we needed to make was to how the tokens get generated.
Now let's go ahead and use a more realistic expires in value.
I'm going to stick with something like seven days.
I'm going to use seven days for signing up and I'm going to use seven days for logging in.
Now if I save mutation.
Jess we should see things working over inside of localhost 4000 I'm going to log in once again this
brand new token should be around and valid for 7 days which means that if I tried to get the user's
profile using it I would expect it to work since seven days have not passed right here.
I'm going to delete my old expired token.
I'm going to paste in that brand new one.
I'm going to fire off the operation.
And what do I get.
I can see that right here.
I am indeed getting the profile back.
Now if I were to sit here and wait for seven days and fire this off again the request would indeed fail
saying that the j w t has expired.
So there we go.
That's all that's necessary to make sure that our Jason Webb tokens expire after a certain amount of
time.
Now it's Challenge time and for this challenge you're going to be creating a new utility function for
generating authentication tokens.
Currently we have this in two places which is pretty error prone especially when it comes to something
as important as authentication.
So there's a chance that we change one and don't change the other.
That would be best to not have duplicate code which is exactly what we have the code highlighted here
is identical to the code highlighted down below.
So how are we going to address this.
Well we're not you are as you're a challenge up above.
Let's talk about what I'd like you to do.
The big picture goal is to create a utility function for generating our JWT leads.
So you're going to create a new file in the utility directory alongside of get user ID.
You're going to create a function in that file which takes in the ID of the user to generate a token
for and it returns the generated token.
Then with that function in place you're going to replace our two existing calls to JWT don't sign this
one and this one with calls to the new function that you've just defined.
So in the end of the day the goal isn't to change the functionality at all.
Things should work exactly as they're working right now.
The goal is to just dry up our code dry standing for.
Don't repeat yourself.
So take as much time as you need to knock this one out and then test your work.
Make sure you can still get an authentication token that's valid when you trying to log in positive
video when you're done come back and click play
how that go let's get to it step one.
I'm going to create a brand new file inside of the tills directory called generate token dot J S and
in here we're going to define our function and properly export it.
And I'm just going to follow the pattern I used over here.
I'll create the function and I'll export it as a default.
So right here Step 1.
I am going to inport JWT from Jason Webb a token since we're gonna be calling JWT sign inside of here.
Then I'm going to create that function.
So Konst generate token.
This is indeed going to be a function and I can just define it as an arrow function and we're going
to export it.
So right here.
Export we're going to export generate tokin and we're going to export it as the default.
Perfect.
Now with this in place we can go ahead and worry about filling this function out.
We're going to take in the User ID which I could just call I.D. or user ID and we are going to return
the generated token.
So right here.
Return and we're going to call JWT dot sign passing in the exact same arguments we had over here.
They're going to be so similar in fact that we can just go ahead and copy the whole call over.
So I'm going to copy one of our two JWT unsigned calls.
I'm going to bring it over to this file.
And the only thing I'm going to change is where the I.D. comes from.
No longer do we have a user object with an id property.
Instead we just have I.D. directly.
Now I am going to call this user ID so I can take advantage of the object property shorthand and there
we go.
We have a completely valid version of generate tokin.
It's OK if yours looks slightly different.
The big picture goal is to just get things functionally equivalent.
Now I'm going to save the generate token file as you can take advantage of it from inside of mutation.
Dot J S that is step 3 we no longer need to import.
Jason Webb token directly since we're going to remove all of our calls from inside of this file.
And I am going to import right here generate token and I'm going to grab that from I've got to go up
a folder into the utility directory and we have our generate token file.
Now we can actually call this down below.
So right here instead of calling JWT sign directly I'm going to call and generate token and I'm going
to pass in the user's ID.
We have user data ID and the same thing is true for longan.
So right here I'm no longer going to manually sign that token instead I'm going to defer that off to
generate token passing in.
Once again user data ID.
Excellent.
The last thing we can do before we save the file is clean up our challenge comments up above.
Now we have a single source of truth when it comes to generating tokens.
If we want to learn how our tokens are generated we don't have to look all around our project for everywhere
they're generated.
Instead we can just focus on a single function generate token to wrap this up.
Let's go ahead and test out the tokens that we get back over in localhost or 4000 after saving all of
my files.
Of course I am going to log in once again.
I'm going to grab this newly generated token and I'm going to try to use it with my me.
Queries are over here getting rid of the old token pasting the new token in firing off the request.
And what do I get.
I get my profile back which is fantastic.
We now have a way to generate tokens that expire after a certain period of time.
And this finally is indeed the end of the section that is for bearing with me through this bonus video
let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.