Hey this is Andrew with a bonus video showing you how you can allow users to update their passwords
so right now when an account is created you can indeed create it with a password.
You actually have to create it with a password.
The problem though is that when you go to update a user you actually can't update their password.
We're going to address that in this video.
To kick things off let's simplify the files we're using I'm going to close all open editors and we are
going to open mutation Dhananjay.
Yes.
And I'm also going to open schema dot graft.
Well the first thing we need to do is update the arguments that update user accepts.
Now we have update user input which is defined down below that is the type for data.
And if I scroll down to that and we can see that when we're updating a user we can choose to provide
the name or the email both being optional.
We're also going to add on password leaving that as an optional string as well.
So when you're updating a user you could update the password or maybe you don't.
That's fine as well.
And that's actually the only change we have to make in schema Dom graphics.
Well we can save this file close it down and from here what we need to do is modify update user down
below.
Update user currently would technically work.
The problem though is that we're not hashing the password.
We want to make sure that we validate and hash the password just like we were doing when a user signs
up.
Now in the end of the day we're going to have a very similar code.
So to avoid duplicating a bunch of code we are going to create a utility function that's responsible
for validating and hashing our password.
We can then use it anywhere we need to do that.
To kick things off we're going to create a brand new file in the utils directory we can call this something
like hash password hash password.
Jay ass.
And as the name suggests we're going to end up creating an export porting a function that validates
the passwords length and then returns the hash.
So right here Konst hash password and we'll talk about the arguments and the function body in just a
second.
And we're going to do is export it.
So export hash password as the default export.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place we can start to incorporate the actual functionality in the end of the
day we are going to need to import B script since we are going to be hashing the password in this file
so I can import the script from a B script J s exactly like we did in our other file in mutation.
J.S. Right here.
Now this function is going to take a single argument to the plain text password that should be validated
and hashed and what we do next is actually going to be really similar to what we do over here already.
These five lines are responsible for validating that length and then hashing the password.
We are going to copy them exactly bring them over to our hash password function and paste them in.
The only thing we're going to do is make a couple small tweaks instead of args dot data dot password.
We have access to password directly via the function argument then down below.
Instead of assigning the hashed password to a variable we're just going to return it.
So right here I am going to return whatever comes back from calling B crypt dot hash which is a promise.
And instead of passing in args data dot password we're just going to pass in.
Password perfect.
So now we have a modified version of that code.
We have a reusable hash password function which still validates the length and still actually returns
the hashed password.
Now we can save this file and use it over in mutation.
J.S. we're going to use it right here for create user and we're also going to use it down below.
When updating a user's password Let's go ahead and start by importing it.
So inport hash password.
From the file we just created.
That's dot dot forward slash you tills forward slash hash password and once we have that imported we
can use it.
So right here we do indeed still need to validate and hash that password and I'm going to go ahead and
get that done by first deleting our if statement which checks its length and then changing what we await
instead of a waiting B script dot hash we are going to await a call to hash password.
And we are going to pass in what the plain text password which we just had access to via args Daten
data password.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place create user is doing exactly what it did before.
We haven't changed as functionality but we have refactored it to be able to use the validation and hashing
functionality.
And that's exactly what we're going to do down below.
So for update user the first thing we want to do is see if the user is indeed updating their password.
There's no need to validate it and hash it if no password was provided to be changed.
We can knock that out with an if statement.
I'm going to perform a simple type check using type of we're going to look at args dot data dot password
and we're going to check if it is a string.
So right here is it a string.
If it is that's great.
We're going to hash out a password.
If it's not that's fine too.
We're not going to hash anything and right here all we do is a sign a new value for args dot data dot
password we're going to get the new value by awaiting a nother call to the hash password function we
created.
And we are going to pass in that plain text password which once again is args dot data dot password.
So what did we do.
We checked if the password is a string if it is we hash it.
And then down below that is what gets saved when the user is updated.
And there we go.
We now have a system for updating the user's password.
And the last thing we're going to do is verify that it actually works over inside of graft UL playground.
Let's go ahead and create a brand new user from scratch so we're going to make sure that we can create
a user and log in then we can update a user's password and still log in.
So over here instead of Gen. we're going to go ahead and sign up.
Sarah I will keep her password the same but I will change her email to Sarah at example dot com.
I'm going to fire that off.
And what do I get back.
I get back some data that looks correct from here.
We're going to fire off a separate log in request to make sure that still works.
Given the fact that we changed how users get created we use that reusable hash password function.
So if I go over to log in I should be able to swap out just for Sarah.
Fire that off and I do indeed get a token back which is great.
I can still log in with the user that was created.
I'm going to grab their token and we're going to move over to update user and give that a try.
So I have update user over here.
I'm going to swap out the old auth token with the new one for Sarah.
And currently we're just changing the user's name instead of changing the user's name.
We're going to go ahead and change the user's password.
So right here I'm going to go ahead and set password equal to something brand new.
I'm going to use ABC 0 9 8 7 6 and if I actually fire that off what happens I can indeed see Sarah's
data returning now not getting the password back and that's a good thing.
I should not be able to view the password from the database under any circumstances even if attached.
Now where do we go from here.
Well we have to make sure we can still log in with this password.
So I'm going to head back over to the loggin request.
After copying the new password to the clipboard I'm going to paste it in.
I'm going to fire it off.
And what do I get.
All right here I was still able to log in.
So there we have it.
We now have a reusable way to validate and hash passwords and it's working really well for us.
We were able to update a user's password via update user and we were still able to successfully create
users using the create user mutation which is now taking advantage of this new function.
That's where we're going to stop for this one.
Thanks for working with me through this update.
That's it for now.
I'll see you in the next one.