Take off this section I want to answer a very important question which is what is a graph.
It's right in the name graph.
Well and it's something that we're going to have to learn a little bit about before we can continue
on.
Now when we're talking about a graph in graph.
Well we're not talking about the kind of graphs or charts we would create in a tool like Excel to plot
some points over time.
When we talk about a graph in engraft Well we're talking about a way to think about all of our application
data and how that data relates to one another.
And we're going to move through quick visualization in just a second to show how this would look in
a real world application.
Before we continue on you might have noticed this is a presentation video I avoid using presentations
like this as much as possible in my courses.
I use them very sparingly only when I truly believe it is the best way to get information across.
And in this video I think a presentation is the best way to explain what a graph is.
Don't worry though like all my courses.
Ninety nine percent of this class is me and you in the text editor writing code.
But going through the process of exploring what a graph is is going to give us a solid foundation for
actually writing code very soon.
For this visualization let's use the example of a blogging application.
So we have users that are going to sign up and log into the application once they're lying down they're
going to be able to create and publish posts and once a post is published other users are going to be
able to read that post and add comments on to it.
So as I described in English there are three main things that we're going to be storing for this application.
We're going to be storing users.
We're going to be storing posts and we're going to be storing comments engraft.
Well these are known as types and types are things that we define when creating our graphed UL API is
something we'll be doing in just a few videos.
So in this case we have a user type we have a post type and we have a comment type of things that we
define and when we define the types that make up our applications we also define the fields associated
with each type the individual pieces of data we want to store.
So in the case of a user what do we want to track.
Well that's really up to us to figure out what makes sense for all of our types were going to have a
unique ID to uniquely identify that user or that post or that comment.
In this case let's say it's the string one and after the ID it's really up to us to choose what we want
to track.
So for a user maybe we want to track their name under a name field we'll store that as a string and
an example would be my name the string Andrew mead we could also choose to track other things like their
age.
And for me that would be the number 27.
Now each type we create is going to have its own set of fields so all users are going to have an ID
a name and an age old posts are going to have a completely different set of fields for a post.
We're still going to have an ID something to uniquely identify that post but then we're going to track
things specific to the post like the post's title the posts Abidi and whether or not the post has been
published.
So in this case I have added a title for my post.
The body is completely empty and this post is not published so we're storing the boolean value false
for unpublished as opposed to the boolean value true.
Saying the post is indeed published the last time that we're going to be working with in this example
is the comment.
So a comment is also going to have an ID.
In this case ninety nine and for comments.
The only thing we're going to keep track of is the comment text and in this case we have a very nice
comment.
Just saying.
Thanks for the post.
So for this visualization we've created three types.
User post and comment each with their own custom set of fields.
All of this should seem familiar because it's exactly how we would represent our data with any standard
database out there.
If I was working with an s ul database I would have a users table a post table and a comments table
where all of the individual fields were individual columns on those tables.
If I was working with a no s u l database like Mongo D.B I would likely have a users collection.
A post collection and a Commins collection where all of these fields were fields on the individual documents
created.
Remember that engraft you l doesn't care what back end you're using.
So in the end of the day it might be an s ul database or it might be a no SU all database.
Either way is perfectly fine.
Now aside from each of our types having their own discrete set of values we also have relationships
between our types.
So for example if a user creates a post that post is associated with that user so we would have a relationship
like the following where a user has many posts via the posts property.
Now to save space here this user just has a single post but he could easily imagine they have zero posts
or they have 42 different posts.
Now if a user has many posts that means a post also belongs to a user.
So each post is associated with a user via the author property on that it now there's relationships
between our other types as well.
For example the comment to post relationship a post can have many comments and maybe we access those
via the comments property and a comment is associated with a post via something like the post property
last up comment to user.
A user can have many comments they've written on all sorts of posts.
Well a comment always belongs to an individual user and we might have that association via the comment
author property.
So in the end of the day our graph could look a little bit like this where we have types user post and
comment.
They have discrete fields and they also have associations between various types.
In the end of the day this is how we're going to be thinking about and representing our data.
Engraft Well that's where we're going to stop for this one.
Now that we know the basics of what a graph looks like in graph Cuil we're actually ready to move on
to the next video where we're actually going to put our hands on the keyboard and write some graph.
Well code we're going to figure out how we can query from a real graph.
Well API I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.