You've learned that graft well is fast and flexible because it's the client that sends a query to the
server asking for the exact data it needs.
In this video you're going to see that in action by creating and running your very first graphical query.
So we're going to be making requests to a real world graphical API.
Now as with a rest API we're going to have a client and a server in the case of this course the client
is going to be a web app and the server is going to be a node.
J.S. l server.
We're not going to worry about either of those just yet.
That would be getting a little bit ahead of ourselves in this video.
We're going to focus on making a graph.
Q Well request to a server I've put together for us allowing us to explore this syntax without needing
to write a ton of code though don't worry we will start setting up our very own graph to API in just
a couple of videos for the moment though let's go ahead and mess around with graphs.
Q Well queries by heading over to a u r l.
This is graph Cuil hyphen demo dot Meade dot I O.
And when you head over there you should see exactly what I have here.
The tool you're seeing here is called graph Q Well playground and it's a little request response tool
for graph UL so we can see what would happen if we submitted a specific query to a specific graph API.
It's a tool we can actually install as a standalone program on our machines and we will be doing that
a little bit later.
By the end of the course you're going to be very familiar with how this tool works.
If you've ever worked with a rest API you've probably used some sort of HTP gooey in the past.
Maybe something like post man or insomnia.
In the end of the day the graft playground tool is the exact same thing on the left hand side.
We're going to type out our queries specifying the data the client wants to request we click the play
button.
It's going to go off and actually make a request to the API to put together and on the right hand side
we're going to get a response.
Now remember with Graph Q Well we just have a single end point.
So there's no need to make any changes to the U r l.
You should already have exactly what I have here and we're not going to make any changes to that.
The only thing we're going to have to change is the code that goes in this box on the left hand side.
This is where we type out the graft UL operations.
We want to perform on our server.
Let's go ahead and start by removing everything inside of here which is just this single comment on
line 1 and it will be perfectly fine to leave that comment in place.
I'm just removing it for simplicity's sake.
Now we're going to go ahead and specify our very first graft Cuil operation.
There are three major operations we can perform on any graph API.
One of them is the query.
And that's what we'll be starting with the query allows us to fetch data.
So right here we start off with our operation type for a query it is query in all lowercase.
Then we're going to type a space.
We're going to open and close a set of curly braces and hit enter inside.
Later in the course we'll be learning all about the other two types of operations we can perform one
being the mutation which allows us to change data.
The other being the subscription which allows us to watch data for changes which is great for real time
applications.
Now we can see we're getting a little error with this query and that's because technically we have an
invalid query.
It's not asking for any data which means that it shouldn't even be sent off since no data is going to
come back.
What we have to do right here inside of these curly braces is specify what fields we want from the graphical
API.
Then we'll have a valid graft you will query that actually fetches some data on this Demel graft UL
I've set up a few different fields.
We can actually query from the server.
One of them is called Hello and to query that field all we do is type the field name right here.
Now what we have here on the left hand side is a completely valid query.
It might look a little bit like Jason or some sort of weird javascript object but it's not it's the
graphical language.
And we'll be exploring it in more detail and looking at all of the awesome stuff it has to offer as
we progress through the course.
For now though we have a perfectly valid operation.
We're performing a query on our server.
We're requesting a single field.
Hello let's go ahead and run our very first GRATHWOHL query by hitting that play button.
And what do we get on the right hand side.
We get back some Jasen data we get back an object with a single property data and on there we have all
of the data we requested.
In this case we requested a single field hello which shows up right here and then we have the actual
data that came back from the server.
In this case it was the string Hello world.
So this is fantastic.
Our very first graph you will query with just three lines of code.
Now let's make this a bit more interesting by requesting more just a single field from the server.
Remember we can request as much or as little data as we need with a graphical query but typically it'll
be more than just one field.
So how do we do that.
Well right here we're just going to add a new line inside of the curly braces for our query operation
and we're going to specify the field we want access to.
I have set up a Netherfield.
For us it is called Course instructor of course instructor is going to return a string.
Much like hello.
And in this case it is going to contain my name.
The Course instructor.
Now you'll notice there is no extra punctuation inside of the curly braces.
We just have the field names on separate lines so I'm not doing anything like adding a comma right ear
like you would see with Jason or a javascript object.
It is just field one a new line field too.
Let's go ahead and actually run this query by clicking that play button.
And what do we get back.
We get back our data object this time with the two properties we've requested.
We have our field hello.
With the string value hello world and we have the field course instructor.
The new one with the string value.
Andrew Mead.
Now so far both of the requests we've made this one and the last one have worked.
We've gotten a valid data response and that's because both of the fields we have requested are real
fields that the server was set up to know about.
What happens though if we type in some random field name that the server does not understand.
For example course price.
Something I have not set up for this API.
We can see that right away we're actually getting an error and if we hover over that we get the following
message cannot query field course price on type query.
Did you mean Course or course instructor.
So we're getting some very useful feedback.
It's saying that the field we're trying to access doesn't exist and it's suggesting some other fields
that actually do exist.
We'll talk about exactly what the type queery with an upper case Q means a bit later when we actually
set things up.
For now the important thing to note is that we're getting very useful feedback on our fields before
we actually ever send the request off.
How's all of this possible.
How for example am I able to type in H and have it know that there is a helo field.
I can actually request that is because by nature all graph QOL API eyes are self documenting it is not
a feature we get with the rest API eyes with the rest API.
Someone needs to manually write and update documentation and in my own personal experience working at
companies the documentation either one that doesn't exist or two is severely outdated and basically
useless.
So what do you end up doing.
You end up just making a dummy request to the end point dumping all of the data out of the console just
to figure out exactly where the data you need lives what fields contain the data I need it to render
this page with graphs you.
We do not run into the same problem because your request dictates your response where specifying the
exact things we want access to.
So we know what the response is going to look like.
We don't have to play that guessing game any more.
All of this is possible because your Grath UL API exposes an application schema which describes all
of the operations that could be performed in the case of the query operation.
It describes all of the fields you're allowed to select.
That's why we're able to see that a field like test is invalid before we ever even send the request
off.
Now using this tool graphed you l playground we can view the schema via this schema.
Tab on the right hand side.
Now there are a few things in here we're not going to talk about just yet.
But let's go ahead and crack it open.
I don't want to leave it as a mystery.
The first four fields are fields.
We're going to ignore there a bit more complex and we'll talk about them in the next video.
That's users posts post and me.
But I want to focus on the last three.
Hello course and course instructor.
Now we can see that for Hello we have the field we can request and we also have the type that we're
going to end up getting back in this case.
It's a string which we saw.
It's also true for Course instructor.
We got a string back and the exclamation mark afterwards just means we're always going to get that back
as opposed to being able to get null back so we're always going to get a string response which is what
we've seen so far.
Now we've already requested hello and course instructor in C in those values.
What I want you to do as your challenge for this video is to change the query to also make a request
for course.
Now this alone might seem like a pretty easy thing to do.
And that's because I want to take this moment to introduce the challenge format like with all of my
courses.
The goal in this course is to get you writing code and solving problems on your own.
That's the only way to actually learn how to use a tool in the real world.
So sure it is important that you follow along with the code I write in the video.
You should have this written out already.
But it's also important that you get a chance to solve problems on your own and that's where the challenges
come in with a challenge I set up a problem.
I want you to solve using what you just learned and then give you a moment to pause the video and you
go off and try to solve that problem.
Then you could play come back and we work through the solution together with these challenges.
I never ask you to do something that you don't already know how to do based off of what was covered
in the course.
I'm also not asking for perfection.
There are challenges you just won't be able to solve the first time around and that's OK.
It's all about improving your problem solving skills and taking your understanding to the next level.
It's important that you follow along with the code in the videos and actually take the challenges seriously.
This is where you're going to build up that pattern recognition muscle memory problem solving skills
and debugging ability all of which are critical if you want to actually use graft well after you're
done the course if you don't follow along with the code in the lessons and you skip the challenges you
might as well just close down you to me right now because you're missing out on most of what this course
has to offer.
All right.
With all of that said let's go ahead and move on to our first challenge.
As I mentioned this one is going to be very simple because it's all about understanding the challenge
format as we move through the course and actually learn more about graft.
Well I'll be asking you to do more write more code and solve more complex problems.
For now your only goal is to change that query to also ask for the course then go ahead and run it and
actually view the response on the right hand side.
Take a moment to pause the video.
Knock that out.
Test your work and when you're done click play
all right not too bad.
So hopefully you took a moment to pause the video and actually add at the course field onto the query.
Let's go ahead and do just that.
I could add it at the end I could add it in the middle I could add it wherever I want.
I'm going to go ahead and toss it in the middle though.
Anywhere would have worked.
So right here we have hello.
We of course and we of course instructor I'm requesting three fields.
I would expect to get 3 fields back.
All being strings.
I'm going to go ahead and click that play button.
And what do I get.
I get graphed well sitting right here which is fantastic if you're also seeing graph.
Well as the value for course then you are all done this challenge and we are all done.
This video we learned quite a bit in this one.
So let's take a quick moment to recap.
The first thing we learned is that there are three main operations we can perform on a graphical API.
One of them being the query the query is how we ask for data and in this case we are specifying our
query asking for three fields.
Hello Of course and course instructor we saw that the request structure dictates the response we asked
for three fields with these names.
We got back three fields with these names.
All of this is possible because graphed QOL exposes the schema allowing you to see exactly what data
you have access to when making queries to an API.
This is a very useful feature.
Making graphics Well self-documenting making it a whole lot easier to actually use this tool.
All right.
In this video we saw some basic queries just requesting a couple of fields here and there in the next
video we're going to dive deeper into some more real world queries and actually explore those other
four things that we saw over inside of the schema.
I'm really excited to get to that and continue on with the course.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.