In this video we're going to wrap up our basic exploration of queries with the graphical playground
in the next video we're actually going to move on and start writing some code inside of our text editor
for the moment though what I want to do is explore how we can query more real world data.
It's nice to be able to query some strings and actually see some data come back but with real applications
we have complex objects and we have arrays of objects.
If we stick with the blogging example we might have an array of posts we want to show to the screen
so we have an array of posts where each item in that array each post is an object with a standard set
of properties.
A Post has an ID a title a body and a published value.
This is exactly what we saw a couple of videos ago when we explored how we can visualize our data as
a graph before we try to query a Florida array of objects.
Let's go ahead and just start with a simple object if we head over to the schema we can explore exactly
what we're going to end up querying.
And that has me now with Hello course and course instructor we got strings back and it was easy to make
sense of right here.
We get string values back but we can see that with me for the first time we're getting back something
different.
In this case it's a user.
Now a user is a custom data type I created for this application.
So for a blogging application we're going to have things like users posts and comments.
If I was creating something like e-commerce software I might have users products reviews and orders
in the end of the day a custom data type like user is nothing more than an object with a standard set
of fields.
If we actually click on me we're going to see the exact fields available on a user that we can query
so we can decide which of these we need and we can structure our query to actually get them.
We don't need to worry about the type definition for the moment we'll actually build out our own custom
types in the next several videos.
The only thing we're concerned about is that when we get a user back we're essentially getting an object
back with five properties which we can choose to select in our query.
Let's go ahead and mess around with an example query right here after our current three fields.
I'm going to try to query for me and you'll notice that when I do this we're actually getting an error.
This is an invalid query.
And if we hover over the error we have the following message field to me of type user must have a selection
of subfields and it's asking us if we meant to put curly braces after me when we're querying on an object
we have to specify which fields from that object we want we can't ask for everything because that defeats
the purpose of graft.
Well which is to have the client request everything it needs nothing more and nothing less.
So let's say I do on some stuff for me maybe I want all five of these in which case I would list all
five.
Let's say we just want to add the ID and the name.
How do we get that done.
Well we start by adding curly braces after me just like this.
Then we list out the fields we want to select off of me.
So me returns the user.
Users have these fields.
Let's go ahead and grab those two.
First up ID I simply list it like I would up here.
Then if I want another field off of me I hit create a new line and I specify that field to right here
I will grab name.
Now we can collapse our schema tab for the moment.
I'm going to click that play button and what do we get.
We get a brand new property on data me which matches up with this.
And you'll notice that instead of getting something back like a string we're actually getting back an
object.
So when we query for a custom type like user We're going to get back an object with all of the fields
we asked for.
In this case we asked for ID and name and we're getting back ID and name.
And you'll notice that once again the structure over here matches the structure over here.
So hello course course instructor and me are top level like they are here ID and name are nested under
me like they are in both examples.
So we've seen a basic example of how we can query on objects we can now add on that third field email
I could send off a new operation and I get back at the same structure.
The only addition is the email property on that me object.
Now that we've queried is some data off of one of our types which is essentially an object.
Let's go ahead and learn how we can query some data off of an array of one of our types or an array
of objects which in the end of the day is where most of our real world application data is going to
end up living.
Now for this example API I've given us two options for this.
The first is users which returns an array of all of the users who currently have signed up for the application.
And the second is posts which returns an array of all of the published posts.
Now this is going to allow us to figure out how we can actually query that data before we use either
though.
I want to talk about the syntax we're seeing right here.
For hello and that hello was the field we can query.
Then we had a colon space followed by the type we expect to get back in this case the schema is saying
for hello you're going to get a string.
And because of the exclamation mark it's saying you're always going to get a string if the exclamation
mark didn't exist.
We might get null back.
So if there was no exclamation mark we could either get a string like hello world or knowl both would
be valid with the exclamation mark.
We have to get a string back.
Now let's look at a more complex type definition like the one for users.
First up we have the opening and closing square bracket.
This is how we define that the return value is an array.
So here we have a string here we have a user here we have an array and the exclamation mark at the very
end says we're always going to get an array back as opposed to being able to get null back.
Now the array might be empty but if we do have items in the array we're saying they're always going
to be of the type user.
Never something like null so user exclamation mark says the array items if they exist will be of type
user.
The exclamation mark lets us know they will always be of type user and never know.
So we would never get an array where the only item was null.
Now this is a very standard type definition for the array of objects.
We're going to learn more about it and we're going to continue to use it throughout the course for now
let's go ahead and see what it takes to actually query for some of this data.
Now we could continue to add on to this query right here but with the graph playground tool we can actually
create a couple of tabs to have a couple of queries running side by side.
So what I'm going to do is create a brand new one allowing us to keep things nice and simple and focused
on what we're trying to learn.
So right here we are still going to create an operation of the type query and we're still going to select
some fields in this case it is users.
Now once again this alone is not enough.
This is not going to return an array of all of the users with all of their fields.
And if we hover over the error we're getting something very similar to what we got when we had just
me with no fields selected will we need to do is specify what fields we want for each user.
So right here we open and close a set of curly braces and this should look familiar.
It's exactly what we ended up doing with me.
So if this was me we could add the fields we want off of the user if it was users we can add the fields
we want off of every user.
So let's go ahead and select a single field off of all of those users.
I'm going to go ahead and grab name.
So what we're doing here is we're grabbing every single user who signed up for the application and we're
getting their name if we go ahead and run the query.
We can see exactly what we get back.
What do we have.
We are the single property on data called users which we should expect since we are selecting a single
thing in our query now in there.
We're not getting an object back like we got for me.
Instead we're getting back an array because users returns an array for each object for each user.
We're getting back the field we asked for in this case we have three objects.
We're getting the name for each.
We have Andrew we have Sarah and we have Michael we could select other things if we wanted to like the
email I could rerun the query and now we're getting angry with his email Sarah with her e-mail and Michael
with his e-mail.
So we're able to select as many or as few things as we need for each user in that array.
Later on in the course we'll also learn about filtering and sorting.
So we could exclude certain people or sort them out medically doing whatever we might need to.
For now though just being able to fetch that data is a great step in the right direction.
Now I'd like to move on to challenge time to crack open the schema and it is going to be your job to
fetch some data using posts now so far we've ignored posts and comments on user.
This is relational data so it links to the posts for that user or the comments that user has made.
And we're going to continue to ignore that for the moment.
We're just going to focus on the fields that actually resolve to a value as opposed to fields that link
to a another custom type.
The same thing is true with posts.
Each post has an ID a title body published author and comments.
For now we're going to completely ignore author and comments author links to the author for the post
and comments links to all of the comments for the post and we'll be diving into relational data in detail
very soon.
But for the moment we're just going to worry about these first four fields.
Your challenge for this video is to create a brand new query.
So crack open a new tab and set up our query operation.
You're going to query for posts and for each post I'd like you to get the ID and the title.
So instead of having an array of users with name and e-mail we would have an array of posts with ID
and title.
Take as much time as you needed to actually get this one done.
It might take 30 seconds.
It might take 5 minutes or 20.
Either way works.
Feel free to refer to the schema and refer to any code we written before or any previous videos to solve
this challenge or any other challenge for that matter when you have the query in place make sure to
actually run it and see if you can't get the right data coming back.
All right.
That is it for the set up.
Take a moment to pause the video try to fetch the idea and title for each post when you're done come
back and click play
how that one go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by creating a new tab for our brand new queery.
Now we have to specify our operation type.
The only operation we know about so far is the query.
So we'll provide that along with our curly braces so we can select the individual fields we want.
Now for this challenge I said you just needed to grab the posts.
So that's the only root field we're going to select.
Now we can't just select posts because what we get back is an array of objects.
So we have to specify what we want off of each of those objects.
What do we want off of each post.
Each post has a few different types.
We can pick from.
We just need ID and title.
So right here we'll set up our curly braces I will specify that I like the idea and I like the title.
And there we go.
That is all we had to do for our queery.
I can click that play button.
It's going to pass the query off to the server.
The response comes back and what do we get.
We get an array of posts as the only property in data.
Now for each array item each object we correctly get the ID for that post and we get the title for the
post.
So the first post graph Cuil 101.
The second post graph UL 201 and the final.
Post programming music.
That was all you had to do for the challenge.
Now we know how to queery on objects and on arrays of objects and that's going to wrap up this little
introduction to graphical queries using the graph Cuil playground.
We will come back to this demo a bit later in the course as we start to explore relational data.
We'll figure out how we can use other properties like author and comments.
But for the moment what I'd like to do is take things into the text editor and start setting up our
own graphical server.
I am super excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right into the next video and see what it takes to use graft well inside
of node j as.