In this video you're going to move away from using Grath you a playground with the demo API and you're
going to move towards Visual Studio code and actually writing code to create your very own graphical
projects.
In this video in particular we're going to be setting up our little boiler plate project with a couple
of nice to have tools for local development especially when we're working with graft UL and node j ass.
So I'm going to crack open my editor for the rest of the course.
I'll be leaving the browser here on the left hand side and on the right hand side I will have the visual
studio code so you can quickly switch between the two.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by creating a new directory for all of the code.
We're going to have in this course I'm going to use command 0 or the command here for your operating
system to open the folder on the desktop.
I'm just going to create a new directory.
You can call it whatever you want.
I'm going to call mine Grath Q L course this will contain all of the files and folders and projects
we end up creating throughout the class.
Let's create that directory.
We're going to crack it open.
And now we're going to focus on actually creating the folder for this first project.
We can call that one something like graph.
Q Well hyphen basics.
Perfect.
So we have the graph tool course directory for all of the code in the course and I have the graph Well
base ex-directory for the specific stuff we're going to explore for this first project since we will
be writing some code in this lesson.
I wanted to remind you that there is a lecture xit available for every single lesson in the class where
we actually write some code that xit contains all of the code up until that point in the course.
So if you lose your project or your projects not working you can always download the lectures to compare
my code to yours and figure out where you went wrong.
So don't forget lectures that for every lecture where we actually write some code to get things off
what I want to do is install and configure a tool called bannable in our project.
Babel is a tool that's going to allow us to use the most advanced cutting edge javascript features today.
In particular we're going to be able to use the six import export syntax.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by pulling up the Web site for Babel.
That is B A B E L Babel J.
S. dot I O.
If you come from a more front end development background you might have actually heard of or even used
a babbel before.
Particularly if you've worked with react.
If you come from strictly a node ingenius background it's likely you've never heard of or even used
babbel before but that's ok.
Setting up babbel is actually really easy.
We're going to be installing two NPM modules and adding about five lines of configuration code to our
project then we'll have babbel all set up and we'll be able to forget about it for the rest of the class.
In the end of the day Babel is a javascript compiler.
So we write some code we send it through babble and babble spits out other code.
This allows us to take advantage of cutting edge features in our code but still have code.
The output from babbel which runs in a wide range of environments.
So if I'm writing an application I might want to take advantage of the great features offered up by
the arrow function but if I want my code to run in an older browser like IEEE 10 I'm going to need a
way to actually convert that arrow function to something that IEEE 10 understands because IEEE 10 does
not and never will support the arrow function.
What's the solution.
The solution is to just pass that code through Babel.
Now as I mentioned in our particular use case we're going to be using Babel so we can access the ESX
import export syntax from.
Note you can learn more about babbel by actually seeing it in action and heading over to the try it
out page on this page we type some code on the left hand side.
The output ends up on the right hand side.
Let's go ahead and give this a try.
I'm going to create a simple statement Konst my function setting and equal to a brand new area function
that takes no arguments and has no function body.
So on the left hand side we had the code that we would write on the right hand side we have the code
that Babolat would spit out.
We can see that Konst has been converted to var since var is understood by a wider range of environments
and we can also see that our arrow function has been converted into a standard function something that
is also supported in a wider range of environments.
So this is just one example of what Babolat can do.
We can actually teach babbled to do almost anything.
If you want to learn more about how to configure babbel you can head over to the set up or Dachs page.
Though we're actually going to go through that process together.
Like I said it's super simple.
Install two things out about six lines of code and we're all done.
So let's go ahead and actually knock that out from Visual Studio code for this course I am going to
be using the integrated terminal provided by visual studio code.
If you're on Linux or Mac OS you're more than welcome to use that as well.
If you're on Windows though I'd suggest using a terminal emulator so you can access the same commands
that Mac OS and Linux users have access to.
They don't easier to follow along with the videos you can grab one of these terminal emulators such
as commander over at S.M. DDR commander dot net here you need to download the application run it and
when you do you'll be brought to a new terminal window where you can access all of the same commands
that I'm about to run.
I'm also going to be using some keyboard shortcuts in Visual Studio code for this advanced class.
I recommend you get familiar with the keyboard shortcuts for your operating system as well.
If you're not sure what a keyboard shortcut is for a particular command you want to perform.
You can always search for it using the command prompt.
So in the end of the day the only one you actually need to remember is the command to shell alchemist's
for me and my particular OS and setup it is shift command p.
You can go ahead and close all of the tabs to actually see the background panel and see what the keyboard
shortcut is for you.
Now I can search for something like toggle terminal and I can see that for me it is this keyboard shortcut
that is control plus the back tick.
So I'm going to go ahead and run that and bam the terminal pops open.
So we will be using keyboard shortcuts for those operations.
I recommend using the command palette to find the keyboard shortcut and then memorize it right here.
We're going to start by changing directories into the graphics.
Well basics project CD space craft Cuil Python basics.
From here we're going to generate a packaged Jason File for this project and we're going to install
the two modules necessary to get Babel up and running since node is a requirement for this course.
You should be familiar with generating a package.
Jason File and installing modules.
I'm going to be using NPM in it to generate my package.
Jason File for this project and I'm not going to actually change any of the default values.
So it's going ask me for about 7 different values.
I'm going to use the default one by just hitting enter about seven or eight different times at the end
it asks me if this package got Jason File looks good.
It does.
I type yes.
Hit enter and we're done.
Now all that command did was it generated are packaged up Jason File.
We're going to have to run an NPM installation command to get those two modules installed for Babel.
So right here I'll use clear to clear the terminal output.
And we're going to use NPM install to install those two modules.
The first module we need is Babel hyphen CLID.
This is going to give us a new command that we can run to actually pass our code through babbel and
have Babel compile it.
I'm going to specify a specific version using the at sign so battle C ally at six point twenty six point
zero which is the latest and the other module.
We're going to need.
Which is actually going to process.
Import Export is babbel hyphen preset hyphen envy.
So this allows us to run a command to compile Babel.
This tells babbel exactly what it should change.
We're going to provide a specific version number for this one too.
That is at one point seven point zero which is the latest we can go ahead and run that command.
That's going to get both of those installed.
Then only have to do is write about four lines of configuration code to tell Babel to use that NVI preset.
So our import export code gets converted correctly and is compatible with Node.
We can add a single file to our project to get that done.
You want to toss this in the root of the graph.
Q Well base x project we need to call that one dot Babel are C and in the end of the day.
This is just a Jason File or we can figure how babbel works.
We're going to provide our root object with a single property.
The pre-sets property.
So right here in double quotes pre-sets the value for pre-sets is an array and we provide as strings
the names of all the presets we want to use.
In this case we installed just one.
So we're going to provide just a single string in this array.
Ian V.
Excellent.
And there we go.
Babbel is all configured and ready to go for the rest of the class.
Now before we can actually run any code we need to create a source directory and some sort of entry
point for our application.
I'm going to create a source folder in the root of the project called SIRC and in there I am going to
create the entry point for this application and I'll call that file something along the lines of index
dot J as we can add some content inside of here like a simple console a dialog call just to make sure
the file runs successfully right here.
Something along the lines of Hello graft UL or any other generic message will get the job done.
The last thing we're gonna do before we actually run this file is to make a new script in package dot
Jason that allows us to run things through Babel.
So right here I'm going to create a new start script so I'll add a new property on to the start object.
We will set its value equal to a string as well.
And this string is going to be the following Babel hyphen Noad space then the path to our Biles source
lowered slash index dot Jay ass babbel node is what we're going to end up using for local development
purposes only.
We'll talk much more about how to create and run this project and production later in the course when
we actually deploy our projects live to the Web.
But for now this is a fantastic way to get started.
If we go ahead and save package dot Jason we can run that starts script right here.
NPM run start.
I'm going to run through the script.
And what do we get.
We get our little message showing up hello graph.
Prints.
So when we run that command a babel grabs the file we specified it passes it through the babbel compiler
using the configuration we provided then the output file is what actually runs the output file isn't
saved anywhere to our hard drive.
It's just executed by the command itself.
Now currently we're not using any feature that would be unsupported otherwise.
So we're not getting any real advantage from babbel that's all going to change though in the very next
video when we start exploring the ESX import export syntax.
So as long as you're seeing Hello graft.
Well printing right here you are all ready to continue on to the next lecture and we're going to dive
a bit deeper into how that syntax works because it's something we'll be using throughout the entire
class.