In this video you're going to learn about the E-6 import export syntax which like require is going to
allow us to break up our application into multiple distinct files.
So instead of having one huge file we can break up our app into many smaller files each concerned with
some sort of specific logical goal.
This is also going to allow us to load in code from third party libraries we install which is something
we'll be doing in the very next video when we install and use a graph QOL library for the moment though
we're going to play around with this new syntax with a couple of local dummy files.
So right here in the source directory I'd like to create a new file we can call it something like my
a module Dhananjay s and this file is going to contain some code that's necessary for index dodgiest
to run.
So maybe I have a few functions or some objects or strings or whatever that I need to export over here.
And inport over here.
How exactly would we get that done.
To kick things off let's say that we want to actually create this string in my module.
So I want to define the string over here.
I want to export it.
I then want to be able to import the string into this file and actually print it using council dot Lague.
How would we get that done.
Let's start from a nice clean slate.
Nothing in either file and we're going to start by adding some content to my module that J S under is
going to create a new variable to store my message Konst message equals.
Then right here we're going to define our message some message from my module.
J S.
Perfect.
Now we actually have to export it.
Creating the variable alone is not enough.
We can use the export statement to get that done.
How do we do that.
We start with export.
Then we set up a pair of curly braces and we list out comma separated all of the things we wanted to
export.
In this case there's just a single variable in the file.
So all we would do is list out message if we had another variable called name.
I could add comma space name to export that as well.
But in this case just one thing to export.
So I'll add just one thing in the curly braces.
Now this file is actually done.
We've created our variable and we've exported it in indexed at J S.
We're now going to import that file.
Grab that variable and then do something simple like print it to the screen.
Though later on we'll be exporting and importing functions and calling those functions.
The import statement has four major components.
The first is just the inport keyword.
So right here in part after that we're going to open and close a set of curly braces and we're going
to list all of the things we actually want to inport.
So if I was exporting 60 different things over here I might not actually need all 60 things over here
so I can list out just the stuff I want.
We only have one thing to choose from.
And I am going to go ahead and grab it.
So I'll list out the variable right here message exactly matching up with what was export it message.
Now you'll notice that this line has become gray.
That's because we're actually not using message down below.
It's just letting us know that we've imported something we're not using.
We'll fix that in a moment when we actually use the message variable after the closing curly brace.
We have to provide the froma keyword and specify where we're getting message from.
In this case we're getting it from the my module file.
So right here I'm going to open and close a set of single quotes and we're going to define a relative
path from index dot J S to the correct module file.
So we'll start with daat forward slash.
This is going to bring us to the same directory as index dot J S which is the source directory.
Since my module sits in the source directory I can access it right here my module.
J ass.
Now you can actually leave off the dot J.S. extension.
It's the default extension and it's not necessary.
So don't forward slash my module gets the job done.
Now we have this thing imported but to make sure we're actually getting the correct value.
Let's go ahead and use it.
Cancel dialog printing the message variable to the console.
You notice that when I added this line this line got syntax highlighting.
Since the content we're importing is actually being used.
Let's go ahead and run this file down below.
NPM run start is going to run our script passing it through Babel.
And what do I get.
I get the correct message some message from my module.
Dot J S.
So there we go.
We've seen our first import and export statement successfully working allowing us to break up our application
into multiple files.
This particular type of export is known as a named export.
So right here I'll leave a little note.
The unnamed export and it's called the named export because it has a name.
There is a specific name or exporting and you have to import it by the same name.
The nice thing with a named expert is we can have as many as we like have as many as needed.
So for example right here I could set up a nother Konst name I could set it equal to the string.
Andrew you can use your own name and we could export that to.
I could add that on to the list.
So after message a space name.
Now this file is exporting to think it would be perfectly fine if indexed out J just needed one of them.
This is still valid code but we can also choose to grab that second one if we wanted to as well.
We grab it by its name then we could add another use of it down below.
Council dot Lague printing the name to the council.
So now we're exporting two named exports we're importing both of them and we're using both just printing
them.
If I save both files and I rerun things from the terminal What do we get.
We get two messages printing.
We have some message from module dot.
J.S. first then we have Andrew Sacket.
Aside from the name and export there is one other type of export we can have and that is the default
export.
The difference between the two types of exports is that the default export has no name.
And you can only have one you can only have one.
So let's actually see this in action down below.
All I'm going to do is create a third string so Konst I'll call this something like location and I'll
just said it equal to a string that has my current city in it.
I'm currently in Philadelphia so I'll toss that right there.
Now to actually export this as the default export we have to modify our export statement.
But I'm going to do is set it up like I would for a named export.
So comma space location.
Then we're going to tag it as the default by using as default.
Afterwards when we tag it as the default we are choosing that one as our default export since we can
only have one.
I couldn't tag message as the default and also tag location as the default.
I have to pick just one at most.
Obviously we already saw you don't need a default export but if you are going to choose to use it you
can pick just one value.
Now this file is all done.
We've successfully set this up as the default export.
Let's go ahead and move into index dot J.S. and see exactly what it takes to grab that value and use
it.
We're going to modify our inport statement and when we want to grab the default export we actually give
it a name right here after the inport keyword.
So I can pick whatever name I want something like my current location.
Then we add a comma.
If we're also providing named exports so this would be example of an import statement that grabs all
types we grab named we grab the defaults.
We could also choose to do something like this.
Import my current location from forward slash my module.
In this case we don't need the comma because we're not grabbing any named exports.
We're just grabbing the default export.
This would be perfectly valid as well.
In our case let's stick with that first line where we grab all three we've successfully loaded that
in and I'm going to go ahead and use it down below counsil dialog.
My current location.
Now you'll notice that the name I chose for the variable over here does not match up with the name over
here.
This is because unlike a named export the default export has no name.
We are importing it by its role.
It is because it's the default export that we're able to get the correct value over here.
Let's go ahead and save all of our files.
I'm going to rerun things from the terminal and we should see our third message printing.
I have the first two correctly and I have the new third message correctly printing Philadelphia to the
screen.
Now remember for these examples I chose to export strings just to keep things simple but in most cases
we would be exporting a function.
So let's see an example of that too.
I'm going to go ahead and set up a fourth export.
So right here Konst and I'm going to call this one.
Something like get greeting get greeting is going to be a function I'll use an arrow function and we
are going to take an argument I'm going to take in some sort of name.
Now down below what is the function itself going to do.
Well I'm going to do is return a template string.
This string is going to use the name to generate some sort of generic greeting.
Others have something simple like.
Welcome to the course followed by the person's name.
So right here I'll add their name in.
There we go.
A very simple function.
We take an argument we return a string.
Now we can set this up as a named export.
Down below.
Let's go ahead and do just that.
So right here get greeting with a comma afterwards you now have a completely valid export statement.
I can save this file.
We can actually load in get greeting and call it over here.
First up let's go ahead and load it in get greeting then let's go ahead and use it.
So I'm going to call cancel that log to print something I'm going to print the return value that comes
back from calling get greeting and since Get greeting does take a name I will pass a name in.
I'm just going to pass in the name of Jessica.
So I would expect in the end of the day to see the message.
Welcome to the course with Jessica printing.
I'm going to save index dot J.S. rerun things from the terminal.
And what do we end up getting.
We get just that.
Welcome to the course Jessica.
So using the import and export statements we can share values between our files and this is something
we're going to be doing throughout the entire course in this video we took a basic look at the syntax.
We'll see more and more real world examples as we move through the class.
We'll also see examples where we load in things like functions from third party libraries.
Now it's Challenge time and for this challenge you're going to be creating a new file like my module
you're going to set up and export a couple of things you're going to use them in this file.
And that'll make sure we actually understand how import and export work down below.
I have a few comments for how to get this done.
So for almost all challenges in this course I am going to give you a list of steps you need to complete
to make sure we're all at least on the same page.
This is just a general guideline.
The actual details of the code are not something I'm ever going to give you in the steps.
That's the whole point of the challenge.
So here's the goal.
The goal is to create a brand new file export a couple of functions and then import and use them over
here.
So step one you're going to create a brand new file called Math dot Jay ass in there.
You're going to define two functions.
First we're going to define an add function.
This should take in two arguments and return the sum.
So add them up return the result.
Step three in that same file you're also going to define a subtract function.
So you'll take in two arguments you'll subtract them and return the result.
Step 4 you're going to set up the add function as the default export and you're going to set up the
subtract function as a named export.
Step 6 from this file index Dhananjay as you are going to import both of those functions and then you're
going to use them to add up to numbers.
Print the result subtract two numbers and print the result making sure you're getting everything correct.
The last thing to do is to actually run your file and ensure that you see the results for your addition
and subtraction operations.
All right take some time to pause the video.
Knock this out then go ahead and test your work when you're done.
Come back and click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off with step 1 or we're going to create that brand new file.
So in the source folder a new file called Mathcad J S and in there we're going to define both add and
subtract so Konst add equals.
Now when it comes to the actual details of some of these challenges it's not too important if you used
something like the function or if you used something like the Arrow function.
If I didn't specify it in the challenge itself you could really go either way just fine.
I'm going to go ahead and use an arrow function though and I am going to use the shorthand syntax for
this simple function so I'm taking into arguments a and b and then I am going to implicitly return the
result of a plus b and I'll do the same thing for subtract.
So right here Konst subtract I'm taking into arguments a and b or Z and Y or one into whatever you chose
to call them is perfectly fine a minus B.
Now that covers step 2 and step 3 step 4 and 5 we want to set up add as the default export and subtract
as the named export.
So I'll use an export statement down below.
Inside of curly braces will set up and as default then a comma space and we'll set up subtract as a
named export.
So we just provide its name and there we go.
Everything in math that J S is all wrapped up and ready to go over inside of index Dhananjay as we can
move on to the last two steps.
We want to inport both of those new functions and then actually used them.
So right here.
Index dot J as a wipe all of the current file contents aside from the challenge steps.
I'm going to use inport to grab both of those things.
We start off with the default export if we're actually going to grab it.
Which I am.
I can call this whatever we like.
I could call it ad but since it's the default.
I could also call it my add function which I'll do just to prove the point.
Then a comma space if we are going to provide some named exports we want as well which we are.
And in this case we just have one called subtract awesome last up.
Where are these coming from.
Well they're coming from the file we just created.
So in single quotes duck forward slash.
Which gets us to the source directory then the files sitting in and right inside of there so math we
don't need to add the JSA extension since Jesus is the default extension it's going to look for.
Now we can use both of them counsil dialog.
I'm going to call my add function.
I'm going to pass in two numbers.
I'll add up one end to minus two resulting in minus one and then I'll do another council log call for
my subtract function call right here.
I'm going to take 10 and I am going to subtract two.
The result being eight.
Finally you needed to test your work.
So if I rerun things from the terminal I should see minus 1 and 8 and that is exactly what I end up
getting.
So there we go.
That is our first semi real world challenge.
The challenges as these ones have shown are going to get a bit harder as we go along.
It's going to give you more to do to test your skills.
With this in place though we now know the basics of the import and export syntax and we're all done
for this video in the next video.
We're actually going to install graphics UL and we're going to load it into our project so we can get
started down the path of creating our very own graphical API.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.