You've spent a bit of time learning about graphics Well queries and you now have a great project structure
in place in this video we're actually going to set up a graphical API.
So by the end you will have a real graphical API server up and running and you'll have your own instance
of graphical playground that you can use to actually make sample queries to the server that you've set
up.
Now remember that using graphical playground is just a temporary way to make sure our server is working
as expected when we perform various operations on it in a real world situation.
These queries would come from something like a mobile device.
Another server or a web browser.
And we'll talk about exactly how we can get all of that done.
Later in the course for now we just want to get a graphical API set up before we install any NPM libraries.
It's important to note that graph.
Well the graph query language is just a specification for how all of this stuff should work.
For example how should queries work in the end of the day.
It's not an implementation so it's up to individual developers to take this document that describes
graphs well and actually implemented for that environment whether it's Android iOS javascript node Python's
C go Lang or whatever we need implementations of graft well to use it in those environments.
So for our purposes we have to find an implementation of the graph.
Q Well spec that actually works with no J ass.
Now that might seem like a weird concept but it's actually the exact same thing we have with javascript
itself.
We have the ECMAScript specification describing how javascript should work.
Then we have various implementations.
For example chrome and node use the V8 engine we have Mozilla using spidermonkey we have Microsoft using
Chikara.
So those are three implementations of the JavaScript spec in our case.
We just have to find an implementation that works with node.
Now you can actually view the spec itself over in the browser.
If you had over to Facebook data get hub I O forward slash graph.
Well we can view all of the versions of the spec we're just going to crack open the latest release really
quick.
And what do we get.
We get a really long document.
This document describes in detail how graphic you all should work you know what you're not going to
find here.
You're not going to find any no J.S. code you're not going to find any Python code or any code other
than graft.
Well this describes the graph query language.
It's up to developers for those other languages.
Python Java and node to actually create their own implementations.
Now at the end of the day what does that really mean.
It just means that we might have multiple options to pick from when we're using graph.
Well in a specific environment there might be multiple clients for iOS.
There might be and are multiple servers for node j s the tool that we're going to be using to get grant
Cuil up and running on Node Adjaye as is graphed well.
Yoga which we can install down in the terminal.
You're more than welcome to use the yarn package manager with this course.
I'm going to be sticking with NPM.
So NPM install which can be shortened to NPM I add the module graph QOL hyphen yoga and I'll be specifying
a specific version the latest at one point fourteen point ten we can go ahead and run this installation
and once it's done what are we going to do.
We're going to pull up the docs and we're actually going to set it up an index dot J ass.
That means we're not going to need any of this code any of this code we had to learn about import export.
So I'm going to wipe index dot J S and I'm also going to delete math Dhananjay ass and the my module
Yes file.
You're more than welcome to keep them around if you want but they're not going to make it into the final
version of this application.
They were added for demonstration purposes only.
Awesome.
So we have graphical yoga installed.
Let's go ahead and pull up the documentation so you know where that lives as well.
I'm going to Google the library name a graph.
Q Well yoga and we're looking for the get hub documentation page that's this first one right here.
Now the question has to be asked why use this particular tool.
Well I use this for all of my personal and professional client projects for two main reasons.
One is that it provides the most advanced features set allowing us to tap into everything graphed UL
has to offer.
The second is that it comes with a very easy set up process so we can get up and running very quickly.
But we can also use the same tool to build the advanced API as with all of the real world features we'd
expect like subscriptions authentication and more now on this page in particular we can learn a bit
about how to actually set up graph Well yoga although we'll be working through that in this video.
And we can also learn about other ways it can be configured and used.
There are various options available to us and we'll explore a lot of these throughout the course as
well where I'd like to start though is by moving into index dot J.S. and getting a barebones version
of graft UL yoga up and running I'm going to collapse the terminal and we're going to start by using
an inport statement to grab something off of the graph.
Q Well yoga library we're going to grab the tool that allows us to create a brand new server right here
that is a named export and it's called Grath QOL server.
No the capitalization here as that is important.
After we have the closing curly brace we use from.
And then we provide where it's coming from.
And it was a local file we would start with Dot forward slash sense it's an NPM library we installed.
We just provide the library name craft Cuil hyphen yoga.
Awesome.
And that's actually all we need to import in order to get graft.
Well yoga up and running.
Now there are two things we have to define before we can start our server.
The first are type definitions and the second are the resolvers for our API.
These are both very important things.
So let's take a moment to talk about what each are to start.
I want to talk about type definitions also known as your application schema the application schema is
super important.
It's where we define very important things like all of the operations that can be performed on the API.
And what are custom data types look like.
Let's bring this back to a real world example by heading back into the graft Well playground for the
demo API that I set up here if we opened the schema tab What were we greeted with we were greeted with
all of the operations we could perform in this case.
We only know about the query operation and we only have queries listed here.
We have seven different queries that can be performed.
All of these were defined in the schema and we're going to learn how we can set up our own queries to
the schema also defines what our data looks like.
So our custom data types.
When we queried for me for example what we got back was a user.
A user had a specific set of fields of various types.
This is also defined in our application schema.
So the schema is super important.
It is a very big piece to the puzzle.
We also have our application resolvers and your resolvers are nothing more than a set of functions.
We're going to define functions that run for each of the operations that can be performed on our API.
So for example the dentally API I created a function for the hello query for the course query for the
course instr. query and for the ME query those functions know what to do when that query runs.
They know how to get and return the correct data.
So these functions will eventually be where we query data from a real database write data or do whatever
is necessary depending on what operation got performed.
So we have our type definition.
This describes the operations and the data structures we have the resolvers.
These are the functions that actually run when various operations are performed.
Let's kick things off with our type definitions right here.
I'm going to create a new Konst called type DAPs and I'm going to set it equal to a template string.
So here I'm using the back tickey to the left of the one key on my keyboard.
Now what goes inside of here is Grath Well code.
So we define our schema in regular old graph and we're going to start learning that syntax right now
what we're going to end up doing is defining just a single query.
So we're going to set up our application so we can query for Hello nothing else to do that.
We start by defining the query type.
That's one of the three built in types when we use the query type we can define the queries for our
application.
So type followed by uppercase Q query which has to match exactly since it's built in.
And then we set up our curly braces.
Now what do we do inside of here.
We define all of the queries we want to support.
So in the case of the demo app I had seven queries I had seven things to find in here.
We're going to stick with just a single thing a single query called hello to divide the query.
We start off with the query name.
In this case hello to I'll type hello out.
Then we add a colon a space and we define the type that should come back when this query is executed.
So we've explored the string type a quite a bit and we're going to stick with that for the moment.
So right here after our colon space that's uppercase as string.
Now that we have this in place we have a completely valid type definition for our API.
While it is a simple one it is indeed going to get the job done.
Now we can leave string like this if we want NULL to be able to be an option for the return value.
We can always add on an exclamation mark to say that hello is always going to return a string and that's
it I'm going to do.
So we're always going to get a string back.
The only other thing we have to do is to define our resolvers since we only have a single operation.
A single query.
We're only going to end up defining a single function right here.
I'm going to create the resolvers object so Konst resolvers equals a new object.
And in general the structure of this object is going to mirror the structure up above.
So we will start with an upper case Q query property.
This is also going to be an object and on there we're going to define various methods.
One method for each query we've set up.
We only have one query so we're only going to define one method and the names need to match.
So down below.
Hello I'm going to go ahead and use the 6 method definition to define this method and all we have to
do is return a string.
We have to return what the expected value is.
So let's use return to return a brand new string.
And I'm going to say this is my first query.
Perfect.
Now this resolver function does get called with some arguments and we are going to explore those later.
They're really important for real world applications.
For the moment though we're going to ignore all of those arguments just returning a static string.
Now that is it.
We have our one operation set up.
We have the code necessary to get data back when that operation is performed and we can go ahead and
actually start up our server and query for that data.
How do we do that.
We do that with two lines of code down below.
First up we have to declare a server so Konst server and we're going to create a new instance of graph
Q L server which re-imported up above.
So new graphics UL server end.
This does expect an object as its argument and there are two properties we have to define.
We have to define type deaths.
Passing an R type definitions.
And we also have to define the resolvers property passing in our resolvers.
Since the property name matches up with a variable with the same name we can use the object property
shorthand like this passing in type deaths and resolvers.
The last thing to do is to use a method on server to start everything up right here.
Server dot start.
We are going to pass to it a callback function.
This function runs when the server is actually up and running.
I know we're going to do is use a cute little council that like to print a message.
The server is up perfect as we go.
It is time to run our application.
I am going to crack open the terminal.
I'm going to clear the terminal output and use NPM run start to start things up.
Now by default graph Cuil yoga is going to try to start up the application on local host port 4000.
So let's head over there in the browser.
I'll make a new tab localhost port 4000 and what we're going to end up seeing is an instance of Grafx
UL playground for the Brynne new API.
We've set up.
Now we can see that it's trying to save all of the requests from our other instance.
Oh we need to do is close down all of these tabs then in a new tab which points to localhost four thousand.
We're going to create our query.
I am going to query for hello which is the only thing that exists.
I'm going to click that play button and what do we get.
We get our message.
This is my first query showing up and this is fantastic.
We were able to set up our very own albeit simple graphics UL API and we were actually able to make
a query to the API.
Getting the correct data back.
Now that we have these servers set up it would actually be very easy to add other operations that someone
could perform.
We can add another query for example.
I am going to hit enter.
Set up a name a query colon space and we're going to have this one return a string as well.
All we need to do to get this to work is to define a resolver for name.
So right here after the hello method I will define the name method.
We're not going to worry about any of the arguments for the moment and I am just going to return my
name as a string.
Andrew Mead.
Now we can save the script.
I can go ahead and use control C to shut down the server.
The up arrow key to reload that last command and enter to rerun it.
Then we can refresh things over in the browser and we can query for that new field right after hello.
We're going to query for name.
Now I can click that play button or I can use command enter to rerun the current query.
That would be I believe control Antar for Windows users and right here we have the latest information.
I had L-L and I have name to wrap up this video.
I would like you to add two more queries to our application.
So right here you're going to add a query for location which is going to return a string.
Just has your location as the string.
You could say something like your city name for example and you're going to set up a bio query which
also returns a string and just add a quick sentence about yourself.
So take some time to add the typedef for both of those queries and the resolver functions for each.
Then restart your server.
Run a new query from graph playground requesting both of those fields and make sure you get the correct
data.
Take a quick moment to pause the video.
Knock that out.
Test your work and when you're done click play
all right how that one go I'm going to kick things off with my type definitions.
That's where I like to start.
So I will define the location query which will return a string and I'll define the bio query which will
also return a string.
We'll get away from strings only in just a second.
Then we're going to remove those challenge comments and I am going to move on to the resolver definitions.
So down below after name comma enter we have to define two new methods for our two new queries.
First up location not worrying about any of the arguments for the moment and just returning a static
string.
For me that would be still Philadelphia after location comma.
Enter for one more method for bio.
We're going to set up that method.
I'm going to return a quick bio.
I'll live in Philly and teach on you to me.
Very exciting stuff.
Now we can go ahead and actually save indexed at Jats.
I can restart my server and we can refresh the browser to make our brand new query.
Right here we have hello we have name.
I am going to add on location and I am going to add on bio command enter to rerun the query and what
do we get.
We get all four fields returning the correct data.
If I crack open the schema we can see that we are getting exactly what we would expect.
We have all of the four queries we set up described right here.
So now we have a set up we can continue to expand on and what I want to talk about in the next video.
Are the other types we can use in Grath.
Well it's not all just about strings we have numbers in booleans too.
We're going to tackle that in the next one.
So stay tuned and I'll see you soon.