In this video you're going to learn about the other types that come with graphs.
Well it is not just strings despite what you might think based half of what we've actually used so far.
There are actually five main types that I want to talk about in this video right here.
We're going to list out all five and you can always refer to the PTF guide for this video to get the
exact list so you don't have to write all of this down.
The first type we have is the string the string type as we've already seen in stores are string based
data.
We also have a Boolean for storing boolean values.
This is great for things like an is published field where the value is either the boolean true or the
boolean false engraft.
Well we can also represent numbers and there are two types for that.
First up we have the INT for storing integers.
So for storing whole numbers like you're age 27 or something like the number of products you have in
stock maybe you have 14 somewhere in the warehouse after and we have float a nother way to represent
our numbers.
This is great for numbers with decimal points like a GPA 3.1 7 for example or something like a ratings
system where a product has been rated four point seven stars by customers.
Last up we have the idea that is capital I capital D and this is a bit unique to graph.
Q Well it's used to represent unique identifiers in the end of the day it is very similar to a string
but we'll explore the differences as we progress through the course.
Now these five types are known as the five scalar types inside of graph.
Q A a scalar value is just a single discrete value so a scalar type is a type that stores a single value
whether that value is a string a boolean an int a float or an ID.
This is the opposite of a non scalar type like an object or an array which is a collection of discrete
values.
So with an object we have many properties with an array we could have many elements in that array will
be covering objects and arrays very soon.
For the moment though in this video I just want to focus on these five types and we're going to do that
by setting up five queries one for each type.
Let's go ahead and remove our existing four queries from R-Type definitions and from the resolvers down
below.
And we're going to set up five new ones and all five of these are going to be things that could describe
a person.
So for example we're going to have an idea a unique identifier for that person and the type is going
to be the ID type.
So uppercase I uppercase D now for almost all of the fields we set up we are going to want to use the
exclamation mark saying that this is something that should always return an ID as opposed to being able
to return NULL now after Id We might have something like name and in the case of name we could use the
string type.
We've already explored before.
After name let's say we want to represent the person's age as an integer.
So right here age colon space upper case I end with an exclamation mark on the end.
Next up we can use a boolean to represent whether or not that given person is employed.
So right here we could set up the field employed.
I could have its value be a boolean and we'll use an exclamation mark to make sure we always get a boolean
back.
They're either unemployed or you are employed.
Now below that we are going to have our final value and this is going to be the G.P.A..
Now the G.P.A. is going to be stored as a float because my GPA could be something like 3.1 7 for example
and I'm actually going to leave the exclamation mark off if I'm not a student.
I'm not going to have a GPA.
So it's OK if I get Knol back.
This basically says it's OK if I get Knol but if I am sending back a non null value it has to be a float.
So we have all five queries set up.
Let's go ahead and create resolvers for each.
I'm going to start with a method for ID after Id have name after name.
We have age then we have employed our boolean value.
And finally we have G.P.A. The one that is optional so we could return NULL from here if we wanted to.
Now for the moment you'll notice that we have individual resolver methods for individual properties
on something like a user.
This is only temporary.
Once we learn about our custom types where we can actually model a user a post a comment or whatever
else makes sense for our application we'll be reducing the number of resolvers.
So this is just a temporary thing.
We will address this shortly.
For the moment though to mess around with all of the scalar types we have access to.
Let's go ahead and return what each expects.
So in ID I am going to return a string.
ABC 1 2 3.
I could also choose to return a number like the number 12 for example.
But in the end of the day that will get converted over to a string so it will look more like this.
I'm going to stick with an actual string ABC one two three for name.
We are obviously returning a string something we've done plenty of times before.
Not much to say there for age.
We're going to go ahead and return an integer.
So I'm going to return twenty seven for employed.
We want to return a boolean.
So I would return true if I was employed or false.
If I was currently unemployed I am self-employed which is definitely a type of employment.
So I'm going to go ahead and return true.
Last up we have our G.P.A. now with the G.P.A..
Yes we could return something like 3.1.
Perfectly valid a perfectly valid float but we could also choose to return NULL because remember for
this type definition we left off the exclamation mark.
This is saying I expect a float back but it would also be fine if you gave me no this is saying I expect
a boolean back end because of the exclamation mark.
It's saying you have to return a boolean.
You can't return it.
No since I currently don't have any sort of GPA I'm not in school right now.
I am going to go ahead and return now.
Now that we have all five set up under both our type definitions and our resolvers Let's go ahead and
save the file restart our server and test things out.
I'm going to shut the server down.
I'm going to start it up once again.
Over inside of the Graf school playground.
I will give things a quick refresh just to update that schema.
And we're going to update our query.
I want I.D. I'd like name spelled correctly of course.
I would also like age.
Then we have employed.
And finally we have G.P.A..
I'm going to fire that query off.
And what do I get back I get back all of the correct values ID.
We have our string name.
We have Andrew age we have the integer 27 employed we have true and for GPA we have knowl for GPA.
Remember we could have also returned a float.
So over here I could return something like three point zero one that would get the job done.
If I save the file and restart the server we can actually query for that data.
So it's perfectly fine to have all but as we can see now it's also perfectly fine to actually return
that float.
So there we have it.
These are the five scalar types that we can work with inside of graft.
Well now is your challenge for the video.
I'd like you to go ahead and add a couple more into the mix up above.
I have a few comments for one I'd like you to do.
So right here you are going to be creating a query definition a query definition and a resolver a resolver
for each of these five properties.
Now in this case let's say we're modeling an e-commerce store.
So we have titles for our products.
We have prices release years ratings and whether or not that product is in stock and we want to represent
all of these using some of our Scheller types.
So the title for example is going to be a simple string for the product name.
And this one is going to be required.
You have to have a title for the price.
We're going to say this is a number represented as a float.
So the price could be nine point nine nine.
We're also going to have an optional release year represented as an integer.
So whether or not it makes sense for your product is up for you to decide because it is in the end of
the day optional.
We also have a rating which is a number stored as a float your rating might be 5 point 0 or 3.6 4.
And it's also optional.
So when your product first goes up we're not going to return a rating like 5 or 0.
We're going to return.
No just saying there is no ratings yet.
Last up in stock that's a boolean.
If it's true the products in stock if it's false the product is not in stock now it's up to you how
do you want to approach this.
You are more than welcome to keep all of these in place and then add these along side.
You can also go ahead and just clear all of your queries and all of your resolver functions and build
up from scratch.
Either way it gets the job done.
So take some time to knock this out and test your work.
Save the file restart the server and actually query for all five of these over inside of the graph.
Playground.
All right.
Pause the video.
Knock this out and when you're done come back and click play
How'd that go.
Let's kick things off by setting up our query definitions for all five.
So first up we have title title is going to return the value of a string.
It's required.
So I'll toss an exclamation mark on the end.
We also have price price is going to be stored as a float and price is also not optional.
So I'm going to be putting an exclamation mark on there too.
We then have the release year the release year is completely optional.
When it is provided though it's going to be represented as an integer.
So right here and next up we have the products aerating the products rading is stored as a float.
This is also optional.
So I'm going to type float with no exclamation mark at the end allowing NULL to be the value for rating.
Last up we have in-stock a product either is or is not in stock.
This one is going to be required.
Boullion excellent.
So we have all five type definitions now we can actually move on to the resolvers down below.
So we're going to start off with title and for title I'm going to return some sort of product name.
I'm going to return a string and I'll just use a book on my desk as the product that is in the War of
Art.
It's a great book about your inner creative battles and overcoming that stuff to get back to work and
get productive and release the stuff that you want to release.
It's a great book.
After the title we're going to set up the price now for the price.
This could be anything.
I don't know what this book actually cost.
Let's just go ahead and say it costs 13 bucks.
So I will return at twelve point nine nine after the price we have our release year release year.
I could dig into the book and see what the Release Year is but I'm going to go ahead and just return
a null sense remember the release year is completely optional so returning NULL is valid after release
year we have our rating for the book.
I definitely enjoyed this one.
So let's say that it has a 5 star ratings are right here.
I'm going to return five.
The last one.
Whether or not the book is in stock in stock.
I'm going to go ahead and say This book is in stock so I will return true as opposed to false.
For the book being out-of-stock now we have all five set up we can remove the challenge comments.
I'm going to go ahead and save this file down below.
We will restart things from the terminal and then we're going to query for all five and graph playground
if we get the correct data back.
We're all done.
So right here we're going to change up that query a little bit.
First up I will refresh the page to grab the latest schema.
I'm going to access the title.
I'm also going to grab the price I'll grab the release year even though we know the release year is
going to be a null value.
After that we have the rating for the book and then whether or not the book is in stock if I execute
that query what do I get back.
I get back all of the data that I just set up.
We have our title the war of our.
We got our price twelve ninety nine.
We don't have a release here.
We have our five star rating and the book is indeed in stock.
So there we go.
You now know about all of the five Scheller types that we can work with inside of graft.
Well we're going to cover next is how we can create custom types to model the real world things that
make up our application.
So in this case we might have a product custom type for all of these five fields.
In the case of the fields we had earlier we would have something like a user custom type and that's
going to make it way easier to maintain and scale our applications.
No longer will we need five functions for five simple pieces of data we'll be able to return everything
that a custom type has with just a single resolver.
Now we're going to get to that in two videos time in the next video which could be considered something
like a bonus.
I'm going to show you how we can automatically restart our server whenever we make any changes to our
application code.
So we don't have to manually restart it every single time we make a change.
Let's go ahead and jump right into that.