In this video we're going to take just a few moments to make some changes to our local development environment
to make going through this course a bit easier.
So we're going to set things up to automatically restart the server.
Any time we make any changes to our application code.
So if I change how my type definitions work for example I won't need to manually shut the server down
and start it up again.
It'll just automatically restart in the background.
So if I have typos like I do right here I won't have to restart things.
I have is stock that should have been in stock and it should have been in stock down below.
But when I save my changes what happens nothing happens.
I have to remember to manually restart things.
And when you're quickly iterating in development so locally on your machine that can be a real burden
now to fix all of this we're going to be using a very popular NPM module called gnomon that's going
to allow us to start up our application and restart it when any of its files change.
Let's head over to package Scott Jason and actually set this up.
In the end of the day we will be doing just two things.
We will install one new module node gnomon and we're going to make a change to the start script.
That's it.
We don't have to make any changes to indexed.
J.S. to get this automatic restarting feature set up down below.
I am going to shut down the server I'll use clear to clear the terminal output.
And we're going to be using NPM install to install gnomon.
I am going to install the latest version that has at one point seventeen point five.
And I'll also toss on the Save dev flag to save this one as a development dependency something not necessary
in production.
Once we run this command it's going to go through that installation process and as I mentioned the only
thing we're going to end up doing now is changing our start script instead of running the babbel node
command.
We will be running the node on command.
So let's take a look at how that's going to go.
While the command will look similar it'll be different enough where I am just going to start from an
empty command and we start off with gnomon.
No gnomon expects the file that you're going to actually run.
So the starting point for your application for us that is still source forward slash index dot J S.
Now this alone would normally be enough.
But since we're using babbel it's not.
We also need to tell gnomon that when it actually runs our file it shouldn't just run it through node
it should run it through Babel node.
We can do that by specifying the X E.S. argument.
So by default it looks like this.
We run the file through node but we don't want that.
We want to run it through Babel node perfect.
So what's this going to do.
It is going to start up our application by running this file through babbel node node is then going
to continue to watch our application files for changes if they ever change.
It's going to restart the server running the new file through babbel node once again.
And there we go.
We have everything all set up.
We can save package data Jason and actually test this out down below.
I'm going to use clear to clear the terminal output then we'll use NPM run start to start things up
when we run the command.
What do we end up getting.
We get a little extra output we get some output from gnomon telling us exactly what it's doing now and
the end of the day though we do still get our server is up message which means in the background we
can still run things.
Never remember I changed that typo in my schema I had is stock instead of the correct in stock.
And you'll notice that over here things haven't updated.
You can either once again manually refresh the page or you can just click this little guy keeping all
of your data in place but just refreshing the schema.
And now we can see it's invalid and I can switch it over to the valid in-stock run things and everything
is working as expected.
Now as we iterate on our application and actually make changes we can see those changes quickly.
We can actually collapse the terminal since it's no longer something we're going to have to use every
single time we make a change.
For example I can change the release year to something like 2008.
I don't really know what year the book was released just to say that was it over here without making
any changes to restarting the server.
I can save the file click that play button and I get my new data showing up.
So that's all I wanted to talk about in this video.
Just a slightly better set up for our local development allowing us to work on the graphics.
Well part of the application and not have to manually restart things in the terminal in the next video
you're going to explore how you can create your own custom types.
I am super excited to get to that.
That's where things are going to start to get a bit more real world.
So let's go ahead and jump right into that.