In this video you're going to learn how to use custom types.
Engraft well so we're going to see what it takes to create our own custom types allowing us to model
the data that makes up our application.
So if we're working with a blogging application we're going to have custom types for all of the different
types of data we have we might have a custom type to represent a user a another one to represent a post
and a third one to represent a comment where each has its own set of fields.
So a user would have something like a name and an email.
A post would have a title and a body and the comment would have something like the comment text and
maybe when the comment was created or who the comment was created.
But we've seen a little of how these custom types work when we messed around with queries using the
demo API earlier in the course.
We saw that some of our queries send back scalar types.
These three for example send back strings but other queries like me send back custom types allowing
us to send back what's essentially an object a set of fields.
So me for example if we explored in the schema sends back a custom type user This user has a set of
defined fields.
Here we have some scalar values and we also have some relational data.
So let's go ahead and see what it actually takes to create a custom type.
In the end of the day all we really need to do is define something new inside of our type definition
R-Type definition starts off with the type keyword and then we go on to pick a type name and this name
is completely up to us.
So if we're creating an application that models blog posts I might use post if I'm creating an application
that models products maybe I use product in this case the first custom type we create is going to model
a user.
So I'm going to call this one user and notice the uppercase first letter.
We are going to have an uppercase first letter for all of the types that we define in graph.
Q L now down below.
What do we do.
We define the fields that make up this type.
So what fields do all users have in this case we could say all users have a unique ID a name and an
email.
And that's exactly what we're going to set up three fields for the user type.
Now to kick this process off it looks very similar to what we did above with our queery definition.
So I'm going to specify a field that a user has.
Let's call this one ID then a colon space and I go on to pick the type for it.
So in this case we will use the ID type and I will add an exclamation mark on there.
This is a required field.
Now next up just hitting Enter we can add a second field onto all of our users.
This one it could be a name so name the value will be a string and this one will always exist as well.
And then we could add a couple more into the mix.
Let's add an email to all of our users will have that be a string and then we'll add an age on as well
and we'll allow the age to be optional.
So we'll set it equal to an int but I will not use an exclamation mark.
And there we go.
We have our very first type definition.
We have our user type and we have the four fields that make up a user.
Now we can actually take advantage of this type throughout our application and for the moment what we're
going to do is create a query that returns a user.
So let's go ahead and empty out all of our resolver methods and all of the queries we have set up and
we're going to create a brand new query and I'm going to call this one.
Me.
Now later on once we set up authentication me is going to return some information about you the logged
in user for the moment though we're just going to return some generic information about a user.
So right here we set up our query we're calling it me.
And now we move on to the type that me is going to end up sending back in the past we only ever used
scalar types.
So I would add string I'd add boolean int float ID.
Those sorts of things.
Now though we can use one of our custom types in this case user so we reference it by its name.
And once again we can decide if we want this to always come back or to allow it to be nullable.
So right now could be NULL if we add an exclamation mark on where saying that you're always going to
get a user back.
Let's go ahead and keep the exclamation mark in place letting us know that me is always going to return
something of the type user.
So we have our type definition all set up.
We have our query in place we have the custom type created.
Now all we need to do is set up a resolver.
And since we only have one query we're only going to have one resolver method right here me.
We're going to set it up and what are we going to do.
We are going to return something that matches up with the user type.
So in this case we're going to return an object with all of the fields that match up with the user fields.
Now this is typically where we would go off and we would actually fetch some data from the database.
But for the moment until we get to that part of the course we're going to stick with static data just
to find in this file.
So I can go ahead and return a new object and have the object properties match up with the user fields.
So I need the first three.
The last one is optional.
I'm going to set up the ID right here.
Matching up with the fields name exactly.
I'll give that a value of 1 2 3 0 9 8 and then we can add on the other fields like a name I will use
a different name like Mike and the email from Mike which I will have as Mike an example a dot com.
And finally the age the age is completely optional.
So I could actually go ahead and leave that off.
This is perfectly valid.
I could also choose to go ahead and add it on setting the age equal to something like twenty eight.
And there we go.
We have our very first query that returns a custom type.
Let's go ahead and save index dot J S and actually test this out.
I am going to refresh the schema to get the latest updates from the server and we can see that none
of these queries exist anymore.
So let's go ahead and delete all of them.
And we're going to use the one and only query we actually have me.
We're going to set up the query but remember that this alone is not enough when we are querying a data
in graph.
Q Well we have to be specific down to the individual scalar values.
So when the query return to scale or value.
This alone would be enough.
We saw that with all of these examples over here in this case though he is not returning a scale or
value.
It is not returning ID float ID Boullion or string it is returning something of the type user.
So if we have a non scalar value we have to provide a selection set for it like we did before.
So we open and close our curly braces and we get down to the actual scalar values we want maybe I just
want the ID in which case this alone is enough.
I can run the query and what do I get.
I get my user's ID back successfully.
I could also choose to grab all of the other fields on me I could grab the name I could grab the email
and I could even grab the age whether or not it's actually something that exists.
If I go ahead and run this query what do I get.
I get my ID.
Mike Mike for example dot com and age all printing to the screen.
Now if the age was not there at all what would we get for age.
We would get null so I'm going to go ahead and remove age completely from the object that we return.
I'll save the file over inside of graft.
Well playground.
All we have to do is rerun the exact same query and this time around we successfully get age as null
and that is indeed correct.
Now if we tried to leave off one of the other properties one of the properties that actually needs to
be there we would get an error related to that.
For example if we leave off email which has been flagged as something that we have to have we are indeed
going to get an error.
I run the script excuse me I run the query and what do I get.
I get an error cannot return NULL for non nullable field user dot email.
So here we are looking at the error structure and in general the important piece to the puzzle is the
message the English readable message allowing you to know exactly what went wrong here it's just saying
that you tried to return NULL for user e-mail.
That's not OK.
So we will be able to go into our code and actually address that whether it meant adding data here or
removing the requirement up above.
For now I am going to keep the requirement and I am going to continue to send an email back resulting
once again in a completely valid setup.
Now you'll notice throughout the course I haven't been using semi-colons to terminate my javascript
statements So for example I don't have a semi-colon here or here or here.
This is all a matter of personal style choice.
So semi-colons are optional in javascript.
We can rely on automatic semi-colon insertion.
Sure there are some places where these semi-colons still plays a role like in the for loop for example.
I'm still going to set up my for a loop with a semicolon in between like the one right here but when
it comes to actually terminating aligns with semi-colons it's all a stylistic choice.
I've been on teams that force you to use semi-colons.
I've been on other teams that force you to not use semi-colons when they're not necessary.
So I'm going to be sticking with this semi-colon lists.
Javascript I recommend giving it a try if you've never tried it before.
I've been hooked on it for about a year now and I am never going back.
All right.
With all of that said let's move on to the challenge for the video.
What you're going to do is create a brand new custom type then you're going to set up a query and resolver
for that.
So up above I'm going to leave some comments for what I'd like you to do.
So step one you're going to be creating a brand new post type.
This is a nother type we're going to need for our blogging application and you're going to add the following
fields ID title body and published to this post type.
Now all of them should be non nullable so they should all have that exclamation mark after the actual
scalar type definition.
And we can have the ID be an ID title and body can be a string and published can be a boolean.
Next up you're going to define a post query that returns a single post much like we did for me.
Returning a single user right here.
Step Five.
Excuse me for is to set up a resolver method to return some post data just like we did for me down below.
So you want to return an object that has all of these fields on it.
Step 5 is to actually test the query out.
So make sure to save your work head over into graft playground and make sure you can query for a post
and get some of the post fields back.
So take some time to knock this one out when you're done.
Make sure to test your work.
Pause the video when you're done come back and click play
how that one go.
I'm going to kick things off with my custom post type definitions or right here type upper case P post.
We then set up our curly braces and this is where we define all of the fields that make up a post.
First one Id almost all of the custom types we create.
Well actually not almost literally all of them are going to have an ID field they're going to have a
unique identifier so right here of the type ID and this one will be marked as non knowable.
Next up on our list we have the post's title.
A non at nullable string.
And the Post's body of the same type.
A non nullable string and last up we have whether or not the post is published that is via the published
property.
A non nullable boolean value.
Excellent.
So we have our post type definition all set up.
Now it's time to actually use it to do that.
We're going to set up a new query that was Step 3 so I am going to set up a query or for post never
turns a single post so I have to reference the custom type by name and I will make sure that it is not
nullable.
So I always get a post back.
Step 4 is to set up that resolver method to return some post data so down below.
We have to set up a resolver for all of our queries.
We don't have one for post.
Let's go ahead and create it right after the closing curly brace for the MI method.
I'll add a comma.
Move to the next line and set up a another method for post.
Once again ignoring the fact that there are arguments that get passed here.
But we're just not using them.
We'll actually start exploring those in the very next video.
For now though what do we have to do.
We have to return an object and this object needs to have all of those fields.
So we need an ID.
I'll use the idea of 0 9 2.
We need a title so title could be something like Cual 101.
A post about how to get started with Graph.
Well we need a body.
The body could be a string that's just completely empty.
Maybe I haven't started working on the post yet.
And lastly whether or not the post is published via the published property I don't have a body for this
one so will say it's not published.
I'll get the published value to false.
Now that we've successfully returned the information necessary we can actually save indexed J.S. refresh
the schema engraft UL playground and make a query for the post.
So right here we see it along side of me.
I'm going to tack it on after me trying to grab a post.
Remember that post does not send back a scalar type.
So we have to provide our selection set.
What scalar fields do I want from the post.
I want the ID I want the title I want the body and I want whether or not the post is published.
Perfect.
I'm going to collapse the schema panel run this query and what do I get.
I get all of the expected data on data.
I have me and post inside of post.
I have the correct values for all of the four fields requested if I chose to not access one like body
for example.
That would be gone.
I would just get the 3i actually accessed my ID my title and whether or not the post is published.
So at this point we can see how we can start to model our application in terms of these custom types
but there are still a lot more questions we need to answer.
For example how do I work with lists.
So how do I work with an array of posts.
How do I set up relationships between these.
A user owns posts and a Post has an author.
All of that is coming up in the next several videos.
We're going to continue to explore these custom type definitions.
For now though we are all done.
I'm going to remove the challenge comments from up above.
Save the file and I will see you in the next one.