In this video you're going to learn all about graphics you well operation arguments.
This is going to allow us to pass data from the client to the server.
So far all of the data has been flowing in the opposite direction.
So it's been going from the server to the client but there are plenty of examples of why we would want
to get data from our client to the server.
Imagine I'm creating a front end for this blog application.
The first thing I'm probably going to do is show them something like a sign up form where I ask them
for their email and their password.
Once I get those pieces of information from the user on the client I need a way to pass those through
to the server.
So the server can actually save a new record to the database.
For example another reason I might want to use operation arguments is if I'm trying to filter some data
so imagine I have a query that returns all posts that someone could read.
So all public published posts now that could be a lot of information so someone goes ahead and they
use the search box to search for a keyword like graft.
Well I want a way to get that key word that string from the client over to the server.
So the server can use it to filter posts.
Maybe I search for that key word in the title anti-body only returning the post if I find it somewhere
in either of those.
So there are tons of different reasons why I would want to get data from the client to the server.
Let's go ahead and take a look at how we can do that by exploring operation arguments and we're going
to start with a very simple query to explore this syntax.
We still need to name this query and I'm going to call this one a greeting and greeting is going to
return a non nullable string.
Now by default a greeting is going to return a generic message something like hello.
But we are going to allow the user to pass their name along with the query.
If they do we'll include that in the query as well saying something like Hello Andrew or Hello Kate.
So to kick things off we have to determine what arguments this query should accept.
And we do that inside of a set of parentheses right here right between the query name and the colon.
In here we define all of the arguments that could be passed along with greeting.
So we have to define all of the required ones if any and any potential optional ones everything has
to be listed inside of the definition for greeting.
In our case we're going to have one.
It's going to be an optional string.
So one can option really provide a name.
If they don't that's fine too.
The first thing we have to do is give a name for the argument I'm going to call this one name.
If I was trying to pass along the age I would call it something like age.
So we have the name argument then we use a colon and a space and we have to be explicit about what type
we are expecting.
Are we expecting a Boolean for this value.
No we're expecting a string.
So we will use the string scalar type.
Now if we were going to force them to provide a name every time greeting was used we would put an exclamation
mark after the type.
In this case without an exclamation mark we're saying that it's perfectly fine to use the greeting query
without providing a name.
So that is it for the query definition here we've determined that the greeting query has one optional
argument name down below.
Let's go ahead and actually set up the resolver method for it right here.
Greeting.
I'm going to set up my arguments I'm going to set up the function body I'll toss the comma right there
and for the moment I'm just going to return a generic static message return Hello.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and figure out what it takes to provide name when we're querying over inside of graft.
Well playground.
I'm going to go ahead and save index Dhananjay ass.
Over here we can start by just grabbing greeting and making sure at least that works.
If I run this query what do I get.
I get my data back.
I get my static hello message when we want to pass data along with one of our operations.
We use parentheses right after the operation name then we specify all of the arguments we want to provide.
Now in this case we don't have to provide any arguments.
We solve that work because the only one that's there name is optional.
But if we do want to provide it we set up the parentheses we determine the key we are trying to set
a value for.
In this case I am trying to set a value for the name argument then a colon space.
And we actually provide that value if it was a number.
I might provide 12 cents.
It's a string.
I am going to provide a string value in this case.
I will just use the name Jess.
So now we are successfully passing a value the string Jess along from the client to the server.
If we run the query what do we get.
We get absolutely no change in the response.
Yes the data is getting passed to the server but it's now up to the actual resolver method to use the
data to make some sort of dynamic response later on in the course we'll be using data to query the database
to save records for the database.
For now though let's just go ahead and use the argument to change the string that gets sent back.
Now the data that was provided in this case the name Jess lives in one of the arguments for our resolver
function.
There are four arguments that get passed to all resolver functions and they are as follows.
The first is parent parent is very common and it's useful when we're working with relational data.
So for example if a user has many posts the parent argument comes into play when figuring out how to
get a user's posts.
We'll touch on that in just a little bit.
The next argument called args This contains the information we need.
This contains the operation arguments supplied.
The third one known as context which is typically shortened to C-T X is very useful for contextual data.
So if a user is logged in context it might contain the idea of that user.
So you could access it throughout the application will be doing just that later in the class.
The last argument is info info contains great information about the actual operations that were sent
along to the server.
And we're going to be exploring that as well.
But as I mentioned the only one that's really important for us at the moment is this one right here
Ark's Argus is an object and it contains all of the argument values provided.
So let's go ahead and just dump Argus to the console console dialog args.
I am going to save indexed japes I will crack open the terminal and we're going to do is send that exact
same query across.
I click the play button over here what do I have.
I have an object with the name property and the value of that is the string.
Yes.
So this is where my data lives.
Now I can actually use that to provide a dynamic response right here.
I'm going to use an IF statement to check if args dot name exists and since it's a string this condition
will also make sure that this code only runs if it's a string that actually has content.
So if the name is provided and it has real content it's not just an empty string.
We are going to return the following using a template string.
I will say hello comma.
Then right here I am going to interpret their name.
So that's args dot name.
And at the very end of the string after their name I'll toss in the exclamation mark.
I can still return the generic message as well.
Right here I will set up an else clause.
Else return exactly what we had before.
Why return the hello string.
So now we are getting some arguments passed in.
If they are provided we do one thing.
If they're not provided we do something else.
I'm going to save index not J S.
Once again I am going to run that exact same query and this time around I get Hello Jess printing.
If I were to query for greeting and leave the arguments off as expected I would get my generic message
hello.
So there we have it.
This is how we can pass data from the client over to the server.
In this example we happen to just have a single argument but that's by no means a limitation.
I could provide more if I wanted to write here after the first I could comma space and define a second.
I could call this one something like job or position and I can pick a type for this one.
I'll make this a string as well.
And then we can choose to use it down below.
So maybe I check if the name is provided and then I use the logical and operator to check if the position
is also provided.
If they're both provided I use the following message.
Hello their name.
Then after the exclamation mark another sentence you are my favorite followed by their position.
So right here we will add in args dot position.
Now I can provide both of these arguments to see my more elaborate message actually sent.
Whoops sorry for jumping around right there.
I'm going to save index dot J s over inside of graph playground.
I am going to also add the position on so comma space position setting it equal to another string and
for this one I'll just call myself a teacher or developer or whatever like that.
Now although to us once again we have to refresh the schema in order for this argument to become valid
once it is added on though.
I can click play and I get my message.
Hello Jess you are my favorite teach.
That should have been teacher.
And while I'm at it I might as well change it to the correct name Andrew.
There we go.
So we have two arguments being passed to greeting and greeting is able to use both of them because we
actually use the args object here and we have to find them up above in the queery definition.
That's where we're going to stop for this one.
Let's move into Challenge time where you're going to be creating a new query that also accepts some
arguments.
Right here there are three steps for getting this done burst up.
You're going to create a new add query that returns a float.
Then you're going to set up add to take two arguments a and b which are required of floats and you're
going to have the resolver send back the sum of the two arguments.
So in the end of the day I should be using the ADD query over here passing in a and b instead of name
and position.
Both of them should be numbers then the actual resolver is just going to add up those two numbers and
return them.
So I would expect to see the sum in the response.
So if I passed in one for a and two for B.
I would expect to see the total three come back.
So you're going to have to define the query with the correct argument definition.
You're going to have to set up the resolver that actually looks for those arguments and returns the
sum and then you're going to have to test your work by creating a query for that and actually running
it making sure you get the correct response.
Once again if you have any trouble going through this you are more than welcome to refer to any code
we've written any videos you've watched or any external resources.
Take as much time as you need to work through this.
If you get stuck try to debug then come back and click play
how that one go.
We're going to kick things off by creating the query definition.
So right here we're going to call this one add add is going to return a float.
Now we do want some arguments for ADD.
That's the whole point of this challenge and we actually want to we want a and b both of them are going
to be required floats.
So a right here is going to be a float we put an exclamation mark on there to ensure it's provided.
And the other one B is also a float also non nullable so the query definition is in place down below
we can actually set up the resolver for ad ad we set up the method.
We are also going to define our arguments.
So we have the parent we have our args we have the context and we have the info you don't need to list
out all four of them.
Listing out all four as habit.
Census is something we'll be doing later in the class right here.
It's time to use the values so we know they're going to be there so I can return args dot a plus args
dot B and that is all we have to do for the resolver.
And that is actually it for the index dot J s changes I'm going to save this file and over inside of
playground I will actually make the correct query.
I'm going to query for ADD.
I'm going to pass in the two arguments it expects a I'll set that equal to 12 and B I'll set that equal
to minus 1.
And there we go.
We just need to refresh the schema to validate all of that.
Now we can actually fire that off and what do I get back.
I correctly get back 11 if I were to change that to one and two and send the request off.
This time I get back 3.
So this is what you should've been able to get done using operation arguments.
All right.
That is it for this video.
We now know how to use operation arguments and that's going to allow us to actually use these arguments
in a real way in the next video we're going to start focusing on how we can work with a ray based data
and arguments are going to come in handy for that because as mentioned in the beginning of this video
arguments will allow us to do things like filter that data sort that the data or do whatever else we
might need to do.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.