In this video you're going to learn how to work with arrays in graph.
Q Well this is going to allow us to exchange arrays back and forth with the graphical API.
So maybe the client needs to send an array as one of the values for an operation argument.
Or maybe the server needs to send an array back as the response for a given operation.
In either case we can do just that using arrays.
Now to start off we're going to explore how we can work with arrays of our scalar types.
So an array of strings or an array of numbers.
Then we're going to move on to a more real world example and learn how we can work with arrays of our
custom types.
So an array of posts or an array of users to kick things off though we are going to start with those
scalar types.
So let's set up a brand new query for that right here.
We're going to set up a query for a grading application.
We're going to call the operation grades and we're going to set it up to return some array based data
for an array type.
We start off with square brackets much like we would if we were creating an array in java script itself.
Now after this we can also choose to put an exclamation mark on there that says we are always going
to get an array back even if it's an empty one.
If we left that off we could indeed get null back as a valid value for grades.
I'm going to leave the exclamation mark on.
So if there are no grades we'll just send back an empty array.
If there are grades we'll send back an array of numbers.
The next thing we have to do is actually specify the type for all of those array elements.
So is it an array of strings and array of integers booleans IDs what.
In this case we are going to use an array of integers where each integer represents the percent you
got on a given exam where a 10 percent would be really bad and a 99 percent would be very good.
So right here if we want an array of ints we have to specify that scalar type right here right now.
In the case of this internal type we can also choose to put an exclamation mark on or leave it off if
we leave it off.
It's nullable meaning that I could have an array where one of the elements is null.
If I add it on it is non nullable meaning that if there is an item in the array it is always going to
be an integer.
So in this example we're saying we're always going to get an array back and if there are items there
are always going to be ense.
It would still be valid to get back an empty array via this type definition.
So now that we have the actual operation defined in our type deaths.
Let's go ahead and set up the grades resolver down below.
I'm going to put that right here after AD.
And before me though the order is not important grades I will set up all of the arguments necessary
for grades even if I'm not going to use them.
It's a good idea to get into this habit for all of your resolver functions so I have parent Next up
I have ARGs that I have the context that I have info and all we're going to do is return an array of
numbers so we can pick some numbers will say that you got a 99 on the first exam then you got cocky
and didn't study and then you got an 80 and then we'll say you got a 93 on the final one.
So here we are returning an array with three integers as are three elements.
Now we can actually test out this new operation.
I am going to save index dot J S and create a new query over engraft Cuil playground.
I'll put this in a new tab just to clean up the output and we will set up the operation a query we are
querying for grades and that is it.
We can now fire off this operation.
And what do we get back.
We get back an array of all of our grades so we have our grades property with our array of those three
integers sitting right inside.
Now in this example you'll notice that we didn't provide anything after the field itself I just specified
grades.
When I did not do is provide a selection set using the curly braces like this where I specify what I
want for each grade.
This is not something we can do for an array of scalar types like an array of integers array of floats
or an array of strings specifying a selection set like that is only something we do for an array of
custom types.
So for example in the demo API we explored that when we wanted to get at Post's array back.
I had to specify which fields I wanted for each individual post.
So with an array of custom types you have to specify that selection set with an array of scalar types.
You can't.
Now in this case we are sending arrays from the server to the client.
Let's see how we could do things in the other direction and to explore this what we're going to do is
set up add to take an array of floats as opposed to specifying just two arguments.
So we'll let the user add up as many numbers as they like as many as they actually provide in that array
to start.
I'm going to delete all of the old arguments we had in place so we'll remove a and will remove B.
Now we have emptied out the premises and we can define the one argument that ad is actually going to
take.
I'll call this something like numbers and this is going to be an array of all of the numbers that you
want to have added up.
So right here for the type definition we will have something very similar to what we had right here
though instead of an array of our ints it will be an array of floats.
So I specify my array.
I'll put the exclamation mark back there.
Meaning that you have to provide the numbers argument then inside of there.
It's an array of floats so float with an exclamation mark.
And there we go.
We are now always going to get an array and when there is an item in the array we know that item is
indeed going to be a float.
With this in place with our type definition actually changed we can go ahead and use this new array
argument down below in the resolver add.
So we can start by removing all of the existing code.
And now we can actually look at args dot numbers to figure out how many numbers we need to add up.
Let's start by checking if there are actually any numbers to add.
So we know there's going to be an array but it might be an empty array.
So we can use an if statement if we're going to check args dot numbers which we know is going to be
an array.
And we're just going to look at its length property.
If the length is indeed equal to zero what are we going to do.
I'm just going to return 0.
So we'll say that if you don't add up any numbers you're going to get ZERO back.
The next thing we want to do down below is run some code for when the numbers length is not zero.
So when there are actually array items to add and for this we're going to use the very popular very
common array reduce method.
If you've never used reduce before it's a handy array method for reducing an array to a single value.
In this case we are trying to reduce an array of numbers to just a single number.
You can always learn more about it by googling and D.N. reduce that'll bring you over to the Mozilla
developer network page for the array reduce method.
We're going to go ahead and actually implement this right here.
And for our purposes let's say we have some sample data being passed in.
Let's just say it's one of five 10 and two so down below.
What are we going to do.
I'm going to return a value that value is going to be the value that comes back from calling args dot
numbers dot reduce.
So here we are just calling reduce on our array sending the return value back as the return value for
ADD.
Now we have to provide a function to reduce.
So we provide a single callback function right here like we do for most of our RE methods such as for
each map and others.
And this it's called with two arguments the first argument is called the accumulator and the second
argument is called current value.
Now if you have an array of a single item and that single item value is always going to be the return
value for reduce this callback function will actually never fire.
It is only when we have at least two items that this callback function comes into place.
So the first time this function runs it is going to have the accumulator value equal to the first item
one and the current value will equal to the second.
Item 5 in this case and it's our job to reduce that to a single value by returning something.
So in this case we're trying to add numbers up.
So I can return the accumulator with the value 1 plus the current value with the value 5 resulting in
a return value of 6.
Now the next time this function runs six is the accumulator and we move on to the next item to get the
new current value.
So we have six as accumulator and we would have 10 as current value we add both of those up and what
do we get back 16.
So then the callback function runs another time with 16 as the accumulator and 2 as current value we
run that.
And what do we get back we get back 18.
And that's exactly what we would get if we added all of these numbers up.
Let's go ahead and actually test our work.
So I'm going to save index Dhananjay ass and we are going to call ad over here.
I'm going to remove my grades queery I will use the Add query operation and right away we're already
getting an error saying we have not provided the argument that it expects but it's referring to a and
b.
Let's refresh the schema to get the same error but with the in numbers argument.
Now we can actually call that passing and the correct arguments.
So numbers is the only one we have.
It is an array of numbers.
So we will set up an array of numbers.
I'm going to use the same numbers from the file 1 5 10 and 2.
I go ahead and run that operation.
And what do I get back.
I get back 18.
So in this example we're actually sending an array from the client to the server.
And now we've seen arrays going in both directions.
So we can send array data either way depending on the needs of our application.
Now in almost all cases arrays are going to be the value that comes back from the server.
It's not that common to be sending arrays from the client to the server though it is indeed possible
and sometimes necessary.
That's actually where I'd like to stop for this one.
Now we haven't talked about arrays of custom types.
That's because I'm breaking up our discussion of arrays into two videos preventing this one from getting
too long.
So in this one we explored arrays of our scalar types in the next one we'll explore arrays of custom
types and there'll be a challenge requiring you to use everything you've learned about arrays.
So far I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.