In this video we're going to continue our discussion on raise by talking about arrays of custom types.
So far all of the arrays we've worked with had been arrays of scalar types.
So an array of integers or an array of floats instead of something like an array of ints we would have
something like an array of users or an array of posts.
This is going to allow us to represent complex more real world data.
So if I want to get an array of all of the posts that someone can actually read I need an array of objects
where each object has the post-Idol the post body and other post related information.
So we're going to kick things off together by talking about how we can work with an array of users using
the user custom type.
Then as your challenge for the video you're going to be working with arrays of posts using the post
custom type defined below for the moment we're going to clean up our application.
So I'm going to remove the greeting add and grade's query.
Those were all useful for exploring various things but they're not actually going to make it into the
final version of our application.
Now down below we can actually remove the three resolver functions for those three queries we just removed.
I'm going to delete all of those.
And that leaves us with just me and post both of which will make it into the final version of our application.
What we're going to do now is add another query which will also make it into the final version of the
application.
And I'm going to call this one a user's.
This will be a way to get all users which can be very useful if you're trying to fetch all authors for
a blog for example.
Now in this case we are still going to get an array as the response value so we will still set up our
square brackets and I'll put an exclamation mark on the end.
Making this a non nullable field.
And now inside of here we have to specify the type.
It's not going to be one of our scalar types so we won't reference one of these five.
Instead it's going to be one of our custom types so will reference either user or post.
In this case for users it's an array of individual users.
So we will use the user custom type right here uppercase you user with an exclamation mark on the end
saying that we're never going to get back a null array element.
If we get back any array elements at all they will always be users.
So essentially it's an array of objects where each object matches up and is validated against this type
definition.
So each object has an ID a name and an email and each object optional has an age.
So some of the array items might have ages.
Others might not.
Now we have the queery definition in place but to see how all of this works we have to set up and fill
out the resolver function for users.
Let's set up our resolver method.
I'm going to call this one the same as the query name.
Users and we are going to set it up with all arguments even if we're not going to use all arguments.
It's just a good idea to get in that habit.
So we have the parent we have our arguments we have the context and we have the info down below what
we need to do is return an array of objects where each object matches up with this schema definition.
Now we can define the array right inside of here but I want to actually define the array up above as
some demo data.
So this data is currently going to live right here as a static array.
Later on the data will actually come from the database.
So I'll just have a little comment right here.
Demo user data and what we're going to do is define an array of a couple of users right here.
Konst users will be an array of objects.
And let's go ahead and define three users for our example purposes.
I'm going to have this first user be myself.
So for the idea I can use whatever I want.
I'll use the number one for the name.
I'm just going to use my first name you can use your first name and for the email I'm just going to
use my first name at example dot com Sarratt here.
Email Andrew at example dot com.
Perfect.
Now this user does indeed meet the minimum criteria for a user object so we have an idea.
We have a name and we have an email with the correct type for each.
Now at this point we could also choose to include an age though it is not necessary per myself.
I will include my own age.
So right here another property age setting an equal to my age 27.
Now this is just one user we can add a couple of more users into the mix to keep things interesting.
Right here I'm going to add a couple of other users.
The next one ID to name I'll use something like Sarah which I had for the demo API.
And then for her e-mail I will use Sarah at example dot com.
And for Sarah I can leave her age off that is valid as well.
Last hour the third and final user id 3 name I'll use something like Mike and then for the email I will
use Mike at example dot com.
Perfect.
So now what do we have.
We have three users and each of these users match up with the schema definition for what a user type
should look like.
At this point we can actually set up users to correctly return that data.
And that's going to be a pretty easy process.
All we have to do is return users just like that.
With this in place we can now save index data J S and actually test out this query over engraft UL playground.
I'm going to remove the ADD queery which no longer exists and we're going to query for the users instead.
Now we do have to refresh the schema in order to actually get the latest.
But this is still invalid because remember we're not getting back an array of scalar types.
We're getting back an array of custom types.
So we do have to provide a selection set specifying what we want from each individual user.
Do I want their ID their name their email her age a combination of multiple fields.
Let's go ahead and say we just want their ID.
This is a perfectly valid query.
We could go ahead and run that.
And what do we get.
We get an array of users back where each one just has the ID property we have ID one ID to an id 3.
I could also choose to add on the other fields I could add on name.
I could add on email and I could add on age requesting everything the server has to offer about a user.
And when I do that what do I get.
I get all of the data back.
Now you'll notice that when I do have an age I get back that age as an integer when I don't have an
age I get back Knol saying that this value does not exist and that's OK because remember age is completely
optional.
There is no exclamation mark after that type definition which means that it is a nullable field.
In this case getting null back is a ok.
Now we didn't get back something like the id the name or the email that would indeed cause a problem
because all three of those are indeed required.
Now this is a fantastic first step but typically when we're working with arrays of our custom types
we want to provide other functionality to the client.
Maybe we want to give them a way to sort the data or a way to filter the data so I could sort alphabetically
by name.
I could sort by age.
I could filter by the name or I could filter by ages within a specific range.
All of this is going to modify either the order in which these items come back or which items come back
altogether.
So if I were to search for just users whose name contains the letter A.
I would get back Andrew.
I would get back Sarah but the third object for Mike would not come back because Mike does not contain
the letter A.
So let's see how we can actually set some of this up using what we now know about Operation arguments
and array data types up above.
What are we going to do.
All we're going to do is set up a single argument for users and we're going to make this one an optional
argument.
So right here I will set up my parentheses.
I'm going to call this one query and query is going to be an optional string.
So if you don't provide query will return all of the users like we currently do.
If you do provide query though we're only going to return users whose name contains the string you provided.
So the query definition is all set up.
Let's go ahead and actually make the necessary changes to users down below.
I'm going to start from a nice clean slate and the first thing we're going to do is see if that argument
was provided or not.
If it wasn't provided we'll just return all of the users like we did previously.
If it was provided we'll add a bit more complex logic to actually return just that users who match the
query to start we'll set up our IF condition.
And in this particular condition we are going to take a look at args dot queery and we're going to run
the code.
If it does not exist.
So if the query wasn't provided or if it was something like an empty string in either case we have nothing
we can actually filter by.
So I will just return all of the users like we had previously.
Now down below this code is only going to run if there is a query actually worth using and what we're
going to do is return another array by using the user's data filter array method.
So right here we provide our callback function.
This function gets called one time for each item in the array.
Since we have an array of users we can call the individual item a user.
We return true if the item is should be kept in the new array.
We return false if it should be filtered out.
So in this case I want to return true when the user's name contains the query.
Let's go ahead and do this in a case insensitive way so we're going to convert everything to lowercase
making sure that the case provided does not come into account when actually doing the thing.
We'll start off with the user's name.
So right here I'm going to return.
We're going to look at user name and we're going to convert it to a lower case.
Then on this string we'll be using the includes method to check if that includes a another string.
If it does we'll get true back meaning that the item will indeed be kept in the new array.
If it doesn't contain the other string will get false back meaning the item will be filtered out.
Right here what's the other string we're trying to search for it is args dot query.
But once again we want to make this completely case insensitive so I'll be converting this to lower
case as well.
And there we go with just a couple of lines of code.
We now have a way to filter our users by their name.
I'm going to save index dot J S.
I am going to rerun the query over here and you'll notice that it still works as expected because the
query argument is optional.
If I wanted to though I could provide it.
Let's go ahead and do that as well.
So right after users we set up our list of arguments we're going to be providing just that one query.
The value is a string so I will set it up as such.
And for the moment I will adjust.
Search for upper case a.
Now we are still getting an error saying this is an invalid and an no an argument.
But if we refresh the schema that will go away.
We can now fire off this operation.
And what do I get back.
I get back.
Andrew and Sarah the two users that have a in their name and you'll notice that while Sarah only has
lower case is the uppercase a query.
Still indeed matches correctly because it is indeed a case insensitive search and this is more like
what we're going to have in the real world.
Sure I wanna get a raise of custom types back but I want to be able to filter and sort that data allowing
me to get just the data I need in the right order.
Now if we provided a query like Q Which didn't match any users names what would we get back.
We would get back an empty array which is perfectly fine.
In this case we're just saying there are no search results matching your search criteria.
Now that we have worked through the users example what I'd like to do is something similar for posts
though that is going to be your challenge for the video.
You're going to create some new sample data.
You'll be setting up a new query with its own arguments and you'll be setting up a resolver function
for the query you create.
So let's go out and talk about exactly what I'd like you to do and I'm going to paste some comments
up top.
There are five steps to getting this done.
Step one is to set up an array of three posts with a dummy post data.
So just like we set up an array of users you're going to have an array of posts where each post has
these four required fields.
Now once you have these dummy data set up you're actually going to use it by creating a post's query
and resolver that returns all of the posts just like we returned all of the users.
A bit earlier in this video.
Step three is to test out the queries so far making sure you actually get all of the dummy posts back.
Step 4 and 5 revolve around you actually adding a query in you're going to add a query argument and
this is going to allow you to search for posts by the title or the body.
So if I provide the search term it something like Test you would search the title and the body.
And as long as one of them contain the search term test that post would be considered a match and should
come back.
If the queery value is nowhere in the title and it's nowhere in the body that one is not a match and
that post should not come back.
Step 5.
Run a few sample queries.
Searching for various posts by titles and bodies making sure you get the correct data back.
So essentially we're doing something very similar to what we did with users though slightly different
since we're working with a different custom type.
Take as much time as you need to knock that out.
Feel free to refer to anything we've done so far including what we just used in this video to get this
done for users.
All right.
Pause the video.
Knock this out.
Test your work and when you're done click play
how how'd you do.
Hopefully you were able to knock that out without too much trouble.
A little trouble is always a good thing.
It means you're pushing your abilities forward.
So let's go ahead and actually knock this out step one.
Setting up an array with some dummy post data.
I'm going to do that down below and I'll just create a concept called post to get that done right here.
An array of objects.
Let's go ahead and add three for the first post.
I'll set up an idea of 10 I'll set up a title of something along the lines of graph Well 1 0 1 for the
body value I can use whatever I like.
This is how to use graph Q QOL for example.
And then a published value to wrap this one up published for this one I'll say is true.
We're going to add a couple of more posts real quick to have some interesting data in the mix ID of
11 for the second one.
I can use a title of graph Well 201 for this one for the body for this one.
I'll say something like this is an advanced graph.
Q Well post then the published value.
I'll say this one is not published just yet one more post and then we're all done with step 1 and we'll
have some dummy data to actually work with ID 12 title I'll use the same title from the demo app programming
music then right ear for the body.
I could leave the body blank if I wanted to.
Maybe I haven't started this one yet and I'll leave the published value set to false.
So right here published false.
Perfect.
So we have our three posts all set up and they all match up with the schema defined down below for what
a post actually is.
Now we've done step 1 and we can move on to Step 2 which is to set up a post's query and resolver that
returns all of the posts so down below where we have our type definition.
I'm going to set up posts.
I'm not going to set up any arguments just yet.
And we are going to return an array of posts so right here we have our array definition.
Then we define the individual elements.
In this case it is a post perfect down below.
We can define the resolver for that new posts query right here posts.
I will set up all of the arguments we have the parent.
We have our arguments we have the context and we have the info.
Then all we're going to do is return every single post that exists by returning the posts array.
This wraps up step 2.
And now we can actually move on to Step 3 to make sure things are working well so far so we're not all
done but I do want to take a moment to actually test the query out and make sure we're at least headed
in the right direction.
So right here I can create a new tab.
I'll make sure to refresh the schema.
I am going to query for posts specifying my selections set and I'm gonna grab all of the fields so I'll
grab the ID.
I'll grab the title.
I'll grab the body.
And finally I will grab the Post's published status.
Excellent we can go ahead and fire off this query and what do we get back.
I get back and array posts with three objects.
We have our first post.
We got the second one and down below we have our third one.
So there we go.
We've successfully completed the first portion of the challenge.
Now what I wanted you to do was add a way to query by the post title or body via a single query argument.
So let's go ahead and move through the process of actually setting that up.
Step 1 is going to be to change our type definition.
So once again we have to provide you the arguments that we want this query to be able to accept.
We're going to have one called query which will be an optional string like it was for users above.
Now we have to make some changes to the code down below to actually knock this out.
So right here I'm going to check if there was no query provided.
If there is no args dot query I am just going to return all of the posts like we were doing previously.
If there is a query we're actually going to use filter once again to just return posts that actually
match the query provided I'll be returning whatever comes back from calling posts.
DUP filter.
I'm going to provide that callback function which will get called with an individual post so I can set
up the post argument and what I'm going to do is perform those checks.
I'll check if the title is a match that I'll check if the body is a match.
Then I will return true if either of them were matches and false.
If both of them or not matches.
So right here Konst is title match.
For example I can set that up to check the title.
So I'm going to look at the post title.
I'm going to convert it to a lower case like I did previously.
I am then going to use includes to see if the query is contained inside the title or right here.
That would be args.
Doc query.
To lower case.
So that is going to be either true or false.
And we're going to do the same thing for the body is body match where we look at the posts body property.
Converting that to lower case and checking if that converted string includes the queries.
So once again ARGs that query to lower case.
Now maybe you didn't create separate variables for these.
That's perfectly fine.
There are a lot of different ways you can solve this challenge.
Next up we are going to return.
Whoops not retry.
We are going to return it spelled correctly and we're going to return.
The following is title match.
Then we're going to use the logical or operator is body match.
So as long as one of these are true the item will be considered a match.
If both of them are false the item won't be considered a match.
So if neither of them match the actual query the post won't be returned as long as either the title
or the body match it will be returned.
Now we've we did step four.
We've actually set up that queery argument and we can move on to Step 5 and run a few sample queries
right here let's just modify the operation.
I will specify queery providing a string value and I will refresh the schema.
So this is actually valid.
And then we can make a few choices.
Let's start with graphs.
Well something that is contained in the title and body for two of our posts.
So right here I'm going to run that.
And what do I get back I get back just two of those.
Now maybe I search for something like advanced if I run that I just get back the one post that has advanced
in the body.
Last up I could run something like music here I get the programming music post.
I could also run a query that returns nothing.
Let's go ahead and search for something like javascript.
In this case what do I get back I get back in no posts letting me know that there are no posts related
to javascript and there we go.
We now have a post's query all set up and you were able to knock that out on your very own.
Let's go ahead and remove the challenge comments and that's where we're going to start for this one.
We now know how to work with arrays of scalar types and arrays of custom types.
And that's going to allow us to create real world API.
Because remember as mentioned earlier in the class all real world data is essentially arrays.
I have an array of orders and array of products and array of users all of the things that make up our
application.
Our arrays of objects.
So we're going to do it from here on out is explore how we can add some relationships between these.
For example users have a set of posts they've written and each post has an author which links to an
individual user so we don't just want to have data set up.
That's not related.
All of this data is relational and we want to make sure that graphed Well actually respects that.
So we're going to see how to start this process off in the very next video which I am super excited
to get to.
So stay tuned and I'll see you then.