In this video you're going to start to learn about relational data.
Engraft Well that's going to allow us to set up relationships between our types.
Currently we only have the user type and the post type but even their relationships exist for example
every post is written by some user and a user can have a collection of posts they've actually worked
on.
So maybe I have 15 different posts or maybe it's fifty five.
What we need to be able to do is set up a relationship between these two and graphs you can get that
done.
No problem.
To explore what this is going to allow us to do I want to jump back into the visualization from earlier
in the course for just a minute.
This is the exact visualization we used earlier in this section to explore what a graph was.
Now we can see that these circles really represent our custom types then down below we have all of the
fields for those types.
So we have user with their fields post with those fields and we have comment which we'll create soon
with fields of its own.
But we have yet to express with graphs.
Well is the relationship between our types and that is what I want to start to focus on.
We're going to focus on the relationship between a user and a post.
So a post has an author property which gives us access to the user so we can that access whatever fields
we need and a user is going to have a post's property which will link to all of the posts that user
actually created.
This is going to allow us to perform some much more interesting and real world queries.
Currently we could set up a query like this.
I ask for all of the posts and I get the idea and title for each something we've actually done before.
What we haven't done before though is to ask for other information about each post like the author's
name which would look a bit more like this here.
I'm not just asking for info about the post.
I'm also following one of the Post's relationships to get some info about the author in this case just
the author's name and remember engraft.
Well it's up to the client to request what data they need.
So I could also choose to add on more.
Maybe I also decide I want the comments for each post as well.
So a query like this would be perfectly valid.
What we need to figure out how to do though is to set up those relationships to get things to work.
As I mentioned we're just going to focus on the author property on post and a post's property on user
just these two relationships and will focus on all the other ones throughout the class.
All right let's jump out of the visualization and back to the editor before we make any changes to our
application code.
I actually want to explore these relational queries by heading over to the demo API which already has
support for them.
So once again you can head over to graft UL hyphen Denno dot Meade dot.
Oh now we have a few of the queries we made earlier in this section.
For example we have this one where we get the ID for every single post.
We could also choose to grab other fields for each post like the title.
And this is exactly what we had in the visualization where I was getting two fields for every single
post.
Now let's say we want to also get the author's name for each post.
How exactly do we get that done.
First up I am going to make the left side a bit smaller to prevent any text wrapping over here.
Then when we're going to do is crack open the schema and head over to the Post's query.
Here we have all of the fields available on each post.
The first four we already explored the type for each being one of the scalar types.
We have ID of the type ID.
I have title and body of the type string and I have published of the type.
Boolean.
What's a bit more interesting is the relational types down below.
I have author which is of the type user and I have comments which is an array of the type comment.
These are the two that were eventually going to set up for post.
For now though let's just focus on this author field.
So if I actually clicked that what do we get we get the user definition.
So what does a user have.
We have ID name email posts and comments.
So what I want to be able to do is get all posts for each post I want to get the ID the title and the
author for the author.
I just want to get the ID and the name.
So let's see how we can set that up.
We're going to add author alongside of the other fields we request for each post.
So right here we're going to add author right alongside of ID and title author.
Perfect.
Now you'll notice that we're getting an error for this and this error should look familiar.
Field author of type user must have a selection of subfields.
Did you mean author with curly braces after it.
Remember when we are trying to queery and we're querying a custom type we can't just get everything
it has to offer.
We have to be specific about what we want.
We saw that with posts in this example and if I go back over to one of the first queries we ran we saw
that with me I couldn't just ask for me.
I had to ask for specific fields on me.
So let's go back to the query we're currently working with and what we're going to do is provide that
selection set right here.
I'm going to open and close a set of curly braces.
Like I mentioned earlier we can pick whatever fields we want from the user.
I'm going to say I just need the ID and the user's name.
Now if we go ahead and run this query what do we get.
Well once again we have a single property on the data object.
So the actual structure of the response still matches the query.
We just have posts for each post.
We have the ID we have the title and we have author which is now an object on author we have ID and
nime once again matching the structure we see over here.
So the first post was indeed written by me Andrew.
So was the second post the third post was written by a different user.
In this case it was written by Sarah.
So now when we're creating our queries we can ask for all of the data we actually need we can ask for
all of the posts getting info we need but we can also get some relational data allowing us to perform
complex yet very real world queries.
I would use this query if I was trying to create a Post's page where you can see all of the posts.
Maybe the most recent coming first.
I want to see the title and who they are.
By then I would click a link to actually go over to the post page and read it.
This is the exact sort of query I would use to get that done.
Now let's get this done for our application so we can actually make this query which we will be able
to do by the end of the video.
So I'm going to go back to our graph.
Well playground.
And for the moment I'm going to remove the queery argument.
Actually I'll remove the arguments prent the C altogether.
Run that query and we get our three posts where we aren't getting are the authors.
Let's go ahead and actually set up that relationship.
So over inside of index j s what we need to do is change the type definition for our custom types if
we want them to have a relationship with another type it has to be set up explicitly in the type definition.
So what we're going to do is create a new field on post right here.
We're going to call that author and it is going to be of the type user and in this case we are going
to make that a non nullable field so every single post definitely has an author.
Someone had to create it.
In some cases it might make sense to have a relationship that is nullable.
In this case though it does not make sense.
So I am going to leave the exclamation mark on.
Now what we need to do is actually look at our application data because currently there is just not
enough information in these two arrays to actually make any association between them.
At no point are we saying which post was created by which user.
Well we're going to do to fix that is to actually add the authors ID right on the post object.
So for the first post I could add on author and I would said equal to one of the ids from above.
So I'll go ahead and use the first user with the ID of one.
Whoops there we go add my comma on and this first object is now complete with the necessary data.
We're going to do the same thing for the second post right here.
I'll add on the author property.
We'll also have this written by the first user so we'll use the ID of one once again.
Then for the last post we're going to have this written by the other user Sarah with an ID of two.
So right here I'm going to add on author with the idea of to.
Now we actually have enough data to make an association.
If someone gave you a post you could see that the idea was one for author.
You could then iterate over this array to find the correct user and you could get the users information
whether you wanted their ID their name their e-mail or their age.
Now that we have the correct data to actually do this let's figure out what it takes to make that relationship
happen.
Since we're working with the Post's query Let's go ahead and look at the posts resolver function down
below.
It's sitting right here and in the end of the day this returns an array of objects where each object
matches up with the post schema.
Now for all of our scalar types we've actually already had the data just sitting right there.
If you want the posts Id title body or published.
That was easy because the object had it all sitting right there.
But with our new field author we need to get a user object which we do not have.
Currently we just have a string.
We have the user's ID so when we're setting up a field whose value is another one of our custom types
we have to define a function that tells graph Q Well how to get.
In this case the author.
If we had the post so we're actually going to do that by defining a new root property on resolvers.
So along side of queery not inside of query we're going to add a new property down below after our query
object definition.
We're going to set up a property that matches up with our type post.
This is going to be an object and we're going to set up a method for each of our fields that actually
link to another type.
In this case that is just author.
So for the moment on this post object I I'm going to define just author and is a resolver method exactly
like the ones we've already explored up above we get access to the same set of arguments.
I have a parent I have my args I have my contacts and I have my info.
And this time around the goal is to return the correct author for the post.
The question is how do we do that.
I need some information from the post object like the author property which contains that ID.
Well the good news is that the post information lives right here on the parent argument so he can use
that to figure out which user object needs to get returned.
Missile process can seem a little weird.
So let's go ahead and actually change our query and talk about what graphical is going to do.
Right here I am going to change it to ask for the author and on the author I am just going to get the
author's name.
Now if we were to run this it would currently fail.
But let's talk about what's going to happen when we do run this.
The first thing graphed you Elgar's going to do is it's going to run the resolver function for the posts
queery so out of all of our code this is the function that's going to run in this case since we're not
calling it with any arguments.
This would run and all of the posts would be returned.
In this case we have three posts now grant you all is going to see what data was requested.
If we just had scalar types that's where things would end because all of the scalar types exist on the
array of posts.
In this case though we've also asked for author author does not live on there.
So what's graphed you going to do.
Graft well for each individual post is going to call this function.
It is going to call it with the post object as the parent argument.
So for the first post it is going to call this method where parent is that first post object for the
second post.
It is going to call this method a again where parent is that second post object.
And as you guessed for the third and final post it is going to call this method again where a parent
is that third post object.
That means on parent we can access things like the post ID parent id.
I could access the title parent title I could access the body I could access published.
I can also access author which is what we want.
So parent dot author is that string the string we have right up here.
It's 2.
Or in the case of the first two posts it's one we can now use that to iterate over the user's array.
Finally correct user and return it.
That's exactly what we're going to do right here.
Let's go ahead and get that done.
I am going to return.
I am going to call users dot find find is similar to filter though it is going to match an individual
array item.
So in this case it will match the first one whose callback function returns true.
Giving us back an individual user object.
So right here we set up our callback function.
It gets called one time for each user until we find a match.
So I'll call the argument user and it's our job to return true if it is a match and false.
Otherwise I'm going to return true.
If user data ID equals the parent dot author property.
So if those are equal we know we've found the match and that user object will get returned if they're
not equal.
We'll continue looking through the user's array and this is it.
This is all we have to do to get the query over here to actually work.
Let's go ahead and save index dot J s head over to the graph.
You will play ground and actually run it.
I'm going to fire off that queery And what do we get back.
We get back our author name for every single post which is fantastic.
Right here we have graphed UL 101 with the author named Andrew.
I have GRATHWOHL 201 also written by Andrew and finally programming music written by Sarah.
Now we can actually use a little bit of that relational data inside of our queries.
I can get all posts and for each post I can get some information about the author.
Now currently this relationship goes in a single direction.
So if I go up to my types the post type has a link to the user type via that author property but the
user type does not have a link to the post type.
We are going to set that up via the Post's property.
So if I do have a user I can access all of their posts.
That would be very useful if I'm showing an author's home page on the site and I want to show just the
posts written by them.
So we're going to figure out how to knock all of this out in the next video.
That's going to allow us to have that relationship set up in both directions.
I know there hasn't been a challenge with relationships yet.
I will give you a challenge where you're going to have to set up the new type comment and set up relationships
with our existing types.
That's all coming up very soon.
For now though let's focus on setting up this relationship between the user and the post via a new posts
field on user.
That's happening in the very next video so stay tuned and I will see you then.