Welcome back.
As promised we're going to be setting up the relationship between the user and the post via a new posts
field onto the user type.
So right here that would be posts and the actual type for posts is going to be exactly the same as the
type for the posts query up above.
We have an array with the individual items being a post that is exactly what we'll have below as well.
So posts is an array a non nullable array.
And inside of there we will have it not at nullable posts.
Excellent.
So this is something we've already done.
We have the exact same code right here where we need to do though is teach graphically well how to get
the posts for a user when it has the user.
This is similar to how we talk graphed well how to get the author when it has the post so down below.
We had already set up post author what we need to set up now is user posts.
Remember if one of our fields is not a scalar type we have to set up a custom resolver function to teach
graph UL how to get the correct data.
So down below after the post object I'm going to add a nother object called user uppercase U user.
And we're going to add a single method posts setting up all of the arguments we know we get we get parent
we get args we get the context and we get info.
Now inside of here what do we have access to what we have access to the user via parent.
Let's visualize this by changing one of our queries over engraft playground.
We had this query we used a little while ago to fetch all of the users and we do get all of the users
back what we want to be able to do that was also get all of their posts.
So right here I would want to be able to access posts picking which fields I want from each post.
Let's say I want the ID and the title so I can show a little preview of all of the user's posts on their
author home page for example.
Now what's going to happen when this query actually runs.
First up it is going to run the resolver method for our users query that lives just up above.
So it is going to run this method.
Now when it returns a value it is going to check if we have requested any of those relational types.
So if we just asked for ID or name or email or age that's it.
Whatever data comes back is going to be the data that comes back in the response.
But if it's see is that McQueary query has asked for relational data in this case posts it is going
to call the user posts method for every single user at found.
So if this function returns six users it's going to call this method six times.
In our case this method is going to return just three users so it will call this function three times.
Each time it calls it it'll be calling it with a different value for parent.
It will be calling it with each of those three objects which means that we can access things like the
parent id the parent name and the parent email we can access anything on the user object.
Now what are we actually going to do.
Well what we're going to do is use the filter method on posts to find just the posts whose author property
matches up with Parent ID.
So that would look a little bit like this.
I will return posts that filter I'm going to pass in that callback function.
We have an array of posts so I'll call the individual item a post and we want to return true if this
post belongs to this author represented by parent.
So right here I will return Post dot author checking if that equals Parent ID.
So if the post's author property matches up with the parents id property we know we've found a match
and will associate that post with that user.
Now what we can actually save index dot J s over inside of the graphical playground I can refresh my
schema.
We can see this is now a valid query and I've actually fire it off.
What do we get.
We get exactly what we would expect for each user.
We have a new posts property its value is an array and it is an array of posts.
So here I can see that Andrew has two posts.
We have graphed Cuil 101 and graph 201 and down below I can see Sarah has a single post programming
music.
And finally we have Mike Mike has no posts.
So what comes back we get back an empty array.
So now we have our relationship set up in two directions given a post we can access its author via the
author property given a user we can access all of their posts via the host's property.
With these relationships set up we can actually do some pretty silly things.
For example over inside of our query I could start with the users then get the users posts then from
the posts I could go back and get the author.
Now this doesn't serve much of a real world purpose but it is indeed valid and totally possible.
So right here I can run this and well we are going to get some redundant data since the ID and name
already exist right here.
The query does indeed work.
So I have my user object that I have the posts object than in there.
I have author with the author object all have the correct fields specified in the query.
Now we might not do something like this because we're asking for the same data over again but once we
set up other custom types and other relationships it'll make a bit more sense.
Maybe for example I want to get old users get all of their posts and then get some comments for the
individual posts.
That's something that's a bit more practical and could serve a real purpose.
So that brings us to the third custom type.
We're gonna need for this application for now which is the comment type So we're going to have a comment.
A comment is associated with a user but a comment is also associated with a post a comment belongs to
a post but a user also wrote it.
And that's what we're going to focus on for the rest of this section.
It is going to be a series of challenges requiring you to use everything you've learned so far in this
section.
Since we are getting to the end of this section on queries I'm really excited to get into this series
of challenges.
Let's go ahead and jump right into the next video and get started with the very first one.