This section is coming to a close and I'd like to wrap up this section with a series of challenge videos.
So it's either going to be two or three videos that's two or three challenges where you're going to
be required to use everything you've learned about graft.
Well in the course so far had some brand new functionality to our application.
The big picture goal is to create the new comment type.
It set up some data for it then create some queries and some relationships between the comment type
and our other types.
That's what we're going to end up accomplishing throughout all of these challenges.
But I'm going to break it up into individual chunks to keep things digestible and actually solvable.
So in this one we're not going to worry about any of the relationships we're just going to worry about
creating some dummy comment data.
Setting up a comment type and creating a new query that we can use to access all of the comments in
our application.
So right here there are a few steps for getting this done.
This is part one.
So step one set up a comment type with ID and text fields.
So we only need these two and both should be non nullable So the ID field of the type ID needs to exist
and the text field of the type string needs to exist.
Next up you're going to create for comments that match up with the comment type so you can create for
comments with whatever ID and text values you want just make sure the ID is unique and not used by any
of our users or posts.
Step 3 you're going to be setting up a comments query with a resolver that returns all of the comments.
So much like we have a user's query and a post's query you're going to be adding a comments query into
the mix and the final step for this first part is to run a query and get all four comments back.
So make sure that the query you've set up and all of the data is actually returning as expected.
Remember don't worry about any relationships between the comment or the user or the Post.
We'll talk about those in the next video.
For now we're just setting up the basic infrastructure to let us eventually set up those relationships.
So it takes some time to knock this one out.
Take as much time as you need.
Pause the video go through other videos if you forget how something works.
Feel free to use Google any resources out there are totally fair game for these challenges.
All right Bob the video when you're done come back and click play.
How did you do.
Hopefully you were able to knock that out without too much trouble.
Let's go ahead and dive right in.
I'm going to start with step one.
Setting up that comment type.
So down below in our type definitions we can add a brand new one a third one right here.
A third custom type type uppercase C comment.
And for this one remember we just need two fields.
We need our ID of the type ID.
And we're also going to add the text for the comment of the type String both being non nullable perfect.
That's all we had to do for step one.
Step two is to create a comments array with four comments.
So we need some sample data later on this data will come from a database right now.
These arrays are getting the job done as we explore the basics of graft well.
So Konst comments equals an array of objects and we're going to add four into the mix.
The idea for this first one could be something like 102 and I'll set up the text.
This worked well for me.
And then I'll say thanks.
The next comment I'll give you an idea of 103.
And for this one we'll say it's a reply to that comment.
So something like.
Glad you enjoyed it.
And then we'll add a couple of more into the mix right here Id 104 text value of this did not work and
then we'll add one final comment right here.
Id 105.
And then I'll say something like.
Text.
Never mind.
I got it to work.
Perfect.
So now we have some sample comment data that we can actually use when we're working with graphs well
and this brings us to step three.
We want to set up a comments queery and a resolver that returns all of the comments so all four comments
that I just created.
Let's go ahead and actually knock this out right here on the query typedef.
So we have users we have posts we are going to set up comments.
We are not going to set up any arguments and we are going to return an array what's inside of the array.
It has individual comments referencing the comment type.
Excellent.
Now the other part of step three was to create the resolver for this new query.
So down below in our query object we're going to have to set that up.
I'll set up comments right here.
We can set up all of those arguments to parent args context and info.
Even though we haven't used all of them and what are we going to do inside of here this one is super
simple.
All we do is we return the comments array we're going to return all the comments no matter what.
And that brings us to the final step.
Step Four which is to actually make a query using the new comments operation and see if that works as
expected.
So I'm going to go ahead and save index dot J s over here inside of localhost 4000 I'm going to crack
open a new tab will perform a query operation at the query that I'm going to use is comments there are
no arguments for this so I won't add any.
And then we can decide what we want from each comment.
I'm going to grab everything I'm going to grab the ID and I'm going to grab the text.
Let's refresh the schema.
To load in the latest right here we now have a perfectly valid query.
I can go ahead and run this.
And what do I get back.
As expected I get back my comments.
So right here I have the comments property n data.
It's an array of objects where each object represents an individual comment and each of these objects
has an ID and a text value.
We have all four comments that we set up Id 102 103 104 and 1 0 5.
So that brings us to the end of this first challenge.
We now have a comment type in place and it's working really well in the next video.
We're going to move on to the next part of this little challenge series where it's going to be up to
you to set up relationships between our comment type and the other types in our application.
I'm really excited to get to part two.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next video.