In part one for our little challenge we set up the basics of the comments type in this video part two.
We're going to start to focus on the relationship between the comment type and the other types in our
application.
And this video specifically will be focusing on the relationship between the comment and the user will
focus on the relationship between the comment and the post in the next video.
So up above let's go ahead and remove the challenge comments from the last video and I'm going to paste
in the part to challenge comments.
Now I know this might seem like a lot of information.
I just wanted to give you discrete steps you could follow to knock this out.
The first thing you're going to do is set up an author field on the comment type Saddam Blough like
we have an author for a post.
All comments are also going to have an author associated with them who wrote the comment.
So that's step one just setting up that property there.
Step two they're going to update all the comments in our array of data to have the new author field
and you're going to have the value be one of the user IDs similar to what we ended up doing with posts.
So all of these comments need to be associated with one of our users via the author property whose value
is the string ID.
That brings us to step three create a resolver for the comments author field that returns the user who
wrote the comment.
This is very similar to what we did for the post's author field down below.
You have to create a resolver for the comment author field.
That brings us to the next steps are right here we have a step for you can run a sample query that gets
all of the comments and gets the author's name.
So if at all comments like we do here but also choose to include the author's name by accessing that.
Now steps 5 6 and 7 are the same thing in the other direction.
So you're going to set up a comments field on the user then you're going to set up the resolver for
user comments to return all of the comments that belong to that user.
And then finally run a sample query.
So fetch all users and also include all of the comments they've made.
So this is similar to what we did with posts a user has the Post's property and user is also going to
have the comments property.
So in the end of the day when I have a comment I should be able to get the author.
And whenever I have a user I should be able to get all of the comments they've written.
So we're going to run and run those two queries to verify everything is working as expected.
All right.
Take a moment to pause the video and knock this out then run some sample queries making sure you can
actually get to everything pause the video.
Test your work when you're done come back and click play.
How'd you do.
Hopefully you were able to knock that out without too much trouble.
I'm going to kick things off by adding the author field on to comment so down below.
We already have comment.
I'm just going to add author on here and sense every single comment is going to have an author associated
with it right here.
User not unknowable perfect.
That brings us to step two.
Step two is to update the actual comments array to include the author field.
So I'm going to say that this first comment came from Mike that would be our third user.
So right here.
Author his ID for Mike.
That is three then I'll say that this one is a response from myself.
The first user.
So right here I'll have an author value of one.
Then right here I will use the second user.
So an author a value of two.
And then finally I'll use myself again.
So author of one and the end of the day it doesn't matter what you did for these values as long as all
of the author fields have a value that matches up with one of the three IDs up above.
All right so that is the end of step two step three Kriti resolver the comments author field that returns
the user who wrote the individual comment.
So down below we're doing something similar to what we did with posts.
So right after the post property I can add on the comment property I can set up my object and once again
we're going to add a single method inside of year author and we're going to have all of those same arguments
parent args context and info.
Perfect.
Now it's the job of this function.
Given the comment the parent to return the correct author.
So right here I am going to return.
I'm going to use user's dat find to find a specific item from this array.
Here we are going to get access to the individual user.
And what am I going to do.
I'm going to return true if the user's I.D. matches up with the comments author property.
That would be parent dot author.
Excellent.
So we have that in place and then actually brings us to step 4 where we test out this initial piece
to the puzzle.
So I want to make sure that I can actually actually access the author property on comments and we're
going to do that by just asking for it right here so I'm going to save index.
Yes I'm going to ask for the author and let's say in this case we just need the author's name and I
will go ahead and refresh the schema to get the latest schema.
And now we can see this query is completely valid.
If I actually go ahead and run it what do I get.
I get Mike for the first comment which is correct but I have Andrew for the second comment.
I have Sara for the third and Andrew again for the fourth.
So there we go.
We have a relationship set up in one direction so that knocks out steps 1 through 4.
We're going to move on to 5 through 7 where we set up the relationship in the opposite direction.
Let's start by setting up a comments field on user.
So down below we have our user type a user already has posts.
Let's also give a user comments it will be an array.
Any individual items will be of the comment type.
Excellent.
That's actually all we have to do for Step Five.
Step Six is to set up the resolver and actually tells graft well how to get the value for comets.
So we're going to do that way down below.
We already have user posts alongside of posts.
We're going to be adding comments so right here.
We set up comments.
I'm going to set up all of those arguments parent args context and info.
And now all we need to do is given the user determine what comments belong to then.
And we're going to do that via comments dot filter.
So right here return comments dot filter.
We are going to provide our callback function.
It's going to get called one time for each comment with the individual comment object we return true
if it does belong to that users are right here.
Return does comment dot author match up with the user's ID.
So is equal to parent dot ID.
All right.
Now we have this in place and we can move on to the final step for this challenge.
That is step 7.
Run a sample query that gets all of the comments for a user.
I'm going to do that over here inside of the browser.
I have that second tab which currently gets all of the users information and I had used that to test
the posts field.
I'm going to remove the posts field and I'm just going to ask for every user getting their ID their
name their email their age and then right here the comments they've created for each comment.
I will ask for the ID and the text getting all information about them.
I can refresh the schema run this query.
And what do I get back I get back all of my comments.
So right here for the first user we have the two comments that they've actually created for the second
user we have their comment.
And for the third one Mike we have his comment as well.
And there we go.
That is the end of this part to challenge.
We now have the relationship between our users and our comments in the next video we're going to wrap
up this section by creating a relationship between comments and posts.
So all comments belong to a specific post and all posts had a collection of comments that have been
left on that individual post.
That's going to wrap up all of the relationships we actually need for these three types.
I am super excited to get to that.
I'm going to go ahead and just wrap up this one by removing the challenge comments.
Stay tuned and I will see you in the very next video.