In this video we're going to wrap up this section and we're going to wrap up our little series of challenges
by setting up a relationship between the post and the comet.
So every comment was commented on his specific post and all posts have a collection of comments associated
with them.
So we need to be able to define in this relationship so we can do useful things like that all of the
comments for a given post when making queries with Graf.
Q Well so to kick things off.
What are we going to do.
Well I'm going to show you exactly what steps you need to take to knock this out.
And as you'll see the steps necessary are almost identical to the steps you went through in the last
video.
We're just working with a different set of types and a different set of field names.
Everything else is pretty much identical.
So once again the big picture goal here is to set up a relationship between the comment and the post
in both directions and we're going to start by setting up a post field on the comment type so down below
much like we have an author field on comment we need a post field uncomment whose value is of the post
type that brings us to step two which is to add the last piece of data for our arrays that's necessary
to get all of this stuff set up each comment needs to store the ID of the post its associated with to
update all comments in the array to have a new post field and just use one of the post IDs.
So down below for this first comment I could add on a new post property and give it the ID of 11 if
I wanted to associate it with this post.
Step 3 you're going to critter resolver for the new field you set up.
So we need to create a resolver for the post field on the comments type that returns the post for a
given comment.
So down below we have our comments object right here.
You need to add to the post method on there and set that up to return the given post when the comment
is passed and remember the comment is passed in as the parent argument.
And that brings us to step four which is to test out this association.
So you're going to make a sample query that gets all of the comments and then get a piece of information
about the post as well.
So right here we get the author for all posts what you could do is get the post title for all comments.
Excuse me.
I said author for all posts.
We get the author name for all comments.
What you're going to do to test things out is to Additionally ask for something like the host title.
All right so that is Steps 1 through 4 which is to get that association working in one direction steps
5 through 7 is to get it working in the other direction you're going to set up a comments field on it.
Post so down below on the post type we need a comments field basically identical to the one we have
on the user type and once you have that field in place what are you going to do.
You're going to set up a resolver function for it.
So we have to set up a resolver function for comments on our post object.
This is going to return all of the comments that are associated with a given post.
So once again way down below.
We have our posts object.
You're going to be adding comments on here and actually getting just the comments from the comments
Auray associated with the given post.
And remember the post will be present via the parent argument that brings you to the final step which
is to test out this association.
So you want to run a sample query that gets all of the posts and then also gets all of their comments.
So we have a query like that right here.
Currently we get all of the posts and we get the author name for each post.
You're also going to get the comments for each post.
You can just get something like the comments Text property.
All right so that is it for this challenge another one of these Association challenges.
Take some time to knock this out.
Feel free to refer to the code we wrote in any videos so far and take as much time as you need.
None of this is a race.
These challenges are designed to be as real world as possible so when you're done the class you can
actually use graphs well in a meaningful way.
Don't short change yourself with them if you get stuck.
Try to work through your issues and use the real tools that developers use to solve problems.
Use tools like Google.
Ask a friend.
You stack overflow.
Use whatever you need including the videos and the Q&amp;A to figure out how to get this done.
All right take some time.
Pause the video when you're done come back and click play.
All right let's go ahead and kick things off with step one.
We're going to set up a post field on comment so down below.
We're going to move to our comment type definition.
We're going to be setting up a new post field whose type is going to be of the post custom type and
we're going to set this up to be non-ID nullable which we've done for pretty much everything so far
except for the user's age.
And that brings us to step two which is to update the comments array and add a post field for each so
we can actually associate a comment with a given post.
So down below.
How are we going to get that done.
Well I'm just going to add post right after author for each.
I'll say that this first post is the one up above.
This guy right here the first post in the array the comment right here.
This second comment I will associate with that first post as well.
So right here the post ID of ten.
Then we have our third comment.
I'm going to associate this with the second post that is the ID of 11 and I'll use the same post for
the last comment.
So right here I'm going to use the post ID of 11 as well.
Perfect.
So now we have all of the data necessary to actually make the association between posts and comments.
Since each comment has the posts Id right inside this brings us to step 3.
Create a resolver for comments post and actually return the correct post.
So down below we have our comments object.
We have to add posts inside of here.
I'm going to add it right after author.
Though it could be before either way works.
We're going to set up all of the arguments we can get.
We have parent args context and info.
No we need to do is return the post given the comment.
So right here I will use posts that find I'm going to have my callback function which gets called one
time for each item in the array.
And what am I going to do with the post.
I'm just going to check if the posts ID matches up with the value for the comment post field.
So right here return does the post ID equal parent dot post so parent up post is the field value just
set up for each comment and we're looking to see if it matches up with the posts ID.
If it does this one is considered the match and it will be used.
And that's actually it for Step 3 which brings us to step 4 Step 4 is to test that this query this association
and at least one direction works.
So I'm going to run a sample query that gets all of the comments and also get some info about the post
for each.
Right here I have the Post's query I'm going to go over to the comments query.
I already ask for the ID and the text as well as the author's name.
I'm just going to ask Additionally for the post's title.
So post then right here title.
If I refresh the schema this query should be valid which it is.
And now we can go ahead and actually fire this off.
I fired off and what do I get back.
I get back a comments array with all four items inside of it and I have the additional post property
for each comment with the field title.
So the title for this first comment correctly graph 101.
Same thing for the second comment.
The third comment is for graph 201 and so is the last.
So now we actually have that association where given a comment I can get the post for it in the last
three steps to get that relationship working in the opposite direction.
So we want to make sure that when we have access to a post we can get all comments for that post which
is going to be important if I'm trying to render something like The Post page where someone can actually
read the post as well as read all of the comments will be starting by setting up the comments field
on our posts tight sit down below we have our posts type what we need is a comments field.
This is going to look similar to the comments field for a user.
It is an array of individual comments using the comment type.
Excellent and now we can move on to the next step.
Step 6 which is to set up a resolver that teaches graphic well how to get the correct value for that
new comments field.
So down below we have our post object on resolvers inside of here.
We're going to set up a new method comments and this is going to be responsible for actually getting
the comments back.
So we get our parent we get our args we get the context and the info and we are going to end up returning
whatever comes back from calling comments dot filter.
We want to find all of the comments that actually match up with this post.
We have an array of comments so we can call the individual item a comment and once again we are going
to return and right here we're going to set up our equality test.
So what do we want to check.
We want to check if the comment post value equals ID apparent ID.
So the comment post value is obviously the post ID and the parent in this case is a post right here
post so we're checking its ID and if these two are indeed a match then we know that this comment is
associated with this post and we're going to keep it in the IRA by returning true from the filter callback.
If it's not a match will return false sense.
That comment isn't associated with that particular post.
Now that we have this in place we can actually move on to the final step for this challenge we're going
to run a sample query we need to get all of the posts and then also get their comments.
I have that right here.
I have a query that gets all of the posts I'm going to refresh the schema.
And we're also going to ask for the comments to simplify the output of just going to remove author.
And I'm also going to remove published and body.
So here we're just asking for all of the posts getting their ID and title and then I'm also going to
ask for comments and in this case I'm going to grab the ID and the text though you could have grabbed
any combination of the two that would have been perfectly fine for the challenge as well.
Right here I am going to fire this off.
And what do we get.
We still get our three posts objects.
We have one right here.
Then down below we have our second one.
And below that we have our third the first two posts have two comments associated with them.
I have this worked well for me.
Thanks and glad you enjoyed it.
And then for the second post I have this did not work and then nevermind I got it to work.
So right here we can see the comments for each post in the third post.
Happens to have no comments.
Now that we have all of these relationships set up we can get all the information necessary.
Maybe I also want to get the post's author.
So right here I get the author and I get their name so I can display that on the page where I read the
post and maybe I also decide I want to display the name of the person who wrote the comment.
So on the individual comment I ask for the author name there as well.
Now we have a more complex but very real world query that's going to give me everything I need so I
can display some information about the post.
I can also display the comments with extra information like who actually wrote it.
So once again graft.
Well the client is who dictates what data comes back.
And as we can see this is actually very useful.
If I was on a desktop application I might run a query like this if I was on mobile I might leave comments
off and just fetch some barebones data then maybe later on I'd actually fetch the comments.
If the user determined they wanted to see them by clicking something like a comments button.
Now at this point we've learned a whole bunch about how to query data.
Currently we are reading a set of static data out of arrays we're not even reading it out of a database.
In the next section we're going to learn about the mutation operator which is going to allow us to perform
the other crud operations.
So crud create read update delete.
We have the R for Read down.
We don't know how to create data.
We don't know how to update data and we don't know how to delete data out all of that is coming up in
the next section which is covering mutations.
I am super excited to get to that and continue on learning all about graphics.
Well let's go ahead and jump right in to the next section.
I'll see you then.