Our time together is unfortunately coming to a close but we still have this one last section and there
are two important things I want to cover in the next video.
I'm going to give you some suggestions for what you can now build with what you've learned in the class.
So we're going to talk about some new features you could add to the blogging app and we'll also talk
about a brand new app.
You can build from the ground up and that would be a great way to get more practice and really solidify
what you learned in the class in the second video in this section.
I'm going to talk about where to go from here.
The class is over.
You've learned a graphic Well where should you go next on your learning journey.
I'm excited to get to both of these.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.