In this video as promised I'm going to go over a few ideas of features you could add to the blogging
application as well as another app you can build.
You can find all of this over at Lincs dot Meade dot I O forward slash graph Q Well ideas that's going
to redirect you over to a text document.
And here I have everything we're going to talk about in this video to start.
Let's talk about new features you can add to the blogging application.
This would be a great first step to take now that the class is over.
It's going to require you to use everything you've learned in the course and there are three feature
ideas I had in mind.
First up I should be able to delete other users comments if the comment is on my post.
So if I write a post about a fun hike I just went on and someone else comes in and starts to call people
names or says something offensive I should be able to delete that comment from my post.
Currently that's not possible.
The goal of the feature is to support that.
So in the end of the day you could delete your own comment on any post out there.
Or you could delete someone else's comment assuming it's on a post you've created so idea too.
I should be able to disable comments on my post.
Maybe you're writing a post and you don't want to deal with the outside world that you do want to publish.
Being able to disable comments would be a great step for that you could add something like comments
and enabled as a boolean field on the individual post.
That's something that someone could then configure when they create or update the post.
The third idea I should be able to have a pinned or featured post I want to share.
This could be set up as a featured post property on the user type.
In this case it would be the type post so it would be optional.
I don't have to have a featured or pinned post but I should be able to.
This could then be used somewhere like my author profile page to render the pinned content first.
So these are just three ideas of what you could add to the application.
Obviously there are plenty of other ones as well.
If you come up with anything else or if you implement any of these three go ahead and share them in
the Q&amp;A for this lesson.
I would love to see what you built.
Whether you added one of these features or came up with something on your own.
All right now let's talk about the new app idea.
You can build it it's going to be something we discussed a bit earlier in the class.
If you remember from when we first explored Prisma you created a little product review Prisma instance
but we never built the no JSA side of things.
So that's the goal here.
A product review website where we have users products and reviews.
Users can create products and users can leave reviews on products.
Now the product could be anything it doesn't have to be something you could buy.
It could be a review website for trails in the area or books or cities or companies to work at for a
trail as an example.
On the trail type you might have the name the distance and the location and for reviews along side of
the text they could provide something.
Maybe how difficult the trail was on a scale of 1 to 10.
For books you can have things like the title the author and the ISBN number on the book and the review
could just be a generic text only review for city you could have something like the name of the city.
Maybe a walkability score can be part of the reviews along with whether they live in the city or are
just visiting as that would affect how you wait the review.
And for a company you could have the name and the location.
Maybe even though you R-AL as part of the company type and further review you could have them include
maybe their salary and their job title along with a standard text description.
So those are just a couple of ideas of things you could review.
Obviously the list goes on and on.
For the product you would add custom fields based off of what you're reviewing and the same is true
with the review.
Just as a reminder trail had things like the location and the trail review had things like the difficulty
score.
So this would be another great thing to build with what you've learned in the class and you can use
the boiler plate project we created in the last section to get this done.
As always if you end up building this or building anything else with graphite you will.
I would love to see that once again just post it in the Q&amp;A and share what you've done whether you shared
just the code or maybe a live example of your app.
I'd love to see it.
All right that is it for this one.
Those are just a couple of ideas of things you can now build with the skills you have and at this point
it's definitely important to build something.
Maybe you'll use graft well in a professional setting in a few months or a year or maybe you're working
on switching jobs right now but it's still going to be a great idea to get some at home practice under
your belt.
That's going to make sure you remember how to solve problems and how to build applications using graft
Well that's it for now.
I'll see you in the next one.