You've made it to the end of the class you now know how to use graph Q Well and at this point you're
probably wondering where do I go from here.
Now for most of my classes I'll answer that question over and over again in the course Q&amp;A.
So this time around I figured I'd make this video giving my official recommendation of what to learn
next.
The fact that you made it to the end of the class suggests you're already pretty familiar with the back
end if you were before.
You definitely are now.
So my recommendation for you is to take some time to explore the front end to learn how to build web
applications in the browser.
Now not everyone is going to want to switch careers or do this for a living but it's definitely something
that's worth while to learn even if your primary focus is still back and development.
It's going to give you everything you need to build full stack applications.
So Down below I have two suggestions.
As always you can find all of my courses at the following you RL.
First up I have the modern javascript boot camp.
This is where I cover the fundamentals of javascript which you already know but it's also where I cover
how to use the Nela javascript in the browser which you may or may not be familiar with.
Next up my real recommendation is the complete re-act web developer course if you already familiar with
the fundamentals of javascript in the browser.
This is the class that is going to take you to the next level you'll be using react to build real world
production ready web applications with all of the features you'd expect.
Things like authentication data validation and more.
So you can always find out more by clicking over to that class.
Check out the promo video and as always the first several videos are available for you to watch for
free before joining.
And as you're working through the course you're going to end up building a couple of applications.
The first one is a little app called indecision.
This is how we're going to start exploring re-act you enter some options in.
I'll enter a new one like take a re-act course you can remove or remove ALL.
Here I can just have the computer pick for me and it says take a javascript course.
So this is our beginner application and once we're comfortable with the fundamentals of react we'll
move on to our budget app where we're going to add a whole bunch more features.
You'll learn how to build out web apps that sort by date we'll be able to sort our data in the correct
order and search for expenses as well as add new ones.
I'll add something in.
Like my gas bill which I believe was about 30 bucks I can even pick the day I paid it and I can enter
a note if I wanted to.
So if this looks like what you're interested in learning I definitely recommend checking out the complete
re-act web developer course.
That's going to give you everything you need to build front ends for your back end.
No.
J.S. apps.
All right.
That is it for me.
And that is it for the class.
I hope to see you in another class sometime soon.